<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5257</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Chaotic mixing in a bounded three-dimensional flow</dc:title><dc:creator>FOUNTAIN, GO</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAKHAR, DV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEZIC, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>OTTINO, JM</dc:creator><dc:subject>volume-preserving flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>stokes flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-dimensional maps</dc:subject><dc:subject>transfer enhancement</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminar-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>streamlines</dc:subject><dc:subject>advection</dc:subject><dc:subject>steady</dc:subject><dc:subject>symmetry</dc:subject><dc:description>Even though the first theoretical example of chaotic advection was a three-dimensional flow (HE:non 1966), the number of theoretical studies addressing chaos and mixing in three-dimensional flows is small. One problem is that an experimentally tractable three-dimensional system that allows detailed experimental and computational investigation had not been available. A prototypical, bounded, three-dimensional, moderate-Reynolds-number flow is presented; this system lends itself to detailed experimental observation and allows high-precision computational inspection of geometrical and dynamical effects. The how structure, captured by means of cuts with a laser sheet (experimental Poincare section), is visualized via continuously injected fluorescent dye streams, and reveals detailed chaotic structures and chains of high-period islands. Numerical experiments are performed and compared with particle image velocimetry (PIV) and flow visualization results. Predictions of existing theories for chaotic advection in three-dimensional volume-preserving flows are tested. The ratio of two frequencies of particle motion - the frequency of motion around the vertical axis and the frequency of recirculation in the plane containing the axis-is identified as the crucial parameter. Using this parameter, the number of islands in the chain can be predicted. The same parameter-using as a base-case the integrable motion-allows the identification of operating conditions where small perturbations lead to nearly complete mixing.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CAMBRIDGE UNIV PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T10:05:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T10:05:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF FLUID MECHANICS, 417(), 265-301</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-1120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S002211200000118X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5257</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5257</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>