<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9687</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stress analyses of laminates under cylindrical bending</dc:title><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENDHARI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>high-order theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>plate deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>refined theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>composite</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminates</dc:subject><dc:subject>composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich</dc:subject><dc:subject>runge-kutta-gill method</dc:subject><dc:subject>cylindrical bending</dc:subject><dc:subject>semi-analytical method</dc:subject><dc:subject>numerical integration</dc:subject><dc:description>A semi-analytical approach for evaluation of stresses and displacements in composite and sandwich laminates Under cylindrical bending subjected to transverse load has been developed in this paper. Two dimensional (21)) partial differential equations (PDEs) of such a laminate are obtained by imposing plane-strain conditions of elasticity. The fundamental dependent variables are so selected in this formulation that they satisfy the continuity of displacements and transverse interlaminar stresses at the laminate interface through the thickness. The set of governing PDEs are transformed into a set Of Coupled first-order ordinary differential equations (ODEs) in thickness direction by assuming Suitable global orthogonal trigonometric functions for the fundamental variables satisfying the boundary conditions. These ODEs are numerically integrated by a specially formulated ODE integrator algorithm involving transformation of a two-point boundary value problem (BVP) into a set of initial value problems (IVPs). Numerical studies on both composite and sandwich laminates for various aspect ratios are performed and presented. Accuracy of the present approach is demonstrated by comparing the results with the available elasticity solution. It is seen that the present results are in excellent agreement with the elasticity solutions. Some new results for sandwich laminates and for uniform loading condition are presented for future reference. Copyright (c) 2006 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T01:01:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T01:01:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMMUNICATIONS IN NUMERICAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING, 24(1), 15-32</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1069-8299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cnm.952</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9687</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>