<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3358</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-24T09:06:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dual-stimuli responsive PNiPAM microgel achieved via layer-by-layer assembly: Magnetic and thermoresponsive</dc:title><dc:creator>WONG, JE</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAHARWAR, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MULLER-SCHULTE, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RICHTERING, W</dc:creator><dc:subject>superparamagnetic nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyelectrolyte multilayers</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomedical applications</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface modification</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug-delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>colloids</dc:subject><dc:subject>cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>shell</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>microgels</dc:subject><dc:subject>layer-by-layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyelectrolytes</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid core-shell</dc:subject><dc:description>We describe the synthesis, characterisation and surface-modification of magnetic narroparticles and a poly(N-isopropylacrylamide) microgel, followed by the assembly and characterisation of magnetic nanoparticles on the microgel. To facilitate this deposition, the surface of the microgel is first modified via the layer-by-layer assembly of polyelectrolytes. One advantage of this concept is that it allows an independent optimization and fine tuning of the magnetic and thermoresponsive properties of individual components (nanoparticles and microgels) before assembling them so that the hybrid core-shell structure retains all the individual properties. The,decisive parameter when exploiting the thermoresponsive and magnetic properties in such hybrid core-shell structures is the amount of heat transfer from the magnetic core onto the thermosensitive (loaded) microgel (for the subsequent heat-triggered release of drugs). Inductive heat study reveals that the heat generated by the magnetic narroparticles is sufficient to cause the collapse of the microgel above its volume phase transition temperature. Successful confinement of positively and negatively charged magnetic nanoparticles between polyelectrolyte layers is achieved using the layer-by-layer deposition onto the microgel. Dynamic light scattering measurements show (i) the presence of each layer successfully deposited, (ii) the preservation of thermoresponsivity in the coated microgel, and (iii) that the magnetic nanoparticles do not get detached during the phase transition of the microgel. Electrophoresis measurements confirm charge reversal at every stage of layering of polycations, polyanions and magnetic nanoparticles. This unique combination of thermoresponsivity and magnetism opens up novel perspectives towards remotely controlled drug carriers. (c) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T14:53:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T14:53:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COLLOID AND INTERFACE SCIENCE, 324(1-2), 47-54</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9797</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2008.05.024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3358</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3358</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>