<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-210</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interpolated candidate motion vectors for boundary matching error concealment technique in video</dc:title><dc:creator>GARG, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>motion estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>vector quantisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>pattern matching</dc:subject><dc:subject>image coding</dc:subject><dc:subject>image compression</dc:subject><dc:description>The pertinency of error concealment (EC) schemes to the encoder-decoder model makes them an attractive choice to conceal the effects of transmission errors in a compressed video bitstream. Among various EC techniques, boundary matching (BM) has been the most popular due to its distortion measure criterion to select the most appropriate motion vector (MV) for damaged macroblock among a set of candidate MVs (CMVs). In a scenario where error bursts do not extend to more than one frame of digital video, the performance of BM can be highly enhanced if the CMVs depend upon an interpolation of surrounding MVs. This interpolation needs to be done, considering the change in their pattern from the reference to the current erroneous frame. This brief proposes a technique to build this novel set of CMVs and compares the results of BM with traditional CMVs qualitatively and quantitatively for MPEG test sequences.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-01T09:47:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:13:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-01T09:47:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:13:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems II: Express Briefs  53(10), 1039-43</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1057-7130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TCSII.2006.882205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/210</dc:identifier><dc:language>en_US</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>