<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4913</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Knowledge-Based Model for Supplementary Irrigation Assessment in Agricultural Watersheds</dc:title><dc:creator>RESHMIDEVI, TV</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>decision-support system</dc:subject><dc:subject>productivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>knowledge-based systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>irrigation</dc:subject><dc:subject>geographic information system</dc:subject><dc:subject>multicriteria decision analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>agricultural watershed</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil moisture</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper a knowledge-based model for supplementary irrigation assessment in rainfed agricultural watersheds is presented. The supplementary irrigation assessment problem is divided into different components and is modeled separately. Geographic Information System (GIS) is used to aggregate spatially varying attributes required for the modeling. A graphical user interface is developed in a GIS platform by using the ERDAS macro language tools. The model was applied to two case study areas in India: a subwatershed of Gandheshwari area (West Bengal), and Harsul watershed (Maharashtra). In the Gandheshwari subwatershed, the water availability was found to be inadequate to meet the irrigation requirement and hence the model identified the areas that can be irrigated with different outsource water supply. On the other hand, surface runoff generated in the Harsul watershed was found to be sufficient to meet the supplementary irrigation requirement, thereby showing the feasibility for supplementary irrigation in the area. Using the model, the effect of any rainfall condition can be simulated and hence appropriate measures can be taken in advance to reduce the risk of crop failure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T12:11:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T12:11:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF IRRIGATION AND DRAINAGE ENGINEERING-ASCE, 136(6), 376-382</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0733-9437</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)IR.1943-4774.0000206</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4913</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4913</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>