<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1461</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>A tool-suite for reachability analysis of concurrent object-oriented programs</dc:title><dc:creator>IYER, SRIDHAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMESH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>object oriented programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>reachability analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed computer systems</dc:subject><dc:description>The object-oriented paradigm provides support for modular and reusable design and is attractive for the construction of large and complex concurrent systems. Reachability analysis is an important and well-known tool for static (pre-run-time) analysis of concurrent programs. However, its direct application to concurrent object-oriented programs has many problems, such as incomplete analysis for reusable classes and increased computational complexity. It also seems impossible to arrive at a single general-purpose strategy that is both safe and effective for all programs. We propose a tool-suite based approach for the reachability analysis of concurrent object-oriented-programs. This approach enables choice of an appropriate `ideal' tool, for the given program and also provides the flexibility for incorporation of additional tools. We have also proposed a novel abstraction-based partitioning methodology for effective reachability analysis of concurrent object-oriented programs. Using this methodology, we have developed a variety of tools, having different degrees of safety, effectiveness and efficiency, for incorporation into the tool-suite. We have formally shown the safety of these tools for appropriate classes of programs and have evaluated their effectiveness and efficiency.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-11T04:08:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:11:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-11T04:08:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:11:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Asia Pacific Software Engineering Conference and International Computer Science Conference, Hong Kong, 2-5 December 1997, 160-169</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8186-8271-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/APSEC.1997.640173</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1461</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>