<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1370</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Artificial neural network models for predicting soil thermal resistivity</dc:title><dc:creator>ERZIN, YUSUF</dc:creator><dc:creator>HANUMANTHA RAO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>backpropagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermodynamic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>neural networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>clay minerals</dc:subject><dc:description>Thermal properties of soils are of great importance in view of the modern trends of utilizing the subsurface for transmission of either heated fluids or high power currents. For these situations, it is essential to estimate the resistance offered by the soil mass in dissipating the heat generated through it. Several investigators have tried to develop mathematical and theoretical models to estimate soil thermal resistivity. However, it is evident that these models are not efficient enough to predict accurate thermal resistivity of soils. This is mainly due to the fact that thermal resistivity of soils is a complex phenomenon that depends upon various parameters viz., type of the soil, particle size distribution and its compaction characteristics (i.e., dry density and moisture content). To overcome this, Artificial Neural Network (ANN) models, which are based on experimentally obtained thermal resistivity values for clay, silt, silty-sand, fine- and coarse-sands, have been developed. Incidentally, these soils are the most commonly encountered soils in nature and exhibit entirely different characteristics. The thermal resistivity of these soils, corresponding to their different compaction states, was obtained with the help of a laboratory thermal probe and compared vis-a&amp;grave;-vis those obtained from the ANN model. The thermal resistivity of these soils obtained from ANN models and experimental investigations are found to match extremely well. The performance indices such as coefficient of determination, root mean square error, mean absolute error, and variance account for were used to control the performance of the prediction capacity of the models developed in this study. In addition to this, thermal resistivity of these soils obtained from ANN models were compared with those computed from the empirical relationships reported in the literature and were found to be superior. The study demonstrates the utility and efficiency of the ANN model for estimating thermal resistivity of soils.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-18T11:42:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:19:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-18T11:42:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:19:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>International Journal of Thermal Sciences 47(10), 1347-1358</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>12900729</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2007.11.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1370</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1370</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>