<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6530</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-24T09:11:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of hydraulic retention time on the biodegradation of complex phenolic mixture from simulated coal wastewater in hybrid UASB reactors</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>sludge blanket reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>anaerobic treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>wastewaters</dc:subject><dc:subject>anaerobic processes</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>methane</dc:subject><dc:subject>coal wastewater</dc:subject><dc:description>This study describes the feasibility of anaerobic treatment of complex phenolics mixture from a simulated synthetic coal wastewater using four identical 13.5 L (effective volume) bench scale hybrid up-flow anaerobic sludge blanket (HUASB) (combining UASB + anaerobic filter) reactors at four different hydraulic retention times (HRT) under mesophilic (27 +/- 5 degrees C) conditions. Synthetic coal wastewater with an average chemical oxygen demand (COD) of 2240 mg/L and phenolics concentration of 752 mg/L was used as substrate. The phenolics contained phenol (490 mg/L); m-, o-, p-cresols (123.0, 58.6, 42 mg/L); 2,4-, 2,5-, 3,4- and 3,5-dimethyl phenols (6.3, 6.3, 4.4 and 21.3 mg/L) as major phenolic compounds. The study demonstrated that at optimum HRT, 24 h, and phenolic loading rate of 0.75 g COD/(m(3)-d), the phenolics and COD removal efficiency of the reactors were 96% and 86%, respectively. Bio-kinetic models were applied to data obtained from experimental studies in hybrid UASB reactor. Grau second-order multi-component substrate removal model was best fitted to the hybrid UASB reactor. The second-order substrate removal rate constant (k(2(s))) was found as 1.72 h(-1) for the hybrid reactor treating complex phenolic mixture. Morphological examination of the sludge revealed rod-type Methanothrix-like, cells to be dominant on the surface. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T20:18:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T20:18:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HAZARDOUS MATERIALS, 153(1-2), 843-851</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2007.09.034</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6530</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6530</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>