<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7856</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of areas for artificial groundwater recharge in Ayyar basin, Tamil Nadu, India through statistical terrain analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>ANBAZHAGAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMASAMY, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>artificial recharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>lineaments</dc:subject><dc:subject>statistical modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>ayyar basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>tamil nadu</dc:subject><dc:description>The paper presents an approach of selecting suitable areas for artificial groundwater recharge structures through remote sensing and integrated terrain analysis by statistical method. The study area "Ayyar basin" is an aquifer system of gneisses and charnockite litho-units in Tiruchirappalli district, Tamil Nadu. The area has witnessed a steady. decline in groundwater table: Hence, the scope for artificial groundwater recharge was studied in this area with the help of Tamil Nadu State Council for Science and Technology (TNSCS&amp;T). Numerical database was generated for water level, lineament density, slope, drainage density, soil type, thickness of soil, thickness of weathered zone, thickness of fractured zone and depth to bedrock through remote sensing and hydrogeological study. These nine variables were used as input parameters and factor analysis with varimax rotation was carried out. In the factor analysis, the factor in which the variables loaded significantly were considered for further analysis. Using factor scores, the domains where the water level was deeper with decrease of slope and drainage density, and increase of lineament density, thickness of soil, thickness of weathered zone, thickness of fractured zone and depth to bedrock were buffered out. The buffered domains derived from each factor were finally integrated and thus the entire study area was fragmented into a number of domains suitable for artificial recharge. Such statistical output has not only helped to identify the suitable locations for artificial recharge but also indicated their controlling terrain characteristics, thus leading to the prioritization of area for specific method of cost effective recharge.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GEOLOGICAL SOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-30T05:06:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-30T05:06:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 67(1), 59-68</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7856</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7856</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>