<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8052</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance evaluation of elitist-mutated multi-objective particle swarm optimization for integrated water resources management</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>ant colony optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>multipurpose reservoir operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>mating optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>hbmo algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>network</dc:subject><dc:subject>decision-making</dc:subject><dc:subject>multi-objective optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle swarm optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>water resources management</dc:subject><dc:description>Optimal allocation of water resources for various stakeholders often involves considerable complexity with several conflicting goals, which often leads to multi-objective optimization. In aid of effective decision-making to the water managers, apart from developing effective multi-objective mathematical models, there is a greater necessity of providing efficient Pareto optimal solutions to the real world problems. This study proposes a swarm-intelligence-based multi-objective technique, namely the elitist-mutated multi-objective particle swarm optimization technique (EM-MOPSO), for arriving at efficient Pareto optimal solutions to the multi-objective water resource management problems. The EM-MOPSO technique is applied to a case study of the multi-objective reservoir operation problem. The model performance is evaluated by comparing with results of a non-dominated sorting genetic algorithm (NSGA-II) model, and it is found that the EM-MOPSO method results in better performance. The developed method can be used as an effective aid for multi-objective decision-making in integrated water resource management.</dc:description><dc:publisher>I W A PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T08:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T08:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HYDROINFORMATICS, 11(1), 79-88</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1464-7141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2166/hydro.2009.042</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8052</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8052</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>