<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14691</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:32:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance of variable curvature sliding isolators in base-isolated benchmark building</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>FRICTION PENDULUM SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEISMIC RESPONSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEFLON BEARINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:description>The performances of variable curvature sliding isolators like variable frequency pendulum isolator (VFPI) and variable curvature friction pendulum system (VCFPS) installed in the base-isolated benchmark building subjected to bi-directionally acting seven strong earthquakes have been studied. The shear type base-isolated benchmark building is modelled as three-dimensional linear elastic structure having three degrees-of-freedom at each floor level. Time domain dynamic analysis of the building has been carried out with the help of constant average acceleration Newmark-Beta method and non-linear isolation forces has been taken care by fourth-order Runge-Kutta method. The force-displacement responses of the VFPI and VCFPS are studied under parametric variations of their key characteristics for the comparative performance evaluation. The time history variations of response characteristics and peak response evaluation criteria are also investigated for overall comparison of their performances. The performance of VFPI and VCFPS are observed both in uniform and hybrid isolation systems. The force-displacement responses of both VFPI and VCFPS subjected to strong near-field earthquakes show excessively large isolator displacements at higher initial radii of curvature of sliding surface. The large isolator displacements of VFPI and VCFPS can be restrained efficiently by addition of viscous fluid dampers in comparison to the increase in coefficient of friction of isolators. Copyright (c) 2010 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:32:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:32:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STRUCTURAL DESIGN OF TALL AND SPECIAL BUILDINGS, 21(5)354-373</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/tal.600</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14691</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>