<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15012</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:32:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Novel Algorithm for Bluetooth ECG</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDYA, UT</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>Bluetooth</dc:subject><dc:subject>fast Fourier transform (FFT)</dc:subject><dc:subject>inverse fast Fourier transform (IFFT)</dc:subject><dc:subject>moving average</dc:subject><dc:subject>root-mean-square deviation (RMSD)</dc:subject><dc:subject>serial port profile (SPP)</dc:subject><dc:subject>S-golay</dc:subject><dc:subject>signal-to-signal-plus-noise ratio (SSNR)</dc:subject><dc:description>In wireless transmission of ECG, data latency will be significant when battery power level and data transmission distance are not maintained. In applications like home monitoring or personalized care, to overcome the joint effect of previous issues of wireless transmission and other ECG measurement noises, a novel filtering strategy is required. Here, a novel algorithm, identified as peak rejection adaptive sampling modified moving average (PRASMMA) algorithm for wireless ECG is introduced. This algorithm first removes error in bit pattern of received data if occurred in wireless transmission and then removes baseline drift. Afterward, a modified moving average is implemented except in the region of each QRS complexes. The algorithm also sets its filtering parameters according to different sampling rate selected for acquisition of signals. To demonstrate the work, a prototyped Bluetooth-based ECG module is used to capture ECG with different sampling rate and in different position of patient. This module transmits ECG wirelessly to Bluetooth-enabled devices where the PRASMMA algorithm is applied on captured ECG. The performance of PRASMMA algorithm is compared with moving average and S-Golay algorithms visually as well as numerically. The results show that the PRASMMA algorithm can significantly improve the ECG reconstruction by efficiently removing the noise and its use can be extended to any parameters where peaks are importance for diagnostic purpose.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:32:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:32:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING, 59(11)3148-3154</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TBME.2012.2217494</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15012</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>