<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18324</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:04:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Theoretical and experimental investigations on Stirling-type pulse tube cryocoolers with U-type configuration to achieve temperature below 20K</dc:title><dc:creator>BADGUJAR, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>ATREY, MD</dc:creator><dc:subject>Multi-staging</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stirling-type pulse tube cryocooler</dc:subject><dc:subject>U-type</dc:subject><dc:subject>double inlet valve</dc:subject><dc:description>To achieve lower temperatures is a subject of recent research and development activities in the field of pulse tube cryocoolers. To reach a temperature of 20K, multi-staging is necessary in Stirling-type pulse tube cryocoolers. In the present work, Sage software is used to design a three-stage gas-coupled as well as thermal-coupled pulse tube cryocooler. A single-stage and a two-stage pulse tube cryocoolers are developed, tested and are coupled by a thermal link to build up a three-stage thermal-coupled pulse tube cryocooler. The lowest temperature of 19.61K is obtained with a cooling capacity of 220mW at 30K at the third stage operating at 17bar charge pressure and 68Hz frequency. The phase-shifting mechanism used is a double inlet valve at the third stage while the inertance tube is used for the other stages.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:04:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:04:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART C-JOURNAL OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERING SCIENCE, 229(6)1112-1121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0954-4062</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2041-2983</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0954406214542490</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18324</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>