<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17462</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:10:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>White Light Emission Through Downconversion of Terbium and Europium Doped CeF3 Nanophosphors</dc:title><dc:creator>VARUN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALRA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>EMITTING-DIODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOWN-CONVERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>White light downconversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanophosphors.</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEDs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rare earth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cerium fluoride</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lanthanides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bio-imaging</dc:subject><dc:description>CeF3 nanophosphors have been extensively investigated in recent years for lighting and numerous bio-applications. Downconversion emissions in CeF3:Eu3+/Tb3+ phosphors were studied with the objective of attaining a white light emitting composition, by means of a simple co-precipitation method. The material was characterized by X-ray Diffraction (XRD), Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM), Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy (FT-IR) and Photoluminescence (PL). Uniformly distributed nanoparticles were obtained with an average particle size range of 8-10 nm. Various studies were undertook utilizing different doping concentrations and respective fluorescence studies were carried out to optimize dopant concentrations while achieving maximum luminescence intensity. From PL results, it was observed that the efficient energy transfers from the donor to the acceptor ions. Different concentrations of Tb3+, Eu3+ were doped in order to achieve a white light emitting phosphor for UV-based Light Emitting Diodes (LEDs). The nanoparticles showed characteristic emission of respective dopants (Eu3+, Tb3+) when excited at the 4f -&gt; aEuro parts per thousand 5d transition of Ce3+. The chromaticity coordinates for CeF3 doped with Eu3+ and Tb3+ were calculated and an emission very close to white light was observed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER/PLENUM PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:10:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:10:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF FLUORESCENCE, 25(5)1501-1505</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1053-0509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-4994</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10895-015-1641-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17462</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>