<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10796</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhancing stress corrosion cracking resistance in Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr alloy through inhibiting recrystallization</dc:title><dc:creator>KANNAN, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>aluminum-alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>scandium</dc:subject><dc:subject>sc</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminium alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress corrosion cracking</dc:subject><dc:subject>recrystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>scandium</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of the work was to inhibit recrystallization in Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr alloy and to evaluate the stress corrosion cracking (SCC) behavior of the alloy in the peak aged condition. For this purpose, scandium addition was made to an Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr alloy as the former inhibits recrystallization The scandium-containing alloy was heat-treated to peak aged condition and compared with the base peak aged alloy which contained recrystallized grains. The SCC susceptibilities of the alloys were evaluated using slow strain rate testing (SSRT) and U-bend techniques. While. the base alloy having recrystallized grains showed drastic loss in ductility in the corrosive environment (3.5 wt.% NaCl solution), the scandium-containing alloy having un-recrystallized and fine grains showed no significant loss in ductility in the similar environment. The fracture surface analysis revealed typical inter-granular cracking of recrystallized grains in the base alloy. whereas in the scandium-containing alloy predominant ductile failure was observed. Thus, the study clearly indicated that inhibiting recrystallization in Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr alloy through scandium addition, the SCC resistance of the alloy can be substantially improved even in the peak aged condition (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T07:02:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T07:02:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 77(2), 249-256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.engfracmech.2009.06.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10796</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10796</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>