<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17607</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:24:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Predictions of lift-off height of turbulent methane and propane flames issuing in cold surroundings using conditional moment closure coupled with an extinction model</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SREEDHARA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>JET DIFFUSION FLAMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>VITIATED COFLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMBUSTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>1ST-ORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lifted flames</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conditional moment closure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extinction model</dc:subject><dc:description>Recently, an extinction model was successfully integrated with a conditional moment closure (CMC) approach to predict lift-off height accurately for the lifted jet diffusion flame discharging to hot surroundings Roy et al. (2014). This method, referred as CMCE, is a low-cost model based on the RANS and first-order CMC approach. The proposed methodology may not be superior compared to involved LES and second-order CMC combination, but enables to simulate industrial problems like gas turbine processes in a reasonable CPU time. Though the credibility of this novel approach was well established by validating its predictions against the experimental data, the applicability of this method and constants involved in this model, for other test cases was questionable. In this brief communication, CMCE model is further validated against lift-off studies of two different fuels issuing in cold surroundings, without changing the model constants used in the earlier work. The results are encouraging and a good match is found for lift-off heights for both the test cases and for varying jet velocities. Large variations are found between the predictions of lift-off heights by CMC and CMCE models. (C) 2014 The Combustion Institute. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:24:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:24:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMBUSTION AND FLAME, 162(4)1164-1166</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0010-2180</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1556-2921</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.combustflame.2014.10.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17607</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>