<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3975</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nonlinear predictive control of systems exhibiting input multiplicities using the multimodel approach</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, KK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, SC</dc:creator><dc:subject>models</dc:subject><dc:description>This work establishes the feasibility of using a multilayer perceptron for the development of a multimodel that combines structurally simple local models developed in different operating regions. The local models either are obtained by linearizing a first principles model or are identified from input-output data using a linear combination of Laguerre filters. In particular, it is shown that the proposed multimodels can capture dynamic and steady-state characteristics of a continuous fermenter, which exhibit input multiplicities and change in the sign of steady-state gains, fairly accurately over a wide operating range. The proposed multimodel is further used to develop a nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) scheme. The effectiveness of the NMPC scheme is demonstrated by simulating a servo problem that requires the fermenter to be controlled at its optimum operating point, which happens to be singular points where the invertibility is lost. The proposed NMPC scheme is found to achieve a smooth transition for large-magnitude setpoint changes and control the systems at the singular operating point even in the presence of measurement noise. The NMPC scheme is also found to be robust to moderate variations in system parameters.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T14:01:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T14:01:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 41(13), 3186-3198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie001049g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3975</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3975</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>