<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2550</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>An efficient numerical scheme to determine the pull-in parameters of an electrostatic micro-actuator with contact type nonlinearity</dc:title><dc:creator>JOGLEKAR, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWASKAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>range</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage</dc:subject><dc:subject>travel</dc:subject><dc:subject>drive</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>rayleigh-ritz method</dc:subject><dc:subject>pull-in instability</dc:subject><dc:subject>pull-in displacement</dc:subject><dc:subject>pull-in voltage</dc:subject><dc:subject>contact type nonlinearity</dc:subject><dc:subject>pull-in efficacy index (pei)</dc:subject><dc:description>In this article, we present an efficient numerical scheme based on the Rayleigh-Ritz method to determine the pull-in parameters of electrostatically actuated microbeams exploiting contact type nonlinearity. A case of an electrostatically actuated cantilevered microbeam is first analyzed using the Rayleigh-Ritz energy technique. The deflection of the microbeam is approximated by a polynomial trial function. The principle of the stationary potential energy leads to a highly nonlinear algebraic equation, which is solved to determine the deflected shape of the microbeam. A novel voltage iteration algorithm is implemented to determine the critical voltage at which the pull-in occurs. The analysis is then extended to the case of cantilever beam making use of the contact type nonlinearity to exhibit an extended travel range. The present case consists of a compression spring getting engaged at the cantilever tip at the critical point where the pull-in occurs. An increase in both travel range and pull-in voltage is observed with the introduction of the compression spring. A performance index is suggested, which combines the gain in the travel range together with the concomitant increase in the pull-in voltage. This index is used to determine the critical bound for the choice of the stiffness of the newly introduced compression member.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T00:31:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T00:31:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL MECHANICAL ENGINEERING CONGRESS AND EXPOSITION 2007, VOL 11 PT A AND PT B: MICRO AND NANO SYSTEMS,483-492</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7918-4305-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2550</dc:identifier><dc:source>ASME International Mechanical Engineering Congress and Exposition,Seattle, WA,NOV 11-15, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>