<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15253</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:50:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>ANGULAR PROPERTIES OF LITHIUM TITANATE PARTICLES-AN EXPERIMENTAL STUDY</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>VINJAMUR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYAMOORTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>angle of repose</dc:subject><dc:subject>angle of internal friction</dc:subject><dc:subject>lithium titanate</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>REPOSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANGLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUIDIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEGREGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWDERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLANKET</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ITER</dc:subject><dc:subject>BED</dc:subject><dc:description>Angle of repose and angle of internal friction are two important macroscopic parameters in characterizing granular materials and reliable flow index in fluidization studies. This paper presents an experimental study to measure the angular properties, namely, angle of repose and angle of internal friction of lithium titanate (Li2TiO3) and silica particles. Lithium titanate is a primary contender for the solid breeder material for fusion reactors. Experimental results showed that the angle of repose of fine Li2TiO3 particles increases with increase in particle size, whereas the angle of internal friction decreases with increase in particle size. It was observed that the angle of repose varies in the range 31.7 to 35.62 deg, whereas angle of internal friction varies in the range 74.3 to 76.3 deg. A relationship between angle of repose and angle of internal friction for Li2TiO3 has been established. These results are useful to understand the flow characteristics of Li2TiO3 particles in a gas fluidized bed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER NUCLEAR SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:50:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:50:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FUSION SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, 62(2)333-338</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15253</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>