<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15854</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:03:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rapid Chloride Ion Permeability of OPC- and PPC-Based Carbonated Concrete</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, BB</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Concrete</dc:subject><dc:subject>w/c</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carbonation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Charge</dc:subject><dc:subject>Permeability</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRENGTH</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the measurement of rapid chloride ion permeability (charge passed) values through carbonated and non carbonated ordinary portland cement (OPC)- and portland pozzolana cement (PPC)-based concretes. When concrete is carbonated, the pores in it are filled by the carbonation products, resulting in lower porosity and permeability and substantially increased compressive strength and giving an impression that concrete is impervious. Hence, an assessment of the influence of carbonation on rapid chloride ion permeability becomes essential. Experimental investigation on carbonation was carried out on three different grades of concretes [water-to-cement (w/c) ratio of 0.40, 0.45, and 0.55], with four curing periods (28, 56, 90, and 120 days), and each for two types of commercially available cement, OPC and PPC. The specimens were kept in an accelerated carbonation chamber for 150 days with 10% carbon dioxide (CO2), and then rapid chloride ion permeability through these carbonated specimens was measured with a rapid chloride ion permeability apparatus. The results indicate that a significant decrease in charge passed through concrete owing to carbonation can lead to misleading results in evaluation of the service life of the concrete structures. It is also observed that a low-w/c concrete with PPC has discernible resistance to carbonation and rapid chloride ion permeability compared with its counterpart OPC. DOI: 10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0000415. (C) 2012 American Society of Civil Engineers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:03:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:03:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS IN CIVIL ENGINEERING, 24(5)606-611</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)MT.1943-5533.0000415</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15854</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>