<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1523</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Determination of design space and optimization of solar water heating systems</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, GOVIND N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEDARE, SHIREESH B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, SANTANU</dc:creator><dc:subject>global optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>pareto principle</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar collectors</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthesis (chemical)</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a methodology is proposed to determine the design space for synthesis, analysis, and optimization of solar water heating systems. The proposed methodology incorporates different design constraints to identify all possible designs or a design space on a collector area vs. storage volume diagram. The design space is represented by tracing constant solar fraction lines on a collector area vs. storage volume diagram. It has been observed that there exists a minimum as well as a maximum storage volume for a given solar fraction and collector area. Similarly existence of a minimum and a maximum collector area is also observed for a fixed solar fraction and storage volume. For multi-objective optimization, a Pareto optimal region is also identified. Based on the identified design space, the solar water heating system is optimized by minimizing annual life cycle cost. Due to uncertainty in solar insolation, system parameters and cost data, global optimization may not be utilized to represent a meaningful design. To overcome this, a region of possible design configurations is also identified in this paper</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-17T14:21:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:01:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-17T14:21:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:01:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Solar Energy 81(8), 958-968</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0038-092X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2006.12.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1523</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1523</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>