<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15880</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:16:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of nitrosyl coordination on the binding mode of quinaldate in selective ruthenium frameworks. Electronic structure and reactivity aspects</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>NO-CENTER-DOT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITRIC-OXIDE DIOXYGENASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>REVERSIBLE BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTODYNAMIC THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANCILLARY LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON PORPHYRIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLABILE RUTHENIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPEROXIDE-DISMUTASE</dc:subject><dc:description>The nitrosyl complexes, [Ru-II(trpy)(L)(NO+)Cl]BF4, [1] BF4, and [Ru-II(trpy)(L)(NO+)](BF4)(2), [2](BF4)(2), (trpy = 2,2':6',2 ''-terpyridine, L- = deprotonated form of unsymmetrical quinaldic acid) have been synthesized. Single crystal X-ray structures of [1]BF4 and [2](BF4)(2) reveal that in the former L- binds to the ruthenium ion selectively in a monodentate fashion through the O- donor whereas the usual bidentate mode of L- (O-, N donors) has been retained in [2](BF4)(2) with the same meridional configuration of trpy being seen in both. The Ru-NO group in [1] BF4 or [2](BF4)(2), exhibits almost linear (sp-hybridized form of NO+) geometry. The difference in bonding mode of the unsymmetrical quinaldate in [1]BF4 and [2](BF4)(2) has been reflected in their corresponding nu(NO)/nu(C-O) frequencies as well as in their NO based two-step reduction processes, {Ru-II-NO+} -&gt; {Ru-II-NO center dot} and {Ru-II-NO center dot}-&gt;{Ru-II-NO-}. The close to bent geometry (sp(2)-hybridized form of NO center dot) of the one-electron reduced 1 or [2](+) is been reflected in their DFT optimized structures. The spin density plot of the reduced species reveals that NO is the primary spin-bearing center with slight delocalization onto the metal ion which has been reflected in its radical EPR spectrum. [1]+ and [2](2+) undergo facile photorelease of NO with significantly different k(NO) (s(-1)) and t(1/2) (s) values which eventually lead to the concomitant formation of the corresponding solvent species. The photoreleased NO center dot can be trapped as an Mb-NO adduct. The reduced species 1 selectively reacts with the molecular oxygen (O-2) at pH similar to 1 to yield the corresponding nitro species, [Ru-II(trpy)(L)(NO2)Cl](-).</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:16:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:16:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 2(8)3437-3446</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2ra00953f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15880</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>