<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14537</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:12:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>The influence of melt-mixing process conditions on electrical conductivity of polypropylene/multiwall carbon nanotubes composites</dc:title><dc:creator>TAMBE, PB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>polypropylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiwalled carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>dispersion</dc:subject><dc:subject>melt mixing</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACRYLONITRILE-BUTADIENE-STYRENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGGLOMERATE DISPERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPOXY COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYCARBONATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATRIX</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MORPHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:description>The influence of melt-mixing parameters on the development of network-like structure of multiwall carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) in injection-molded polypropylene (PP)/MWNTs composites was assessed through AC electrical conductivity measurements. A higher melt-mixing temperature (260 degrees C as compared to 200, 220, and 240 degrees C) at a fixed rotational speed of the screws (150 rpm) and at a fixed mixing time (15 min) has yielded maximum improvement in electrical conductivity in PP/MWNTs composites of 3 wt % MWNTs content. Next to higher melt-mixing temperature, a variation in the melt-mixing time has also led to a variation in electrical conductivity of the composites. Raman spectroscopic analysis revealed an increase in the ratio of intensity due to G-band over that of D-band (IG/ID) of the MWNTs in the skin region as compared to the core region of the injection-molded composites irrespective of the melt-mixing conditions. Microscopic observations could not provide much insight into the variation of MWNTs network-like structure in various PP/MWNTs composites. An attempt has been made to understand the variation of network-like structure of MWNTs in PP/MWNTs composites as a function of melt-mixing parameters through electrical conductivity measurements, Raman spectroscopic analysis, and morphological investigations. (C) 2012 Wiley Periodicals, Inc. J. Appl. Polym. Sci., 2013</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:12:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:12:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED POLYMER SCIENCE, 127(2)1017-1026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/app.37889</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14537</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>