<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2712</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamics of polymer adsorption</dc:title><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANOOP, GV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATTANAYEK, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>desorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>state</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>field</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work a mean field, continuum model has been developed to predict dynamics of polymer adsorption from solution, on solid surface. Diffusion of a polymer molecule is described in two steps i.e. formulation of "free" (unconnected) segment diffusion, and imposition of the segmental connectivity constraint. Diffusion of a free segment, in a time variant Self-Consistent Field (SCF), is described by the Fokker-Planck equation, while the segmental connectivity is described by the random-flight model. The adsorbing surface is treated as a singular phase having zero thickness, but a finite capacity to hold the adsorbed species. A boundary condition, which accounts for interfacial equilibrium as well as configurational constraint imposed by the impenetrable surface, has been formulated. Flory-Huggins theory has been used to estimate the mean field potential. The model equations have been solved to obtain segmental concentration distribution as a function of time, from which other relevant quantities like rate of adsorption, volume fraction etc., are estimated. Steady state adsorption characteristics can also be obtained as a special case of the model.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IMPERIAL COLLEGE PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T09:23:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T09:23:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>STRUCTURE AND DYNAMICS OF MATERIALS IN THE MESOSCOPIC DOMAIN,317-325</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-86094-190-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2712</dc:identifier><dc:source>4th Meeting of the Royal-Society-Unilever-Indo-UK Forum in Materials Science and Engineering,PUNE, INDIA,</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>