<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14225</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:50:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Calix[4]arene-Based 1,3-Diconjugate of Salicylyl Imine Having Dibenzyl Amine Moiety (L): Synthesis, Characterization, Receptor Properties toward Fe(2+), Cu(2+), and Zn(2+), Crystal Structures of Its Zn(2+) and Cu(2+) Complexes, and Selective Phosphate Sensing by the [ZnL]</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSEPH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHINTA, JP</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>LOWER RIM</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIFUNCTIONAL FLUORESCENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIHYDROXYPHOSPHONIC ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANION RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL-IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:description>A calix[4]arene conjugate bearing salicylyl imine having dibenzyl moiety (L) has been synthesized and characterized, and its ability to recognize three most important essential elements of human system, viz., iron, copper, and zinc, has been addressed by colorimetry and fluorescence techniques. L acts as a sensor for Cu(2+) and Fe(2+) by exhibiting visual color change and for Zn(2+) based on fluorescence spectroscopy. L shows a minimum detection limit of 3.96 +/- 0.42 and 4.51 +/- 0.53 ppm and 45 +/- 4 ppb, respectively, toward Fe(2+), Cu(2+), and Zn(2+). The in situ prepared [ZnL] exhibits phosphate sensing among 14 anions studied with a detection limit of 247 +/- 25 ppb. The complexes of Zn(2+), Cu(2+), and Fe(2+) of L have been synthesized and characterized by different techniques. The crystalline nature of the zinc and copper comlexes and the noncrystalline nature of simple Land its iron complex have been demonstrated by powder XRD. The structures of Cu(2+) and Zn(2+) complexes have been established by single crystal XRD wherein these were found to be 1:1 monomeric and 2:2 dimeric, respectively, using N(2)O(2) as binding core. The geometries exhibited by the Zn(2+) and the Cu(2+) complexes were found to be distorted tetrahedral and distorted:I square planar, respectively. The iron complex of L exists in 1:1 stoichiometry as evident from the mass spectrometry and elemental analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:50:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:50:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY,50(15)7050-7058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic200544a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14225</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>