<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7498</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of tablet-coating parameters for a pan coater through video imaging and Monte Carlo simulation</dc:title><dc:creator>KANDELA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHEOREY, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>pan coating</dc:subject><dc:subject>tablet movement</dc:subject><dc:subject>video imaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>monte carlo simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>coating variability</dc:subject><dc:description>The movement of tablets in a pan coater and the exposure of different surfaces of tablets for deposition of coatings by spray-coating have been studied by video imaging and Monte Carlo simulation techniques. A representative variety of tablets of different shapes and sizes were used at different pan loads and at various pan speeds. A single "tracer" tablet was used to track the motion of tablets and coating variables such as circulation time, surface time, projected surface area and surface velocity of a tablet were determined from the video imaging experiments. The coating uniformity is described in terms of the coating variation from tablet to tablet CV(tt) and a new parameter CV(st) the coating variation on a single tablet. The effect of shape of tablets on coating uniformity was analyzed by introducing a "sphericity" of tablet (phi(s)) into the CV models. The methodology, new models and the analysis developed here incorporating the additional parameters will help users to optimize the coating process in pan-coating operations. (C) 2010</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-28T21:07:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-28T21:07:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POWDER TECHNOLOGY, 204(1), 103-112</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-5910</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2010.07.024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7498</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7498</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>