<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12161</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Shock wave driven microparticles for pharmaceutical applications</dc:title><dc:creator>MENEZES, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>TAKAYAMA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOJANI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSEINI, SHR</dc:creator><dc:subject>drug-delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>invivo</dc:subject><dc:subject>flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>tube</dc:subject><dc:subject>gas</dc:subject><dc:subject>shock wave</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>microparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>laser</dc:subject><dc:subject>biolistic</dc:subject><dc:description>Ablation created by a Q-switched Nd:Yttrium Aluminum Garnet (Nd:YAG) laser beam focusing on a thin aluminum foil surface spontaneously generates a shock wave that propagates through the foil and deforms it at a high speed. This high-speed foil deformation can project dry micro- particles deposited on the anterior surface of the foil at high speeds such that the particles have sufficient momentum to penetrate soft targets. We used this method of particle acceleration to develop a drug delivery device to deliver DNA/drug coated microparticles into soft human-body targets for pharmaceutical applications. The device physics has been studied by observing the process of particle acceleration using a high-speed video camera in a shadowgraph system. Though the initial rate of foil deformation is over 5 km/s, the observed particle velocities are in the range of 900-400 m/s over a distance of 1.5-10 mm from the launch pad. The device has been tested by delivering microparticles into liver tissues of experimental rats and artificial soft human-body targets, modeled using gelatin. The penetration depths observed in the experimental targets are quite encouraging to develop a future clinical therapeutic device for treatments such as gene therapy, treatment of cancer and tumor cells, epidermal and mucosal immunizations etc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T18:41:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T18:41:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SHOCK WAVES, 18(5), 393-400</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0938-1287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00193-008-0163-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12161</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12161</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>