<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18107</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:57:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurement of Steady-State CHF in Horizontal Channels for Low-Pressure, Low-Flow Conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>BABURAJAN, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BISHT, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAIKWAD, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>CRITICAL HEAT-FLUX</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOOK-UP TABLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>VERTICAL TUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental investigations on critical heat flux (CHF) are mostly on vertical channels involving high mass fluxes and high system pressures. Reported studies on CHF in horizontal flow channels under low-pressure, low-flow (LPLF) conditions are limited. Understanding CHF is essential in the design and operation of heat exchangers and heat-generating devices including fuel channels of nuclear reactors. The present work investigates CHF in horizontal tubes for low steady flow at atmospheric pressure conditions. Appearance of a "red hot" spot on the test section is considered to be the occurrence of critical heat flux condition in this study. Present data could not be predicted using the reported method of applying a correction factor for the vertical lookup table data. A correlation using the experimental data is developed incorporating the fluid-to-fluid modeling parameters for the prediction of CHF in horizontal channels under LPLF conditions. Numerical study using thermal hydraulic system code RELAP5 suggests liquid film dryout as the mechanism of CHF occurrence in the present investigations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HEAT TRANSFER ENGINEERING, 36(4SI)418-428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0145-7632</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1521-0537</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01457632.2014.924071</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18107</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>