<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4270</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-06T03:35:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Monte Carlo approach for incorporation of memory effect in switched gate bias experiments</dc:title><dc:creator>SUBBARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>interface trap formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>devices</dc:subject><dc:description>This article presents a Monte Carlo approach to simulate the dispersive transport of holes/H+ ions in silicon-dioxide using simplified formalism of continuous time random walk theory given by Montroll and Scher [E. W. Montroll and H. Scher, J. Stat. Phys. 9, 101 (1973); H. Scher and E. W. Montroll, Phys. Rev. B 12, 2455 (1975)]. It has been shown that the simulated results of this approach match quite well with the theoretical predictions for a value of dispersion coefficient, alpha, =0.5 which validates our Monte Carlo simulator. We have used this simulator to resolve the memory effect observed by Saks et al. [N. S. Saks, D. B. Brown, and R. W. Rendell, IEEE Trans. Nucl. Sci. 38, 1130 (1991)] in their simulations of switched gate bias experiments in context with the hydrogen ion transport model for the buildup of radiation-induced interface states. We have accounted for the memory effect, which is related with the dwell time of an ion at the last hopping site just before field switching, by treating the first hop after field switching differently from all other hops. We have shown that the memory effect can be incorporated by modifying the value of cu only for the first hop after field switching depending on the dwell time at the last hopping site just before field switching. We have found that a logarithmic relationship between the two gives a very good match between the simulated and the experimental results of half-time (the time required to build 50% of saturated interface states) versus time of field switching, t(switch), relationship. (C) 1998</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T12:08:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T12:08:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 83(6), 3419-3422</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.367109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4270</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4270</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>