<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1695</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>My world - social networking through mobile computing and context aware application</dc:title><dc:creator>SORATHIA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>interface design</dc:subject><dc:subject>mobile computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>3g</dc:subject><dc:subject>social networking</dc:subject><dc:subject>system aided application</dc:subject><dc:description>Social networking websites are being regularly used by individuals, groups, friends, colleagues etc. where they share information, communicate with each other by means of using websites like facebook, orkut. twitter, my space &amp; many more. Increasing internet connectivity and rapid adoption of mobile devices, social networking have migrated to mobile platform; which is accessible anywhere, anytime users' want. In this paper, we describe design of a new concept mobile application based on contact based social networking. In addition to this, it also describes how a system-aided application can enhance user experiences; helping users to understand other users' activity, help them navigate easily and encourage the use of this application. This application is focused on activity sharing, real time location sharing and media sharing between phonebook contacts.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T09:19:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T09:19:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTELLIGENT INTERACTIVE ASSISTANCE AND MOBILE MULTIMEDIA COMPUTING,53,179-188</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-642-10262-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1865-0929</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14863</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1695</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Intelligent Interactive Assistance and Mobile Multimedia Computing (IMC 2009),Rostock, GERMANY,NOV 09-11, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>