<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1193</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:09:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydrogen in chemical vapour deposited diamond films</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARDA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVASTHI, DK</dc:creator><dc:subject>microwave plasma</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal-conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>defects</dc:subject><dc:subject>cvd</dc:subject><dc:description>Thin films of diamond were deposited at 20, 40 and 70 Torr by MPCVD and at 40, 100 and 140 Torr by HFCVD while keeping the substrate temperature constant The films were characterised using micro-Raman spectroscopy, X-Ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). Micro-Raman spectra show a sharp peak centered near the natural diamond line (approximate to 1332 cm(-1)) accompanied by a non-diamond band at approximate to 1450-1550 cm(-1). Intense peaks corresponding to (111), (400) and (311) reflections are observed in XRD. Diamond crystallites with sharp facets are seen in SEM. Plasma diagnostics in the MPCVD system were also performed at various conditions in order to estimate the H atom concentration in the gas phase. Elastic recoil detection analysis was used to measure the H concentration. It is observed that the H concentration shows contrasting trends in the films grown by MPCVD and HFCVD at various growth pressures. H concentration is found to be 1.0, 0.8 and 0.7 at % in the films grown at 20, 40 and 70 Torr, respectively, in MPCVD apparatus. Conversely, the H concentration in the films grown by HFCVD increases systematically with growth pressure (0.5, 1.1 and 1.4 at % at 40, 100 and 140 Torr, respectively). Non-diamond carbon impurities correlate well with H content Results of micro-Raman spectroscopy, SEM and plasma diagnostic are discussed in the framework of a growth model. Results of H content in the diamond films obtained by various techniques are compared. Copyright (C) 1996 Elsevier Science Ltd</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T13:40:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T13:40:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>VACUUM,47(11)1259-1264</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0042-207X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0042-207X(96)00166-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1193</dc:identifier><dc:source>Workshop on Studies of Diamond, Diamond Like Carbon (DLC) and Fullerene Films with Ion Beams,NEW DELHI, INDIA,SEP   29, 1995</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>