<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12014</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Two-dimensional incompressible viscous flow simulation using velocity-vorticity dual reciprocity boundary element method</dc:title><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>YOUNG, DL</dc:creator><dc:subject>navier-stokes equations</dc:subject><dc:subject>navier-stokes equations</dc:subject><dc:subject>velocity-vorticity</dc:subject><dc:subject>dual reciprocity boundary element method</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes a computational model based on the dual reciprocity boundary element method (DRBEM) for the solution of two-dimensional incompressible viscous flow problems. The model is based on the Navier-Stokes equations in velocity-vorticity variables. The model includes the solution of vorticity transport equation for vorticity whose solenoidal vorticity components are obtained by solving Poisson equations involving the velocity and vorticity components. Both the Poisson equations and the vorticity transport equations are solved iteratively using DRBEM and combined to determine the velocity and vorticity vectors. In DRBEM, all source terms, advective terms and time dependent terms are converted into boundary integrals and hence the computational domain of the problem reduces by one. Internal points are considered wherever solution is required. The model has been applied to simulate two-dimensional incompressible viscous flow problems with low Reynolds (Re) number in a typical square cavity. Results are obtained and compared with other models. The DRBEM model has been found to be reasonable and satisfactory.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC THEORETICAL APPLIED MECHANICS, R O C</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T07:29:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T07:29:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MECHANICS, 20(3), 177-185</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1727-7191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12014</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>