<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1585</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simple surface modification techniques for immobilization of biomolecules on SU-8</dc:title><dc:creator>DEEPU, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAI, VVR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>wave-guide</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoresist</dc:subject><dc:subject>mems</dc:subject><dc:subject>dna</dc:subject><dc:description>SU-8, an epoxy based negative photoresist polymer has found wide range of applications in the field of microfabrication based biosensors. SU-8 surfaces need to be modified in order to immobilize bioreceptors. We studied the possibility of grafting desired functional groups by means of simple chemical treatments under normal laboratory conditions. These chemical treatments involve the use of crosslinkers that are expected to react with epoxy groups or hydroxyl groups generated by acid/alkali treatment. Here, a comparison of the results obtained on surface modification using glycine and 11-mercapto undecanoic acid as crosslinkers is presented. Human Immunoglobin G (HIgG) was covalently immobilized to carboxylic acid on SU-8 surface using carbodiimide/succinimide chemistry. The activity of immobilized HIgG was verified by using fluorescence imaging of FITC tagged goat anti HIgG bound to the surface. Fluorescence imaging was used to determine the chemistry best suited to functionalize SU-8 surface for biosensor applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T02:29:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T02:29:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE-MATERIALS IN MEDICINE,20,25-28</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-4530</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10856-008-3471-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14796</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1585</dc:identifier><dc:source>Symposium on Materials for Biomedical Applications,Bangalore, INDIA,</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>