<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17872</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T05:57:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Models for pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour analysis at unprotected mid-block crosswalks under mixed traffic conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>KADALI, BR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDAGIRI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RATHI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>ARTIFICIAL NEURAL-NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CROSSINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERSECTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHOICE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAFETY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pedestrian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mid-block</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gap</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rolling behaviour</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANN</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mixed traffic</dc:subject><dc:description>Pedestrian safety is an important aspect while crossing the road and it can be explained by pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour. The statistical models such as multiple linear regression (MLR) is often used to model linear relationships between dependent variable (viz., pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour) and independent variables, due to their ability to quantitatively predict the effect of various factors on the dependent variable. However such linear models cannot consider the effect of several variables on the output variable, due to primary assumptions of normality, linear, homoscedasticity and multicollinearity. In this regard, the non-linear models based on the artificial neural network (ANN), which are free from assumptions of linear models, can be easily employed for obtaining the effect of several input variables on the pedestrian accepted gap size. However, researchers have rarely applied ANN modelling technique for predicting the pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour, as the pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour depends on several pedestrian, traffic and vehicular characteristics. The ANN based models would be quite useful in establishing relationship between these factors on the pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour at midblock crosswalks under mixed traffic conditions. In this direction, the present study adopts both MLR as well as ANN with different pedestrian, traffic and vehicular characteristics to assess the significant contributing factors for pedestrians' gap acceptance behaviour at unprotected mid-block crosswalks under mixed traffic conditions. For this purpose, a video graphic survey was conducted at a six lane divided road at unprotected mid-block crossing in Mumbai, India. The data such as pedestrian (gender and age), vehicular, traffic and pedestrian behavioural characteristics were extracted to model pedestrian accepted gaps. The model results show that pedestrian rolling behaviour has a significant effect on pedestrian accepted gap size. The model results concluded that ANN has a better prediction with possibility to consider the effect of more number of variables on the pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour as compared to the MLR model under mixed traffic conditions. However, the quantification of significant contributing variables on pedestrian accepted gap size is easy by MLR model as compared to the ANN technique. So, both models have their own significant role in pedestrian gap acceptance analysis. The developed models may be useful to enhance the existing mid-block crosswalk facilities or planning new facilities by more accurate prediction of the pedestrian gap acceptance behaviour considering the influence of various factors under mixed traffic conditions. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSPORTATION RESEARCH PART F-TRAFFIC PSYCHOLOGY AND BEHAVIOUR, 32,114-126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1369-8478</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-5517</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.trf.2015.05.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17872</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>