<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9143</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic, transport and thermal properties of ternary indides R2CoIn8 (R = rare earths and Y)</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, DA</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOMY, CV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALIK, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>heavy-fermion compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>superconductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>ce</dc:subject><dc:description>The magnetic properties of the R2CoIn8 series of compounds are studied. Y2CoIn8 shows a Pauli paramagnetic behaviour. Ce2CoIn8 shows a heavy fermion and Kondo behaviour. Pr2CoIn8 shows a dominating crystal field effect. The compounds with other magnetic rare earths ( R = Sm, Nd, Gd, Tb, Dy and Ho) show antiferromagnetic ordering at low temperatures with T-N = 12, 10, 33.5, 30, 17.4 and 7.6 K, respectively. Dy2CoIn8, Ho2CoIn8 and Nd2CoIn8 show metamagnetic transitions and a field- induced ferromagnetic transition at 2 K and above approximate to 82, 54 and 85 kOe respectively. Gd2CoIn8 is a strong antiferromagnet. Sm2CoIn8 shows a dominating antiferromagnetic behaviour with a ferromagnetic component at low temperatures. Tb2CoIn8 shows a ferromagnetic component at low temperatures with the possibility of superconducting behaviour below 2.5 K. The compound also shows metamagnetic transitions in the magnetic isotherm and the possibility of complicated magnetic structure below the transition temperature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T20:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T20:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 19(13), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/19/13/136216</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9143</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9143</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>