<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14202</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:38:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis of covalently linked boron-dipyrromethene-chromophore conjugates using 3-bromo boron-dipyrromethene as a key precursor</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ENERGY-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>BUILDING-BLOCKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BODIPY DYES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROGENERATED CHEMILUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>COUPLING REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>APPENDED SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BORADIAZAINDACENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PORPHYRIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Boron-dipyrromethene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chromophores</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anthracene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Porphyrin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sapphyrin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy transfer</dc:subject><dc:description>3-Bromo boron dipyrromethene (3-bromo BODIPY) has been used as key synthon to prepare one ethynyl bridged and six ethynylphenyl bridged BODIPY-chromophore conjugates using mild Pd(0) coupling conditions. The chromophores possessing very distinct features, such as anthracene, BODIPY, terpyridine, porphyrin. Zn(II)porphyrin, 21,23-dithiaporphyrin and thiasapphyrin were connected at 3-position of boronboron-dipyrromethene dye by coupling of 3-bromo BODIPY with ethynyl or ethynylphenyl chromophore in toluene/triethylamine in the presence of catalytic amount of AsPh(3)/Pd(2)(dba)(3) at 40 degrees C followed by column chromatographic purification. The spectral studies indicated that the interaction is stronger in ethynyl bridged BODIPY-chromophore conjugate compared to ethynylphenyl bridged BODIPY-chromophore conjugates. The steady-state fluorescence indicated that in ethynyl bridged BODIPY-anthracene conjugate, the BODIPY unit act as energy acceptor and showed a possibility of energy transfer from donor anthracene unit to acceptor BODIPY unit on selective excitation of anthracene unit. However, in ethynylphenyl bridged BODIPY-porphyrin conjugates, the BODIPY unit act as energy donor and exhibited a possibility of singlet-singlet energy transfer from BODIPY unit to porphyrin unit. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:38:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:38:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TETRAHEDRON,67(32)5816-5824</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-4020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tet.2011.05.089</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14202</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>