<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-925</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:55:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulation based synthesis, design and optimization of pressure swing adsorption (PSA) processes</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJASREE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHARIR, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>process engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>design theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>Process synthesis is one of the important aspects in the design of adsorption processes, especially in the case of pressure swing adsorption (PSA) processes. A process simulator which can help in taking decisions on the number of beds, operating configurations and operating parameters (pressure ratio, cycle step times, flow velocity, feed/purge ratio, etc.) can minimize the necessity of pilot plant studies, resolve commissioning problems and help in optimal operation. This work makes an attempt at simulation based on-line synthesis, design and optimization of PSA processes. A simulation/tuning/optimization software has been developed for PSA processes for multicomponent separation. Adaptive simulation based process synthesis and optimization strategies have been demonstrated using a rigorous simulation (called Process) as an emulation of a flexible PSA plant instead of an actual plant and a less rigorous model as its simulation. The findings based on this study appear to be an effective approach to optimal synthesis, design and optimization of any PSA processes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-13T07:03:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:01:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-13T07:03:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:01:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computers &amp; Chemical Engineering 24(11), 2493-2505</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0098-1354(00)00606-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/925</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/925</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>