<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8898</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>A reliable parallel-adaptive algorithm with back-tracking for QFT template generation</dc:title><dc:creator>S, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NATARAJ, PSV</dc:creator><dc:description>The recently proposed parallel-adaptive (PA) algorithm reliably generates the frequency response template of a given system to a prescribed accuracy. However, It suffers from an Inherent disadvantage in that the system parameters are always bisected along the maximum width coordinate direction, without due consideration of whether the function widths are thereby significantly reduced or not. Due to the disadvantage, the template generated may comprise of an unnecessarily large number of angle-magnitude rectangles. In this paper, an improved version of the PA algorithm, called the parallel-adaptive algorithm with back-tracking (PABT) Is proposed. In this, parameters are bisected only along favorable directions. Performances of PABT and PA algorithms are compared on a set of ten transfer function examples. PABT algorithm generates a system template comprising of lesser number of rectangles, and hence is superior to the PA algorithm.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ELECTRONICS TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T04:47:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T04:47:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IETE TECHNICAL REVIEW, 18(1), 57-60</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-4602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8898</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8898</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>