<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1671</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cathodic electro-deposition of low-temperature curable water-soluble polyepoxide coatings</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIVEDI, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>water-soluble</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyepoxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>cathodic electro-deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>self-curable</dc:subject><dc:subject>low-temperature cure</dc:subject><dc:description>Epoxidised phenol-novolac (EPN) type of polyepoxide resin was used for developing water-soluble cathodically electro-depositable coatings which could be self-curable without using any external/additional cross-linking agent. The self-curing of cathodically deposited films could be effected at a low temperature of 80 degreesC in 30 min, as compared to 150-170 degreesC in 30 min practised presently in many commercial cathodic electro-deposition (CED) installations. In this work, effect of varying molar ratio of secondary amines such as diethanol amine (DEtOA) and diethyl amine to epoxidised phenol-novolac (EPN) on the solubility of EPN-secondary amine adducts prepared at 80, 60 and 30 degreesC for varying reaction times was investigated. Self-curing characteristics of EPN-DEtOA (1:2 moles) adduct at 30-160 degreesC were studied. Kinetics of film growth during CED was investigated by using aqueous solutions of acetic acid neutralised EPN-DEtOA (1:2 moles) adduct. Variables for kinetic studies were deposition time (30-600s), applied voltage (5-250V) and solution concentration (1-20% (w/w)). By carrying out CED of polyepoxide films, values of electro-deposition (ED) characteristics found were: ED yield as 5.89 mg/cm(2) Coulombic yield as 19.78 mg/C and dry film thickness (DFT) as 52.12 mum Plots of DFT vs, deposition time (t), DFT vs. t(1/2) and current density vs. field strength were drawn to calculate the values of Coulombic efficiency of the process and film conductivity. Cathodically electro-deposited films were finally characterised for physical properties, chemical resistance and corrosion protection. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T07:52:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T07:52:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROGRESS IN ORGANIC COATINGS,40,63-74</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-9440</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0300-9440(00)00152-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14844</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1671</dc:identifier><dc:source>25th Athens Conference on Organic Coatings,VOULIAGMENI, GREECE,JUL 05-09, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>