<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2450</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-11T04:28:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>CIM and IEC 61850 integration issues : application to power systems</dc:title><dc:creator>PRADEEP, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHURAJU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>WARRIER, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHERIAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>Common Information Model (CIM) is emerging as a standard for information modelling for power control centers. While, IEC 61850 by International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) is emerging as a standard for achieving interoperability and automation at the substation level. In future, once these two standards are well adopted, the issue of integration of these standards becomes imminent. Some efforts reported towards the integration of these standards have been surveyed. This paper describes a possible approach for the integration of IEC 61850 and CIM standards based on mapping between the representation of elements of these two standards. This enables seamless data transfer from one standard to the other. Mapping between the objects of IEC 61850 and CIM standards both in the static and dynamic models is discussed. A CIM based topology processing application is used to demonstrate the design of the data transfer between the standards. The scope and status of implementation of CIM in the Indian power sector is briefed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T18:19:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T18:19:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2009 IEEE POWER &amp; ENERGY SOCIETY GENERAL MEETING, VOLS 1-8,5282-5287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-4240-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15786</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2450</dc:identifier><dc:source>General Meeting of the IEEE-Power-and-Energy-Society,Calgary, CANADA,JUL 26-30, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>