<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17290</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:17:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Time-resolved spectral analysis of prompt emission from long gamma-ray bursts with GeV emission</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASAK, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHESHWARI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>gamma rays: bursts</dc:subject><dc:subject>gamma rays: observations</dc:subject><dc:subject>methods: data analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERMI OBSERVATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BATSE OBSERVATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHYSICAL ORIGINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPONENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRBS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PULSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREAK</dc:subject><dc:description>We performed detailed time-resolved spectroscopy of bright long gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) which show significant GeV emissions (GRB 080916C, GRB 090902B and GRB 090926A). In addition to the standard Band model, we also use a model consisting of a black body and a power law to fit the spectra. We find that for the latter model there are indications of an additional soft component in the spectra. While previous studies have shown that such models are required for GRB 090902B, here we find that a composite spectral model consisting of two blackbodies and a power law adequately fits the data of all the three bright GRBs. We investigate the evolution of the spectral parameters and find several interesting features that appear in all three GRBs, like (a) temperatures of the blackbodies are strongly correlated with each other, (b) fluxes in the black body components are strongly correlated with each other, (c) the temperatures of the black body trace the profile of the individual pulses of the GRBs, and (d) the characteristics of power law components like the spectral index and the delayed onset bear a close similarity to the emission characteristics in the GeV regions. We discuss the implications of these results and the possibility of identifying the radiation mechanisms during the prompt emission of GRBs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ASTRONOMICAL OBSERVATORIES, CHIN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:17:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:17:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RESEARCH IN ASTRONOMY AND ASTROPHYSICS, 14(1)35-46</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1674-4527</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1674-4527/14/1/003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17290</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>