<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15833</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:52:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>In-house calibration of pressure transducers and effect of material thickness</dc:title><dc:creator>DAVE, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASAKA, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>in-house calibration device</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-soil calibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>particulate material</dc:subject><dc:subject>sand layer thickness</dc:subject><dc:description>Pressure transducers are increasingly used within soil mass or at soil-structure interface for appraisal of stresses acting at point of installation. Calibration of pressure transducers provides a unique relationship between applied pressure and voltage or strain sensed by transducer during various loading conditions and is crucial for proper interpretation of results obtained from pressure transducers. In the present study an in-house calibration device is used to calibrate pressure transducers and the study is divided into two parts: 1) demonstration of developed calibration device for fluid and in-soil calibration of pressure transducers; 2) effect of soil layer thickness on the earth pressure cell (EPC) output. Results obtained from the present study revealed successful performance of the developed calibration device, and significant effect of sand layer thickness on the calibration results. The optimum sand layer thickness is obtained as 1.5 times the diameter of EPC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TECHNO-PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:52:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:52:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOMECHANICS AND ENGINEERING, 5(1)1-15</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15833</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>