<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-478</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>MPOE based adaptive space-time multiuser detector for multipath CDMA channels</dc:title><dc:creator>DUA, ADITYA</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>adaptive signal detection</dc:subject><dc:subject>antenna arrays</dc:subject><dc:subject>code division multiple access</dc:subject><dc:subject>error statistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>multipath channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiuser channels</dc:subject><dc:description>DS-CDMA is a popular multiple access technology for wireless communication. The performance of DS-CDMA is limited by multiple access interference and multipath distortion. Multiuser detection and space-time processing techniques are employed to improve the performance of DS-CDMA. An adaptive space-time multiuser detector based on the minimum probability of error (MPOE) criterion is proposed here for an asynchronous multipath DS-CDMA channel, with the receiver employing multiple antennas. The receiver structure is derived for gradient descent based adaptation. A blind version of the receiver is also proposed. It is seen that the MPOE receiver offers BER performance comparable to the optimal non-adaptive MMSE detector in steady state, however with much lower computational complexity and a faster convergence rate compared to other adaptive implementations of the MMSE detector (LMS, RLS).</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-23T06:47:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T05:27:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-23T06:47:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T05:27:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (V 3), Orlando, USA, 13-17 May 2002, III-2593-III-2596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-7402-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICASSP.2002.1005216</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/478</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/478</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>