<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15900</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:26:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hot wire chemical vapor deposited boron carbide thin film/crystalline silicon diode for neutron detection application</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOPKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Boron carbide (BC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>HWCVD</dc:subject><dc:subject>PECVD</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ortho-carborane (o-C2B10H12)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neutron detector</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:description>Boron carbide films have been deposited on n-type crystalline silicon substrate by hot wire chemical vapor deposition technique using ortho-carborane precursor. The deposited films have been characterized by secondary ion mass spectrometry for their isotopic study which shows the presence of B-10 in the film making them suitable for thermal neutron absorber application. These films have a p-type semiconducting nature and hence can be employed to form a p-n junction with n-type silicon. We have demonstrated for the first time the formation of a p-n junction with films deposited by hot wire chemical vapor deposition technique. The current-voltage characteristics of the diode have been measured and the characteristics show low leakage current ((nA) under bar) in the reverse bias condition. From capacitance-voltage study, it is observed that the depletion width is of the order of few microns which is sufficient for detection of alpha particle released by B-10 in the n, alpha reaction. The results of this study indicate that hot wire chemical vapor deposited boron carbide/crystalline silicon diode could be used as a compact device for thermal neutron detection. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:26:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:26:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLID-STATE ELECTRONICS, 78156-158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sse.2012.05.032</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15900</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>