<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1667</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>FPGA based high performance double-precision matrix multiplication</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, VBY</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATKAR, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAN, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>high performance computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>matrix multiplication</dc:subject><dc:subject>rank-1 scheme</dc:subject><dc:subject>fpga implementation</dc:subject><dc:subject>memory-bandwidth trade-off</dc:subject><dc:subject>scalability</dc:subject><dc:description>We present two designs (I and II) for IEEE 754 double precision floating point matrix multiplication, optimized for implementation on high-end FPGAs. It forms the kernel in many important tile-based BLAS algorithms, making an excellent candidate for acceleration. The designs, both based on the rank-1 update scheme, can handle arbitrary matrix sizes, and are able to sustain their peak performance except during an initial latency period. Through these designs, the trade-offs involved in terms of local-memory and bandwidth for an FPGA implementation are demonstrated and an analysis is presented for the optimal choice of design parameters. The designs, implemented on a Virtex-5 SX240T FPGA, scale gracefully from 1 to 40 processing elements(PEs) with a less than 1% degradation in the design frequency of 373 MHz. With 40 PEs and a design speed of 373 MHz, a sustained performance of 29.8 GFLOPS is possible with a bandwidth requirement of 750 MB/s for design-II and 5.9 GB/s for design-I. This compares favourably with both related art and general purpose CPU implementations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER/PLENUM PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T07:22:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T07:22:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PARALLEL PROGRAMMING,38,322-338</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-7458</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10766-010-0131-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14840</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1667</dc:identifier><dc:source>22nd International Conference on VLSI Design/8th International Conference on Embedded Systems,New Delhi, INDIA,JAN, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>