<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16028</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:08:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Theoretical modeling of guided wave propagation in a sandwich plate subjected to transient surface excitations</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>POL, CB</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sandwich structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Global matrix method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Guided wave mode</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transient sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wavelet transformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAMB WAVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOADS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSPECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIBRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEAMS</dc:subject><dc:description>A fast and efficient two-dimensional (2D) semi-analytical model based on global matrix method is developed to study the general characteristics of guided wave propagation in a honeycomb composite sandwich structure (HCSS) subjected to time-dependent transient surface excitations. The HCSS used in this study has an extremely lightweight and thick nomex honeycomb core, which is sandwiched between two thin graphite woven composite skins. The homogenized material properties of the skin and the core are considered to be elastic and quasi-isotropic in nature. Far-field time history of surface displacements are calculated for vertical and horizontal tone-burst surface excitations that are representative of thickness and radial mode of vibrations of piezoelectric transducers, respectively. Results are compared with those obtained from Finite element modeling (FEM) in LS-DYNA showing good agreement. Wavelet transform is then performed on the time-domain signal to obtain the group velocities of the propagating modes for their accurate identification on the basis of the theoretical dispersion curve. It is found that the response signal is dominated by the first anti-symmetric mode for a vertical excitation, whereas, the signal characteristics are multimodal in nature with dominating higher order symmetric and anti-symmetric modes for a horizontal excitation. The model is expected to be helpful for appropriate guided wave mode tuning and rapid analysis of data for experimental detection of disbonds in these novel structures. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:08:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:08:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF SOLIDS AND STRUCTURES, 49(23-24)3233-3241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsolstr.2012.06.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16028</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>