<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14793</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:52:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Formation of Carbon Nanotube Bucky Paper and Feasibility Study for Filtration at the Nano and Molecular Scale</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJPAI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENTE, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>GAS SEPARATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMBRANES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SELECTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILTERS</dc:subject><dc:description>Presence of abundant pores and highly entangled nanotubes make bucky paper (BP) a natural candidate for filtration related applications. Both single- and multiwall carbon nanotube (SWNT and MWNT) BPs were fabricated via self-assembly. Average diameter of the pores on the surface of MWNT BP appeared to be 33 +/- 15 nm. However, due to the high tortuousity of BP, the cutoff size, estimated by filtration of colloidal dispersions of Au and CdS nanoparticles of different diameters, turned out to be 4-5 nm. The particle sizes were verified using microscopic and spectroscopic methods. The flux of Au nanoparticle solutions through BP was about 1000 L h(-1) m(-2) bar(-1). Highly flexible and robust SWNT BPs were prepared very easily, even without proper dispersion. It was found that the crystallinity and purity of the SWNTs had a bigger role than the quality of dispersion in determining the final mechanical strength of BP. The density of SWNT BP was estimated to be 1.3 +/- 0.3 g/cm(3) after correcting for the weights of the impurities. This is among the highest ever reported. The average wall to wall separation of adjacent tubes was estimated to be 0.35 +/- 0.2 nm, which is very close to the ideal value. The SWNT BP was also found to be impervious to liquids such as water, n-hexane, acetone, and isopropyl alcohol, indirectly verifying its close knit structure and small pore size. This is indicative of its possible use as a molecular sieve membrane.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:52:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:52:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY C, 116(35)19025-19031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp305677h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14793</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>