<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16767</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:35:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>An integrated flood inundation model for coastal urban watershed of Navi Mumbai, India</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AT</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, EP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, BK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Mass balance approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>Raster flood model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tidal modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Detention pond</dc:subject><dc:subject>Finite element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>OVERLAND-FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>DETENTION-POND</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>AREAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GIS</dc:subject><dc:description>Most urban agglomerations located in the Mumbai coastal region in India are vulnerable to flooding due to increasing frequency of the short-duration heavy rainfall, by virtue of their location at foothills on one side and tidal variations on the other side. Steep slopes in the catchment ensure fast runoff and tidal variation adds to backwater effect in the drainage system, which together are favorable for flooding. The present study simulates the flood inundation due to heavy rainfall and high-tide conditions in a coastal urban catchment within Mumbai region with detention pond. Overland flow is modeled using a mass balance approach, which can adapt to hilly slopes and smoothly accommodate detention pond hydraulics. Dynamic wave channel routing based on finite element method captures the backwater effects due to tidal variation, and raster-based flood inundation model enables direct use of digital elevation model. The integrated model is capable of simulating detention pond hydraulics within the raster flood model for heavy rainfall events. The database required for the model is obtained from the geographical information system (GIS) and remote sensing techniques. Application of the integrated model to literature problems and the catchment of the study area for two non-flooding events gave satisfactory results. Further, the model is applied to an extreme rainfall event of July 26, 2005, coinciding with high-tide conditions, which revealed vulnerability of the area to flooding despite of an existing detention pond. A sensitivity analysis on the location of detention pond indicated that catchment response can be better governed by relocating the detention pond to upstream of existing detention pond especially when heavy rainfall events are becoming frequent.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:35:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:35:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURAL HAZARDS, 73(2)403-425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-030X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-0840</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-014-1079-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16767</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>