<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17662</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:52:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance evaluation of ceiling crystallization for suppressing buoyancy-induced convection in mass transfer applications: An interferometric study</dc:title><dc:creator>VARMA, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>STRONG MAGNETIC-FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>3-DIMENSIONAL RECONSTRUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LYSOZYME CRYSTAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-SOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE-TENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLIDIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOMOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diffusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crystal growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aqueous solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interferometry</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study is concerned with the investigation of the phenomena of solute transport in aqueous solution-based crystal growth processes when the growing crystal is fixed in the upside-down (ceiling) configuration. The ceiling crystallization method has been employed for suppressing the adverse effects of buoyancy when the crystal growth experiments are conducted under normal gravity conditions. A Mach-Zehnder interferometer has been employed to record the line-of-sight images of the concentration field. In order to assess the feasibility of the ceiling crystallization approach for creating diffusion-dominated conditions, the results have been compared with that of the conventionally employed approach wherein the growing crystal is platform-supported. Experiments have been carried out for two levels of supersaturation i.e. sigma = 2% and 4% and sodium chlorate (NaCIO3) has been chosen as the model material. Results have been presented in the form of interferometric images of the concentration field, two-dimensional concentration contours and spatio-temporal variations of supersaturation around the growing crystal in both the configurations considered. Results of the experiments clearly reveal the suppression of buoyancy-induced convection currents and the formation of an extended horizontally stratified depletion zone around the growing crystal in ceiling configuration. The mass transport phenomenon was seen to be diffusion-dominated, thus eliminating the possibilities of sharp variations in the supersaturation levels in the vicinity of the crystal, which otherwise deteriorate the quality of the growing crystal in convection-dominated conditions. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:52:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:52:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 84,61-72</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-2189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2014.12.050</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17662</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>