<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18067</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:36:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Application of SWAT Model and Geospatial Techniques for Sediment-Yield Modeling in Ungauged Watersheds</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHANJAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, EP</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:subject>SOIL-EROSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sediment loads</dc:subject><dc:subject>Model studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geographic information systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:description>Extensive soil erosion has already contributed significantly to the impoverishment of land and people throughout the world. The soil lost is deposited in various reservoirs, thus reducing their capacity. Furthermore, essential plant nutrients are also lost along with the eroded topsoil. Modeling provides an approach for quantification of sediment yield. Sediment yield models ranging from empirical to distributed have been developed by many researchers. In this study, an attempt was made to use the soil and water assessment tool (SWAT) model and Geospatial techniques in an integrated way for modeling runoff and sediment yield for Khadakohol and Harsul watersheds in India. The SWAT model was calibrated for the monsoon months of a year and validated for other years. In countries like India, quantification of runoff/sediment yield is mainly constrained by the nonavailability of observed data and hence, regionalization of parameters was attempted, where the calibrated parameters from Khadakohol was used to Harsul and its applicability was assessed in an ungauged context and the results are found to be encouraging.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:36:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:36:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HYDROLOGIC ENGINEERING, 20(6SI)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1084-0699</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1943-5584</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)HE.1943-5584.0001123</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18067</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>