<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1177</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental study and theoretical analysis of local heat transfer distribution between smooth flat surface and impinging air jet from a circular straight pipe nozzle</dc:title><dc:creator>KATTI, VADIRAJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>heating equipment</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>boundary layers</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluid dynamics</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental investigation is performed to study the effect of jet-to-plate spacing and Reynolds number on the local heat transfer distribution to normally impinging submerged circular air jet on a smooth and flat surface. A single jet from a straight circular nozzle of length-to-diameter ratio (l/d) of 83 is tested. Reynolds number based on nozzle exit condition is varied between 12,000 and 28,000 and jet-to-plate spacing between 0.5 and 8 nozzle diameters. The local heat transfer characteristics are estimated using thermal images obtained by infrared thermal imaging technique. Measurements for the static wall pressure distribution due to impinging jet at different jet-to-plate spacing are made. The local heat transfer distributions are analyzed based on theoretical predictions and experimental results of the fluid flow characteristics in the various regions of jet impingement. The heat transfer at the stagnation point is analyzed from the static wall pressure distribution. Semi-analytical solution for heat transfer in the stagnation region is obtained assuming an axisymmetric laminar boundary layer with favourable pressure gradient. The heat transfer in the wall jet region is studied considering fluid flow over a flat plate of constant heat flux. However, heat transfers in the transition region are explained from reported fluid dynamic behaviour in this region. Correlations for the local Nusselt numbers in different regions are obtained and compared with experimental results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-21T14:08:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:01:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-21T14:08:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:01:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer 51(17-18), 4480-4495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2007.12.024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1177</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>