<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14168</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:44:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Failure probability evaluation of passive system using fuzzy Monte Carlo simulation</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, MH</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAIKWAD, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>RELIABILITY EVALUATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Passive systems have become an inherent feature of the advanced reactors. The main reason being the passive systems are, theoretically, more reliable than the active ones. Nevertheless the passive system may fail to fulfill its mission not only because of a consequence of classical mechanical failure of component (passive or active) of the passive system, but also due to the deviation from expected behavior due to physical phenomena mainly related to thermal hydraulic or due to different boundary or initial conditions. In this paper the methodology used for performing the passive system reliability analysis has been discussed. A case study on passive decay heat removal system (PDHRS) of large sized pressurized heavy water reactor (PHWR) has been discussed. Thermal hydraulic analysis have been carried out by using RELAP5 code to generate the response surface (from various ranges of identified key parameter values), keeping the criterion as clad surface temperature exceeding certain critical value. Some uncertainties, due to incomplete information, cannot be handled satisfactorily in the probability theory and the fuzzy set theory is more appropriate. In this study the random variables are considered as fuzzy numbers and the fuzzy set theory is employed. In addition, the Monte Carlo simulation technique is utilized to evaluate the probability of failure of system. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:44:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:44:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN,241(5)1864-1872</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2011.02.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14168</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>