<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12599</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Statistical mechanics for analytic planning: an application to domestic air traffic in China</dc:title><dc:creator>HUBER, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>airport planning</dc:subject><dc:subject>power law distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>preferential attachment</dc:subject><dc:subject>de-peaking</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport networks</dc:subject><dc:description>Statistical mechanics has shown its usefulness when assessing the topology of many networks, including those of infrastructure. Its principles take into account the large-scale and network-wide effects of changes in its key parameters, which in turn may provide critical input when planning for infrastructure projects. One objective would be to modify the pattern of capacity expansions inside a system to make it less exposed to local shortfalls in demand. To illustrate our point, we shall use domestic air traffic in China; airports are spatially distributed and they also need to respond to the potential demand that they face locally. Airlines that control parts of the traffic system are identified as agents. A relationship between the agent's behavior and the system-wide level of variance in traffic flows can be established by regression analysis. It is shown how intervention on these agents would reduce negative traffic variance while enhancing a more balanced, less costly growth of the system itself.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T05:28:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T05:28:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSPORTATION PLANNING AND TECHNOLOGY, 33(7), 551-567</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0308-1060</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03081060.2010.512214</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12599</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12599</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>