<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14139</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:30:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>On the choice of importance distributions for unconstrained and constrained state estimation using particle filter</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAKASH, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, SL</dc:creator><dc:subject>ENSEMBLE KALMAN FILTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAYESIAN-ESTIMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DATA RECONCILIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>APPROXIMATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nonlinear observers</dc:subject><dc:subject>Particle filters</dc:subject><dc:subject>Constrained state estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Importance sampling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Truncated distributions and unscented particle filter</dc:subject><dc:description>Recursive state estimation of constrained nonlinear dynamical system has attracted the attention of many researchers in recent years. For nonlinear/non-Gaussian state estimation problems, particle filters have been widely used (Arulampalam et al. [1]). As pointed out by Daum [2], particle filters require a proposal distribution and the choice of proposal distribution is the key design issue. In this paper, a novel approach for generating the proposal distribution based on a constrained Extended Kalman filter (C-EKF), Constrained Unscented Kalman filter (C-UKF) and constrained Ensemble Kalman filter (C-EnkF) has been proposed. The efficacy of the proposed state estimation algorithms using a particle filter is illustrated via a successful implementation on a simulated gas-phase reactor, involving constraints on estimated state variables and another example problem, which involves constraints on the process noise (Rao et al. [10]). We also propose a state estimation scheme for estimating state variables in an autonomous hybrid system using particle filter with Unscented Kalman filter as a proposal and unconstrained Ensemble Kalman filter (EnKF) as a proposal. The efficacy of the proposed state estimation scheme for an autonomous hybrid system is demonstrated by conducting simulation studies on a three-tank hybrid system. The simulation studies underline the crucial role played by the choice of proposal distribution in formulation of particle filters. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:30:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:30:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PROCESS CONTROL,21(1)3-16</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-1524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jprocont.2010.08.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14139</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>