<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17576</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:08:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Constraints based analysis of extended cybernetic models</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDLI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MODAK, JM</dc:creator><dc:subject>BACTERIAL-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENE-EXPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMAL STRATEGISTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADAPTIVE EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROBIAL-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>METABOLISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROORGANISMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cybernetic model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Constraints based analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Linear growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optimal growth</dc:subject><dc:description>The cybernetic modeling framework provides an interesting approach to model the regulatory phenomena occurring in microorganisms. In the present work, we adopt a constraints based approach to analyze the nonlinear behavior of the extended equations of the cybernetic model. We first show that the cybernetic model exhibits linear growth behavior under the constraint of no resource allocation for the induction of the key enzyme. We then quantify the maximum achievable specific growth rate of microorganisms on mixtures of substitutable substrates under various kinds of regulation and show its use in gaining an understanding of the regulatory strategies of microorganisms. Finally, we show that Saccharomyces cerevisiae exhibits suboptimal dynamic growth with a long diauxic lag phase when growing on a mixture of glucose and galactose and discuss on its potential to achieve optimal growth with a significantly reduced diauxic lag period. The analysis carried out in the present study illustrates the utility of adopting a constraints based approach to understand the dynamic growth strategies of microorganisms. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ireland Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:08:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:08:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOSYSTEMS, 137,45-54</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0303-2647</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-8324</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biosystems.2015.09.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17576</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>