<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15307</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T17:17:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Room temperature relaxor ferroelectricity and spin glass behavior in Sr2FeTiO6 double perovskite</dc:title><dc:creator>LEKSHMI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PILLAI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANTHOSH, PN</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARMA, MR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Disordered systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crystal structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dielectric response</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spin glasses</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDES</dc:subject><dc:description>The structure, dielectric and magnetic properties of complex Sr2FeTiO6 double perovskite have been investigated. Reitveld analysis of X-ray powder diffraction pattern reveals that the material is stabilized in a cubic perovskite phase with Pm (3) over barm space group without the B-site cations ordering. The temperature evolution of crystal structural studies indicates the absence of structural changes with temperature. The scanning electron micrograph exhibits heterogeneous grain distribution with average grain size of 1-7.5 mu m. The bond valence sum calculations and diffusion-assisted small-polaron hopping conduction mechanism confirm the mixed valence state of Fe/Ti ions. Dielectric spectra show a broad dielectric anomaly coupled with a shift in dielectric maxima towards higher temperature with frequency, exhibiting a typical relaxor ferroelectric behavior. The relaxor behavior has been quantitatively characterized based on the phenomenological parameters (T-m, T-B, gamma, Delta T-relax). The agreement of dielectric relaxation with non-linear Vogel Fulcher relation indicates that the system is indeed a relaxor exhibiting glassy characteristics. The transport studies show a semiconductor like behavior and a negligible magnetoresistance. Furthermore, the magnetic characterisation exhibits a non-metallic spin-glass-like state below 16 K, driven by competing interactions between the antiferromagnetic and the ferromagnetic states. (C) 2012 Elsevier B. V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:17:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:17:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ALLOYS AND COMPOUNDS, 52290-95</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2012.01.091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15307</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>