<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18074</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:40:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetocaloric properties, exchange bias, and critical behavior of Ge substituted Ni50Mn36Sn14 Heusler alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJI, GR</dc:creator><dc:creator>UTHAMAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>THOMAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARMA, MR</dc:creator><dc:subject>MAGNETIC ENTROPY CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDUCED SHAPE RECOVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NI-MN-SB</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MARTENSITIC TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of Ge substitution on the magnetic, magnetocaloric, and exchange bias properties of Heusler alloy system Ni50Mn36Sn14-xGex (x = 1, 2) has been investigated. With the increase of Ge content, the cell volume decreases due to the smaller Ge radius and the martensitic transition temperature increases, while the Curie temperature of the austenite phase shows a small decrease. Metamagnetic behavior is observed in the low temperature magnetization isotherms for x = 1, whereas it is less pronounced in x = 2. The maximum magnetic entropy changes associated with the martensitic transition are 7.8 J/kg K and 2.3 J/kg K for x = 1 and 2, respectively, for a field change of 5 T. Relative cooling power is found to be more in the vicinity of the Curie temperature of the austenite phase, compared to that at the martensitic transition temperature in both x = 1 and 2. At low temperatures, both the samples exhibit exchange bias effect, with x = 2 showing higher value of exchange bias field. This is ascribed to the coexistence of ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic interactions in these alloys. Further, the critical behavior of the austenite phase of both the alloys is studied and the values of the critical exponents are found to be different from the mean field values, which is attributed to the magnetic inhomogeneity originated due to Ge substitution. (C) 2015 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:40:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:40:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 117(10)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4914527</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18074</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>