<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8755</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of engineered opals for photonic band gap properties at visible wavelengths</dc:title><dc:creator>VIJAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>spontaneous emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>conducting polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>sio2 nanospheres</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>spheres</dc:subject><dc:subject>dye</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhancement</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecules</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>range</dc:subject><dc:subject>photonic crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>opals</dc:subject><dc:subject>sintering</dc:subject><dc:subject>transfer matrix method</dc:subject><dc:description>We have performed calculations using a modified Transfer Matrix method to study the photonic band gap properties of bare opals of different diameters, different number of layers, sintered opals with filling fractions varying between 0.74 and 1.00, partial and complete coating with semi-conducting GaN and lastly, inverted opals. The two prominent directions of [00 1] and [ 111 ] have been analyzed. Sintering improves the pseudo-gap and shifts the energy range of its occurrence, while partial coating gives a larger fall in transmission coefficient than complete coating. Inverted opals in GaN background show a stop band with lower transmission coefficient compared to coated opals due to an improvement in dielectric contrast. Our computational approach with the modified transfer matrix method based on a cubic unit cell in spherical polar coordinates is easier to implement with comparable accuracy as other methods to study electromagnetic wave propagation in different directions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ASSOC CULTIVATION SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T10:02:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T10:02:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF PHYSICS AND PROCEEDINGS OF THE INDIAN ASSOCIATION FOR THE CULTIVATION OF SCIENCE-PART B, 77B(2), 201-205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0252-9254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8755</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8755</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>