<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6848</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>p-i interface engineering and i-layer control of hot-wire a-Si:H based p-i-n solar cells using in-situ ellipsometry</dc:title><dc:creator>BAUER, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, RO</dc:creator><dc:creator>HERBST, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>DIEHL, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHRODER, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>amorphous-silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>deposition method</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>amorphous silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>conversion efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>ellipsometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>i-v characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>interfaces</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper we report on the effect of monitoring the i-layer region near the p-i interface with the help of in-situ kinetic and spectroscopic ellipsometry on the performance of hot-wire deposited hydrogenated amorphous silicon p-i-n solar cells. It is very clearly observed that the microstructure at the p-i interface region in terms of the Si-Si bond packing density and surface roughness significantly affects the cell performance. The filament temperature, T-Fil, Was the main parameter varied to control the above mentioned two properties near the p-i interface as well as in the bulk i-layer. In order to achieve significant enhancement in the cell performance we extended the idea of the ''soft start'', earlier employed for the glow discharge deposited solar cells, to the hot-wire deposited i-layer. We were able to control the i-layer properties at the p-i interface and in the bulk independently and correlate these to the cell performance. It is shown that a major increase in cell performance can be achieved by improving the microstructure of the growing film directly at the p-i interface. Most interestingly, no significant deterioration in cell efficiency has been observed if only the p-i interface was properly controlled but the i-layer was of lower quality. These results are also shown to be consistent with model calculations of a numerical simulation. Our results therefore provide a clue to prepare hot-wire a-Si:H based solar cells with high efficiency and in the whole at high growth rates, which is needed for a more economic a-Si:H solar cell production.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T01:36:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T01:36:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLAR ENERGY MATERIALS AND SOLAR CELLS, 43(4), 413-424</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-0248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0927-0248(96)00055-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6848</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6848</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>