<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14662</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:17:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular dynamics simulations of certain mutant peptide models from staphylococcal nuclease reveal that initial hydrophobic collapse associated with turn propensity drives -hairpin folding</dc:title><dc:creator>SHUKLA, RT</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SASIDHAR, YU</dc:creator><dc:subject>-turn</dc:subject><dc:subject>-hairpin</dc:subject><dc:subject>glycine mutants</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrophobic collapse</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular dynamics simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein folding</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACID-BINDING PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLE MESH EWALD</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-HAIRPIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOOP PROPENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SECONDARY STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN-EXCHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>WW DOMAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERPLAY</dc:subject><dc:description>An important nucleation event during the folding of staphylococcal nuclease involves the formation of a -hairpin by the sequence (21)DTVKLMYKGQPMTFR(35). Earlier studies show that the turn sequence YKGQP' has an important role in the folding of this -hairpin. To understand the active or passive nature of the turn sequence YKGQP' in the folding of the aforementioned -hairpin sequence, we studied glycine mutant peptides Ac-(2)DTVKLMYGGQPMTFR(16)-NMe (K9G:15), Ac-(2)DTVKLMYKGGPMTFR(16)-NMe (Q11G:15), Ac-(2)DTVKLMYGGGPMTFR(16)-NMe (K9G/Q11G:15), and Ac-(2)DTVKLMGGGGGMTFR(16)-NMe (penta-G:15) by using molecular dynamics simulations, starting with two different unfolded states, polyproline II and extended conformational forms. Further, 5mer mutant turn peptides Ac-(2)YGGQP(6)-NMe (K3G:5), Ac-(2)YKGGP(6)-NMe (Q5G:5), Ac-(2)YGGGP(6)-NMe (K3G/Q5G:5), and Ac-(2)GGGGG(6)-NMe (penta-G:5) were also studied individually. Our results show that an initial hydrophobic collapse and loop closure occurs in all 15mer mutants, but only K9G:15 mutant forms a stable native-like -hairpin. In the other 15mer mutants, the hydrophobic collapsed state would not proceed to -hairpin formation. Of the different simulations performed for the penta-G:15 mutant, in only one simulation a nonnative -hairpin conformation is sampled with highly flexible loop region ((8)GGGGG(12)), which has no specific conformational preference as a 5mer. While the sequence YGGQP' in the K3G:5 simulation shows relatively higher -turn propensity, the presence of this sequence in K9G:15 peptide seems to be driving the -hairpin formation. Thus, these results seem to suggest that for the formation of a stable-hairpin, the initial hydrophobic collapse is to be assisted by a turn propensity. Initial hydrophobic collapse alone is not sufficient to guide -hairpin formation. Copyright (c) 2013 European Peptide Society and John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:17:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:17:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PEPTIDE SCIENCE, 19(8)516-527</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/psc.2530</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14662</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>