<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4592</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Application of the Taguchi analytical method for optimization of effective parameters of the chemical vapor deposition process controlling the production of nanotubes/nanobeads</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>APTE, PR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANDARE, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZACHARIA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>wall carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>single-wall</dc:subject><dc:subject>camphor</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>strain</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>taguchi optimization for cnt</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon nanotube</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon nanobeads</dc:subject><dc:subject>cvid for cnt</dc:subject><dc:subject>cnt by taguchi optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>cnb by taguchi optimization</dc:subject><dc:description>Seven variable parameters of the chemical vapor deposition system have been optimized with the help of the Taguchi analytical method for getting a desired product, e.g., carbon nanotubes or carbon nanobeads. It is observed that almost all selected parameters influence the growth of carbon nanotubes. However, among them, the nature of precursor (racemic, R or Technical grade camphor) and the carrier gas (hydrogen, argon and mixture of argon/hydrogen) seem to be more important parameters affecting the growth of carbon nanotubes. Whereas, for the growth of nanobeads, out of seven parameters, only two, i.e., catalyst (powder of iron, cobalt, and nickel) and temperature (1023 K, 1123 K, and 1273 K), are the most influential parameters. Systematic defects or islands on the substrate surface enhance nucleation of novel carbon materials. Quantitative contributions of process parameters as well as optimum factor levels are obtained by performing analysis of variance (ANOVA) and analysis of mean (ANOM), respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T02:18:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T02:18:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY, 5(2), 288-295</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1533-4880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jnn.2005.035</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4592</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>