<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14712</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:43:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comprehensive study on molecular beam epitaxy-grown InAs sub-monolayer quantum dots with different capping combinations</dc:title><dc:creator>SENGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHADI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHUR, KL</dc:creator><dc:subject>WELL INFRARED PHOTODETECTORS</dc:subject><dc:description>Here the authors report a comprehensive study on InAs sub-monolayer quantum dots with different capping layers. After performing systematic optimization of InAs deposition and GaAs thickness, they grew three samples, namely A, B and C, using solid-state molecular beam epitaxy with identical architecture but different capping materials (2nm of GaAs, InGaAs-GaAs, and InAlGaAs-GaAs, respectively). Photoluminescence emission peaks due to the ground state transition from the dots were observed at 898, 917, and 867nm for samples A, B, and C, respectively. Narrow full-width half-maxima (19-32meV) of the emission peaks indicates high uniformity of dot size distribution. Using the conventional Arrhenius plot, the authors calculated the thermal activation energies from temperature-dependent photoluminescence experiment for samples A, B, and C as 49, 112, and 109meV, respectively. To complete the study, single-pixel photodetectors were fabricated from samples A, B, and C and temperature-dependent dark current variation with applied bias voltage was measured. Dark current was calculated to be in the range of 10(-5)-10(-4) A/cm(2) at a 0.5V applied bias at 77 K. The activation energies calculated from temperature-dependent dark current measurement for samples A, B, and C were 75, 160, and 155meV, respectively, and followed the trend observed in temperature-dependent photoluminescence measurements. (C) 2013 American Vacuum Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A V S AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:43:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:43:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VACUUM SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY B, 31(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1116/1.4805018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14712</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>