<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17992</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:58:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fluorescent ZnO for imaging and induction of DNA fragmentation and ROS-mediated apoptosis in cancer cells</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>ZINC-OXIDE NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MITOCHONDRIAL DAMAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICA NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATIVE STRESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VIVO</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOXICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYTOTOXICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISSOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARCHITECTURES</dc:subject><dc:description>Fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC)-encapsulated ZnO nanocomposite has been synthesized using the soft chemical approach. X-ray diffraction reveals the formation of highly crystalline single-phase hexagonal wurtzite nanostructure. TEM and SEM micrographs indicate the formation of spherical porous nanoassembly of ZnO of size similar to 100-400 nm. On the other hand, FITC-ZnO nanocomposite is spherical and porous but with a uniform size of similar to 150 nm. The size of single particles is similar to 20 nm for the ZnO nanoassembly and similar to 15 nm for FITC-ZnO nanocomposite. The UV-visible, fluorescence, FTIR and XPS spectra confirm the formation of FITC-ZnO nanocomposite. The FITC-ZnO nanocomposite demonstrates excellent selectivity in preferential killing of cervical (HeLa) and breast (MCF-7) cancer cells with minimal toxicity to normal fibroblast cells (L929). Apoptotic cells are observed and analyzed by confocal microscopy and flow cytometry. Our results show that cytotoxicity of FITC-ZnO nanocomposite towards cancer cells is due to the generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and preferential dissolution of Zn2+ ions in an acidic cancer microenvironment. Furthermore, generated ROS and dissolved Zn+2 ions induce cellular apoptosis, DNA fragmentation, and depolarization of mitochondrial membrane and cell cycle arrest in S phase. The FITC encapsulated multifunctional ZnO nanocomposite can be used as smart nanostructures for cell imaging and cancer therapy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY B, 3(9)1968-1978</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-750X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7518</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4tb01661k</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17992</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>