<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2920</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Generation of super-resolution images from blurred observations using Markov random fields</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJAN, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHURI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>superresolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>restoration</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a new technique for generating a high resolution image from a blurred image sequence; this is also referred to as super-resolution restoration of images. The image sequence consists of decimated, blurred and noisy versions of the high resolution image. The high resolution image is modeled as a Markov random field (MRF) and a maximum aposteriori (MAP) estimation technique is used. A simple gradient descent method is used to optimize the functional. Further, line fields are introduced in the cost function and optimization using Graduated Non-Convexity (GNC) is shown to yield improved results. Lastly, we present results of optimization using Simulated Annealing (SA).</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T22:17:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T22:17:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2001 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ACOUSTICS, SPEECH, AND SIGNAL PROCESSING, VOLS I-VI, PROCEEDINGS: VOL I: SPEECH PROCESSING 1; VOL II: SPEECH PROCESSING 2 IND TECHNOL TRACK DESIGN &amp; IMPLEMENTATION OF SIGNAL PROCESSING SYSTEMS NEURALNETWORKS FOR SIGNAL PROCESSING; VOL III: IMAGE &amp; MULTIDIMENSIONAL SIGNAL PROCESSING MULTIMEDIA SIGNAL PROCESSING - VOL IV: SIGNAL PROCESSING FOR COMMUNICATIONS; VOL V: SIGNAL PROCESSING EDUCATION SENSOR ARRAY &amp; MULTICHANNEL SIGNAL PROCESSING AUDIO &amp; ELECTROACOUSTICS; VOL VI: SIGNAL PROCESSING THEORY &amp; METHODS STUDENT FORUM,1837-1840</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-7041-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-6149</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16432</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2920</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing,SALT LAKE CITY, UT,MAY 07-11, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>