<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17956</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:40:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Proposal for a Domain Wall Nano-Oscillator driven by Non-uniform Spin Currents</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURALIDHARAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>TULAPURKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>MAGNETIC TUNNEL-JUNCTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TORQUE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERROMAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESONANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:description>We propose a new mechanism and a related device concept for a robust, magnetic field tunable radio-frequency (rf) oscillator using the self oscillation of a magnetic domain wall subject to a uniform static magnetic field and a spatially non-uniform vertical dc spin current. The self oscillation of the domain wall is created as it translates periodically between two unstable positions, one being in the region where both the dc spin current and the magnetic field are present, and the other, being where only the magnetic field is present. The vertical dc spin current pushes it away from one unstable position while the magnetic field pushes it away from the other. We show that such oscillations are stable under noise and can exhibit a quality factor of over 1000. A domain wall under dynamic translation, not only being a source for rich physics, is also a promising candidate for advancements in nanoelectronics with the actively researched racetrack memory architecture, digital and analog switching paradigms as candidate examples. Devising a stable rf oscillator using a domain wall is hence another step towards the realization of an all domain wall logic scheme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:40:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:40:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, 5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2045-2322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep14647</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17956</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>