<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15364</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:42:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Response of piping system with semi-active variable stiffness damper under tri-directional seismic excitation</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, GR</dc:creator><dc:subject>ISOLATED BUILDINGS</dc:subject><dc:description>Seismic loads on piping system due to earthquakes can cause excessive vibrations, which can lead to serious instability resulting in damage or complete failure. In this paper, semi-active variable stiffness dampers (SAVSDs) have been studied to mitigate seismic response and vibration control of piping system used in the process industries, fossil and fissile fuel power plant. The SAVSD changes its stiffness depending upon the piping response and accordingly adds the control forces in the piping system. A study is conducted on the performance of SAVSD due to variation in device stiffness ratios in the switching control law and modified switching control law, which plays an important role in the present control algorithm of the damper. The effectiveness of the SAVSD in terms of reduction in the responses, namely, displacements, accelerations and base shear of the piping system is investigated by comparing uncontrolled responses under four different artificial earthquake motions with increasing amplitudes. The analytical results demonstrate that the SAVSDs under particular optimum parameters are very effective and practically implementable for the seismic response mitigation, vibration control and seismic requalification of piping systems. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:42:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:42:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 258130-143</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2013.01.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15364</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>