<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1575</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mafic xenoliths in Proterozoic kimberlites from Eastern Dharwar Craton, India: Mineralogy and P–T regime</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANILKUMAR, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAKUR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATI, JK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAYAK, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>proterozoic kimberlites</dc:subject><dc:subject>clinopyroxene</dc:subject><dc:subject>geothermobarometric</dc:subject><dc:subject>eclogite</dc:subject><dc:subject>metamorphosed  oceanic</dc:subject><dc:description>Mafic xenoliths of garnet pyroxenite and eclogite from the Wajrakarur, Narayanpet and Raichur kimberlite fields in the Archaean Eastern Dharwar Craton (EDC) of southern India have been studied. The composition of clinopyroxene shows transition from omphacite (3–6 wt% Na2O) in eclogites to Ca pyroxene (&lt;3 wt% Na2O) in garnet pyroxenites. Some of the xenoliths have additional phases such as kyanite, enstatite, chromian spinel or rutile as discrete grains. Clinopyroxene in a rutile eclogite has an XMg value of 0.70, which is unusually low compared to the XMg range of 0.91–0.97 for all other samples. Garnet in the rutile eclogite is also highly iron-rich with an end member composition of Prp26.5Alm52.5Grs14.7Adr5.1TiAdr0.3Sps1.0Uv0.1. Garnets in several xenoliths are Cr-rich with up to 8 mol% knorringite component. Geothermobarometric calculations in Cr-rich xenoliths yield different P–T ranges for eclogites and garnet pyroxenites with average P–T conditions of 36 kbar and 1080 °C, and 27 kbar and 830 °C, respectively. The calculated P–T ranges approximate to a 45 mW m−2 model geotherm, which is on the higher side of the typical range of xenolith/xenocryst geotherms (35–45 mW m−2) for several Archaean cratons in the world. This indicates that the EDC was hotter than many other shield regions of the world in the mid-Proterozoic period when kimberlites intruded the craton. Textural and mineral chemical characteristics of the mafic xenoliths favour a magmatic cumulate process for their origin as opposed to subducted and metamorphosed oceanic crust.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-27T08:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-27T08:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Asian Earth Sciences 34(3), 336-346</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1575</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>