<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16307</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:02:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nano-scale NiSi and n-type silicon based Schottky barrier diode as a near infra-red detector for room temperature operation</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MIDYA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>OPTICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NICKEL SILICIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTODETECTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEIGHT</dc:subject><dc:description>The fabrication of nano-scale NiSi/n-Si Schottky barrier diode by rapid thermal annealing process is reported. The characterization of the nano-scale NiSi film was performed using Micro-Raman Spectroscopy and X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS). The thickness of the film (27nm) has been measured by cross-sectional Secondary Electron Microscopy and XPS based depth profile method. Current-voltage (I-V) characteristics show an excellent rectification ratio (I-ON/I-OFF = 10(5)) at a bias voltage of +/- 1V. The diode ideality factor is 1.28. The barrier height was also determined independently based on I-V (0.62 eV) and high frequency capacitance-voltage technique (0.76 eV), and the correlation between them has explained. The diode photo-response was measured in the range of 1.35-2.5 mu m under different reverse bias conditions (0.0-1.0 V). The response is observed to increase with increasing reverse bias. From the photo-responsivity study, the zero bias barrier height was determined to be 0.54 eV. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:02:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:02:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 116(12)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4896365</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16307</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>