<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15154</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:28:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Alteration in cell surface properties of Burkholderia spp. during surfactant-aided biodegradation of petroleum hydrocarbons</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHANTY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Direct interfacial uptake</dc:subject><dc:subject>Contact angle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cell surface charge</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zeta potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface functional groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRUDE-OIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>BACTERIAL SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXIGUOBACTERIUM-AURANTIACUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>INFRARED-SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>N-ALKANES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROPHOBICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRAINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE</dc:subject><dc:description>Chemical surfactants may impact microbial cell surface properties, i.e., cell surface hydrophobicity (CSH) and cell surface charge, and may thus affect the uptake of components from non-aqueous phase liquids (NAPLs). This work explored the impact of Triton X-100, Igepal CA 630, and Tween 80 (at twice the critical micelle concentration, CMC) on the cell surface characteristics of Burkholderia cultures, Burkholderia cepacia (ES1, aliphatic degrader) and Burkholderia multivorans (NG1, aromatic degrader), when grown on a six-component model NAPL. In the presence of Triton X-100, NAPL biodegradation was enhanced from 21% to 60% in B. cepacia and from 18% to 53% in B. multivorans. CSH based on water contact angle (50-52A degrees) was in the same range for both strains while zeta potential at neutral pH was -38 and -31 mV for B. cepacia and B. multivorans, respectively. In the presence of Triton X-100, their CSH increased to greater than 75A degrees and the zeta potential decreased. This induced a change in the mode of uptake and initiated aliphatic hydrocarbon degradation by B. multivorans and increased the rate of aliphatic hydrocarbon degradation in B. cepacia. Igepal CA 630 and Tween 80 also altered the cell surface properties. For B. cepacia grown in the presence of Triton X-100 at two and five times its CMC, CSH increased significantly in the log growth phase. Growth in the presence of the chemical surfactants also affected the abundance of chemical functional groups on the cell surface. Cell surface changes had maximum impact on NAPL degradation in the presence of emulsifying surfactants, Triton X-100 and Igepal CA630.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:28:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:28:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED MICROBIOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 94(1)193-204</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00253-011-3703-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15154</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>