<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15243</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:45:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>The Impact of n-p-n Selector-Based Bipolar RRAM Cross-Point on Array Performance</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAPATI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BORKAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASAN, VSS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAFNA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARKARE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>LODHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>Bipolar Resistive RAM (RRAM)</dc:subject><dc:subject>circuit model</dc:subject><dc:subject>cross-point memory array</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-p-n selector</dc:subject><dc:subject>punch-through bipolar selector device</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistance ratio (RR)</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMORY DEVICE</dc:subject><dc:description>Recently, we have presented a circuit model of the n-p-n selector, validated by experimentally calibrated TCAD data and implemented in SPICE for cross-point memory array performance analysis. In this paper, we study the array circuit performance during memory operations and present five interesting insights. First, power consumption minimization during set/reset operation produces the dominant constraint that defines selector/memory pairing, and consequently the cross-point non-linearity, i.e., ON-OFF current ratio (K-I). Second, an optimal K-I exists (e. g., 104 for 1-M array size), which implies that excessively higher K-I degrades performance. Third, parallel read operation (i.e., N bits/read) can be performed and N increases with higher resistance in low-resistance state (R-LRS) without compromising read margin (RM). Fourth, higher resistance ratio improves RM. Finally, read circuit with an improved sensitivity is highly attractive as 2x lesser RM requirement can improve parallel read capability by 10x.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:45:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:45:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ELECTRON DEVICES, 60(10)3385-3392</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9383</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9646</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TED.2013.2279553</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15243</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>