<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6867</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>pH-sensitive freeze-dried chitosan-polyvinyl pyrrolidone hydrogels as controlled release system for antibiotic delivery</dc:title><dc:creator>RISBUD, MV</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARDIKAR, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHONDE, RR</dc:creator><dc:subject>oral sustained delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug-delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>helicobacter-pylori</dc:subject><dc:subject>invitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>ulcer</dc:subject><dc:subject>chitosan</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyvinyl pyrrolidone</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogel</dc:subject><dc:subject>controlled release</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug delivery</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of this study was to develop a pH-sensitive chitosan/polyvinyl pyrrolidone (PVP) based controlled drug release system for antibiotic delivery. The hydrogels were synthesised by crosslinking chitosan and PVP blend with glutaraldehyde to form a semi-interpenetrating polymer network (semi-IPN). The semi-IPN formation was confirmed by Fourier transform infrared spectroscopic (FTIR) analysis. Semi-IPNs, viz, air-dried and freeze-dried, were compared for their surface morphology, wettability, swelling properties and pH-dependent swelling. Air- and freeze-dried membranes were also incorporated with amoxicillin and antibiotic release was studied. Porous freeze-dried hydrogels (pore diameter, 39.20+/-2.66 mu m) exhibited superior pH-dependent swelling properties over non-porous air-dried hydrogels. A high octane contact angle (144.20+/-0.580) of hydrogel was indicative of its hydrophilic nature. Increased swelling of hydrogels, under acidic conditions, was due to the protonation of a primary amino group on chitosan, as confirmed by FTIR analysis. Freeze-dried membranes released around 73% of the amoxicillin (33% by air-dried) in 3 h at pH 1.0 and, thus, had superior drug-release properties to air-dried hydrogels. Freeze-dried membranes could serve as potent candidates for antibiotic delivery in an acidic environment. (C) 2000   .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T09:40:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T09:40:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CONTROLLED RELEASE, 68(1), 23-30</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-3659</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0168-3659(00)00208-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6867</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6867</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>