<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14864</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:07:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular Interpretation of ACTH-beta-Endorphin Coaggregation: Relevance to Secretory Granule Biogenesis</dc:title><dc:creator>RANGANATHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGRU, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PADINHATEERI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>HUMAN-DISEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGGREGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEPTIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMYLOIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HORMONES</dc:subject><dc:description>Peptide/protein hormones could be stored as non-toxic amyloid-like structures in pituitary secretory granules. ACTH and beta-endorphin are two of the important peptide hormones that get co-stored in the pituitary secretory granules. Here, we study molecular interactions between ACTH and beta-endorphin and their colocalization in the form of amyloid aggregates. Although ACTH is known to be a part of ACTH-beta-endorphin aggregate, ACTH alone cannot aggregate into amyloid under various plausible conditions. Using all atom molecular dynamics simulation we investigate the early molecular interaction events in the ACTH-beta-endorphin system, beta-endorphin-only system and ACTH-only system. We find that beta-endorphin and ACTH formed an interacting unit, whereas negligible interactions were observed between ACTH molecules in ACTH-only system. Our data suggest that ACTH is not only involved in interaction with beta-endorphin but also enhances the stability of mixed oligomers of the entire system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PUBLIC LIBRARY SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:07:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:07:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PLOS ONE, 7(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0031924</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14864</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>