<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1211</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>In-situ reaction sintering of porous mullite-bonded silicon carbide, its mechanical behavior and high temperature applications</dc:title><dc:creator>BARDHAN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>aqueous suspension</dc:subject><dc:subject>ceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>fabrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>mullite</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon carbide</dc:subject><dc:subject>porous materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal shock resistance</dc:subject><dc:description>The purpose of this work was to study reaction bonding technique as an effective way to produce porous silicon carbide ceramics. These can be tailored to have near-zero dimensional change while sintering, high service temperature under load and excellent thermal shock resistance. Sintered porous mullite-bonded silicon carbide was produced having an open porosity of 20-25%. XRD and SEM were used to confirm formation of the mullite phase and to Study the sample microstructure. Rectangular bars of the material made using the slip-casting method were tested for thermal shock resistance as a function of the critical quench temperature difference the samples could withstand. Cyclic quench tests carried out from 1000 degrees C to 5 degrees C showed a loss in elastic (Young's) modulus of the order of 40% of the initial value in the first 6-8 cycles. Further thermal cycling did not have a significant influence on the elastic modulus. The possibility of the use of porous mullite-bonded silicon carbide in various metal-melting/casting applications has been investigated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CERAMIC SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T11:42:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T11:42:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MECHANICAL PROPERTIES AND PROCESSING OF CERAMIC BINARY,TERNARY, AND COMPOSITE SYSTEMS,29(2)127-140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-470-34492-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-6219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/9780470456361.ch13</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14404</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1211</dc:identifier><dc:source>32nd International Conference on Advanced Ceramics and Composites,Daytona Beach, FL,JAN 27-FEB 01, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>