<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15009</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:30:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Growth-related model of the GAL system in Saccharomyces cerevisiae predicts behaviour of several mutant strains</dc:title><dc:creator>PANNALA, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAZARIKA, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARTIYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>GENETIC SWITCH</dc:subject><dc:subject>KLUYVEROMYCES-LACTIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSCRIPTIONAL MEMORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGULATORY PROTEINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLUCOSE REPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GALACTOSE REGULON</dc:subject><dc:subject>YEAST</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORK</dc:subject><dc:subject>GALACTOKINASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The genetic regulatory network responds dynamically to perturbations in the intracellular and extracellular environments of an organism. The GAL system in the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae has evolved to utilise galactose as an alternative carbon and energy source, in the absence of glucose in the environment. This work contains a modified dynamic model for GAL system in S. cerevisiae, which includes a novel mechanism for Ga13p activation upon induction with galactose. The modification enables the model to simulate the experimental observation that in absence of galactose, oversynthesis of Ga13p can also induce the GAL system. Subsequently, the model is related to growth on galactose and glucose in a structured manner. The growth-related models are validated with experimental data for growth on individual substrates as well as mixed substrates. Finally, the model is tested for its prediction of a variety of known mutant behaviours. The exercise shows that the authors' model with a single set of parameters is able to capture the rich behaviour of the GAL system in S. cerevisiae.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:30:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:30:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IET SYSTEMS BIOLOGY, 6(2)44-U48</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/iet-syb.2010.0060</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15009</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>