<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4118</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tetranuclear complexes of [Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](+) with TCNX ligands (TCNX = TCNE, TCNQ, TCNB): Intramolecular electron transfer alternatives in compounds (mu(4)-TCNX)[MLn](4)</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITY, AN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHWEDERSKI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZALIS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>FIEDLER, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUBOC, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>GRUNERT, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUTLICH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAIM, W</dc:creator><dc:subject>order regular approximation</dc:subject><dc:subject>density-functional calculations</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-carbonyl-complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic-based magnet</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-metal</dc:subject><dc:subject>equals 7,7,8,8-tetracyanoquinodimethane</dc:subject><dc:subject>coordination chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation-states</dc:subject><dc:subject>charge-transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>valence</dc:subject><dc:description>The complexes {(mu(4)-TCNX)[Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](4)}(BF4)(4) were prepared as light-sensitive materials from [Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5) (THF)](BF4) and the corresponding TCNX ligands (TCNE = tetracyanoethene, TCNQ = 7,7,8,8-tetracyano-p-quinodimethane, TCNB = 1,2,4,5-tetracyanobenzene). Whereas the TCNE and TCNQ complexes are extremely easily reduced species with reduction potentials &gt;+0.3 V vs ferrocenium/ferrocene, the tetranuclear complex of TCNB exhibits a significantly more negative reduction potential at about -1.0 V. Even for the complexes with strongly pi-accepting TCNE and TCNQ, the very positive reduction potentials, the unusually high nitrile stretching frequencies &gt; 2235 cm(-1), and the high-energy charge-transfer transitions indicate negligible metal-to-ligand electron transfer in the ground state, corresponding to a largely unperturbed (TCNX degrees)(Fe-II)(4) formulation of oxidation states as caused by orthogonality between the metal-centered HOMO and the pi* LUMO of TCNX. Mossbauer spectroscopy confirms the low-spin iron(II) state, and DFT calculations suggest coplanar TCNE and TCNQ bridging ligands in the complex tetracations. One-electron reduction to the 3+ forms of the TCNE and TCNQ complexes produces EPR spectra which confirm the predominant ligand character of the then singly occupied MO through isotropic g values slightly below 2, in addition to a negligible g anisotropy of frozen solutions at frequencies up to 285 GHz and also through an unusually well-resolved solution X band EPR spectrum of {(mu(4)-TCNE)[Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](4)}(3+) which shows the presence of four equivalent [Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](+) moieties through Fe-57 and C-13(CO) hyperfine coupling in nonenriched material. DFT calculations reproduce the experimental EPR data. A survey of discrete TCNE and TCNQ complexes [(mu(4)-TCNX)(MLn)(4)] exhibits a dichotomy between the systems {(mu(4)-TCNX)[Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](4)}(4+) and {(mu(4)-TCNQ)[Re(CO)(3)(bpy)](4)}(4+) with their negligible metal-to-ligand electron transfer and several other compounds of TCNE or TCNQ with Mn, Ru, Os, or Cu complex fragments which display evidence for a strong such interaction, i.e., an appreciable value delta in the formulation {(mu(4)-TCNX delta-)[Mx+delta/4Ln](4)}. Irreversibility of the first reduction of {(mu(4)-TCNB)[Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](4)}(BF4)(4) precluded spectroelectrochemical studies; however, the high-energy CN stretching frequencies and charge transfer absorptions of that TCNB analogue also confirm the exceptional position of the complexes {(mu(4)-TCNX)[Fe(CO)(2)(C5H5)](4)}(BF4)(4).</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T01:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T01:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 46(18), 7312-7320</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic062253k</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4118</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>