<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8712</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spectroscopic studies of hydrogen related defects in CVD diamond</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDEY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUGANDHI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>D'CUNHA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIKDER, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>cvd diamond</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman spectra</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen related defects</dc:subject><dc:description>Thin diamond films prepared by the hot filament chemical vapour deposition (HFCVD) method at various deposition pressures have been characterized using a variety of spectroscopic techniques. Interpretation of the spectral details have provided useful information about the nature of the films. Deposition pressure appears to affect the quality of the diamond films which is reflected in terms of the position and width of the characteristic Raman peak of diamond. Raman spectra of the films prepared at low deposition pressures showed the presence of a sharp peak at similar to 1332 cm(-1) characteristic of the T-2g mode of diamond. The study of the effect of deposition pressure on the diamond growth, shows that in the range between 20 torr and 60 torr, there is little effect on the width and the shift of the 1332 cm(-1) Raman peak. However, at higher pressures the peak showed a blue shift and was considerably broadened. These studies indicate the development of strain in the lattice due to the introduction of unetched hydride layer, at higher deposition pressures, as well as distortions in the lattice leading to partial lifting of the degeneracy of the T-2g mode. A broad band corresponding to the non-diamond phase (which exists at the grain boundaries, interface or as inclusions inside the grain), which can be attributed to the effect of hydrogen impurity creeping into the lattice at higher deposition pressures is also observed. SEM and XRD patterns have confirmed the dominance of diamond phase in these films.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T07:40:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T07:40:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 21(6), 479-484</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-4707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02790350</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8712</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8712</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>