<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3720</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of Multiple Reactions on a Bipolar Electrode</dc:title><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GURUMOORTHY, AVP</dc:creator><dc:creator>CONTRACTOR, AQ</dc:creator><dc:subject>fluidized-bed electrode</dc:subject><dc:subject>spherical ultramicroelectrodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemical-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>dispersions</dc:subject><dc:subject>evolution</dc:subject><dc:description>Open bipolar electrolysis is a useful technique for conducting electrolytic processes in low concentrations of electrolytes or in nonaqueous solutions. In bipolar electrolysis, both cathodic and anodic reactions occur on the same electrode. In this paper, we analyze the case of multiple reactions occurring in a bipolar manner oil a single metal spheroid Simulations are conducted for various cases involving two redox reactions. Effects of the parameters such as intensity of the imposed electric field, the Nernst potentials, exchange current densities, and transfer coefficients oil the current density and the extent of coupling between the reactions have been investigated The asymptotic cases of low and high imposed electric fields are also considered, for which simple analytic solutions are derived. Together, they cover a major operating region of practical importance. Some important insights into coupling of the reactions oil the bipolar electrode have been obtained. These provide useful criteria for design of bipolar electrolytic systems</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T16:38:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T16:38:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 48(21), 9441-9456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie900437n</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3720</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3720</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>