<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18137</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:13:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>A new compact polarimetric SAR decomposition technique</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUHURI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURENDAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>RADAR OBSERVATIONS</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we have proposed a new decomposition technique for compact polarimetric (CP) synthetic aperture radar (SAR) data. In the proposed decomposition, the odd and the even bounce scattering powers P-S and P-D are, respectively, obtained by combining the powers received in the opposite-sense circular (OC) polarization and the same-sense circular (SC) polarization transmitted with the polarized power fraction (Omega). The volume scattering power P-V is obtained by combining the total power with the unpolarized power fraction (1 - Omega). The parameter Omega is a function of both the transmitting and the receiving ellipticities (chi(t), chi(r)) and orientations (psi(t)psi(r)). These parameters thus provide a wider degree of freedom to accommodate a range of scattering mechanisms which are not reflected in the existing approaches. The proposed method is applied on simulated CP-SAR data obtained from full-polarimetric E-SAR (Experimental Synthetic Aperture Radar) and AIRSAR (Airborne Synthetic Aperture Radar) L-band data sets. The proposed decomposition shows appreciable improvements in the scattering powers compared to the m - delta and the m - chi decompositions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:13:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:13:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>REMOTE SENSING LETTERS, 6(12)914-923</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2150-704X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2150-7058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/2150704X.2015.1088669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18137</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>