<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-691</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:08:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Estimation of soil-moisture and surface-roughness parameters from backscattering coefficient</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>microwave</dc:subject><dc:subject>dependence</dc:subject><dc:subject>models</dc:subject><dc:description>A statistical inversion technique was implemented to estimate soil moisture and surface roughness parameters from the remotely sensed multifrequency backscattering coefficients. Both two- and three-frequency approaches were examined and tested in detail for the inversion technique. Initially the technique was tested with a simulated data set generated from various scattering models. Later it was applied to an experimental data set that pro ided, for a w ide range of surface roughness and soil moisture, backscattering coefficients at many incidence angles and frequencies. It was found that, in general, the three-frequency approach produce more accurate results. However, under a favorable combination of frequencies and incidence angles, both approaches give results with a comparable accuracy. There is a potential that soil moisture could be estimated to an accuracy of about 2%. In the mean time the surface roughness parameters could be estimated to an accuracy of better than 10%.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-10T15:05:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:08:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-10T15:05:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:08:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Note</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING,31(5)1094-1099</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-2892</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/36.263781</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/691</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>