<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18361</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:35:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assessment of MRI-Based Automated Fetal Cerebral Cortical Folding Measures in Prediction of Gestational Age in the Third Trimester</dc:title><dc:creator>WU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>AWATE, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>LICHT, DJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>CLOUCHOUX, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>DU PLESSIS, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVANTS, BB</dc:creator><dc:creator>VOSSOUGH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GEE, JC</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIMPEROPOULOS, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>IN-UTERO</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOLUME RECONSTRUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BRAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORTEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATTERNS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEWBORN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPE</dc:subject><dc:description>BACKGROUND AND PURPOSE: Traditional methods of dating a pregnancy based on history or sonographic assessment have a large variation in the third trimester. We aimed to assess the ability of various quantitative measures of brain cortical folding on MR imaging in determining fetal gestational age in the third trimester. MATERIALS AND METHODS: We evaluated 8 different quantitative cortical folding measures to predict gestational age in 33 healthy fetuses by using T2-weighted fetal MR imaging. We compared the accuracy of the prediction of gestational age by these cortical folding measures with the accuracy of prediction by brain volume measurement and by a previously reported semiquantitative visual scale of brain maturity. Regression models were constructed, and measurement biases and variances were determined via a cross-validation procedure. RESULTS: The cortical folding measures are accurate in the estimation and prediction of gestational age (mean of the absolute error, 0.43 +/- 0.45 weeks) and perform better than (P = .024) brain volume (mean of the absolute error, 0.72 +/- 0.61 weeks) or sonography measures (SDs approximately 1.5 weeks, as reported in literature). Prediction accuracy is comparable with that of the semiquantitative visual assessment score (mean, 0.57 +/- 0.41 weeks). CONCLUSIONS: Quantitative cortical folding measures such as global average curvedness can be an accurate and reliable estimator of gestational age and brain maturity for healthy fetuses in the third trimester and have the potential to be an indicator of brain-growth delays for at-risk fetuses and preterm neonates.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC NEURORADIOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:35:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:35:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AMERICAN JOURNAL OF NEURORADIOLOGY, 36(7)1369-1374</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0195-6108</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1936-959X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3174/ajnr.A4357</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18361</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>