<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2823</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>The Chylla-Haase problem : a neural network controller</dc:title><dc:creator>BHAT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANAVAR, RN</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper presents the solution to an industrial challenge problem using neural networks. The control problem statement is authored by R. W. Chylla and D. R. Haase and ap pears in a special issue of [1]. The objective is to maintain reaction temperature of a semibatch polymerization reactor at a set point inspite of a variety of conditions ranging from raw material impurity, product variety, repeated batching and varying ambient temperature. Although the reader configuration and control requirements appear simple, the realities of the problem make it a challenging problem to tackle. The controller design methodology is based on process inverse dynamics modelling. The learning data-base for the controller training is generated in an open loop fashion and Graining of the network is carried out off-line by considering the future plant outputs as the reference set points. The learning procedure is not goal directed in that an explicit goal is not defined. This paper follows the design of the controller.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T14:22:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T14:22:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE 1998 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON CONTROL APPLICATIONS, VOLS 1 AND 2,192-196</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-4104-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16323</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2823</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Conference on Control Applications,TRIESTE, ITALY,SEP 01-04, 1998</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>