<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15198</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:50:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Monitoring torque and traverse force in friction stir welding from input electrical signatures of driving motors</dc:title><dc:creator>MEHTA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Friction stir welding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Torque</dc:subject><dc:subject>Traverse force</dc:subject><dc:subject>Temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEAK TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CUTTING FORCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOOLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>PIN</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental measurements of torque, traverse force and thermal cycles in friction stir welding (FSW) are challenging due to the simultaneous rotational and linear motions of the tool and the deformation of workpiece material around the tool pin. We propose here a methodology to measure the torque and the traverse force by monitoring the current and power transients of the electrical motors that drive the rotational and linear motions of the FSW tool respectively. The measured values of torque and traverse force in FSW of AA 7075-T6 and AA 2524-T351 at different combinations of tool rotational speed and tool shoulder diameter are validated with the corresponding computed results from a well tested numerical model. The proposed method alleviates the need to use expensive torque and force dynamometers, and provides an economical and robust route for indirect measurement of real time torque and traverse force in FSW.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MANEY PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:50:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:50:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF WELDING AND JOINING, 18(3)191-197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1179/1362171812Y.0000000084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15198</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>