<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8687</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>PALEOMAGNETISM AND ROCK MAGNETISM OF THE DECCAN TRAPS</dc:title><dc:creator>RADHAKRISHNAMURTY, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBBARAO, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>narmada region</dc:subject><dc:subject>basalts</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanomagnetites</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>paleomagnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>grains</dc:subject><dc:subject>paleomagnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>deccan traps</dc:subject><dc:subject>domain states</dc:subject><dc:subject>rock magnetism</dc:subject><dc:description>Extensive work on the palaeomagnetism of the Deccan traps by several workers has revealed only one reversal (normal-reverse-normal) of the geomagnetic field during the period of eruption of these flows. The scatter in the natural remanent magnetic directions of different flows in a sequence of these traps is rather large and it persists even after magnetic cleaning. Generally this large scatter of directions is attributed to the geomagnetic secular variation during formation of the traps. Recent studies of the magnetic properties of the trap samples indicate that the presence of multidomain magnetite in a lava sequence differs from locality to locality in the Deccan trap province and so the stability of their natural remanent magnetization. While these features can be clearly perceived, an understanding of the same seems to be quite difficult. However, it appears that part of the scatter in directions could be due to the alteration of the magnetic minerals in the Deccan traps and hence it would not be proper to relate the entire scatter to the secular variation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T06:11:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T06:11:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>1990</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INDIAN ACADEMY OF SCIENCES-EARTH AND PLANETARY SCIENCES, 99(4), 669-680</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8687</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>