<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8552</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design and implementation of FPGA-based phase modulation control for series resonant inverters</dc:title><dc:creator>GAYATHRI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, MC</dc:creator><dc:subject>series resonant inverter</dc:subject><dc:subject>zero-voltage switching</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase modulation control</dc:subject><dc:subject>digital control</dc:subject><dc:subject>fpga</dc:subject><dc:subject>limit cycle</dc:subject><dc:description>Owing to the tremendous advances in the digital technology, and improved reliability and performance of the digital control mechanisms, this paper focuses on design and implementation of digital controller using FPGA-based circuit design approach. The digital controller proposed is designed for series resonant inverter used in DC-DC converter applications. Phase modulation technique is proposed for the realization of digital controller on FPGA. The Series Resonant Converter (SRC) is considered in this paper as a preferred converter topology for high power, high voltage power supplies. This paper studies the implementation of phase shift modulation technique using FPGA. The inverter designed, is IGBT based, and Zero Voltage Switching (ZVS) technique is implemented due to reduced stresses on devices and increased efficiency. The phase modulated series resonant inverters (PM-SRC) promotes ZVS operation when its switching frequency is greater than resonant frequency. The designed PM controller is realized using FPGA on which control algorithm and other features of a controller are developed. The series resonant inverter is built and tested for full load under open loop and closed loop conditions at a switching frequency of 20 kHz. The results are presented under varying load conditions. The simulation and the experimental results were found to match closely.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T21:38:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T21:38:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SADHANA-ACADEMY PROCEEDINGS IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES, 33(5), 505-522</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-2499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8552</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8552</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>