<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10303</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Numerical and model studies of strip footing supported by a reinforced granular fill-soft soil system</dc:title><dc:creator>LEE, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANJUNATH, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEWAIKAR, DM</dc:creator><dc:subject>bearing capacity</dc:subject><dc:subject>foundation</dc:subject><dc:subject>clay</dc:subject><dc:subject>model tests</dc:subject><dc:subject>footing</dc:subject><dc:subject>bearing capacity</dc:subject><dc:subject>granular fill</dc:subject><dc:subject>clays</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite elements</dc:subject><dc:subject>geotextiles</dc:subject><dc:description>Laboratory model tests have been carried out using a rigid strip footing supported on dense sand overlying soft clay with and without a layer of geotextile reinforcement at the interface. The study aimed at determining the effect of geotextile reinforcement and the thickness of a sand layer on the ultimate bearing capacity and settlement characteristics of the footing resting on a granular fill - soft soil system. It was found that the bearing capacity increases with an increase in the ratio of sand thickness to footing width until it reaches a critical value, which can be considered as the optimum limit of improvement of the bearing capacity of the layered soil. The installation of a geotextile reinforcement at the interface resulted in an appreciable increase in bearing capacity and decrease in settlement of the footing. The optimum thickness of the sand layer for a geotextile-reinforced foundation was found to be 0.8 times the width of the footing, which was significantly lower than that of an unreinforced foundation. The results of the laboratory model tests were validated by a comparison with the results of a finite element analysis. The results obtained using the finite element model compared well with data obtained from the laboratory tests. Additional parametric study was carried out by the finite element model to supplement the results of the laboratory model tests. Design recommendations are given based on the results of the finite element model and laboratory model studies for a rigid footing supported on a reinforced granular fill - soft soil system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL RESEARCH COUNCIL CANADA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:19:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:19:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CANADIAN GEOTECHNICAL JOURNAL, 36(5), 793-806</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-3674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1139/cgj-36-5-793</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10303</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>