<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15759</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:15:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biomarker signatures from Neoproterozoic-Early Cambrian oil, western India</dc:title><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>STABLE CARBON-ISOTOPE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITIONAL ENVIRONMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROCARBON BIOMARKERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR FOSSILS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EASTERN SIBERIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOURCE ROCKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRUDE OILS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEDIMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BASIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PETROLEUM</dc:subject><dc:description>The Neoproterozoic-Early Cambrian time is the cradle of multicellular, eukaryotic life and thereafter metazoan life started populating the planet. Biomarkers, which record the chronicles of biotic events on Earth, have been investigated using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry from a suite of nine oil samples extracted from oil stained sediments and a crude oil of Neoproterozoic-Early Cambrian age from Bikaner-Nagaur Basin, western India. The biomarker distribution is characterized by high concentration of both tricyclic terpanes and pentacyclic hopanes. The predominance of C-29 regular sterane over C-27 and C-28 steranes indicates green algal contribution and may imply the prominence and diversification of the same algal group. The low pristane/phytane ratio and occurrence of substantial quantity of gammacerane, monomethyl 2-methyl-2-(2,4,8-trimethyltridecyl) chroman and 1,1,7,8-tetramethyl-1,2,3,4 tetrahydrophenanthrene are indicative of stratified water column as well as anoxic and enhanced salinity condition of the environment of deposition. This paper reports for the first time the presence of methyltrimethyltridecyl chromans (MTTCs) from Neoproterozoic-Early Cambrian time. Putative C-19 norsteranes, probably indicative of sponge input, are recorded in the studied samples and also reported from other infracambrian oils and sediments. Normal alkanes (n-C-17 and n-C-18) and isoprenoids (pristane and phytane) are highly depleted in delta C-13. The overall biomarker distribution and carbon isotope data of oils from Bikaner-Nagaur Basin show similarities with those of other infracambrian oils like Huqf oils from Oman and Baykit High oils from eastern Siberia. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:15:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:15:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANIC GEOCHEMISTRY, 5668-80</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.orggeochem.2012.12.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15759</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>