<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11997</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Disruption of MRG19 results in altered nitrogen metabolic status and defective pseudohyphal development in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, PJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>glutamate-dehydrogenase</dc:subject><dc:subject>catabolite repression</dc:subject><dc:subject>filamentous growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>yeast-cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>differentiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding</dc:subject><dc:subject>gene</dc:subject><dc:subject>gln3</dc:subject><dc:subject>transcription</dc:subject><dc:description>It was previously shown that MRG19 downregulates carbon metabolism in Saccharomyces cerevisiae upon glucose exhaustion, and that the gene is glucose repressed. Here, it is shown that glucose repression of MRG19 is overcome upon nitrogen withdrawal, suggesting that MRG19 is a regulator of carbon and nitrogen metabolism. beta-Galactosidase activity fostered by the promoter of GDH1/3, which encode anabolic enzymes of nitrogen metabolism, was altered in an MRG19 disruptant. As compared to the wild-type strain, the MRG19 disruptant showed a decrease in the ratio of 2-oxoglutarate to glutamate under nitrogen-limited conditions. MRG19 disruptants showed reduced pseudohyphal formation and enhanced sporulation, a phenomenon that occurs under conditions of both nitrogen and carbon withdrawal. These studies revealed that MRG19 regulates carbon and nitrogen metabolism, as well as morphogenetic changes, suggesting that MRG19 is a component of the link between the metabolic status of the cell and the corresponding developmental pathway.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC GENERAL MICROBIOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:32:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:32:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROBIOLOGY-SGM, 151(), 91-98</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-0872</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1099/mic.0.27347-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11997</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11997</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>