<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4759</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-17T11:00:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hadron optics in three-dimensional invariant coordinate space from deeply virtual Compton scattering</dc:title><dc:creator>BRODSKY, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARINDRANATH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARY, JP</dc:creator><dc:subject>relativistic front description</dc:subject><dc:subject>paraxial-wave optics</dc:subject><dc:subject>inelastic scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>parton distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>qcd</dc:subject><dc:subject>spin</dc:subject><dc:subject>representation</dc:subject><dc:subject>momentum</dc:subject><dc:subject>protons</dc:subject><dc:subject>models</dc:subject><dc:description>The Fourier transform of the deeply virtual Compton scattering amplitude (DVCS) with respect to the skewness parameter zeta=Q(2)/2p center dot q can be used to provide an image of the target hadron in the boost-invariant variable sigma, the coordinate conjugate to light-front time tau=t+z/c. As an illustration, we construct a consistent covariant model of the DVCS amplitude and its associated generalized parton distributions using the quantum fluctuations of a fermion state at one loop in QED, thus providing a representation of the light-front wave functions (LFWFs) of a lepton in sigma space. A consistent model for hadronic amplitudes can then be obtained by differentiating the light-front wave functions with respect to the bound-state mass. The resulting DVCS helicity amplitudes are evaluated as a function of sigma and the impact parameter b(perpendicular to), thus providing a light-front image of the target hadron in a frame-independent three-dimensional light-front coordinate space. Models for the LFWFs of hadrons in (3+1) dimensions displaying confinement at large distances and conformal symmetry at short distances have been obtained using the AdS/CFT method. We also compute the LFWFs in this model in invariant three-dimensional coordinate space. We find that, in the models studied, the Fourier transform of the DVCS amplitudes exhibit diffraction patterns. The results are analogous to the diffractive scattering of a wave in optics where the distribution in sigma measures the physical size of the scattering center in a one-dimensional system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T14:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T14:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW D, 75(1), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-7998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.75.014003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4759</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4759</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>