<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2443</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Organic sensors for explosive detection</dc:title><dc:creator>DUDHE, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEENA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>tnt</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>ofet</dc:subject><dc:subject>tnt</dc:subject><dc:subject>rdx</dc:subject><dc:subject>p3ht</dc:subject><dc:subject>cutpp</dc:subject><dc:subject>microcantilever</dc:subject><dc:subject>su-8</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer composite cantilever</dc:subject><dc:subject>explosive detection</dc:subject><dc:description>Organic field effect transistors and polymer microcantilevers are two different classes of organic sensors with potential applications in biochemical sensing. Organic field effect transistors based on poly (3-hexylthiophene) and Cull tetraphenylporphyrin composite were investigated as sensors for detection of vapors of nitrobased explosive compounds. Significant changes, suitable for sensor response, were observed in transistor -on parallel to current (Ion) and conductance (S) after exposure. A similar device response was, however, not observed for oxidizing agents such as benzoquinone and benzophenone. Polymer microcantilevers offer a sensitive cost effective platform for explosive gas detection. These sensors with optical and electrical transduction mechanisms were designed and fabricated using SU-8 polymer and they are further functionalized with appropriate coating for explosive detection. Optical and electrical responses of respective microcantilevers to TNT vapors are also reported here.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T17:47:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T17:47:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2009 4TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTERS AND DEVICES FOR COMMUNICATION (CODEC 2009),510-515</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-5073-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15780</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2443</dc:identifier><dc:source>4th International Conference on Computers and Devices for Communication,Kolkata, INDIA,DEC 14-16, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>