<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9852</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental Results on the Use of High Frequency Resonance Technique for Tapered Roller Bearing Diagnostics</dc:title><dc:creator>ANDHARE, AB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANIK, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>rolling element bearing</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>defects</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration monitoring</dc:subject><dc:subject>bearing defect diagnosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>envelope detection</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents results of experiments per-formed towards diagnosis of localized defects in tapered roller bearings, using High Frequency Resonance Technique (HFRT). A special feature of the work is that instead of using analog filter and envelope detector for HFRT, digital filtering and envelope detection were used. To practically test this technique, an experimental setup was designed and fabricated for testing various tapered roller bearings to obtain their vibration characteristics. For the purpose of testing, a few defect-free and defective tapered roller bearings were tested using the fabricated set up-the defective bearings tested included bearings with outer race defects, roller defects and combination of both. Based on the above experiments it has been shown that HFRT is an objective technique and thus useful to diagnose point defects in tapered roller bearings. In addition, due its digital implementation, the HFRT demonstrated in this paper is cheaper than its analog counterpart.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KRISHTEL EMAGING SOLUTIONS PVT LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T11:40:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T11:40:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN VIBRATION ENGINEERING, 8(4), 329-338</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0972-5768</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9852</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9852</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>