<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9420</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydraulic resistance of rigid polyurethane foams. II. Effect of variation of surfactant, water, and nucleating agent concentrations on foam structure and properties</dc:title><dc:creator>MONDAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAKHAR, DV</dc:creator><dc:subject>polyurethanes</dc:subject><dc:subject>rigid foam</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfactant concentration</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydraulic resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>structure-property relations</dc:subject><dc:description>Hydraulic resistance of rigid polyurethane foams to penetration by water at high pressures is studied in this work in the context of buoyancy applications. Micron sized silica particles are used as nucleating agents. The effect of the variation of the concentrations of the surfactant, water, and nucleating agent on cell structure, closed cell content, and compressive modulus, is examined. Foams have densities in the range of 145 to 165 kg/m(3). At a particular water concentration, with increase in the concentration of the surfactant, the window area of the cells becomes smaller and the hydraulic resistance of the foam increases. A cell window is the lamella of the foam material that separates two adjacent cells. With increase in the concentration of water keeping surfactant concentration constant, the average window area remains almost the same but the cell window area distribution becomes wider and the hydraulic resistance of the foams decreases. Foams made with silica have smaller cell windows but lower hydraulic resistance than that of the foams made without silica. (C) 2004 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T07:01:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T07:01:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED POLYMER SCIENCE, 93(6), 2830-2837</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8995</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/app.20762</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9420</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9420</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>