<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16251</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T09:09:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular fossils in Cretaceous condensate from western India</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Cretaceous</dc:subject><dc:subject>condensate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jaisalmer basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomarkers</dc:subject><dc:subject>conifer source</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORGANIC-MATTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>GIPPSLAND-BASIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRUDE OILS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOMARKERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROCARBONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUSTRALIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEDIMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GERMANY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENVIRONMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study reports the biomarker distribution of condensate belonging to the early Cretaceous time frame using gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC MS). The early Cretaceous palaeoenvironment was inscribed into these molecular fossils which reflected the source and conditions of deposition of the condensate. The saturate fraction of the condensate is characterized by normal alkanes ranging from n-C-9 to n-C-29 (CPI-1.13), cycloalkanes and C-14 and C-15 sesquiterpanes. The aromatic fraction comprises of naphthalene, phenanthrene, their methylated derivatives and cyclohexylbenzenes. Isohexylalkylnaphthalenes, a product of rearrangement process of terpenoids, is detected in the condensate. Several aromatic sesquiterpenoids and diterpenoids have been recorded. Dihydro-ar-curcumene, cadalene and ionene form the assemblage of sesquiterpenoids which are indicative of higher plant input. Aromatic diterpenoid fraction comprises of simonellite and retene. These compounds are also indicative of higher plants, particularly conifer source which had been a predominant flora during the Cretaceous time.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:09:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:09:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 123(5)923-934</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-774X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16251</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>