<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14883</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:17:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dibromidochlorido{2-[(dimethylamino)-methyl]phenyl-kappa N-2,C-1}tellurium(IV)</dc:title><dc:creator>RAKESH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTCHER, RJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>N,N-DIMETHYLBENZYLAMINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHLORIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:description>The title compound, C9H13Br2ClNTe, was synthesized by reacting [2-(dimethylaminomethyl) phenyl] tellurium(II) chloride with Br-2. As a consequence, the Cl and Br atoms are not well ordered but distributed over the three possible positions such that the overall stiochiometry is two Br atoms and one Cl atom. The scrambling of the Br and Cl atoms indicates a small energy barrier for the exchange process between the apical and equatorial positions. Overall, the Te atom geometry is slightly distorted square pyramidal (tau = 0.052 for the major component). However, there is a weak secondary interaction between the Te atoms and the disordered Br/Cl atoms of a nearby molecule. The Te-Br and Te-Cl distances in both disorder components fall into two groups; a longer distance for the Br/Cl involved in this secondary interaction [2.6945 (17) angstrom for Br and 2.601 (9) angstrom for Cl] and shorter bond distances to the remaining halogen atoms, indicating that this interaction has slightly weakened the Te-X bond, as is the case in the previously reported tribromido structure [Singh et al. (1990). J. Chem. Soc. Dalton Trans. pp. 907-913]. Otherwise, the metrical parameters in the two structures are not significantly different. An intermolecular C-H center dot center dot center dot Br interaction occurs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:17:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:17:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA CRYSTALLOGRAPHICA SECTION E-STRUCTURE REPORTS ONLINE, 68</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1107/S1600536811054560</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14883</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>