<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6765</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mesoporous H-AlMCM-48: highly efficient solid acid catalyst</dc:title><dc:creator>DAPURKAR, SE</dc:creator><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>friedel-crafts alkylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular-sieve mcm-48</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray-diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic-hydrocarbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>tertiary butylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>fine chemicals</dc:subject><dc:subject>t-butylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminosilicate</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolites</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesoporous</dc:subject><dc:subject>almcm-48</dc:subject><dc:subject>almcm-41</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid acid catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>tert-butyl phenol</dc:subject><dc:description>Mesoporous cubic Na-AlMCM-48 molecular sieve catalyst with a Si/Al (molar) ratio of 60 was synthesized hydrothermally and characterized by various analytical and spectroscopic techniques. Al-27 MAS-NNIR results indicate that the presence of aluminum in tetrahedral framework (Bronsted acid site) in both as-synthesized and calcined samples. However, in the case of the latter, a small amount of aluminum was found to be in octahedral coordination. This observation is well supported by NH3-TPD studies over protonated catalyst (H-AlMCM-48), where desorption profile at higher temperature shows features characteristic of Lewis acid sites. Further, these studies also indicate that the presence of high concentration of moderate-to-strong Bronsted acid sites at lower temperature, which are more suitable for the para-selective tertiary-butylation reaction of phenol. Hence, in the present investigation, the reaction was carried out H-AIMCM-48, which however showed much higher activity as compared to the hexagonal H-AlMCM-41. In addition, it was also found that the former does not get deactivated owing to three-dimensional pore system while the latter is susceptible to deactivation on account of one-dimensional pore system. (C) 2003</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T19:38:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T19:38:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED CATALYSIS A-GENERAL, 254(2), 239-249</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0926-860X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0926-860X(03)00486-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6765</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>