<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2624</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Active separation control in circular and transitioning S-Duct diffusers using vortex generator jets</dc:title><dc:creator>PRADEEP, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SULLEREY, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>turbulent-boundary-layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>fences</dc:subject><dc:subject>s-duct diffusers</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>active flow control</dc:subject><dc:subject>vortex generator jets</dc:subject><dc:description>Performance enhancement of three-dimensional S-duct diffusers by separation control using vortex generator jets is the objective of the current experimental investigation. Two different diffuser geometries namely, a circular diffuser and a rectangular - to - circular transitioning diffuser were studied in uniform inflow conditions at a Reynolds number of 7.8 x 105 and the performance evaluation of the diffusers was carried out in terms of static pressure improvement and quality (flow uniformity) of the exit flow. Detailed measurements that included total pressure, velocity distribution, surface static pressure, skin friction and boundary layer measurements were taken and these results are presented here in terms of static pressure rise, distortion coefficient and total pressure loss coefficient at the duct exit. The mass flow rate of the air injected through the VGJ was about 0.06 percent of the main flow for separation control. The distortion coefficient reduced by over 25 percent and the total pressure loss coefficient reduced by about 30 percent in both the diffusers. The physical mechanism of the flow control devices used has been explored using smoke visualization images.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T13:45:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T13:45:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE ASME FLUIDS ENGINEERING DIVISION SUMMER CONFERENCE, VOL 2,715-723</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7918-4751-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16027</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2624</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd US-European Fluids Engineering Division Summer Meeting/14th International Conference on Nuclear Engineering,Miami, FL,JUL 17-20, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>