<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6163</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling of microbial growth for sequential utilization in a multisubstrate environment</dc:title><dc:creator>DOSHI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RENGASWAMY, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>optimal strategists</dc:subject><dc:subject>yeast</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>cybernetic model</dc:subject><dc:subject>saccharomyces cerevisiae</dc:subject><dc:subject>klebsiella oxytoca</dc:subject><dc:subject>multisubstrate</dc:subject><dc:description>Microbial growth in multisubstrate environments is posed as a problem of multivariable constraint optimization. The optimization aims at maximizing the instantaneous growth rate of cells. The model developed for microbial growth using this hypothesis involves simple representation of complex cell structure as an optimization function which regulates the interplay of cellular machinery. The model parameters are estimated using single substrate growth data. Model simulation fits very well with earlier published experimental data of bacterial growth of Klensiella oxytoca on a variety of sugar mixtures involving glucose, fructose, lactose, and xylose. Moreover, the model is also able to predict the diauxic growth of Saccharomyces cerevisiae on glucose and galactose. One of the interesting outcomes of the above representation is the ability to prove analytically that the growth on the mixture of two sugars will be diauxic if one of the substrates has a very low K-s value and a high mu(m) value. (C) 1997 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T08:16:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T08:16:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCESS BIOCHEMISTRY, 32(8), 643-650</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-9592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0032-9592(97)00013-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6163</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6163</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>