<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17582</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:11:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Insight into the mechanical integrity of few-layers graphene upon lithiation/delithiation via in situ monitoring of stress development</dc:title><dc:creator>SONIA, FJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHOJU, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASLAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>LI-ION BATTERIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LITHIUM-ION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERCALATION COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE-ELECTRODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-LAYER</dc:subject><dc:subject>LITHIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:description>By monitoring the stress developments in situ during lithiation/delithiation of few layers graphene films, we report here for the first time an interesting observation of stress release/reversal just within the potential ranges corresponding to the co-existences of pristine graphene, dilute stage I and stage IV Li-graphite intercalation compounds (Li-GICs). This, along with supporting observations related to the presence of cracks in the graphene films upon electrochemical cycling and enhanced I-D/I-G ratio in Raman spectra recorded upon cycling primarily within the potential regimes corresponding to the stress release/reversal, indicate possible occurrences of mechanical/structural degradation mainly during the initial stages of lithiation and later stages of delithiation. This observation is being supported by a geometric model which estimates the strains induced in the individual graphene layers at the interfaces between the different Li-GICs at the various stages of lithia don; and as a function of distance from the current collector. On a slightly different note, the experimentally recorded magnitude of net lithiation induced reversible in-plane stress development was similar to 11 GPa. This is in fair agreement with that expected based on the theoretical dilation of similar to 1% along the graphene layers upon lithiation as per the classical Li-intercalation mechanism (i.e., up to formation of LiC6). (c) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CARBON, 88,206-214</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-6223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2015.02.078</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17582</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>