<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9570</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>A continuous process for the recovery of lactic acid by reactive distillation</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>NANAVATI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>NORONHA, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>electrodialysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>fermentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>lactic acid recovery</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactive distillation</dc:subject><dc:subject>esterification</dc:subject><dc:subject>ion-exchange resin</dc:subject><dc:description>Separation and purification of lactic acid from the fermentation broth are difficult because of its nonvolatile nature and the presence of other organic acids. Esterification of lactic acid with methanol followed by hydrolysis of the separated methyl lactate is an effective technique for this purpose. A continuous process for recovery is proposed and various aspects are evaluated through simulation and experiments. In the proposed route, a vapor stream containing methyl lactate is removed from a two-phase CSTR, used for esterification, operated under boiling conditions. The ester thus separated from the aqueous solution is further hydrolyzed in a reactive distillation column. Continuous removal of the volatile component (i.e. methanol) from the reaction zone increases conversion, thus pure lactic acid is obtained from the bottom of reactive distillation column. The results obtained in the experiments are compared with the simulation results. Further simulation studies were performed to obtain the suitable operating conditions for higher conversion and concentration of lactic acid. (c) 2006 Society of Chemical Industry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:25:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:25:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 81(11), 1767-1777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-2575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jctb.1603</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9570</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9570</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>