<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10495</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Aerosol size and chemical characteristics at Mumbai, India, during the INDOEX-IFP (1999)</dc:title><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, CK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSSON, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, MS</dc:creator><dc:subject>sea-salt sulfate</dc:subject><dc:subject>atmospheric aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>elemental carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>source identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>southern california</dc:subject><dc:subject>hong-kong</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrate</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle</dc:subject><dc:subject>air</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>pm-10</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerosol size distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>bc</dc:subject><dc:subject>oc</dc:subject><dc:subject>ions</dc:subject><dc:subject>trace elements</dc:subject><dc:description>Aerosol size and chemical characteristics govern their optical and radiative effects and their potential for cloud nucleation. This paper reports the size and chemical characteristics of surface aerosols measured at Mumbai during the Indian Ocean Experiment-Intensive Field Phase (INDOEX-IFP), January-March 1999. Carbonaceous (30%) and ionic (20%) constituents contributed significantly to aerosol mass. High black carbon concentrations and a low organic to black carbon ratio implied the predominance of primary carbonaceous aerosol, while a high nss-sulphate contribution in the fine mode, suggested a probable anthropogenic origin. Non-sea-salt potassium (nss-K(+)) and black carbon concentrations correlated during January and early February, with nss-K(+) in the fine mode contributing 86% of totalK(+), implying a common origin from a local biomass-burning source. Crustal sources were dominant during late-February and March, with 69% of the aerosol mass present in the coarse mode, and 60% of the variation in PM-10 measured during 12:00-16:00 h being explained by a crustal source factor. Chloride depletion was estimated throughout the study, more significantly during January and early February, from the higher RH and lower Ca(2+)/Na(2+) ratios. A negative correlation was obtained of chloride with nitrate, indicating probable nitrate substitution. During late-February and March, nitrate correlated with calcium suggesting an association with soil. Nss-sulphate correlated with calcium but not sodium, implying a probable association with crustal aerosols. (C) 2002 . .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T10:57:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T10:57:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT, 36(12), 1979-1991</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1352-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1352-2310(02)00167-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10495</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>