<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10094</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimisation of iodometric method of gold analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATGADDE, LG</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHENOY, UR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, S</dc:creator><dc:description>Gold can be estimated by potentiometry, polarography, spectrophotometry, atomic absorption spectroscopy, inductively coupled plasma emission spectroscopy (ICP) and X-ray fluorescence techniques. These techniques require sophisticated instruments necessitating a high capital investment. For a small industrial laboratory these techniques become uneconomical An iodometric technique is still the easiest ar-td cheapest technique. Although this technique wets discovered in 1898 and refined till 1966, it has certain limitations in that the pH of the gold solution and the quantity of potassium iodide to be added are not very well optimised. These are important parameters, which determine the accuracy and reproducibility of the method. In the present work. the effect of pH of chloroauric acid solution and amount of Kl added on the estimated value of gold have been investigated The gold values obtained were compared with the values obtained by the ICP technique. It was found that a pH range of 0-3 and a ratio of 1:6 for HAuCl4:Kl were the most optimum. These results have been explained on the basis of the reactions involved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>METAL FINISHERS ASSOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T18:03:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T18:03:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE METAL FINISHERS ASSOCIATION OF INDIA, 6(3), 217-221</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-5304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10094</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10094</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>