<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18348</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:29:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Defect-rich ZnO quantum dots as a potential multifunctional sunscreen and cosmetic active ingredient</dc:title><dc:creator>ASOK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, MN</dc:creator><dc:subject>HUMAN-SKIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUTOFLUORESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>atomic defects</dc:subject><dc:subject>camouflaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>colloids</dc:subject><dc:subject>cosmetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>inorganic chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>inorganic materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>luminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photobiology-16</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:subject>sunscreen</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZnO</dc:subject><dc:description>In sunscreens, ZnO nanoparticles (NPs) are used as inorganic UV filter which have a prominent band edge emission in the UVA region (similar to 385 nm). When applied to biological surface, this highly penetrating UVA emission from ZnO NPs would enhance the generation of reactive oxygen species resulting in oxidative stress. Therefore, the elimination of this harmful UVA emission from ZnO NPs are much sought after for the development of safer sunscreens. In this paper we introduce the use of defect-rich ZnO (D-ZnO) quantum dots (QDs) as a multifunctional active ingredient in sunscreen/cosmetic application. These D-ZnO QDs make use of their defect energy levels to emit in visible region by bypassing their harmful band edge emission at UVA region. The D-ZnO QDs also showed prominent visible luminescence which matches well with the autofluorescence of in vivo human skin. Hence, this visible luminescence could be useful for camouflaging, thereby enabling its potential as a biologically safe active ingredient for both cosmetic and UV screening applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WALTER DE GRUYTER GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:29:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:29:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PURE AND APPLIED CHEMISTRY, 87(42257)971-977</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0033-4545</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1365-3075</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1515/pac-2015-0307</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18348</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>