<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9614</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>EFFECT OF CROSS-SECTIONAL WARPING OF ANISOTROPIC SANDWICH LAMINATES DUE TO DYNAMIC LOADS USING A REFINED THEORY AND C(0) FINITE-ELEMENTS</dc:title><dc:creator>MALLIKARJUNA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>higher-order theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:description>An attempt has been made to study the effect of cross-sectional warping in the symmetrically laminated anisotropic composite sandwich plates for transient loads. A higher-order shear deformation theory (HOST) is used in conjunction with the simple displacement based C0 finite element method (FEM). As is well-known, the classical first-order theories hitherto considered were inadequate to describe the propagation of waves in the highly orthotropic sandwich laminates. The present theory, which is more accurate than the Reissner-Mindlin theory, is applied herein, for the evaluation of plate response to different types of dynamic loads. An explicit central difference scheme is employed for the integration of dynamic equations of equilibrium with a diagonalized mass matrix obtained by a special procedure applicable to quadrilateral isoparametric elements. The numerical results of the present investigation have been compared with the first-order shear deformation theory (FOST) and the differences between HOST and FOST are examined. The results presented here should be useful in obtaining better correlation between theory and experiment, and to numerical analysts in verifying their results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T20:23:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T20:23:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL FOR NUMERICAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING, 35(10), 2031-2047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5981</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9614</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9614</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>