<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9239</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-20T03:14:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hemorheological changes in blood transfusion-treated beta thalassemia major patients</dc:title><dc:creator>MANGALANI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LOKESHWAR, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGESWARI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:subject>mutations</dc:subject><dc:subject>thalassemia</dc:subject><dc:subject>blood viscosity</dc:subject><dc:subject>red cell rigidity</dc:subject><dc:description>Beta thalassemia major is an inherited impairment of haemoglobin structure, in which there is partial or complete failure to synthesize a specific type of globin chain. The study was undertaken to assess the hemorheological changes in beta thalassemic major patients. We studied hemorheological parameters in thalassemic patients (n = 37) immediately after blood transfusion. The parameters studied were whole blood viscosity (WBV), plasma viscosity (PV), red cell rigidity (RCR) and hematocrit (Hct). Blood samples from age- and sex-matched normal controls were also analysed for comparison. Statistical analysis was done using Student's t-test and p values were recorded. The results showed a significant decrease in level of WBV and Hct in patients when compared to normal controls. However, the red cell rigidity was higher when compared to normal controls. Increase in RCR should show an increase in WBV. But in our study cases there was a significant decrease in WBV which was probably due to the significant decrease in level of hematocrit.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOS PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:52:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:52:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CLINICAL HEMORHEOLOGY AND MICROCIRCULATION, 18(2-3), 99-102</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1386-0291</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9239</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9239</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>