<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11239</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Renewable energy in India: Status and potential</dc:title><dc:creator>PILLAI, IR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>program</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>renewable energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>diffusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:description>A majority of the Indian population does not have access to convenient energy services (LPG, electricity). Though India has made significant progress in renewable energy, the share of modern renewables in the energy mix is marginal. This paper reviews the status and potential of different renewables (except biomass) in India. This paper documents the trends in the growth of renewables in India and establishes diffusion model as a basis for setting targets. The diffusion model is fitted tot the past trends for wind, small hydro and solar water heating and is used to establish future targets. The economic viability and green house gas (GHG) saving potential is estimated for each option. Several renewables have high growth rates, for example wind, Photovoltaic (PV) module manufacture and solar water heaters. New technologies like Tidal, OTEC, Solar thermal power plants and geothermal power plants are at the demonstration stage and future dissemination will depend on the experience of these projects. (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T07:31:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T07:31:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY, 34(8), 970-980</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-5442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2008.10.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11239</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11239</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>