<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16733</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:18:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Transformer-Less Grid Feeding Current Source Inverter for Solar Photovoltaic System</dc:title><dc:creator>ANAND, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUNDLAPALLI, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Current source inverter (CSI)</dc:subject><dc:subject>grid feeding system</dc:subject><dc:subject>operation life</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar photovoltaic (PV)</dc:subject><dc:subject>CURRENT-SOURCE CONVERTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER POINT TRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONNECTED INVERTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOSSES</dc:subject><dc:description>High efficiency and operating life of grid feeding solar photovoltaic (PV) inverters are demanded. Due to reduced dc-link capacitor requirement, current source inverter (CSI) offers higher reliability than the voltage source based solar inverter. However, conventional three-phase pulse width modulated (PWM) current source based solar inverter injects high earth leakage current into the grid. In order to suppress this current, an isolation transformer can be used. Use of this transformer increases the cost and size, and decreases overall efficiency. In order to address the aforementioned limitations, a modified CSI is proposed in this paper. The proposed inverter suppresses the earth leakage current without using an isolation transformer, thereby increasing the efficiency and reducing cost as compared to conventional current source based solar inverters. A mathematical model of the system is derived based on which controller for the operation of the inverter is designed. The effectiveness of the scheme is verified through detailed simulation study. To confirm the viability of the scheme, experimental studies are carried out on a scaled-down laboratory prototype.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:18:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:18:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS, 61(10)5334-5344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0278-0046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIE.2014.2300038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16733</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>