<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18307</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:56:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Faster Algorithms for Algebraic Path Properties in Recursive State Machines with Constant Treewidth</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>IBSEN-JENSEN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAVLOGIANNIS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOYAL, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Interprocedural analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Constant treewidth graphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dataflow analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reachability and shortest path</dc:subject><dc:description>Interprocedural analysis is at the heart of numerous applications in programming languages, such as alias analysis, constant propagation, etc. Recursive state machines (RSMs) are standard models for interprocedural analysis. We consider a general framework with RSMs where the transitions are labeled from a semiring, and path properties are algebraic with semiring operations. RSMs with algebraic path properties can model interprocedural dataflow analysis problems, the shortest path problem, the most probable path problem, etc. The traditional algorithms for interprocedural analysis focus on path properties where the starting point is fixed as the entry point of a specific method. In this work, we consider possible multiple queries as required in many applications such as in alias analysis. The study of multiple queries allows us to bring in a very important algorithmic distinction between the resource usage of the one-time preprocessing vs for each individual query. The second aspect that we consider is that the control flow graphs for most programs have constant treewidth. Our main contributions are simple and implementable algorithms that support multiple queries for algebraic path properties for RSMs that have constant treewidth. Our theoretical results show that our algorithms have small additional one-time preprocessing, but can answer subsequent queries significantly faster as compared to the current best-known solutions for several important problems, such as interprocedural reachability and shortest path. We provide a prototype implementation for interprocedural reachability and intraprocedural shortest path that gives a significant speed-up on several benchmarks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACM SIGPLAN NOTICES, 50(1)97-109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0362-1340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-1160</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2676726.2676979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18307</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>