<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14087</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:04:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of natural circulation in cavities with uniform heat generation for different Prandtl number fluids</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAITONDE, UN</dc:creator><dc:subject>RECTANGULAR ENCLOSURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SQUARE CAVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONVECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Natural convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rayleigh number</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heat generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cavity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Correlations</dc:subject><dc:description>Natural convection in enclosures with uniform heat generation and isothermal side walls is studied here. For the rectangular enclosure, two-dimensional conservation equations are solved using SIMPLE algorithm. Parametric studies are conducted to examine the effects of orientation of the cavity, fluid properties (Pr number), and aspect ratio for Rayleigh numbers up to 10(6). For a horizontal square cavity, the flow becomes periodically oscillating at Ra = 5 x 10(4) and chaotic at Ra = 8 x 10(5). With a slight increase in the inclination angle, the oscillations die and for inclination angles greater than 15, the flow attain a steady state over a range of Ra. It is found that for tall cavities (aspect ratio &gt; 1), the steady-state solution is obtained for all values of Ra considered here. However, for wide cavities (aspect ratio &lt; 1), an oscillatory flow regime is observed. The maximum temperature within the cavity is calculated for the range of Ra, aspect ratio and Pr number. Correlations for the maximum cavity temperature is presented here. The values of critical Rayleigh number at which the convection sets in the rectangular cavity are also studied and two distinct criteria are determined to evaluate the critical Rayleigh number. Further, a three-dimensional simulation is performed for a cubic cavity. It is found that the steady state solutions are obtained for all Rayleigh number, except at Ra = 10(5). This is in contrast to the predictions for a two-dimensional square cavity, which has an oscillatory zone from Ra = 5x 10(4) onwards. 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:04:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:04:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER,54(7-8)1465-1474</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2010.11.046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14087</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>