<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14530</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:08:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of Microstructure on Uniaxial Strain Localization in AA5754 Aluminum Sheets Produced by Various Processing Routes</dc:title><dc:creator>TEWARI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYALAKSHMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIWARI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BISWAS, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUBIC, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SACHDEV, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>VOLUME FRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:description>The application of lightweight aluminum sheets to fabricate automotive components for vehicle weight reduction continues to be limited due to their low formability and high cost. This report summarizes a metallurgical investigation of the influence of various microstructural attributes on the forming and failure characteristics of aluminum sheets produced by lower cost continuous casting processes. The study has identified the combination of microstructural attributes, such as grain size, texture, and second phase particle distribution, in the sheets which make some sheets more formable than others and has traced the origin of these features to the processing history. The results show that the microstructural features present in the sheets have their origin in the casting, rolling, and recrystallization processes involved in their fabrication.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:08:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:08:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 44A(5)2382-2398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-012-1581-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14530</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>