<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15226</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:36:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of the Volume-to-Surface Ratio of Cultures on Escherichia coli Growth: An Experimental and Theoretical Analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>MARTINEZ, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUHSE, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RIVERA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>AYALA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARMANANDA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANCHEZ, J</dc:creator><dc:description>The growth dynamics of bacterial populations are usually represented by the classical S-shaped profiles composed of lag, exponential and stationary growth phases. Although exceptions to this classical behavior occur, they are normally produced under non-standard conditions such as supply of two carbohydrates as sole carbon source. However, we here report variations in the classic S-shaped growth profiles of Escherichia coli under standard culturing conditions; explicitly, we found growth during transition to the stationary phase wherein the bacterial growth rate inversely depended on the volume-to-surface ratio of cultures (V/S); the reasons for this behavior were experimentally explored. To complement our experimental analysis, a theoretical model that rationalizes the bacterial response was developed; simulations based on the developed model essentially reproduced experimental growth curves. We consequently conclude that the effect of V/S on E. coli growth reflects an interplay between auto-catalytic bacterial growth, bacterial growth auto-inhibition, and, the relief of that inhibition.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:36:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:36:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT MICROBIOLOGY, 65(1)60-65</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00284-012-0128-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15226</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>