<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4985</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Active flow control in circular and transitioning S-duct diffusers</dc:title><dc:creator>PRADEEP, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SULLEREY, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>vortex generator jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulent-boundary-layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>separation control</dc:subject><dc:subject>uncertainty analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>distortion</dc:subject><dc:subject>fences</dc:subject><dc:description>Performance enhancement of three-dimensional S-duct diffusers by secondary flow and separation control using vortex generator jets is the objective of the current experimental investigation. Two different diffuser geometries namely, a circular diffuser and a rectangular-to-circular transitioning diffuser were studied. The experiments were performed in uniform inflow conditions at a Reynolds number of 7.8 X 10(5) and the performance evaluation of the diffusers was carried out in terms of static pressure recovery and quality (flow uniformity) of the exit flow. Detailed measurements that included total pressure, velocity distribution, surface static pressure, skin friction, and boundary layer measurements were taken and these results are presented here in terms of static pressure rise, distortion coefficient, total pressure loss coefficient, and the transverse velocity vectors at the duct exit. The use of vortex generator jets resulted in around 26% in total pressure loss and about 22% decrease inflow distortion coefficients in the circular and transitioning diffusers. The mass flow rate of the air injected through the VGJ was about 0.1% of the mass flow rate of the main flow for secondary flow control and about 0.06% of the main flow for separation control. The physical mechanism of the flow control devices used has been explored. The structure of the vortices generated by the control methods are presented in the form of smoke visualization images. The method of flow control used here is perceived to have applications in turbomachinery like turbines and compressors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASME-AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T16:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T16:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF FLUIDS ENGINEERING-TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASME, 128(6), 1192-1203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-2202</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/1.2353263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4985</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4985</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>