<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11190</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>PREDICTION OF FORMING LIMITS USING HOSFORD MODIFIED YIELD CRITERION</dc:title><dc:creator>PADWAL, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATURVEDI, RC</dc:creator><dc:subject>sheet-metal</dc:subject><dc:description>A new generalized anisotropic yield criterion has been suggested by Hosford. This criterion has been used in prediction of forming limits by Graf and Hosford using M-K analysis for a material with normal anisotropy. In this paper the effect of planar anisotropy has been incorporated and the procedure for calculation of forming limits has been modified using the approach suggested by Parmar and Mellor. The results are compared with those of Graf and Hosford in the case of planar isotropy to validate the model and procedure. The results are also compared with the predictions of the M-K model using Hill's old and new (after Parmar and Mellor) yield criteria as well as experimental values obtained under conditions of both in-plane and punch stretching. It is observed that the effect of planar anisotropy is negligible while the predictions are strongly dependent on exponent "a" (exponent in yield criterion), Predictions with a = 5, 6 or 8 match the experimental results much better than predictions using the M-K model with Hill's old criterion, or even the new criterion used by Parmar and Mellor.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T04:22:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T04:22:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MECHANICAL SCIENCES, 34(7), 541-547</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7403</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0020-7403(92)90029-G</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11190</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>