<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18096</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:51:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Familial Parkinson Disease-associated Mutations Alter the Site-specific Microenvironment and Dynamics of alpha-Synuclein</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DWIVEDI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANOOP, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHITE, GM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOMBRABAIL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAMOORTHY, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>TIME-RESOLVED FLUORESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOINDUCED CROSS-LINKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMYLOID FIBRIL FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREE-ENERGY LANDSCAPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRYPTOPHAN FLUORESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>E46K MUTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEWY BODIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>WILD-TYPE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEURON DEATH</dc:subject><dc:subject>-Synuclein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amyloid</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluorescence Anisotropy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Parkinson Disease</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protein Aggregation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Protein Misfolding</dc:subject><dc:description>Background: Aggregation of -Syn is associated with PD pathogenesis. Results: Despite being natively unfolded, a site-specific structure exists in -Syn that is significantly altered by familial PD-associated E46K, A53T, and A30P mutations. Conclusion: Altered site-specific structure of the PD-associated mutants may attribute to their different aggregation propensity. Significance: This study contributes to understanding the relationship between structure and aggregation of -Syn. Human -synuclein (-Syn) is a natively unstructured protein whose aggregation into amyloid fibrils is associated with Parkinson disease (PD) pathogenesis. Mutations of -Syn, E46K, A53T, and A30P, have been linked to the familial form of PD. In vitro aggregation studies suggest that increased propensity to form non-fibrillar oligomers is the shared property of these familial PD-associated mutants. However, the structural basis of the altered aggregation propensities of these PD-associated mutants is not yet clear. To understand this, we studied the site-specific structural dynamics of wild type (WT) -Syn and its three PD mutants (A53T, E46K, and A30P). Tryptophan (Trp) was substituted at the N terminus, central hydrophobic region, and C terminus of all -Syns. Using various biophysical techniques including time-resolved fluorescence studies, we show that irrespective of similar secondary structure and early oligomerization propensities, familial PD-associated mutations alter the site-specific microenvironment, solvent exposure, and conformational flexibility of the protein. Our results further show that the common structural feature of the three PD-associated mutants is more compact and rigid sites at their N and C termini compared with WT -Syn that may facilitate the formation of a partially folded intermediate that eventually leads to their increased oligomerization propensities.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:51:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:51:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY, 290(12)7804-7822</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1083-351X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M114.598607</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18096</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>