<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17310</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:28:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pseudomonas putida CSV86: A Candidate Genome for Genetic Bioaugmentation</dc:title><dc:creator>PALIWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJU, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MODAK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUROHIT, HJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>AROMATIC-COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSCRIPTIONAL REGULATOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREFERENTIAL UTILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATHWAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NAHR</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSERTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEQUENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BACTERIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLUCOSE</dc:subject><dc:description>Pseudomonas putida CSV86, a plasmid-free strain possessing capability to transfer the naphthalene degradation property, has been explored for its metabolic diversity through genome sequencing. The analysis of draft genome sequence of CSV86 (6.4 Mb) revealed the presence of genes involved in the degradation of naphthalene, salicylate, benzoate, benzylalcohol, p-hydroxybenzoate, phenylacetate and p-hydroxyphenylacetate on the chromosome thus ensuring the stability of the catabolic potential. Moreover, genes involved in the metabolism of phenylpropanoid and homogentisate, as well as heavy metal resistance, were additionally identified. Ability to grow on vanillin, veratraldehyde and ferulic acid, detection of inducible homogentisate dioxygenase and growth on aromatic compounds in the presence of heavy metals like copper, cadmium, cobalt and arsenic confirm in silico observations reflecting the metabolic versatility. In silico analysis revealed the arrangement of genes in the order: tRNA(Gly), integrase followed by nah operon, supporting earlier hypothesis of existence of a genomic island (GI) for naphthalene degradation. Deciphering the genomic architecture of CSV86 for aromatic degradation pathways and identification of elements responsible for horizontal gene transfer (HGT) suggests that genetic bioaugmentation strategies could be planned using CSV86 for effective bioremediation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PUBLIC LIBRARY SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:28:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:28:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PLOS ONE, 9(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1932-6203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0084000</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17310</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>