<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17768</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:33:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis and characterization of bulk Cu2ZnSnX4 (X: S, Se) via thermodynamically supported mechano-chemical process</dc:title><dc:creator>PAREEK, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALASUBRAMANIAM, KR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>PULSED-LASER DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLAR-CELL</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>KESTERITE CU2ZNSNS4</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLVOTHERMAL METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>ABSORBER MATERIAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SULFURIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cu2ZnSnS4</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cu2ZnSnSe4</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kesterite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mechano-chemical synthesis</dc:subject><dc:description>Materials with the general formula, Cu2ZnSnX4 (CZTX: X: Group 16 elements), with X being S/Se, have been receiving considerable attention due to their utility as an absorber layer in solar photovoltaics (PV). This paper reports on the synthesis of CZTSe and CZTS nanocrystalline powders at low temperatures, starting from elemental metal and chalcogen powders, via the low cost, scalable technique of ball milling. The prepared samples were well characterized using the different characterization tools. XRD, Raman, SEM and TEM studies confirm the formation of single-phase, stoichiometric, nano-crystalline kesterite CZTS and CZTSe powders. The low temperature phase selection of the complex quaternary compound in this system is seen as a direct consequence of the thermodynamic facilitation, coupled with the capability of mechano-chemical synthesis to aid in overcoming kinetic constraints. The optical bandgap of the various samples of CZTS was observed in the range of 1.4-1.6 eV and corresponding values for CZTSe was observed to be in the range of 1.08-1.18 eV. Our work provides a pathway for developing cheap, scalable, and ink-based techniques for low cost solar PV. (C) 2015 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:33:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:33:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS CHARACTERIZATION, 103,42-49</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1044-5803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matchar.2015.03.014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17768</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>