<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14040</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:29:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of D-alpha-tocopheryl polyethylene glycol 1000 succinate (TPGS) on surfactant monolayers</dc:title><dc:creator>SHAH, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>RESPIRATORY-DISTRESS-SYNDROME</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACUTE LUNG INJURY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PULMONARY SURFACTANT</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLEIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>N-ACETYLCYSTEINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILM FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VITAMIN-E</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>D-alpha-Tocopheryl polyethylene glycol 1000 succinate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pulmonary surfactant</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface tension</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liposomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monolayer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Capillary surfactometer</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, the effects of an amphiphilic polymer, D-alpha-tocopheryl polyethylene glycol 1000 succinate (TPGS) on model surfactant monolayers dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC), a binary mixture of DPPC with palmitoyloleoyl phosphatidylglycerol (DPPC-POPG) 9:1 (w/w) and binary mixture of DPPC and oleic acid (DPPC-OA) were evaluated. The ability of TPGS to act as an antioxidant adjuvant for pulmonary surfactants was also evaluated. Compression isotherms of surfactant monolayers at 37 degrees C in a Langmuir-Blodgett trough showed that DPPC and DPPC:TPGS mixed monolayers (1:0.25-1:1, w/w) exhibited low minimum surface tensions (MST) of 1-2 mN/m. Similarly [DPPC:POPG (9:1, w/w)]:TPGS mixed films of 1:0.25-1:1 weight ratios reached 1-2 mN/m MST. DPPC:POPG:TPGS liposomes adsorbed to surface tensions of 29-31 mN/m within 1 s. While monolayers of DPPC:OA (1:1, w/w) reached high MST of similar to 11 mN/m, DPPC:OA:TPGS (1:1:0.25, w/w) film reached near zero MST suggesting that low concentrations of TPGS reverses the effect of OA on DPPC monolayer. Capillary surfactometer studies showed DPPC:TPGS and [DPPC:POPG (9:1, w/w)]:TPGS liposomes maintained 84-95% airway patency. Fluorescence spectroscopy of Laurdan loaded DPPC:TPGS and DPPC:POPG:TPGS liposomes revealed no segregation of lipid domains in the lipid bilayer. Addition of TPGS to soybean liposome significantly reduced thiobarbituric acid reactive substance (TBARS) by 29-39% confirming its antioxidant nature. The results suggest a potential use of TPGS as an adjuvant to improve the surfactant activity as well as act as an antioxidant by scavenging free radicals. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:29:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:29:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES,85(2)116-124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-7765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfb.2011.01.021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14040</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>