<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13948</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:17:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Closed-form empirical relations to predict the static pull-in parameters of electrostatically actuated microcantilevers having linear width variation</dc:title><dc:creator>JOGLEKAR, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWASKAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>MICROELECTROMECHANICAL SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOPOLOGY OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMS DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOLTAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROBEAM</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROACTUATORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFLECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:description>We develop novel closed-form empirical relations to estimate the static pull-in parameters of electrostatically actuated tapered width microcantilever beams. A computationally efficient single degree-of-freedom model is employed in the setting of Ritz energy technique to extract the static pull-in parameters of the distributed electromechanical model that takes into account the effects of fringing field capacitance. The accuracy of this single-dof model together with the variable-width equivalent of the Palmer's fringing model is established through a comparison with 3D finite element simulations. A unique surface fitting model is proposed to characterize the variations of both the pull-in displacement and pull-in voltage, over a realistically wide range of system parameters. Optimum coefficients of the proposed surface fitting model are obtained using nonlinear regression analysis. Empirical estimates of pull-in parameters are validated against finite element simulations, and available experimental and numerical data. An excellent agreement indicates that the proposed relationships are sufficiently accurate to be safely used for the electromechanical design of tapered microcantilever beams.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:17:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:17:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROSYSTEM TECHNOLOGIES-MICRO-AND NANOSYSTEMS-INFORMATION STORAGE AND PROCESSING SYSTEMS,17(1)35-45</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0946-7076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00542-010-1153-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13948</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>