<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1181</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:09:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Studies of defects and annealing behavior of silicon irradiated with 70 MeV Fe-56 ions</dc:title><dc:creator>DUBEY, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>YADAV, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAMALAPURKAR, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOKHALE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHANTY, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANJILAL, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>implantation</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>high energy irradiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron ions</dc:subject><dc:subject>hrxrd</dc:subject><dc:subject>esr</dc:subject><dc:subject>current-voltage</dc:subject><dc:subject>defects</dc:subject><dc:subject>annealing</dc:subject><dc:description>The effects of 70 MeV irradiation of iron ions in p-type silicon at fluences between 1 x 10(12) and 5 x 10(14) ions cm(-2) were investigated by high resolution X-ray diffraction (HRXRD), electron spin resonance (ESR) and current-voltage measurements. The irradiated samples were isochronally annealed in nitrogen ambient up to 973 K for 2 min using the rapid thermal annealing (RTA) system. The screw dislocation density of the annealed sample (5 x 101 4 ions cm(-2)) estimated at each stage of annealing from the broadening of the HRXRD peak was observed to change from 8.70 x 10(7) to 1.58 x 10(7) cm(-2) with increasing temperatures. The strain and stress parameters estimated at each stage of annealing using the FWHM of omega-scan clearly indicate relative trend towards the un-irradiated silicon sample. The electron spin resonance studies indicate the presence of the dangling bond state of silicon (Si equivalent to Si) and complex defects. The annealing at 873 K was found to be sufficient for complete removal of the defect centers induced due to irradiation. The I-V studies performed on the irradiated samples before and after annealing indicate that the defects created as a consequence of irradiation trap the charge carriers. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T08:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T08:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION B-BEAM INTERACTIONS WITH MATERIALS AND ATOMS,244(1)157-160</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-583X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nimb.2005.11.031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14376</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1181</dc:identifier><dc:source>Indo German Workshop on Synthesis and Modifications of Nano-Structured Materials by Energetic Ion Beams,New Delhi, INDIA,FEB 20-24, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>