<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14937</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:53:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural, magnetic, and textural properties of iron oxide-reduced graphene oxide hybrids and their use for the electrochemical detection of chromium</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAKASH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>LITHIUM-ION BATTERIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORE-SHELL NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANODE MATERIAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERAPEUTIC APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPARENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:description>Superparamagnetic Fe3O4 nanoparticles were anchored on reduced graphene oxide (RGO) nanosheets by co-precipitation of iron salts in the presence of different amounts of graphene oxide (GO). A pH dependent zeta potential and good aqueous dispersions were observed for the three hybrids of Fe3O4 and RGO. The structure, morphology and microstructure of the hybrids were examined by X-ray diffraction, transmission electron microscopy (TEM), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, Raman and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. TEM images reveal lattice fringes (d(311) = 0.26 nm) of Fe3O4 nanoparticles with clear stacked layers of RGO nanosheets. The textural properties including the pore size distribution and loading of Fe3O4 nanoparticles to form Fe3O4-RGO hybrids have been controlled by changing the concentration of GO. An observed maximum (similar to 10 nm) in pore size distribution for the sample with 0.25 mg ml(-1) of GO is different from that prepared using 1.0 mg ml(-1) GO. The superparamagnetic behavior is also lost in the latter and it exhibits a ferrimagnetic nature. The electrochemical behavior of the hybrids towards chromium ion was assessed and a novel electrode system using cyclic voltammetry for the preparation of an electrochemical sensor platform is proposed. The textural properties seem to influence the electrochemical and magnetic behavior of the hybrids. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:53:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:53:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CARBON, 50(11)4209-4219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2012.05.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14937</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>