<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8950</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Multistability of signal transduction motifs</dc:title><dc:creator>SAEZ-RODRIGUEZ, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAMMERLE-FICKINGER, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DALAL, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>KLAMT, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GILLES, ED</dc:creator><dc:creator>CONRADI, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>complex isothermal reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-reaction networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple steady-states</dc:subject><dc:subject>gene-expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>deficiency-one</dc:subject><dc:subject>combinatorial complexity</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems biology</dc:subject><dc:subject>single-cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>models</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphorylation</dc:subject><dc:description>Protein domains are the basic units of signalling processes. The mechanisms they are involved in usually follow recurring patterns, such as phosphorylation/dephosphorylation cycles. A set of common motifs was defined and their dynamic models were analysed with respect to number and stability of steady states. In a first step, Feinberg's chemical reaction network theory was used to determine whether a motif can show multistationarity or not. The analysis revealed that, apart from double-step activation motifs including a distributive mechanism, only those motifs involving an autocatalytic reaction can show multistationarity. To further characterise these motifs, a large number of randomly chosen parameter sets leading to bistability was generated, followed by a bifurcation analysis of each parameter set and a statistical evaluation of the results. The statistical results can be used to explore robustness against noise, pointing to the observation that multistationarity at the single-motif level may not be a robust property; the range of protein concentrations compatible with multistationarity is fairly narrow. Furthermore, experimental evidence suggests that protein concentrations vary substantially between cells. Considering a motif designed to be a bistable switch, this implies that fluctuation of protein concentrations between cells would prevent a significant proportion of motifs from acting as a switch. The authors consider this to be a first step towards a catalogue of fully characterised signalling modules.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T07:48:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T07:48:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IET SYSTEMS BIOLOGY, 2(2), 80-93</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1751-8849</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/iet-syb:20070012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8950</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8950</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>