<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9544</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis and characterization of N-substituted hyperbranched polyureas</dc:title><dc:creator>AMBADE, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>building-blocks</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic polyamides</dc:subject><dc:subject>urea linkages</dc:subject><dc:subject>dendrimers</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyurethanes</dc:subject><dc:subject>architecture</dc:subject><dc:subject>derivatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>micelles</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrene</dc:subject><dc:subject>hyperbranched polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>internal functionalization</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-substitution, polyurea</dc:subject><dc:description>N,N'-disubstituted hyperbranched polyureas with methyl, benzyl, and allyl substitutents were synthesized starting from AB(2) monomers based on 3,5-diamino benzoic acid. Carbonyl azide approach, which generates isocyanate group in situ on thermal decomposition, was used for the protection of isocyanate functional groups. The N-substituted hyperbranched polymers can be considered as the new class of internally functionalized hyperbranched polyureas wherein the substituent can function either as receptor or as a chemical entity for selective transformations as a tool to tailor the properties. The chain-ends were also modified by attaching long chain aliphatic groups to fully realize the interior functionalization. This approach opens up a possible synthetic route wherein different functional substituents can be used to generate a library of internally functionalized. hyperbranched polymers. All the hyperbranched polyureas were characterized by FTIR, H-1-NMR, DSC, TGA, and size exclusion chromatography. Degree of branching in these N,N'-disubstituted hyperbranched polyureas, as calculated by H-1-NMR spectroscopy using model compounds, was found to be lower than the unsubstituted hyperbranched polyurea and is attributed to the lower reactivity of N-substituted amines compared to that of unsubstituted amines. (C) 2004 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T15:46:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T15:46:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF POLYMER SCIENCE PART A-POLYMER CHEMISTRY, 42(20), 5134-5145</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0887-624X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pola.20295</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9544</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9544</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>