<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17057</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T18:02:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cost-benefit analysis of different hydrogen production technologies using AHP and Fuzzy AHP</dc:title><dc:creator>THENGANE, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOADLEY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Hydrogen</dc:subject><dc:subject>Analytic hierarchy process</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cost-benefit analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fuzzy analytic hierarchy process</dc:subject><dc:subject>Renewable</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANALYTIC HIERARCHY PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIFE-CYCLE ASSESSMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DECISION-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY-SOURCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER-PLANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUEL-CELL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EIGENVECTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SELECTION</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, cost-benefit analysis is performed to compare eight different hydrogen production technologies using the classical analytic hierarchy process (AHP) and the Fuzzy AHP. The technologies considered are steam methane reforming, coal gasification, partial oxidation of hydrocarbons, biomass gasification, photovoltaic-based electrolysis, wind-based electrolysis, hydro-based electrolysis, and water splitting by chemical looping. For each of the hydrogen production technologies, five criteria are used for evaluation: greenhouse gas emissions, raw material and utilities consumption, energy efficiency, scalability, as well as waste disposal and atmospheric emissions. The results obtained for benefits category using AHP and Fuzzy AHP are plotted against the normalized equivalent annual costs of each technology. It is concluded that the fossil fuel based processes appear to have less beneficial qualities including greater environmental impacts, but are more cost-effective. On the other hand, the renewable based processes appear to have more benefits as well as being more expensive for hydrogen production. However, the cost-benefit analysis results imply that the process of water splitting by chemical looping among the renewable approaches is the most promising new technology. Copyright (C) 2014, Hydrogen Energy Publications, LLC. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:02:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:02:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYDROGEN ENERGY, 39(28)15293-15306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-3199</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-3487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2014.07.107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17057</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>