<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9521</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulated folding in polypeptides of diversified molecular tacticity: Implications for protein folding and de novo design</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RANBHOR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DURANI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>gramicidin</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulated annealing</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular tacticity</dc:subject><dc:subject>de novo protein design</dc:subject><dc:subject>heterochiral peptides</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein folding</dc:subject><dc:description>Stereochemistry could be a powerful variable for conformational tune up of polypeptides for de novo design. It may be also useful probe of possible role of interamide energetics in selection and stabilization of conformation. The homopolypeptides Ac-Xxx(30)-NHMe, with Xxx = Ala, Val, and Leu, of diversified stereochemical structure are generated by simulated racemization with a modified GROMOS-96 force field The polypeptides, and other systematic stereochemical variants, are folded by simulated annealing with another modified GROMOS-96 force field under the dielectric constant values 1, 4, and 10. The resultant 15,000 molecular folds of isotactic (poly-L-chiral), syndiotactic (alternating L,D-chiral), and heterotactic (random-L,D-chiral) stereochemical structure, belonging to three polypeptide series, achieved under three different folding conditions, are assessed statistically for structure-to-energy-to-conformation relationship. The results suggest that interamide electrostatics could be a major factor in secondgry-structure selection in polypeptides while main-chain stereochemistry could dictate molecular packing and therefore the relative magnitude of hydrogen-bond and Lennard-Jones (LJ) contributions in conformational energy. A method for computational design of heterotactic molecular folds in polypeptide structure has been developed, and the first road map for a chiral tune up of polypeptide structure based on stereochemical engineering has been laid down. Broad implications for protein structure, folding, and de novo design are briefly discussed &amp;COPY; 2005 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T14:07:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T14:07:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOPOLYMERS, 78(2), 96-105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-3525</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/bip.20241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9521</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9521</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>