<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10389</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>A CAD-compatible closed form approximation for the inversion charge areal density in double-gate MOSFETs</dc:title><dc:creator>HARIHARAN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>current model</dc:subject><dc:subject>dg mosfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>approximation</dc:subject><dc:subject>charge</dc:subject><dc:subject>compact model</dc:subject><dc:subject>dgfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>lambert</dc:subject><dc:subject>mosfet</dc:subject><dc:description>In developing the drain current model of a symmetrically driven, undoped (or lightly doped) symmetric double-gate MOSFET (SDGFEr), one encounters a transcendental equation relating the value of an intermediate variable beta (which is related to the inversion charge areal density and also surface-potential) to the gate and drain voltages; as a result, it doesn't have a closed form solution. From a compact modeling perspective, it is desirable to have closed form expressions in order to implement them in a circuit simulator. In this paper, we present an accurate closed form approximation for the inversion charge areal density, based on the Lambert-W function. We benchmark our approximation against other existing approximations and show that our approximation is computationally the most efficient and numerically the most robust, at a reduced but acceptable accuracy. Hence, it is suitable for use in implementing inversion charge based compact models. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T04:30:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T04:30:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLID-STATE ELECTRONICS, 53(2), 218-224</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0038-1101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sse.2008.11.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10389</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10389</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>