<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3153</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intramolecular interactions between chalcogen atoms: organoseleniums derived from 1-bromo-4-tert-butyl-2,6-di(formyl)benzene</dc:title><dc:creator>ZADE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTCHER, RJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>und ihrer derivate</dc:subject><dc:subject>glutathione-peroxidase activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>chiral selenium electrophiles</dc:subject><dc:subject>se-77 nmr-spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray crystallography</dc:subject><dc:subject>stable selenenic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>se-c atoms</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>asymmetric methoxyselenenylation</dc:subject><dc:description>The synthesis and characterization of a series of low-valent organoselenium compounds derived from 1-bromo-4-tert-butyl-2,6-di(formyl)benzene (22) is described. The synthesis of diselenide 25 was achieved by the lithiation route whereas bis(4-tert-butyl-2,6-di(formyl)phenyl) diselenide (26) was synthesized by treating 22 with disodium diselenide. A series of monoselenides (27, 28, and 29) was obtained by facile nucleophilic substitution of bromine in 22, using the corresponding selenolates as nucleophiles. The halogenation reactions of bis(4-tert-butyl-2,6-di(formyl)phenyl) diselenide (26) did not afford the corresponding selenenyl halides but resulted in the isolation of an unexpected cyclic selenenate ester 34 as a product. The selenide 32 was synthesized by the treatment of dimethoxymethyl diselenide with trilithiated 2-bromo-5-tert-butyl-NM-di(phenyl)isophthalamide. The existence of potential (SeO)-O-... intramolecular nonbonding interactions was examined by IR, H-1, and Se-77 NMR spectroscopy, X-ray crystallography, and computational studies. The X-ray crystal structures of 26 and 27, having two ortho formyl groups, reveal the absence of any (SeO)-O-... interactions. However, the (SeO)-O-... interactions were observed in the selenenate ester 34 where one of the formyl groups has been utilized for the selenenate ring formation. The crystal structures of 26 and 27 exhibited intermolecular short-range C-H... Se interactions (hydrogen bonding). Although there are four heteroatoms in carbamoyl moieties ortho to selenium capable of forming a five-membered ring on intramolecular coordination, no such intramolecular (SeX)-X-... (X = N, O) interaction was observed in the crystal structure of 32. The density functional theory calculations at the B3LYP/6-31G* level predicted that for all the diformyl systems (47a-c, 48a-c), the anti,anti conformer (when both formyl oxygen atoms point away from the selenium) is more stable. This preference was found to be reversed in the monoformyl-substituted systems (50a,b, 51a,b), where the syn conformer (when formyl oxygen is near the selenium) is energetically more favorable than the anti conformer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-15T08:48:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-15T08:48:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY,70(9)3693-3704</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo0478656</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13961</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3153</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>