<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14038</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:28:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Formation of zinc oxide nanoparticles of different shapes in water-in-oil microemulsion</dc:title><dc:creator>SARKAR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIKKU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAPAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHILAR, KC</dc:creator><dc:subject>SOL-GEL PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNO PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERMICELLAR EXCHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>W/O MICROEMULSIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>REVERSED MICELLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water-in-oil microemulsion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zinc oxide nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Triton X-100</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water pools</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper we report the direct synthesis of pure monodispersed zinc oxide nanoparticles of different shapes by basic hydrolysis of zinc nitrate with suitable control of the reactant concentrations in the water in oil microemulsion of Triton X-100/hexanol/cyclohexane. Pure hexagonal wurtzite zinc oxide nanoparticles were obtained in each case. Reaction with a weak base ammonium hydroxide yields highly monodispersed nearly spherical nanoparticles in the range 2.1-7.7 nm whereas reaction with strong base sodium hydroxide forms nanorods at lower reactant concentration and larger rectangular nanoparticles at higher reactant concentration. Optical properties of these zinc oxide nanoparticles were studied at room temperature by taking the optical absorption and luminescence spectra. All samples show strong absorption in the UV range and are nearly transparent in the visible range. The band gap luminescence is predominant in the zinc oxide nanoparticles prepared by this technique, along with two smaller defect induced peaks at 426-488 nm,while the green defect induced luminescence (between 500 and 550 nm) typical of zinc oxide is strongly quenched. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:28:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:28:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COLLOIDS AND SURFACES A-PHYSICOCHEMICAL AND ENGINEERING ASPECTS,381(1-3)123-129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-7757</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2011.03.041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14038</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>