<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14771</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:41:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Functional Genetic Variants of the Catecholamine-Release-Inhibitory Peptide Catestatin in an Indian Population ALLELE-SPECIFIC EFFECTS ON METABOLIC TRAITS</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, BS</dc:creator><dc:creator>OBBINENI, JM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHU, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALLU, PKR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAMANIAN, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>SONAWANE, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SASI, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SENAPATI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOMATHI, BS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MULLASARI, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAPATRA, NR</dc:creator><dc:subject>NICOTINIC ACETYLCHOLINE-RECEPTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHROMOGRANIN-A FRAGMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENDOGENOUS PEPTIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRANULE BIOGENESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLOOD-PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYPERTENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PANCREASTATIN</dc:subject><dc:description>Catestatin (CST), a chromogranin A (CHGA)-derived peptide, is a potent inhibitor of catecholamine release from adrenal chromaffin cells and postganglionic sympathetic axons. We re-sequenced the CST region of CHGA in an Indian population (n = 1010) and detected two amino acid substitution variants: G364S and G367V. Synthesized CST variant peptides (viz. CST-Ser-364 and CST-Val-367) were significantly less potent than the wild type peptide (CST-WT) to inhibit nicotine-stimulated catecholamine secretion from PC12 cells. Consistently, the rank-order of blockade of nicotinic acetylcholine receptor (nAChR)-stimulated inward current and intracellular Ca2+ rise by these peptides in PC12 cells was: CST-WT &gt; CST-Ser-364 &gt; CST-Val-367. Structural analysis by CD spectroscopy coupled with molecular dynamics simulations revealed the following order of alpha-helical content: CST-WT &gt; CST-Ser-364 &gt; CST-Val-367; docking of CST peptides onto a major human nAChR subtype and molecular dynamics simulations also predicted the above rank order for their binding affinity with nAChR and the extent of occlusion of the receptor pore, providing a mechanistic basis for differential potencies. The G364S polymorphism was in strong linkage disequilibrium with several common CHGA genetic variations. Interestingly, the Ser-364 allele (detected in similar to 15% subjects) was strongly associated with profound reduction (up to similar to 2.1-fold) in plasma norepinephrine/epinephrine levels consistent with the diminished nAChR desensitization-blocking effect of CST-Ser-364 as compared with CST-WT. Additionally, the Ser-364 allele showed strong associations with elevated levels of plasma triglyceride and glucose levels. In conclusion, a common CHGA variant in an Indian population influences several biochemical parameters relevant to cardiovascular/metabolic disorders.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:41:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:41:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY, 287(52)43840-43852</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M112.407916</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14771</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>