<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1171</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>A generalized procedure for determining thermal resistivity of soils</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIDU, ARNEPALLI DALI</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>fabrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>compaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle size analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>project management</dc:subject><dc:subject>sand</dc:subject><dc:description>Estimation of thermal resistivity of soils is very important for various engineering projects. Many researchers have demonstrated that, soil thermal resistivity is a property of the soil that depends on various parameters such as type of soil, particle size distribution, and compaction characteristics and hence its estimation based on existing empirical and mathematical models is difficult. This calls for fabrication of a device that can be used for determining soil thermal resistivity directly. Usually, small size, laboratory thermal resistivity probes have been used for this purpose and their efficiency in measuring soil thermal resistivity has already been established. However, as natural soils consist of various size fractions, ranging from clay to gravel, the laboratory thermal probes cannot be used very efficiently. This necessitates fabrication of a field thermal probe that can be used to measure thermal resistivity of a soil either in its remolded state or under in situ conditions. With this in view, efforts were made to develop a field thermal probe, which works on the principle of transient method and is a magnified version of the laboratory thermal probe developed by the authors. Based on the results obtained efforts have been made to develop generalized relationships for estimating the soil thermal resistivity by knowing the dry density, moisture content and percent size fraction of the various particle sizes, and validation of the proposed generalized equations have been done with the results available in the literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-21T07:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:58:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-21T07:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:58:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>International Journal of Thermal Sciences 43(1), 43-51</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1290-0729</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1290-0729(03)00103-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1171</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1171</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>