<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3608</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Washing of marine coastal sand in a batch reactor: Sorption and desorption of BTEX</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, BH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SWAMINATHAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASOLEKAR, SR</dc:creator><dc:subject>activated carbon adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic pollutant sorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>contaminated soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>natural sediments</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrophobic pollutants</dc:subject><dc:subject>heavy-metals</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>remediation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sites</dc:subject><dc:subject>prediction</dc:subject><dc:description>This study addresses the issues related to decontamination of marine beach sand accidentally contaminated by petroleum products. Sorption and desorption of BTEX (i.e., benzene, toluene, ethylbenzene, and xylene) onto the sand from Uran Beach, located near the city of Mumbai, India, were studied, and isotherms were determined using the bottle point method to estimate sorption coefficients. Alternatively, QSARs (i.e., quantitative structure activity relationships) were developed and used to estimate the sorption coefficients. Experiments for kinetics of volatilization as well as for kinetics of sorption and desorption in the presence of volatilization were conducted in a fabricated laboratory batch reactor. A mathematical model describing the fate of volatile hydrophobic organic pollutants like BTEX (via sorption and desorption in presence of volatilization) in a batch sediment-washing reactor was proposed. The experimental kinetic data were compared with the values predicted using the proposed models for sorption and desorption, and the optimum values of overall mass transfer coefficients for sorption (K(S)a(S)) and desorption (K(d)a(d)) were estimated. This was achieved by minimization of errors while using the sorption coefficients (K-p) Obtained from either laboratory isotherm studies or the QSARs developed in the present study. Independent experimental data were also collected and used for calibration of the model for volatilization, and the values of the overall mass transfer coefficient for volatilization (K(g)a(g)) were estimated for BTEX. In these exercises of minimization of errors, comparable cumulative errors were obtained from the use of K-p values derived from experimental isotherms and QSARs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AIR &amp; WASTE MANAGEMENT ASSOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE AIR &amp; WASTE MANAGEMENT ASSOCIATION, 51(7), 1043-1059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1047-3289</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3608</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3608</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>