<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1290</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of glass resistive plate chambers for INO experiment</dc:title><dc:creator>DATAR, VM</dc:creator><dc:creator>JENA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALMANI, SD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MONDAL, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGARAJ, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, LV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAF, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATYANARAYANA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHINDE, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>ino ical detector</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistive plate chambers</dc:subject><dc:subject>long-term stability</dc:subject><dc:description>The India-based Neutrino Observatory (INO) collaboration is planning to build a massive 50 kton magnetised Iron Calorimeter (ICAL) detector, to study atmospheric neutrinos and to make precision measurements of the parameters related to neutrino oscillations. Glass Resistive Plate Chambers (RPCs) of about 2 m x 2 m in size are going to be used as active elements for the ICAL detector. We have fabricated a large number of glass RPC prototypes of I m x 1 m in size and have studied their performance and long term stability. In the process, we have developed and produced a number of materials and components required for fabrication of RPCs. We have also designed and optimised a number of fabrication and quality control procedures for assembling the gas gaps. In this paper we will review our various activities towards development of glass RPCs for the INO ICAL detector. We will present results of the characterisation studies of the RPCs and discuss our plans to prototype 2 m x 2 m sized RPCs. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T18:07:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T18:07:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION A-ACCELERATORS SPECTROMETERS DETECTORS AND ASSOCIATED EQUIPMENT,602(3)744-748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-9002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nima.2008.12.129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14476</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1290</dc:identifier><dc:source>9th International Workshop on Resistive Plate Chambers and Related Detectors,Bombay, INDIA,FEB 13-16, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>