<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9032</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>A first-principles comparison of the electronic properties of MgCyNi3 and ZnCyNi3 alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSEPH, PJT</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>nonoxide perovskite mgcni3</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-metals</dc:subject><dc:subject>superconductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel</dc:subject><dc:subject>metamagnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>mgcxni3</dc:subject><dc:subject>kobalt</dc:subject><dc:subject>mangan</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:description>First-principles, density-functional-based electronic structure calculations are employed to study the changes in the electronic properties of ZnCyNi3 and MgCyNi3 using the Korringa-Kohn-Rostoker coherent-potential approximation method in the atomic sphere approximation (KKR-ASA CPA). As a function of decreasing C atomic percentage, we find a steady decrease in the lattice constant and bulk modulus in both alloys. However, the pressure derivative of the bulk modulus displays an opposite trend. Following the Debye model, which relates the pressure derivative of the bulk modulus to the average phonon frequency of the crystal, it can thus be argued that ZnCNi3 and its disordered alloys possess a different phonon spectrum in comparison to its MgCNi3 counterparts. This is further justified by the marked similarity we find in the electronic structure properties such as the variation in the density of states and the Hopfield parameters calculated for these alloys. The effects on the equation of state parameters and the density of states at the Fermi energy, for partial replacement of Mg by Zn, are also discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T12:50:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T12:50:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 18(23), 5333-5347</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/18/23/007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9032</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9032</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>