<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16122</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:56:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Immobilized silver nanoparticles enhance contact killing and show highest efficacy: elucidation of the mechanism of bactericidal action of silver</dc:title><dc:creator>AGNIHOTRI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>HOLLOW-FIBER MEMBRANE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZEBRAFISH EMBRYOS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MULTILAYER FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL-IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOXICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSILVER</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISSOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Antimicrobial materials with immobilized/entrapped silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) are of considerable interest. There is significant debate on the mode of bactericidal action of AgNPs, and both contact killing and/or ion mediated killing have been proposed. In this study, AgNPs were immobilized on an amine-functionalized silica surface and their bactericidal activity was studied concurrently with the silver release profile over time. This was compared with similar studies performed using colloidal AgNPs and AgCl surfaces that released Ag ions. We conclude that contact killing is the predominant bactericidal mechanism and surface immobilized nanoparticles show greater efficacy than colloidal AgNPs, as well as a higher concentration of silver ions in solution. In addition, the AgNP immobilized substrate was used multiple times with good efficacy, indicating this immobilization protocol is effective for retaining AgNPs while maintaining their disinfection potential. The antibacterial surface was found to be extremely stable in aqueous medium and no significant leaching (similar to 1.15% of total silver deposited) of the AgNPs was observed. Thus, immobilization of AgNPs on a surface may promote reuse, reduce environmental risks associated with leaching of AgNPs and enhance cost effectiveness.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:56:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:56:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOSCALE, 5(16)7328-7340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c3nr00024a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16122</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>