<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16649</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T13:02:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural, Petrological, and Chronological Constraints from Eastern India and Implications for the similar to 1.0 Ga Assembly of Greater India</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHAKAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHYANARAYANAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>SHRIMP ZIRCON AGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>U-PB</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON-MICROPROBE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TECTONIC ZONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGHBHUM CRATON</dc:subject><dc:subject>GNEISSIC COMPLEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>GHATS BELT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MESOPROTEROZOIC GRANULITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PSEUDOSECTION ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE METAMORPHISM</dc:subject><dc:description>The Great Proterozoic Fold Belt of India (GIPFOB) is the inferred accretion zone between the North India Block (NIB) and the South India Block (SIB). Mesoscopic structures, phase petrology, and U-Th-Pb (total) monazite ages in the Bangriposi Shear Zone (BSZ) located in the eastern syntaxis of the GIPFOB along the fringe of the Paleo/Mesoarchean Singhbhum Craton (SC) are examined to constrain the time of NIB-SIB assembly. The BSZ at the eastern fringe of the Archean Singhbhum Craton is a NNE-trending west-vergent 0.95-1.0 Ga greenschist-facies (&lt;0.6 GPa at 500-30 degrees C) sinistral-reverse shear zone. The BSZ is dominated by Meso/Neoarchean (2.6-3.1 Ga) cratonic lithologies and an overlying suite of intensely to weakly deformed cobble/granule quartz conglomerates interbanded with quartzite, low-grade phyllites and mafic schist, and gabbro-wehrlite complexes. The precursors to the low-grade conglomeratephyllite-quartzite sequence and the obducted ultrahigh-pressure (5.3-5.9 GPa at 1200-1230 degrees C) wehrlite body constitute a 0.95-1.0 Ga tectonic m lange interleaved with cratonic (Archean) lithologies of higher metamorphic grade. The lack of Mesoproterozoic (1.5-1.7 Ga) metamorphism in the BSZ and neighboring areas, which are common along the NW/N margin of the Singhbhum Craton and the accreted southern meta-flysch belt of the North Singhbhum Mobile Belt (NSMB) is significant. It is suggested that the northern meta-flysch belt of the NSMB and the Singhbhum Craton were not juxtaposed until similar to 1.0 Ga. These crustal domains were finally accreted during the final stages (0.95-1.0 Ga) of Rodinia supercontinent assembly forming a +shaped similar to 1.0 Ga tectonic zone in eastern India. The "Greater</dc:description><dc:publisher>UNIV CHICAGO PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:02:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:02:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEOLOGY, 122(4)411-432</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-1376</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1537-5269</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1086/676459</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16649</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>