<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1995</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>A numerical abstract domain based on expression abstraction and max operator with application in timing analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>GULAVANI, LS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GULWANI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>predicate abstraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>linear ranking</dc:subject><dc:subject>programs</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes a precise numerical abstract domain for use in timing analysis. The numerical abstract domain is parameterized by a linear abstract domain and is constructed by means of two domain lifting operations. One domain lifting operation is based on the principle of expression abstraction (which involves defining a set of expressions and specifying their semantics using a collection of directed inference rules) and has a more general applicability. It lifts any given abstract domain to include reasoning about a given set of expressions whose semantics is abstracted using a set of axioms. The other domain lifting operation incorporates disjunctive reasoning into a given linear relational abstract domain via introduction of max expressions. We present experimental results demonstrating the potential of the new numerical abstract domain to discover a wide variety of timing bounds (including polynomial, disjunctive, logarithmic, exponential, etc.) for small C programs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T00:05:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T00:05:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTER AIDED VERIFICATION,5123,370-384</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-540-70543-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15275</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1995</dc:identifier><dc:source>20th International Conference on Computer Aided Verification,Princeton, NJ,JUL 07, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>