<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18403</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:56:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>A PRIORI ERROR ESTIMATES FOR FINITE VOLUME ELEMENT APPROXIMATIONS TO SECOND ORDER LINEAR HYPERBOLIC INTEGRO-DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS</dc:title><dc:creator>KARAA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANI, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>QUADRATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Finite volume element</dc:subject><dc:subject>hyperbolic integro-differential equation</dc:subject><dc:subject>semidiscrete method</dc:subject><dc:subject>numerical quadrature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ritz-Volterra projection</dc:subject><dc:subject>completely discrete scheme</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal error estimates</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, both semidiscrete and completely discrete finite volume element methods (FVEMs) are analyzed for approximating solutions of a class of linear hyperbolic integro-differential equations in a two-dimensional convex polygonal domain. The effect of numerical quadrature is also examined. In the semidiscrete case, optimal error estimates in L-infinity (L-2) and L-infinity(H-1) norms are shown to hold with minimal regularity assumptions on the initial data, whereas quasi-optimal estimate is derived in L-infinity(L-infinity) norm under higher regularity on the data. Based on a second order explicit method in time, a completely discrete scheme is examined and optimal error estimates are established with a mild condition on the space and time discretizing parameters. Finally, some numerical experiments are conducted which confirm the theoretical order of convergence.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ISCI-INST SCIENTIFIC COMPUTING &amp; INFORMATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:56:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:56:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF NUMERICAL ANALYSIS AND MODELING, 12(3)401-429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1705-5105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18403</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>