<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9968</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flow of a Robertson-Stiff fluid between two approaching disks</dc:title><dc:creator>BATRA, RL</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARTHASARATHY, H</dc:creator><dc:description>The rheological behavior of drilling fluids, bentonite suspensions, cement slurries, and polymer gels has been found to be best described by the Robertson-Stiff model. Such fluids are pseudoplastic and are characterized by a yield value. The steady, isothermal, incompressible flow of these fluids between two disks approaching each other with constant relative velocity under the action of a normal load has been analyzed. A basic characteristic of such fluids is the presence of a plug core of zero velocity gradient in the region under consideration. The nature, extent, and shape of the core have been determined for various values of the model parameters. The plug core occurs symmetrically in the middle of the region between the disks. The thickness of the core increases from the periphery to the center of the disks. The pressure drop and the maximum value of the applied load have been calculated for various values of yield number and flow behavior index.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MARCEL DEKKER INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T09:51:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T09:51:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER-PLASTICS TECHNOLOGY AND ENGINEERING, 35(3), 497-516</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-2559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03602559608000934</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9968</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9968</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>