<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4905</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of pier and deck flexibility on the seismic response of isolated bridges</dc:title><dc:creator>KUNDE, MC</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>rubber bearings</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>isolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>bridge decks</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquakes</dc:subject><dc:description>The seismic response of bridges isolated by elastomeric bearings and the sliding system is investigated under two horizontal components of real earthquake ground motions. The selected bridges consist of multispan continuous deck supported on the piers and abutments. Three different mathematical models of the isolated bridge are considered for the analytical seismic response by considering and ignoring the flexibility of the deck and piers. The mathematical formulation for seismic response analysis of various mathematical models of the bridges isolated by different isolation systems is presented. The accuracy and computational efficiency of various mathematical models of isolated bridges is investigated by comparing their responses under different system parameters and earthquake ground motions. The important parameters selected are the flexibility of deck, piers, and isolation systems. There was significant difference in the computational time required for different models, but it was observed that the seismic response of the bridges obtained from different equivalent mathematical models is quite comparable even for an unsymmetrical bridge. Thus, the earthquake response of a seismically isolated bridge can be effectively obtained by modeling it as a single-degree-of-freedom system (i.e., considering the piers and deck as rigid) supported on an isolation system in two horizontal directions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T11:45:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T11:45:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BRIDGE ENGINEERING, 11(1), 109-121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1084-0702</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)1084-0702(2006)11:1(109)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4905</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4905</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>