<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14640</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:06:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Screening Crystal Morphologies from Crystal Structure</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TUNG, HH</dc:creator><dc:creator>BORDAWEKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMKRISHNA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>3-DIMENSIONAL MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPE EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISAPPEARANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HABIT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Crystal morphology is a critical determinant of the physical properties of crystalline materials. Face-specific growth rates can be used to compute dynamic and steady-state morphologies of crystals growing in a specific environment. The synthesis of crystals with desired morphologies requires a framework to guide the selection of environmental conditions. The framework developed here utilizes combinatorics to generate a graph of different morphologies connected by edges describing morphology transformations. These edges collectively form a polyhedral cone containing domains of different morphologies in a crystal-state space. The face-specific growth rates of crystals allow the identification of accessible regions within the polyhedral cone using a generalized single-crystal model. Here, we introduce morphology domain as a fundamental property of crystals which can be used to screen crystallization conditions for the controlled synthesis of desired crystal morphologies that is both facile and readily usable. A user-friendly tool, MorphologyDomain, is presented that facilitates diverse applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:06:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:06:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CRYSTAL GROWTH &amp; DESIGN, 13(4)1390-1396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/cg400009m</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14640</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>