<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4898</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cost models for water supply distribution systems</dc:title><dc:creator>CLARK, RM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIVAGANESAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SELVAKUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SETHI, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>contaminant propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>organics</dc:subject><dc:subject>outbreak</dc:subject><dc:subject>missouri</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality</dc:subject><dc:subject>gac</dc:subject><dc:subject>water supply</dc:subject><dc:subject>costs</dc:subject><dc:subject>water distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>rehabilitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>regression models</dc:subject><dc:subject>pipes</dc:subject><dc:description>A major challenge for society in the 21st century will be replacement, design, and optimal management of urban infrastructure. It is estimated that the current worldwide demand for infrastructure investment is approximately three trillion dollars annually. A Drinking Water Infrastructure Needs Survey conducted by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency estimated that community water systems nationwide have an immediate need of $12.1 billion in infrastructure investment, primarily to protect against microbiological contamination. This paper presents equations that can be used to estimate the cost of system construction, expansion, and rehabilitation and repair for distribution system components. Equations have been developed for installation of new pipe, trenching, embedment, and the other unit operations that are required to replace or construct new distribution system components. Equations have also been developed to estimate the cost of cement mortar lining, sliplining, and corrosion control. These equations can be used in an additive manner to estimate the cost of all of the unit operations required for replacing or laying new distribution system piping, and for a limited set of rehabilitation and repair options.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T11:25:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T11:25:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF WATER RESOURCES PLANNING AND MANAGEMENT-ASCE, 128(5), 312-321</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0733-9496</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)0733-9496(2002)128:5(312)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4898</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4898</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>