<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12541</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Miscibility of InxGa1-xAs alloys: a study using atomistic simulations</dc:title><dc:creator>ADHIKARI, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>molecular-dynamics simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>valence force-field</dc:subject><dc:subject>monte-carlo-simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermodynamic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>ternary</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>solubility</dc:subject><dc:subject>valence force field model</dc:subject><dc:subject>tersoff potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>monte carlo method</dc:subject><dc:subject>inxga1-xas</dc:subject><dc:description>Atomistic simulations are used in combination with the two potential energy functions, namely, the Valence Force Field (VFF) model and the Tersoff model, to study the solution thermodynamics of InxGa1-xAs alloy. The simulation data, in the form of a T - x diagram, is contrasted with the results obtained by using the Ho and Stringfellow approach. It is observed that for the VFF model, the upper critical solution temperature obtained from simulation data is approximately 850 K, which is higher than the 729 K predicted by the Ho and Stringfellow treatment. The composition range for which the two-phase heterogeneous region exists is wider than that predicted by the Ho and Stringfellow approach. The Tersoff model predicts a complex miscibility diagram, where the 850 K temperature corresponds to the approximate 'eutectic' temperature. Further improvement of model predictions may be made possible by investigation of temperature and composition dependent interaction parameter in a modified regular solution theory, and investigation of non-random, non-ideal solution models in the Ho and Stringfellow treatment, development of temperature dependent VFF model parameters and adjustment of Tersoff model parameters to account for longer range interactions which exist at temperatures above 850 K. The miscibility diagram constructed using the Tersoff model simulation data can be used to provide information on the phase stability and equilibrium Indium content at any given temperature for the crystalline solid solution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T02:03:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T02:03:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MOLECULAR PHYSICS, 107(16), 1641-1648</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0026-8976</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00268970903008465</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12541</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12541</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>