<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10709</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-15T11:58:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Determination of directions of horizontal principal stress and identification of active faults in Kachchh (India) by electromagnetic radiation (EMR)</dc:title><dc:creator>MALLIK, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANGERER, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>GREILING, RO</dc:creator><dc:subject>moment tensor solutions</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake prediction</dc:subject><dc:subject>global seismicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>western india</dc:subject><dc:subject>fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>rocks</dc:subject><dc:subject>generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>germany</dc:subject><dc:subject>electromagnetic radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>kachchh</dc:subject><dc:subject>bhuj</dc:subject><dc:subject>fault</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>cerescope</dc:subject><dc:description>The Kachchh basin in the western India is known for its recent high seismicity. This study presents an application of the geogenic Electromagnetic Radiation (EMR) technique for deciphering the directions of principal horizontal stress in the eastern Kachchh. The principal direction of horizontal stress obtained from EMR differs from those obtained from earthquake focal plane solutions. The major horizontal principal stress based on the EMR study shows an azimuth of N60 degrees E +/- 10 degrees. The principal directions of EMR emissions are parallel to the acute bisector of conjugate microcracks. The azimuthal distribution of EMR signal and dimension of microcracks suggest that the EM emissions are transversely polarized. The study also deals with the first application of electromagnetic radiation emissions to identify active fracture planes in sandstones that could become potential active faults later, which might be seismogenic or nonseimogenic. This study is based on linear profiling at six different places across two major faults, the Kachchh Mainland Fault (KMF) and the South Wagad Fault (SWF) in the eastern Kachchh. Anomalously, high EMR emissions are observed in the eastern part of the KMF, indicating active surface deformation. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T01:05:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T01:05:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEODYNAMICS, 45(4-5), 234-245</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0264-3707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jog.2008.01.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10709</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10709</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>