<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8309</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-14T05:07:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Loop Configuration on Steam Drum Level Control for a Multiple Drum Interconnected Loops Pressure Tube Type Boiling Water Reactor</dc:title><dc:creator>GAIKWAD, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYAN, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>IYER, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARTIYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>LELE, HG</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>model-predictive control</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase natural circulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>control-system</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>4-tank system</dc:subject><dc:subject>boiler model</dc:subject><dc:subject>power-plant</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>transient</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>bwr</dc:subject><dc:subject>innovative three-element steam drum level control</dc:subject><dc:subject>modeling simulation control of nuclear power plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>plant transient and safety analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>relap5</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal hydraulics</dc:subject><dc:description>For AHWR (Advanced Heavy Water Reactor), a pressure tube type Boiling Water Reactor (BWR) with parallel inter-connected loops, the Steam Drum (SD) level control is closely related to Main Heat Transport (MHT) coolant inventory and sustained heat removal through natural circulation, hence overall safety of the power plant. The MHT configuration with multiple (four) interconnected loops influences the SD level control in a manner which has not been previously addressed. The MHT configuration has been chosen based on comprehensive overall design requirements and certain Postulated Initiated Event (PIEs) for Loss of Coolant Accident (LOCA), which postulates a double ended break in the four partitioned Emergency Core Cooling System (ECCS) header. A conventional individual three-element SD level controller can not account for the highly coupled and interacting behaviors, of the four SD levels. An innovative three-element SD level control scheme is proposed to overcome this situation. The response obtained for a variety of unsymmetrical disturbances shows that the SD levels do not diverge and quickly settle to the various new set points assigned. The proposed scheme also leads to enhanced safety margins for most of the PIEs considered with a little influence on the 100% full power steady-state design conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T01:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T01:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON NUCLEAR SCIENCE, 56(6), 3712-3725</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TNS.2009.2033682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8309</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>