<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18382</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:46:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Structural Equation Modelling Approach for Massive Blended Synchronous Teacher Training</dc:title><dc:creator>KANNAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>SELF-DETERMINATION THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>USER ACCEPTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TECHNOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EDUCATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SATISFACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTENTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blended teacher training</dc:subject><dc:subject>ICT enabled workshops</dc:subject><dc:subject>Synchronous distance education</dc:subject><dc:subject>Technology Acceptance Model (TAM)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extrinsic motivation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intrinsic motivation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Structural equation modelling (SEM)</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a structural equation modelling (SEM) approach for blended synchronous teacher training workshop. It examines the relationship among various factors that influence the Satisfaction (SAT) of participating teachers. Data were collected with the help of a questionnaire from about 500 engineering college teachers. These teachers had attended a blended synchronous distance mode workshop, conducted by IIT Bombay, on "Computational fluid dynamics" in June 2012. The research model was tested using the SEM approach and was found to have a good fit. Ten hypotheses were tested using path analysis. The variable that had the largest effect on Satisfaction (SAT) was Technology effectiveness (TE). The variables that had medium effect on Satisfaction (SAT) were, Behaviour intention to use (BIU), Perceived usefulness (PU), Instructor effectiveness (IE) and Extrinsic motivation (EM). The result on the role of TE in blended synchronous teacher training supports the existing body of literature. Moreover, we found that IE was fully mediated through PU and BIU and thereby implying that TE has a significant role if supported by IE, PU and BIU. Finally, we discuss the implications of our study and make suggestions for further improvement of blended synchronous mode teacher training model.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC, LEARNING  TECHNOLOGY TASK FORCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:46:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:46:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EDUCATIONAL TECHNOLOGY &amp; SOCIETY, 18(3)1-15</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1436-4522</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18382</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>