<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16661</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T13:05:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Grain Growth and beta-Mg17Al12 Intermetallic Phase Dissolution During Heat Treatment and Its Impact on Deformation Behavior of AZ80 Mg-Alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>PALAI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>HODGSON, PD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>AZ80 magnesium alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength asymmetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL ANISOTROPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNESIUM ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>AZ31</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZN</dc:subject><dc:subject>AL</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEET</dc:subject><dc:subject>TWINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:description>Microstructure evolution after solutionizing and ageing treatment of cast AZ80 Mg alloy were investigated using optical and scanning electron microscopy. Effect of these treatments on grain size, beta-Mg17Al12 intermetallic phase, mechanical behavior, and flow asymmetry were investigated. The initial continuous network of beta-phase found to be reduced after solutionizing. The dissolution of beta-phase and simultaneous grain growth are found to be interrelated. Mechanical properties including yield strength, maximum strength (ultimate compressive strength), and maximum strain attainable in compressive found almost twice than the corresponding values obtained in tension. The asymmetry in compressive and tensile properties is found to decrease with grain size at certain solutionizing duration. Particular heat treatment found to offer best combination of tensile compressive flow properties in AZ80 Mg alloy. Aging under certain conditions found to minimize the strength asymmetry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:05:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:05:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS ENGINEERING AND PERFORMANCE, 23(1)77-82</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1059-9495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1544-1024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11665-013-0722-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16661</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>