<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1719</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Myelin growth and coiling</dc:title><dc:creator>HARAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANOHAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>lamellar phases</dc:subject><dc:subject>organization</dc:subject><dc:subject>myelins</dc:subject><dc:subject>coiling</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerosol-ot</dc:subject><dc:subject>para-toluene sulfonic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphatidycholine</dc:subject><dc:description>Surfactants form a variety of microstructures in solution, some of which are equilibrium and the others are non-equilibrium microstructures. During the dissolution of a surfactant in a solvent, various types of non-equilibrium microstructures have been observed. The most interesting and fascinating non-equilibrium microstructure is the 'Myelin Figure'. In the present report the swelling and dissolution dynamics of the myelin growth in the surfactants Aerosol-OT (AOT) and phosphatidylcholine (PC) in aqueous medium have been studied. The effect of the additive para-toluene sulfonic acid (PTS) on the dynamics and the shape of these myelin structures have been investigated. The observation of coiling transformations in the presence of these additives has been studied. It is shown that the molecular diffusion of the surfactant from the interface and the flexibility of the interface are the two important parameters for formation, growth and coiling of myelin structures. Chemical reactions in myelins have been carried out to throw light on the water transport during the myelin growth. (C) 2002 Published by Elsevier Science B.V.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T21:56:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T21:56:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>COLLOIDS AND SURFACES A-PHYSICOCHEMICAL AND ENGINEERING ASPECTS,205,21-30</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-7757</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0927-7757(01)01144-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14988</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1719</dc:identifier><dc:source>Indo French Workshop on Advances in the Understanding of Adsorption Phenomena at Solid/Aqueous Solution Interfaces,PUNE, INDIA,FEB 11-16, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>