<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4576</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tripartite Entanglement versus Tripartite Nonlocality in Three-Qubit Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger-Class States</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINCLAIR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEBNATH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RUNGTA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>STOCK, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>quantum nonlocality</dc:subject><dc:subject>inequality</dc:subject><dc:subject>qubits</dc:subject><dc:description>We analyze the relationship between tripartite entanglement and genuine tripartite nonlocality for three-qubit pure states in the Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger class. We consider a family of states known as the generalized Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger states and derive an analytical expression relating the three-tangle, which quantifies tripartite entanglement, to the Svetlichny inequality, which is a Bell-type inequality that is violated only when all three qubits are nonlocally correlated. We show that states with three-tangle less than 1/2 do not violate the Svetlichny inequality. On the other hand, a set of states known as the maximal slice states does violate the Svetlichny inequality, and exactly analogous to the two-qubit case, the amount of violation is directly related to the degree of tripartite entanglement. We discuss further interesting properties of the generalized Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger and maximal slice states.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T00:59:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T00:59:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW LETTERS, 102(25), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0031-9007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevLett.102.250404</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4576</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4576</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>