<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16774</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:38:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Type II phosphatidylinositol 4-kinases interact with Fc epsilon RI gamma subunit in RBL-2H3 cells</dc:title><dc:creator>BOJJIREDDY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAHMANYAM, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>Type II PtdIns 4-kinase</dc:subject><dc:subject>RBL-2H3 cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>FceRI gamma</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mast cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>AFFINITY IGE RECEPTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>TYROSINE KINASE SYK</dc:subject><dc:subject>RBL 2H3 CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPLENIC LYMPHOCYTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZETA-CHAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHORYLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEGRANULATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Ligation of high-affinity IgE receptor I (Fc epsilon RI) on RBL-2H3 cells leads to recruitment of Fc epsilon RI and type II phosphatidylinositol 4-kinases (PtdIns 4-kinases) into lipid rafts. Lipid raft integrity is required for the activation of type II PtdIns 4-kinases and signal transduction through Fc epsilon RI gamma during RBL-2H3 cell activation. However, the molecular mechanism by which PtdIns 4-kinases are coupled to Fc epsilon RI signaling is elusive. Here, we report association of type II PtdIns 4-kinase activity with Fc epsilon RI gamma subunit in anti-Fc epsilon RI gamma immunoprecipitates. Fc epsilon RI gamma-associated PtdIns 4-kinase activity increases threefold upon Fc epsilon RI ligation in anti-Fc epsilon RI gamma immunoprecipitates. Biochemical characterization of PtdIns 4-kinase activity associated with Fc epsilon RI gamma reveals that it is a type II PtdIns 4-kinases. Canonical tyrosine residues mutation in Fc epsilon RI gamma ITAM (Y65 and Y76) reveals that these two tyrosine residues in gamma subunit are required for its interaction with type II PtdIns 4-kinases.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:38:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:38:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MOLECULAR AND CELLULAR BIOCHEMISTRY, 390(1/2)197-203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-8177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-4919</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11010-014-1970-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16774</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>