<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12057</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Chitosan reinforced apatite-wollastonite coating by electrophoretic deposition on titanium implants</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SONI, VP</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>simulated body-fluid</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydroxyapatite</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocompatibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>bioceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>tissue</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>vivo</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel bioactive porous apatite-wollastonite/chitosan composite coating was prepared by electrophoretic deposition. The influence of synthesis parameters like pH of suspension and current density was studied and optimized. X-ray diffraction confirmed crystalline phase of apatite wollastonite in powder as well as composite coating with coat crystallinity of 65%. Scanning electron microscope showed that the porosity had interconnections with good homogeneity between the phases. The addition of chitosan increased the adhesive strength of the composite coating. Young's modulus of the coating was found to be 9.23 GPa. One of our key findings was sheet-like apatite growth unlike ball-like growth found in bioceramics. Role of chitosan was studied in apatite growth mechanism in simulated body fluid. In presence of chitosan, dense negatively charged surface with homogenous nucleation was the primary factor for sheet-like evolution of apatite layer. The results suggest that incorporation of chitosan with apatite-wollastonite in composite coating could provide excellent in vitro bioactivity with enhanced mechanical properties.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:42:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:42:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE-MATERIALS IN MEDICINE, 20(7), 1427-1436</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-4530</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10856-009-3712-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12057</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12057</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>