<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6184</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimum sizing of wind-battery systems incorporating resource uncertainty</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEDARE, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>energy-conversion system</dc:subject><dc:subject>integrated diesel generator</dc:subject><dc:subject>water-heating systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>design-space approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>power-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance assessment</dc:subject><dc:subject>size optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>remote areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>wind-battery system</dc:subject><dc:subject>chance constrained programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>sizing curve</dc:subject><dc:subject>design space</dc:subject><dc:subject>wind resource uncertainty</dc:subject><dc:description>The inherent uncertainty of the wind is a major impediment for successful implementation of wind based power generation technology A methodology has been proposed in this paper to incorporate wind speed uncertainty in sizing wind-battery system for isolated applications. The uncertainty associated with the wind speed is incorporated using chance constraint programming approach. For a pre-specified reliability requirement, a deterministic equivalent energy balance equation may be derived from the chance constraint that allows time series simulation of the entire system. This results in a generation of the entire set of feasible design options, satisfying different system level constraints, on a battery capacity vs. generator rating diagram, also known as the design space The proposed methodology highlights the tradeoffs between the wind turbine rating, rotor diameter and the battery size for a given reliability of power supply The optimum configuration is chosen on the basis of the minimum cost of energy (US$/kWh) It is shown with the help of illustrative examples that the proposed methodology is generic and flexible to incorporate alternate sub-component models (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T09:43:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T09:43:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED ENERGY, 87(8), 2712-2727</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-2619</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2010.03.027</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6184</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>