<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11605</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stall inception and its control in an axial flow fan under dynamic inflow distortion</dc:title><dc:creator>SALUNKHE, PB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRADEEP, AM</dc:creator><dc:subject>inlet distortion</dc:subject><dc:subject>rotating stall</dc:subject><dc:subject>compressor</dc:subject><dc:subject>engine</dc:subject><dc:subject>tip injection</dc:subject><dc:subject>inflow distortion</dc:subject><dc:subject>rotating stall</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow instability</dc:subject><dc:description>The present experimental study demonstrates the effects of clean and distorted inflow conditions on the performance and nature of stall inception in a single stage axial flow fan. A 90 degrees distortion screen located upstream of the rotor leading edge was rotated up to 40 per cent of the rotor speed in the clockwise (co-rotation) and counterclockwise (counter-rotation) directions to generate dynamic inflow distortion. It was observed that the stall margin deteriorated substantially under co-rotating inflow distortion as compared to counter-rotating inflow distortion. The degradation in stall margin was about 15 per cent and 1.98 per cent under co- and counter-rotating inflow distortions, respectively. Tip injection was used as a means of enhancing the fan performance under distorted inflow. With tip injection under co-rotating inflow distortion, about 2.8 per cent improvement in stall margin was observed. The improvement in stall margin under counter-rotating inflow distortion with tip injection was 2.98 per cent. The unsteady static pressure traces show clear differences in the nature of stall inception under co-and counter-rotating inflow distortions. The stall inception occurs through long-length-scale disturbances under co-rotating inflow distortion, while the mode of stall inception under clean flow and counter-rotating inflow distortions was through short-length-scale disturbances. The nature of stall inception under dynamic inflow distortion with tip injection remains the same as without tip injection.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERING PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T08:43:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T08:43:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART A-JOURNAL OF POWER AND ENERGY, 224(A3), 383-398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-6509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1243/09576509JPE876</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11605</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11605</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>