<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15348</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:34:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Studies on the solubility of hydrogen in molten Pb83Li17 eutectic alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIRPUDE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAMURTHY, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>Pb83Li17 eutectic alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogen solubility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusion reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tritium</dc:subject><dc:subject>ITER</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEAD-LITHIUM ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIQUID</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISOTOPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Lead-lithium eutectic (Pb87Li17) alloy is a candidate material to be used as a secondary tritium breeder, neutron multiplier and heat transfer agent in the fusion reactor. The tritium thus produced in the alloy may be soluble or appear as a new phase of lithium-tritides and/or lead-tritides, which eventually affect the performance of Pb83Li17 eutectic. Therefore, solubility of tritium in the alloy at the operating conditions of the fusion reactor is a subject matter of investigation. Tritium being the isotope of hydrogen behaves more or less similar to the hydrogen. In the present investigation the solubility of hydrogen in the Pb83Li17 has been investigated as a function of temperature and pressure. It was found that, hydrogen solubility in the Pb87Li17 alloy is almost constant above 350 degrees C. Hydrogen solubility increases with increase of temperature up to 400 degrees C. Hydrogen solubility is 120 ppm at 400 degrees C and 800 Torr hydrogen pressure: The solubility decreases on further rise in temperature from 400 degrees C. However, at all the temperatures hydrogen solubility increased with increase of partial pressure of hydrogen. Copyright (c) 2013, Hydrogen Energy Publications, LLC. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:34:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:34:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYDROGEN ENERGY, 38(14)6002-6007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2013.03.033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15348</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>