<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14035</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:27:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Petrology, palynology and organic geochemistry of Eocene lignite of Matanomadh, Kutch Basin, western India: Implications to depositional environment and hydrocarbon source potential</dc:title><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEWS, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, BD</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARASWATI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANN, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>COAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOSSIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLASSIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eocene lignites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Matanomadh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kutch Basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Macerals</dc:subject><dc:subject>Palynomorphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biomarkers</dc:subject><dc:description>Petrological, palynological and organic-geochemical investigations were undertaken to determine the source vegetation, depositional conditions and hydrocarbon source potential of Eocene Matanomadh lignites from Kutch Basin, western India. The maceral study reveals that studied lignites are rich in huminite (ay. 63%) with sub-ordinate amount of liptinite (ay. 19%) and low inertinite (ay. 3%), along with low to moderately high associated mineral matters (ay. 15%). The overall petrographic composition points to a lagoonal condition for the formation of these lignites. The mean huminite reflectance values (R(r): 0.28-0.34%, ay. 0.31%) as well as low Rock-Eval T(max) (av. 417 degrees C) values for the seams, suggest brown coal or lignitic stage/rank for the studied lignites. The palynological assemblages, dominated by tropical angiospermic pollen, suggest prevalence of warm humid tropical climate during the deposition of these lignites. The total organic carbon (TOC) content of lignites ranges between 26 and 58 wt.%, whereas the TOC content of the associated carbonaceous shales is around 4 wt.%. The Hydrogen Index (HI) ranging from 23 to 452 mg HC/g TOC indicates that the lignite sequence has the potential to produce mixed oil and gaseous hydrocarbons on maturation. The major pyrolysis products of lignites, derived from Curie point pyrolysis-GC-MS, are straight chain aliphatics, phenols and cadalene-based C(15) bicyclic sesquiterpenoids. The exclusive occurrence of C(15) bicyclic sesquiterpenoids suggests that these compounds are derived from dammar resin of angiosperm plants, belonging to family Dipterocarpaceae. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:27:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:27:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF COAL GEOLOGY,85(1)91-102</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0166-5162</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.coal.2010.10.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14035</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>