<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15422</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:22:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>PbCu3TeO7: an S=1/2 staircase kagome lattice with significant intra-plane and inter-plane couplings</dc:title><dc:creator>KOTESWARARAO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>JEON, BG</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASGUPTA, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, KH</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOU, FC</dc:creator><dc:subject>MUFFIN-TIN ORBITALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTIFERROMAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>NI3V2O8</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT</dc:subject><dc:description>We have synthesized polycrystalline and single-crystal samples of PbCu3TeO7 and studied its properties via magnetic susceptibility, chi(T), and heat-capacity, C-p(T), measurements and also electronic structure calculations. Whereas the crystal structure is suggestive of the presence of a quasi-2D network of Cu2+(S = 1/2) buckled staircase kagome layers, the chi(T) data show magnetic anisotropy and three magnetic anomalies at temperatures T-N1 similar to 36 K, T-N2 similar to 25 K, and T-N3 similar to 17 K. The chi(T) data follow the Curie-Weiss law above 200 K and a Curie-Weiss temperature theta(CW) similar to -150 K is obtained. The data deviate from the simple Curie-Weiss law below 200 K, which is well above T-N1, suggesting the presence of competing magnetic interactions. The magnetic anomaly at T-N3 appears to be of first order from magnetization measurements, although our C-p(T) results do not display any anomaly at T-N3. The hopping integrals obtained from our electronic structure calculations suggest the presence of significant intra-kagome (next-nearest neighbor and diagonal) and inter-kagome couplings. These couplings take the PbCu3TeO7 system away from a disordered ground state and lead to long-range order, in contrast to what might be expected for an ideal (isotropic) 2D kagome system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:22:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:22:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 25(33)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/25/33/336003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15422</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>