<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11924</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interrogating modernity, gendering 'tradition': Teatr tales from Goa</dc:title><dc:creator>ROBINSON, R</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper examines the teatr, a form of popular theatre in contemporary Goa, and the ways in which it engages with the modern, defining and 'fixing', in the same moment, a particular variant of 'tradition'. The plays of this genre revolve around questions of modern In a complex articulation of the realms and global and the local, modern culture, social mores, politics and economics, tourism and the global media are all represented queried, even critiqued. Simultaneously tradition, gender and relations are viewed as requiring protection from the harmful effects of the modern. Thus, we are offered particularly glorified representation of the 'traditional' Goan woman and her immurement the family. Scholars studying cinema, theatre and the arts have spoken of similar constructions elsewhere. Given their pervasiveness, the temptation to read these constructions a constituting a homogeneous dominant ideology are great. However while the teatrs containing women within tradition, there are ruptures and moments with different ideas and voices surface. The paper argues that these moments are worth holding as traces of alternative, though suppressed, models, and as reminders of what the dominant ideology has to counter in establishing and maintaining its hegemony.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS PVT LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T02:32:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T02:32:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CONTRIBUTIONS TO INDIAN SOCIOLOGY, 33(3), 503-539</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0069-9667</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/006996679903300302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11924</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11924</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>