<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15960</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:34:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Coupling effect of piezoelectric wafer transducers in distortions of primary Lamb wave modes</dc:title><dc:creator>BIJUDAS, CR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUJUMDAR, PM</dc:creator><dc:subject>PROPAGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:description>Piezoelectric wafer transducers (PWT) are widely used for Lamb wave based damage detection schemes. The size of the damage that can be detected is dependent on the wavelength of the Lamb wave employed. Thus it is essential to explore the higher frequency range within the (fundamental) bandwidth of S-0 and A(0) modes, however below the cut-off frequencies of A(1) and S-1. It is observed that the Lamb wave modes S-0 and A(0) generated using PWT undergo distortion within this fundamental bandwidth. This behavior is experimentally observed for different PWT sizes and types. The nature of this observed distortion is very different from the distortion of wave modes due to dispersion. In addition, the distortion, in many cases, tends towards the appearance of new wave modes close to the S-0 and A(0) modes. To understand this experimental observation, a theoretical study is performed. First, finite element (FE) simulations of Lamb waves considering pin-force, thermal analogy, and couple field models of surface mounted PWT are carried out. These simulation studies reveal that the wavepacket distortion can be attributed mostly to electro-mechanical coupling effect of the PWT. Next, the dispersion plot of piezoelectric layer considering electro-mechanical coupling is obtained using spectral finite element (SFE) method. These dispersion characteristics of the PWT are found to be significantly different from the conventional Lamb wave dispersion characteristics and may explain the experimental observation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:34:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:34:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS AND STRUCTURES, 22(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0964-1726</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-665X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0964-1726/22/6/065007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15960</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>