<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9717</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>A PATH ORDERING FOR PROVING TERMINATION OF AC REWRITE SYSTEMS</dc:title><dc:creator>KAPUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIVAKUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHANG, HT</dc:creator><dc:subject>ac rewrite systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>path ordering</dc:subject><dc:description>We describe a method that extends the lexicographic recursive path ordering of Dershowitz and Kamin and Levy for proving termination of associative-commutative (AC) rewrite systems. Instead of comparing the arguments of an AC-operator using the multiset extension, we partition them into disjoint subsets and use each subset only once for comparison. To preserve transitivity, we introduce two techniques - pseudocopying and elevating of arguments of an AC operator. This method imposes no restrictions at all on the underlying precedence relation on function symbols. It can therefore prove termination of a much more extensive class of AC rewrite systems than can previous methods, such as associative path ordering, that restrict AC operators to be minimal or subminimal in precedence. A number of examples illustrating the power of the approach are discussed. The method has been implemented in RRL, Rewrite Rule Laboratory, a theorem-proving environment based on rewrite techniques and completion.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T03:01:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T03:01:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF AUTOMATED REASONING, 14(2), 293-316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-7433</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF00881859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9717</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9717</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>