<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4700</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-12T06:29:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ab initio many-body calculations on infinite carbon and boron-nitrogen chains</dc:title><dc:creator>ABDURAHMAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKLA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOLG, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>borazine-based polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitride nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>cohesive properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>atomic chains</dc:subject><dc:subject>rings</dc:subject><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>abinitio</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyyne</dc:subject><dc:subject>fullerenes</dc:subject><dc:subject>solids</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper we report first-principles calculations on the ground-state electronic structure of two infinite one-dimensional systems: (a) a chain of carbon atoms and (b) a chain of alternating boron and nitrogen atoms. Meanfield results were obtained using the restricted Hartree-Fock approach, while the many-body effects were taken into account by second-order Moller-Plesset perturbation theory and the coupled-cluster approach. The calculations were performed using 6-31G** basis sets, including the d-type polarization functions. Both at the Hartree-Fock (HF) and the correlated levels, we find that the infinite carbon chain exhibits bond alternation with alternating single and triple bonds, while the boron-nitrogen chain exhibits equidistant bonds. In addition, we also performed density-functional-theory-based local-density-approximation (LDA) calculations on the infinite carbon chain using the same basis set. Our LDA results, in contradiction to our HF and correlated results, predict a very small bond alternation. Based upon our LDA results for the carbon chain, which are in agreement with an earlier LDA calculation [E. J. Bylaska, J. H. Weare, and R. Kawai, Phys. Rev. B 58, R7488 (1998)], we conclude that the LDA significantly underestimates Peierls distortion. This emphasizes that the inclusion of many-particle effects is very important for the correct description of Peierls distortion in one-dimensional systems.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T10:27:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T10:27:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 65(11), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.65.115106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4700</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4700</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>