<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16299</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T10:58:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Methotrexate conjugated magnetic nanoparticle for targeted drug delivery and thermal therapy</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>FE3O4 NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:description>A simple soft chemical approach is used for the preparation of citrate functionalized iron oxide (Fe3O4) aqueous colloidal magnetic nanoparticles (CA-MNPs) of average size similar to 10 nm. The CA-MNPs exhibit superparamagnetic behavior at room temperature with strong field dependent magnetic responsivity. The CA-MNPs can be conjugated with Methotrexate (MTX) drug through amide bonds between the carboxylic group on the surface of MNPs and amine group of MTX. The surface functionalization of Fe3O4 nanoparticles with citric acid and conjugation of MTX drug is evident from FTIR spectroscopy, zeta-potential measurement, and elemental and thermal analyses. From the drug release study, it has been observed that this bonding of MTX conjugated MNPs (MTX-MNPs) is cleaved by the intracellular enzymes in lysosome, and MTX is delivered largely inside target cancerous cells at lower pH, thereby reducing toxicity to normal cells. Also, it has been observed that the intercellular uptake of MTX-MNPs is higher compared to CA-MNPs. In addition, the aqueous colloidal stability, optimal magnetization, and good specific absorption rate (under external AC magnetic field) of CA-MNPs act as effective heating source for thermal therapy. Cytotoxicity study of MTX-MNPs shows the reduction of cellular viability for human cervical cancer cells (HeLa). Further, a synergistic effect of MTX-MNPs shows a more effective tumor cell death due to the combined effect of thermo-chemotherapy. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T10:58:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T10:58:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 115(17)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4866080</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16299</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>