<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14861</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:05:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Response of Foundations Subjected to Blast Loadings: State of the Art Review</dc:title><dc:creator>RANJAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEEPANKAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAPILESH, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>Foundations</dc:subject><dc:subject>blast loading</dc:subject><dc:subject>blast wave propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil structure interaction and soil model</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL RESPONSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NUMERICAL-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE-PROPAGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROUND SHOCK</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIBRATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESS</dc:subject><dc:description>Terrorist attacks worldwide in recent years pose big threat to the humankind which generates blast load to the structure/foundation. Protecting foundation systems from such attacks has become a major concern for designers. Terrorist attack may be in the form of missile attack which will penetrate the ground and then explode. Mining, quarrying, construction activities and all other operations which involve the use of explosives for rock breaking are some of the other sources of blast load. Blast is generally of small duration and having very high frequency and pressure hence, it needs to be considered in design. Blast load is a non-oscillatory pulse load. Due to blast, foundation elements may be severely damaged or destroyed and this may in turn result in to excessive settlements and failure of superstructure. Blast can have effect on bearing capacity and it can cause liquefaction as well. Hence, a better understanding is required to protect foundation systems and to prevent failure of supported superstructure subjected to blast loadings.</dc:description><dc:publisher>DISASTER ADVANCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DISASTER ADVANCES, 5(1)54-63</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14861</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>