<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4471</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Superconductivity and transport behavior of laser ablated Au-added YBa2Cu3O7-delta thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>PINTO, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>APTE, PR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, MSR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DSOUZA, CP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAI, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYARAGHAVAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GNANASEKAR, KI</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>gold</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhancement</dc:subject><dc:description>We report here a systematic investigation of superconducting properties of Au-added YBa2CU3O7-delta(YBCO) thin films in situ grown by pulsed laser ablation method. Films are highly c-axis oriented while the corresponding bulk samples contain multiphases. The superconducting transition temperature T-c of films remains close to 90 K even for large concentration of Au (up to 10% by weight) and the critical current denisty J(c) is about 5X10(6) A cm(-2) at 77 K (in self-field) with higher reproducibility when compared with that of undoped films of YBCO on [100] LaAlO3. Preliminary investigations indicate that Au gets rejected by the grains and dopes the grain boundaries thus improving the stability of the boundaries and hence of the films. Our result also demonstrates that pulsed laser deposition can be used to grow films of compounds that generally do not form as a single phase in bulk by the conventional solid state methods and hence offers unique possibilities in terms of exploring structure-property relationships in thin films. (C) 1996</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T16:48:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T16:48:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 68(7), 1006-1008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.116210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4471</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4471</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>