<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1459</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-06T10:53:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Anomalous magnetoresistance in antiferromagnetic polycrystalline materials R2Ni3Si5 (R equals rare earth)</dc:title><dc:creator>MAZUMDAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGARAJAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>PADALIA, BD</dc:creator><dc:creator>GODART, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>giant magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>ce2ni3si5</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicide</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:description>Magnetoresistance (MR) studies on polycrystalline R2Ni3Si5, (R=Y, rare earth) which order antiferromagnetically at low temperatures, are reported here. MR of the Nd, Sm, and Tb members of the series exhibit positive giant magnetoresistance, largest among polycrystalline materials (85%, 75%, and 58% for Tb2Ni3Si5, Sm2Ni3Si5, and Nd2Ni3Si5, respectively, at 4.4 K in a field of 45 kG). These materials have, to the best of our knowledge, the largest positive GMR reported ever for any bulk polycrystalline compounds. The magnitude of MR does not correlate with the rare earth magnetic moments. We believe that the structure of these materials, which can be considered as a naturally occurring multilayer of wavy planes of rare earth atoms separated by Ni-Si network, plays a role. The isothermal MR of other members of this series (R=Pr,Dy,Ho) exhibits a maximum and a minimum, below their respective T-N's. We interpret these in terms of a metamagnetic transition and short-range ferromagnetic correlations. The short-range ferromagnetic correlations seem to be dominant in the temperature region just above T-N. (C) 1997 American Institute of Physics.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T07:47:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T07:47:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS,81(8)5781-5783</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.364666</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14614</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1459</dc:identifier><dc:source>41st Annual Conference on Magnetism and Magnetic Materials,ATLANTA, GA,NOV 12-15, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>