<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8210</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Active gate control of series connected IGBTs using positive current feedback technique</dc:title><dc:creator>KRISHNA, DVMM</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>active gate control</dc:subject><dc:subject>current feedback</dc:subject><dc:subject>high voltage</dc:subject><dc:subject>series connection of insulated gate bipolar transistors</dc:subject><dc:subject>(igbts)</dc:subject><dc:description>Controllable devices like insulated gate bipolar transistors; (IGBTs) are very popular on account of their highly desirable features. This prompts their use in high-voltage applications. But high-voltage IGBT development is facing constraints and there is a requirement for series connection of these devices to enhance their voltage withstanding capability. The series connection of IGBTs, however, has its own problems (e.g., dynamic voltage imbalances leading to device break down etc.). Active gate control offers a good solution to this problem. In this brief, a novel scheme of "active gate control using a positive current feedback" is proposed. The system uses a current feed back network where the gate voltage is dependent on the current through the device but not on the over-voltage across the device (the existing trend). The scheme has been simulated using PSPICE and validated experimentally. Analytical and control aspects are discussed. All the results are included. It is concluded that the proposed technique leads to a simple modular control circuit, wider range of operating currents, and increased system stability.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T19:14:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T19:14:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON CIRCUITS AND SYSTEMS II-EXPRESS BRIEFS, 52(5), 261-265</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1057-7130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TCSII.2005.846306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8210</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>