<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2745</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Integrity of Incoloy-825 cladded mild steel in sour gas service</dc:title><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATTANAIK, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANTO, PF</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHUGH, SK</dc:creator><dc:description>The corrosion of pipeline which carries crude petroleum products is a serious problem in petroleum industries. Thus selection of material for combating pipeline corrosion is an important aspect. Various kinds of pipelines with different kinds of coatings from inside or use of inhibitors or other control methods are usually employed to combat the corrosion of pipelines. A recent concept is the use of nickel base alloy cladding in the inside of the mild steel pipe to control the corrosion from the highly sour gas environment. Recently M/s ONGC, an Indian company, laid Incloloy cladded mild steel gas pipelines for their transportation. In the present work, the corrosion behavior of this Incoloy and Incoloy cladded mild steel in sour gas environment was investigated using high pressure high temperature tests, sulfide stress corrosion cracking test, stress corrosion cracking and constant extension rate tests. The results of High Pressure High Temperature tests help to predict life of the material as well as suggest a method of repairing the defect if it is formed during service conditions. The results of Sulfide Stress Corrosion Cracking and Constant Extension Rate tests revealed that the suceptibility of the material to Sulfide Stress Corrosion Cracking was not affected by welding. The 'C' ring and `U' bend test results showed that the material was not susceptible to Stress Corrosion Cracking. The present work justifies the selection of Incoloy cladded Mild Steel for sour gas service.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T10:19:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T10:19:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>CORROSION AND ITS CONTROLS, VOLS I AND II,1134-1142</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-444-82916-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16264</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2745</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Corrosion (CORCON 97),MUMBAI, INDIA,DEC 03-06, 1997</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>