<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1464</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Towards a programming model and middleware architecture for self-configuring systems</dc:title><dc:creator>BELLUR, UMESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARENDRA, NC</dc:creator><dc:subject>middleware</dc:subject><dc:subject>semantics</dc:subject><dc:subject>software architecture</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication services</dc:subject><dc:description>Today's distributed computing solutions are mostly static in nature and variations in system behavior have to be compiled into the system in advance, because today's technology does not permit self-configuring through dynamic rebinding of components. Self-configuring systems need a design approach based on behavioral specification as well as a middleware layer that can use these specifications to dynamically bind system components at run-time. In this paper, we present a service-oriented programming model and middleware for self-configuring systems. Our approach is based on semantic descriptions of components augmented with contextually dependent non-functional requirements for accomplishing the dynamic binding. For this purpose, we model service inter-dependencies as variability points. The middleware dynamically re-configures system behavior by mapping the variability points to components providing the needed functionality. Along with the middleware design needed for such an approach, we also present our programming model-called reconfigurable programming-and show how it can be used to put together self-configuring systems.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-11T04:14:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-11T04:14:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the First International Conference on Communication System Software and Middleware, New Delhi, India, 8-12 January 2006, 1-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-9575-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/COMSWA.2006.1665173</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1464</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1464</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>