<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4157</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Water complexes of styrene and 4-fluorostyrene: A combined electronic, vibrational spectroscopic and ab-initio investigation</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, PC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:subject>double-resonance spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescence spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzene</dc:subject><dc:subject>absorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectrum</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>state</dc:subject><dc:description>The binary complexes of water with styrene and fluorostyrene were investigated using LIF and FDIR spectroscopic techniques. The difference in the shifts of S-1 -&gt; S-0 electronic transitions clearly points out the disparity in the intermolecular structures of these two binary complexes. The FDIR spectra in the O-H stretching region indicate that water is a hydrogen bond donor in both complexes. The formation of a single O-H center dot center dot center dot pi hydrogen-bonded complex with styrene and an in-plane complex with fluorostyrene was inferred based on the analysis of the FDIR spectra in combination with ab initio calculations. The in-plane complex with fluorostyrene is characterized by the presence of O-H center dot center dot center dot F and C-H center dot center dot center dot O hydrogen bonds, leading to formation of a stable six-membered ring. The synergistic effect of O-H center dot center dot center dot F and C-H center dot center dot center dot O hydrogen bonds overwhelms the O-H center dot center dot center dot pi interaction in fluorostyrene-water complexes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T04:48:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T04:48:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 112(40), 9702-9707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp801856r</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4157</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4157</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>