<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7728</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>STRUCTURAL AND ELECTRICAL-PROPERTIES OF CADMIUM-OXIDE FILMS DEPOSITED BY THE ACTIVATED REACTIVE EVAPORATION TECHNIQUE</dc:title><dc:creator>PHATAK, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAL, R</dc:creator><dc:description>Transparent and conducting films of cadmium oxide were deposited on glass substrates by the activated reactive evaporation (ARE) technique for the first time. The sublimating nature of cadmium coupled with the reduction in ambient pressure due to oxygen consumption during deposition causes loss of control, which can be mitigated by introducing oxygen to maintain the pressure. The effect of boat temperature and substrate temperature on the structural and electrical properties of the films is reported. These properties are found to be strongly dependent on substrate temperature whereas the boat temperature has little influence. Films are polycrystalline even when substrate temperature is as low as 30-degrees-C. As the substrate temperature increases, the films exhibit increasing preferred orientation in (100) direction and a reduction in lattice strain. Simultaneously, the mobility and carrier concentration also improve. The ARE process enables deposition of excellent transparent and conducting films with conductivity about 2500-OMEGA--1 cm-1 which is as good as the best reported for CdO films.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T13:31:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T13:31:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS, 209(2), 240-249</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0040-6090(92)90681-Z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7728</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7728</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>