<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15330</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:25:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrical Transport and Breakdown in Graphene Multilayers Loaded with Electron Beam Induced Deposited Platinum</dc:title><dc:creator>KUSHRESTHA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KORATKAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>multilayer graphene sheets</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron beam induced deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>current-voltage characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON</dc:subject><dc:description>We demonstrate here the effect of electron beam induced deposited platinum on the electrical transport through multilayer graphene sheets. Platinum metal is deposited at different positions on the graphene multilayers, i.e., including as well as excluding the bottom contact sites and the change in electrical conductance of the same multilayer graphene sheets before and after platinum deposition is segregated. An improvement in electrical conductance is observed even if the metal is deposited at the part of the graphene sheets that does not touch the bottom gold electrodes, and hence this experimental approach directly demonstrates that the contact improvement is not the sole reason for the improved electrical conduction. The improvement in electrical performance of the graphene sheets is explained in terms of the doping of graphene sheets caused by the charge transfer between the deposited metal and the graphene and thereby modified density of states for electrical conduction. Metal deposition also leads to the increased interlayer interaction of the graphene sheets as revealed by the transmission electron microscopy analysis. Further, two types of breakdown behaviors viz. sharp and stepped breakdowns observed for these graphene devices are explained in terms of the effective graphene-metal contact area. These studies reveal the implications of top metal contact fabrication on graphene for electronic devices.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:25:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:25:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACS APPLIED MATERIALS &amp; INTERFACES, 5(8)3424-3430</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/am400489y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15330</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>