<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16298</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T10:57:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Morphology and Curie temperature engineering in crystalline La0.7Sr0.3MnO3 films on Si by pulsed laser deposition</dc:title><dc:creator>NORI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALE, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJU, NRC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUTAR, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PINTO, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>MANGANITE THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXYGEN-PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICON</dc:subject><dc:subject>JUNCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>XPS</dc:subject><dc:description>Of all the colossal magnetoresistant manganites, La0.7Sr0.3MnO3 (LSMO) exhibits magnetic and electronic state transitions above room temperature, and therefore holds immense technological potential in spintronic devices and hybrid heterojunctions. As the first step towards this goal, it needs to be integrated with silicon via a well-defined process that provides morphology and phase control, along with reproducibility. This work demonstrates the development of pulsed laser deposition (PLD) process parameter regimes for dense and columnar morphology LSMO films directly on Si. These regimes are postulated on the foundations of a pressure-distance scaling law and their limits are defined post experimental validation. The laser spot size is seen to play an important role in tandem with the pressure-distance scaling law to provide morphology control during LSMO deposition on lattice-mismatched Si substrate. Additionally, phase stability of the deposited films in these regimes is evaluated through magnetometry measurements and the Curie temperatures obtained are 349 K (for dense morphology) and 355 K (for columnar morphology)-the highest reported for LSMO films on Si so far. X-ray diffraction studies on phase evolution with variation in laser energy density and substrate temperature reveals the emergence of texture. Quantitative limits for all the key PLD process parameters are demonstrated in order enable morphological and structural engineering of LSMO films deposited directly on Si. These results are expected to boost the realization of top-down and bottom-up LSMO device architectures on the Si platform for a variety of applications. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T10:57:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T10:57:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 115(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4862909</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16298</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>