<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15918</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:35:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Polyaniline-iron oxide nanohybrid film as multi-functional label-free electrochemical and biomagnetic sensor for catechol</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LANG, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>PANI-iron oxide nanohybrid</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spectroelectrochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Impedance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biomagnetic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Catechol</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERAPEUTIC APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODIFIED ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCATALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROQUINONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARRAYS</dc:subject><dc:description>Polyaniline-iron oxide magnetic nanohybrid was synthesized and characterized using various spectroscopic, microstructural and electrochemical techniques. The smart integration of Fe3O4 nanoparticles within the polyaniline (PANI) matrix yielded a mesoporous nanohybrid (Fe3O4@PANI) with high surface area (94 m(2) g(-1)) and average pore width of 12.8 nm. Catechol is quasi-reversibly oxidized to o-quinone and reduced at the Fe3O4@PANI modified electrodes. The amperometric current response toward catechol was evaluated using the nanohybrid and the sensitivity and detection limit were found to be 312 mu A mu L-1 and 0.2 nM, respectively. The results from electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) indicated that the increased solution resistance (R-s) was due to elevated adsorption of catechol on the modified electrodes. Photoluminescence spectra showed ligand-to-metal charge transfer (LMCT) between p-pi orbitals of the phenolate oxygen in catechol and the d-sigma* metal orbital of Fe3O4@PANI nanohybrid. Potential dependent spectroelectrochemical behavior of Fe3O4@PANI nanohybrid toward catechol was studied using UV/vis/NIR spectroscopy. The binding activity of the biomagnetic particles to catechol through Brownian relaxation was evident from AC susceptibility measurements. The proposed sensor was used for successful recovery of catechol in tap water samples. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:35:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:35:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANALYTICA CHIMICA ACTA, 7958-14</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.aca.2013.07.043</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15918</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>