<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14756</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:33:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of Multiphase Microstructure with Bainite, Martensite, and Retained Austenite in a Co-Containing Steel Through Quenching and Partitioning (Q&amp;P) Treatment</dc:title><dc:creator>SAMANTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>HALDAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>M-S</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRIP STEELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERRITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEARLITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICON</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:description>The quenching and partitioning (Q&amp;P) treatment of steel aims to produce a higher fraction of retained austenite by carbon partitioning from supersaturated martensite. Q&amp;P studies done so far, relies on the basic concept of suppression of carbide formation by the addition of Si and/or Al. In the present study Q&amp;P treatment is performed on a steel containing 0.32 C, 1.78 Mn, 0.64 Si, 1.75 Al, and 1.20 Co (all wt pct). A combination of 0.64 Si and 1.75 Al is chosen to suppress the carbide precipitation and therefore, to achieve carbon partitioning after quenching. Addition of Co along with Al is expected to accelerate the bainite transformation during Q&amp;P treatment by increasing the driving force for transformation. The final aim is to develop a multiphase microstructure containing bainite, martensite, and the retained austenite and to study the effect of processing parameters (especially, quenching temperature and homogenization time) on the fraction and stability of retained austenite. A higher fraction of retained austenite (similar to 13 pct) has indeed been achieved by Q&amp;P treatment, compared to that obtained after direct-quenching (2.7 pct) or isothermal bainitic transformation (9.7 pct). Carbon partitioning during martensitic and bainitic transformations increased the stability of retained austenite.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:33:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:33:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 44A(13)5653-5664</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1543-1940</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-013-1929-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14756</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>