<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-244</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>CIPP based characterization of VBR traffic and related statistical multiplexer performance</dc:title><dc:creator>MANIVASAKAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARANDIKAR, ABHAY</dc:creator><dc:subject>poisson distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>correlation methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>packet switching</dc:subject><dc:subject>queueing theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication traffic</dc:subject><dc:subject>visual communication</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we propose a new traffic model (with correlations in interarrivals), herein referred to as correlated interarrival time Poisson process (CIPP), for modeling the VBR video traffic. The CTPP-a generalization of the Poisson process with stationary increments-is parameterized by a correlation parameter `ρ' which represents the degree of correlation in adjacent interarrivals in addition to `λ' the intensity of the process. We present the theory for the CTPP/M/1 queue and derive the corresponding expressions for queueing performance measures of interest. We undertake the performance modeling of a statistical multiplexer with VBR video traffic input using the CIPP/M1 queue. The simulation results show that the CIPP/M1 queue approximates well the queueing situation as encountered by the VBR traffic in broadband networks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-10T04:57:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T06:42:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-10T04:57:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T06:42:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Global Telecommunications Conference (V 1A), Rio de Janeireo, Brazil, 12 May-12 September 1999, 194-198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-5796-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/GLOCOM.1999.831634</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/244</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/244</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>