<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1180</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pressure drop characteristics in a rotating smooth square channel with a sharp 180° bend</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDULA, RP</dc:creator><dc:subject>reynolds number</dc:subject><dc:subject>gas turbines</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure drop</dc:subject><dc:subject>cooling</dc:subject><dc:description>The results of an experimental study to investigate the local pressure drop characteristics in a square cross-sectioned smooth channel with a sharp 180° bend rotating about an axis normal to the free-stream direction are reported here. The sharp 180° turn was obtained by dividing a rectangular passage into two channels using a divider wall with a rounded tip at the location where the flow negotiates the turn. The study was carried out for three ratios of divider wall thickness to hydraulic diameter (W/D), namely, 0.24, 0.37 and 0.73 all with a rounded tip divider wall and only for a bend with a W/D ratio of 0.37, the influence of a sharp tip divider wall was studied. Experiments were conducted for a Reynolds number varying from 10 000 to 17 000 with the rotation number (ωD/V) varying from 0 to 0.38. The pressure drop distribution, normalized with the mainstream fluid dynamic pressure head, is presented for the leading, trailing and the outer surfaces. The results indicate that the local pressure drop characteristics in the bend region are significantly affected by a change in the rotation number but the influence of the Reynolds number is weak. The friction factor is less sensitive to rotation for the bend with a W/D ratio of 0.24 when compared to bends with W/D ratios of 0.37 and 0.73. Friction factor correlations are presented which fit the experimental data within 10% for the range of parameters studied.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-21T14:08:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:03:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-21T14:08:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:03:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Experimental Thermal and Fluid Science 21(4), 198-205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0894-1777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0894-1777(00)00003-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1180</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1180</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>