<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14638</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:05:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Rhodanine Derivative CCR-11 Inhibits Bacterial Proliferation by Inhibiting the Assembly and GTPase Activity of FtsZ</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>JINDAL, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUROLIA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>CELL-DIVISION PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYTOKINESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>RING</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUANTITATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TARGET</dc:subject><dc:description>A perturbation of FtsZ assembly dynamics has been shown to inhibit bacterial cytokinesis. In this study, the antibacterial activity of 151 rhodanine compounds was assayed using Bacillus subtilis cells. Of 151 compounds, eight strongly inhibited bacterial proliferation at 2 mu M. Subsequently, we used the elongation of B. subtilis cells as a secondary screen to identify potential FtsZ-targeted antibacterial agents. We found that three compounds significantly increased bacterial cell length. One of the three compounds, namely, CCR-11 [(E)-2-thioxo-5-({[3-(trifluoromethyl)phenyl]furan-2-yl}methylene)thiazolidin-4-one], inhibited the assembly and GTPase activity of FtsZ in vitro. CCR-11 bound to FtsZ with a dissociation constant of 1.5 +/- 0.3 mu M. A docking analysis indicated that CCR-11 may bind to FtsZ in a cavity adjacent to the T7 loop and that short halogen oxygen, H-bonding, and hydrophobic interactions might be important for the binding of CCR-11 with FtsZ. CCR-11 inhibited the proliferation of B. subtilis cells with a half-maximal inhibitory concentration (IC50) of 1.2 +/- 0.2 mu M and a minimal inhibitory concentration of 3 mu M. It also potently inhibited proliferation of Mycobacterium smegmatis cells. Further, CCR-11 perturbed Z-ring formation in B. subtilis cells; however, it neither visibly affected nucleoid segregation nor altered the membrane integrity of the cells. CCR-11 inhibited HeLa cell proliferation with an IC50 value of 18.1 +/- 0.2,mu M (similar to 15 x IC50 of B. subtilis cell proliferation). The results suggested that CCR-11 inhibits bacterial cytokinesis by inhibiting FtsZ assembly, and it can be used as a lead molecule to develop FtsZ-targeted antibacterial agents.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:05:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:05:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHEMISTRY, 51(27)5434-5442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/bi201813u</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14638</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>