<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15338</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:29:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>External field characterization using CHAMP satellite data for induction studies</dc:title><dc:creator>KUNAGU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHAR, E</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHAMP satellite data</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetosphere</dc:subject><dc:subject>external field characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>EM induction response</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERIOD GEOMAGNETIC-VARIATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MANTLE BENEATH EUROPE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROMAGNETIC INDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-FIELDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EARTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESPONSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CURRENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGION</dc:subject><dc:description>Knowledge of external inducing source field morphology is essential for precise estimation of electromagnetic (EM) induction response. A better characterization of the external source field of magnetospheric origin can be achieved by decomposing it into outer and inner magnetospheric contributions, which are best represented in Geocentric Solar Magnetospheric (GSM) and Solar Magnetic (SM) reference frames, respectively. Thus we propose a spherical harmonic (SH) model to estimate the outer magnetospheric contribution, following the iterative reweighted least squares approach, using the vector magnetic data of the CHAMP satellite. The data covers almost a complete solar cycle from July 2001 to September 2010, spanning 54,474 orbits. The SH model, developed using orbit-averaged vector magnetic data, reveals the existence of a stable outer magnetospheric contribution of about 7.39 nT. This stable field was removed from the CHAMP data after transforming to SM frame. The residual field in the SM frame acts as a primary source for induction in the Earth. The analysis of this time-series using wavelet transformation showed a dominant 27-day periodicity of the geomagnetic field. Therefore, we calculated the inductive EM C-response function in a least squares sense considering the 27-day period variation as the inducing signal. From the estimated C-response, we have determined that the global depth to the perfect substitute conductor is about 1132 km and its conductivity is around 1.05 S/m.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:29:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:29:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 122(3)651-660</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15338</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>