<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14703</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:38:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ground-state energy trends in single and multilayered coupled InAs/GaAs quantum dots capped with InGaAs layers: Effects of InGaAs layer thickness and annealing temperature</dc:title><dc:creator>SHAH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>JEJURIKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Nanostructures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crystal growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERBAND-TRANSITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPENDENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAP</dc:subject><dc:description>Vertically coupled, multilayered InAs/GaAs quantum dots (QDs) covered with thin InGaAs strain-reducing layers (SRLs) are in demand for various technological applications. We investigated low temperature photoluminescence of single and multilayered structures in which the SRL thickness was varied. The SRL layer was responsible for high activation energies. Deviation of experimental data from ;the Varshni (1967) model, E(T) = E - infinity T-2/T + beta, suggests that the InAs-layered QDs have properties different from those in bulk material. Anomalous ground-state peak linewidths (FWHM), especially for annealed multilayer structures, were observed. A ground-state peak blue-shift with a broadened linewidth was also observed. Loss of intensity was detected in samples annealed at 800 degrees C. Presence of SRLs prevents formation of non-radiative centers under high temperature annealing. The results indicate the potential importance of such structures in optoelectronic applications. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:38:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:38:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS RESEARCH BULLETIN, 48(8)2933-2939</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2013.04.028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14703</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>