<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14295</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T09:32:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nanoweb anodes composed of one-dimensional, high aspect ratio, size tunable electrospun ZnFe(2)O(4) nanofibers for lithium ion batteries</dc:title><dc:creator>TEH, PF</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAMANA, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASAN, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLE-SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO3O4</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONVERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC</dc:subject><dc:description>Nanowebs consisting of interwoven ZnFe(2)O(4) nanofibers are synthesized by a simple electrospinning technique, to be employed as an environmentally friendly anode in lithium ion batteries. Effect of precursor viscosity on the growth mechanism of electrospun ZnFe(2)O(4) nanofibers (ZFO-NF) and ZnFe(2)O(4) nanorods (ZFO-NR) is studied by microscopy and diffraction techniques. Structural characterization by powder X-ray diffraction, FESEM and HRTEM studies evaluates the single phase nature of ZnFe(2)O(4), which consists of 11(3) nm nanocrystals that self-agglomerate to form nanofibers after thermal treatment. FESEM micrographs depict the self-assembly of electrospun ZnFe(2)O(4) nanofibers into intertwined porous nanowebs with a continuous framework. Benefitting from the one-dimensional functional nanostructured architecture, the application of electrospun nanowebs with ZnFe(2)O(4) nanofiber (ZFO-NF) anodes in lithium ion batteries exhibits excellent cyclability and retains a reversible capacity of 733(10) mAh g(-1) up to 30 cycles at 60 mA g(-1) as compared to ZnFe(2)O(4) nanorods (ZFO-NR) with a capacity of similar to 200 mAh g(-1). In addition, the importance of providing electronic wiring during lithiation/delithiation, especially in prolonged cycling, is emphasized.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:32:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:32:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY,21(38)14999-15008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-9428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c1jm12088c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14295</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>