<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18264</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:34:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Business Process Model for Deriving CIM Profile: A Case Study for Indian Utility</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRAMOHAN, LS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOOLLA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:subject>Business process modeling notation (BPMN)</dc:subject><dc:subject>common information model (CIM)</dc:subject><dc:subject>day-ahead market (DAM)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indian distribution utility</dc:subject><dc:description>Common information model (CIM) in vogue represents transmission and distribution components, and market operations in the perspective of electrical system, as unified modeling language (UML) objects. UML is object centric. CIM can offer interoperability and facilitate model exchange for large systems and is being adopted by many utilities. However, dealing effectively with multiple business processes is the backbone of the restructured power systems. Since CIM lacks chronological process sense, this has to be superimposed on CIM models, which is not easy due to inherent limitations of UML. To overcome this, this paper proposes to utilize business process modeling notation (BPMN) standards as a kind of pre-processor. BPMN is used to represent process centric interoperability requirements as business objects. UML object representation in CIM model is derived subsequently from it. The proposal is illustrated with an application use case-deriving CIM model of day-ahead market (DAM) transaction of distribution company, from its business process representation. Semantic model of DAM transaction using CIM IEC 62325 (Markets) and extensions required are presented with a sample Indian system. DAM models in BPMN and CIM can be utilized to build an efficient software application.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:34:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:34:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER SYSTEMS, 30(1)132-141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8950</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-0679</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPWRS.2014.2324826</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18264</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>