<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14047</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:33:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Higher order shear deformation effects on analysis of laminates with piezoelectric fibre reinforced composite actuators</dc:title><dc:creator>SHIYEKAR, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>STATIC ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMIC-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FINITE-ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>REFINED THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Higher order theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Piezoelectric fiber reinforced composites (PFRC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laminates</dc:subject><dc:description>A complete analytical solution for cross-ply composite laminates integrated with piezoelectric fiber-reinforced composite (PFRC) actuators under bi-directional bending is presented in this paper. A higher order shear and normal deformation theory (HOSNT12) is used to analyze such hybrid or smart laminates subjected to electromechanical loading. The displacement function of the present model is approximated by employing Taylor's series in the thickness coordinate, while the electro-static potential is assumed to be layer wise (LW) linear through the thickness of PFRC. The equations of equilibrium are obtained using principle of minimum potential energy and solution is by Navier's technique. Transverse shear stresses are presented at the interface of PFRC actuator and laminate under the action of electrostatic potentials. Results are compared with first order shear deformation theory (FOST) and exact solution. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:33:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:33:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPOSITE STRUCTURES,93(12)3252-3261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compstruct.2011.05.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14047</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>