<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16094</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:42:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Reduced-Order Model and Stability Analysis of Low-Voltage DC Microgrid</dc:title><dc:creator>ANAND, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>DC microgrid</dc:subject><dc:subject>droop controller</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISTRIBUTED POWER-SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTROL STRATEGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARALLEL OPERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INVERTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPEDANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOADS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AC</dc:subject><dc:description>Depleting fossil fuels, increasing energy demand, and need for high-reliability power supply motivate the use of dc microgrids. This paper analyzes the stability of low-voltage dc microgrid systems. Sources are controlled using a droop-based decentralized controller. Various components of the system have been modeled. A linearized system model is derived using small-signal approximation. The stability of the system is analyzed by identifying the eigenvalues of the system matrix. The sufficiency condition for stable operation of the system is derived. It provides upper bound on droop constants and is useful during planning and designing of dc microgrids. Furthermore, the sensitivity of system poles to variation in cable resistance and inductance is identified. It is proved that the poles move further inside the negative real plane with a decrease in inductance or an increase in resistance. The method proposed in this paper is applicable to any interconnecting structure of sources and loads. The results obtained by analysis are verified by detailed simulation study. Root locus plots are included to confirm the movement of system poles. The viability of the model is confirmed by experimental results from a scaled-down laboratory prototype of a dc microgrid developed for the purpose.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:41:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:41:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS, 60(11)5040-5049</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0278-0046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIE.2012.2227902</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16094</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>