<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9885</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of process for thermo-mechanical treatment of ultrahigh strength steel prepared by electroslag refining</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITY, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALLAL, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAWALLA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>mechanical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>inoculation</dc:subject><dc:subject>prediction</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>electroslag refining</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermomechanical treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>ultrahigh strength steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>ttt and cct diagram</dc:subject><dc:subject>rolling parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructures</dc:subject><dc:description>Thermomechanical treatment (TMT) is the simultaneous use of work hardening, and grain refinement along with solid solution and precipitation strengthening. In this investigation, four alloys, with a base composition of 2 center dot 8%C, 1.0%Mn, 4 center dot 2%Cr, 1 center dot 0%Mo, 0 center dot 34%V, were prepared by electroslag refining (ESR) and by addition of small amounts of Ti and Nb and by increasing Cr and V to 4 center dot 8 and 0 center dot 48% respectively. In two of the alloys a yield strength in excess of 1550 Wa was obtained in the as cast quenched and tempered condition. Attempts were made to further increase the yield strength by thermomechanical treatment. The process parameters for thermomechanical treatment were optimised by adopting procedures such as calculation of stability of precipitates, hot compression test, determination of cooling rates in different coolants, and modelling of TTT and CCT diagrams. The process involved prerolling of the ESR ingot to a bar at 1200 degrees C, followed by hot rolling in two passes starting from 950 degrees C and finishing at 850 degrees C with equal deformation of 25% in each pass to convert the bar into plates. These were immediately cooled in one of the cooling media: air, polymer-water solution (1 : 1 center dot 5) and oil. Yield strength in excess of 1750 Wa was obtained in oil cooled specimens of the alloy with titanium addition and that where Cr and V were increased. The niobium added specimen gave strengths, similar to that obtained for the base alloy, in spite of the fact that the as cast alloy had shown very high strengths, presumably because of the high soaking temperatures and grain growth. Air cooling gave the lowest strengths and oil cooling the highest.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MANEY PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T13:45:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T13:45:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IRONMAKING &amp; STEELMAKING, 34(4), 332-342</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-9233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1179/174328107X168156</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9885</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>