<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13946</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:16:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>A correlation between Schmidt hammer rebound numbers with impact strength index, slake durability index and P-wave velocity</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANDELWAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:subject>UNIAXIAL COMPRESSIVE STRENGTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROCK</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schmidt hammer rebound number</dc:subject><dc:subject>Impact strength index</dc:subject><dc:subject>Slake durability index</dc:subject><dc:subject>P-wave velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>t test</dc:subject><dc:description>The main objective of this study was to establish statistical relationship between Schmidt hammer rebound numbers with impact strength index (ISI), slake durability index (SDI) and P-wave velocity. These are important properties to characterize a rock mass and are being widely used in geological and geotechnical engineering. Due to its importance, Schmidt hammer rebound number is considered as one of the most important property for the determination of other properties, like ISI, SDI and P-wave velocity. Determination of these properties in the laboratory is time consuming and tedious as well as requiring expertise, whereas Schmidt hammer rebound number can be easily obtained on site which in addition is non-destructive. So, in this study, an attempt has been made to determine these index properties in the laboratory and each index property was correlated with Schmidt hammer rebound values. Empirical equations have been developed to predict ISI, SDI and P-wave velocity using rebound values. It was found that Schmidt hammer rebound number shows linear relation with ISI and SDI, whereas exponential relation with P-wave velocity. To check the sensitivity of empirical relations, Student's t test was done to verify the correlation between rebound values and other rock index properties.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:16:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:16:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES,100(1)189-195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1437-3254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00531-009-0506-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13946</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>