<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3032</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Noncovalent synthesis of hierarchical zinc phosphates from a single zn(4)o(12)p(4) double-four-ring building block: dimensionality control through the choice of auxiliary ligands</dc:title><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUPPUSWAMY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOGOI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOOMISHANKAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>STEINER, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>extended structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen bonds</dc:subject><dc:subject>noncovalent interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>supramolecular chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>zinc</dc:subject><dc:subject>tert-butyl phosphate</dc:subject><dc:subject>source molecular precursors</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>di(tert-butyl)phosphate complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural-characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal phosphonate</dc:subject><dc:subject>ancillary ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>gallium</dc:subject><dc:subject>di</dc:subject><dc:description>In contrast to the well-known reaction of phosphonic acids RP(O)(OH)(2) with divalent transition-metal ions that yields layered metal phosphonates [RPO(3)M(H(2)O)](n), the 2,6-diisopropylphenyl ester of phosphoric acid, dippH(2), reacts with zinc acetate in methanol under ambient conditions to afford tetrameric zinc phosphate [(ArO)PO(3)Zn(MeOH)](4) (1). The coordinated methanol in 1 can be readily exchanged by stronger Lewis basic ligands at room temperature. This strategy opens up a new avenue for building double-four-ring (D4R) cubane-based supramolecular assemblies through strong intercubane hydrogen-bonding interactions. Seventeen pyridinic ligands have been used to synthesize as many D4R cubanes [(ArO)PO(3)Zn(L)](4) (2-18) from 1. The ligands have been chosen in such a way that the majority of them contain an additional functional group that could be used for noncovalent synthesis of extended structures. When the ligand does not contain any other hydrogen-bonding donor-acceptor sites (e.g., 2,4,6-trimethylpyridine (collidine)), zero-dimensional D4R cubanes have been obtained. The use of pyridine, lutidine, 2-aminopyridine, and 2,6-diaminopyridine, however, results in the formation of linear or zigzag one-dimensional assemblies of D4R cubanes through strong intermolecular C-H center dot center dot center dot O or N-H center dot center dot center dot O interactions. Construction of two-dimensional assemblies of zinc phosphates has been achieved by employing 2-hydroxypyridine or 2-methylimidazole as the exo-cubane ligand on zinc centers. The introduction of an alcohol side chain on the pyridinic ligand in such a way that the -CH(2)OH group cannot participate in intracubane hydrogen bonding (e.g., pyridine-3-methanol, pyridine-4-methanol, and 3,5-dimethylpyrazole-N-ethanol) leads to the facile noncovalent synthesis of three-dimensional framework structures. Apart from being useful as building blocks for noncovalent synthesis of zeolite-like materials, compounds 1-18 can also be thermolyzed at approximately 500 degrees C to yield high-purity zinc pyrophosphate (Zn(2)P(2)O(7)) ceramic material.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-12T14:05:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-12T14:05:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL,16(3)994-1009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-6539</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/chem.200901994</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13794</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3032</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>