<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18429</identifier><datestamp>2016-04-29T14:27:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>A unified approach to choice experiments</dc:title><dc:creator>Das, Ashish</dc:creator><dc:creator>Singh, Rakhi</dc:creator><dc:subject>Choice set</dc:subject><dc:subject>Information Matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>Linear Model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multinomial logit model</dc:subject><dc:description>Choice experiments have practical significance from the industry point of view and are useful in marketing, transport, government planning, etc. Several author-groups have contributed to the theoretical development of choice experiments and for finding optimal choice designs. The author-groups Street-Burgess and Huber-Zwerina have adopted different approaches and used seemingly different information matrices under the multinomial logit model. There have also been some confusion regarding the inference parameters expressed as linear functions of the option effects $\tau$. We discuss these aspects and highlight how these approaches are related to one another.
Recently, Sun and Dean (2016) have advocated an information matrix for orthonormal contrasts $B_0\tau$, adopting a linear model approach, which is different from the standard information matrix used in the literature for choice experiments under the multinomial logit model. We study their information matrix vis-a-vis the traditional information matrix and find some lacunae in their approach. We provide an alternate linear model approach to model choice experiments such that the information matrix of $B_0\tau$ is same as the information matrix under the multinomial logit model.</dc:description><dc:date>2016-04-29T14:27:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-04-29T14:27:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-04-29</dc:date><dc:type>Technical Report</dc:type><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18429</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>