<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18062</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:34:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>A comprehensive framework of brand name classification</dc:title><dc:creator>ARORA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALRO, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>PHONETIC SYMBOLISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSIGHTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOUND</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREFERENCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCIENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>brand name classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>invented brand names</dc:subject><dc:subject>sound symbolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>content analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>linguistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>non-word names</dc:subject><dc:description>Research on brand naming has recently taken center stage in marketing literature. This study formulates a comprehensive classification of brand names that incorporates frameworks from existing literature and current naming methods used by practitioners. A content analysis of the top 500 global brand names based on manifest content, across 11 product categories, was conducted to understand the current brand-naming trends. The results confirm extensive use of the promoter's name and place of origin (39.7 per cent of all brand names coded), compounding (34.1 per cent), abbreviations (18.2 per cent) and blending (7.9 per cent). Category-wise analysis indicates that certain categories, such as durables, follow the aggregate pattern of 61.5 per cent semantic word names, 53.0 per cent invented word names and 23.6 per cent non-word names. FMCG brands, on the other hand, show differing patterns because of disproportionately low abbreviations in the distribution. Further,. 2 tests using equal expected frequencies of the three dimensions; semantic, invented and non-word names, showed that there appears to be significant differences in frequency between these dimensions. Practitioners may consider using these newly defined categories, such as semantically related acronyms, in creating distinctive brand names. This study also analyzes the use of sound symbolic names for brands.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PALGRAVE MACMILLAN LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:34:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:34:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BRAND MANAGEMENT, 22(2)79-116</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-231X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1479-1803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1057/bm.2015.8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18062</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>