<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8680</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>On the optical and electrical properties of rf and a.c. plasma polymerized aniline thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>SAJEEV, US</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHAI, CJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAVANAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASHOKAN, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATACHALAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHARAMAN, MR</dc:creator><dc:subject>conducting polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasma polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical band gap</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyaniline</dc:subject><dc:subject>a.c. and rf plasma polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>doped polyaniline</dc:subject><dc:description>Polyaniline is a widely studied conducting polymer and is a useful material in its bulk and thin film form for many applications, because of its excellent optical and electrical properties. Pristine and iodine doped polyaniline thin films were prepared by a.c. and rf plasma polymerization techniques separately for the comparison of their optical and electrical properties. Doping of iodine was effected in situ. The structural properties of these films were evaluated by FTIR spectroscopy and the optical band gap was estimated from UV-vis-NIR measurements. Comparative studies on the structural, optical and electrical properties of a.c. and rf polymerization are presented here. It has been found that the optical band gap of the polyaniline thin films prepared by rf and a.c. plasma polymerization techniques differ considerably and the band gap is further reduced by in situ doping of iodine. The electrical conductivity measurements on these films show a higher value of electrical conductivity in the case of rf plasma polymerized thin films when compared to the a.c. plasma polymerized films. Also, it is found that the iodine doping enhanced conductivity of the polymer thin films considerably. The results are compared and correlated and have been explained with respect to the different structures adopted under these two preparation techniques.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 29(2), 159-163</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-4707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02704609</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8680</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8680</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>