<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-363</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>A simple wind driven self-excited induction generator with regulated output voltage</dc:title><dc:creator>WEKHANDE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, VIVEK</dc:creator><dc:subject>dc-ac power convertor</dc:subject><dc:subject>pwm invertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>asynchronous generators</dc:subject><dc:subject>closed loop system</dc:subject><dc:description>Induction generators are widely used in nonconventional power generation. Self-excited, squirrel cage induction generators are ideally suited for remote, stand-alone applications due to their robust construction. A new closed loop IGBT based PWM controller is proposed for a self-excited induction generator. The proposed controller regulates the excitation current of the induction generator to regulate the generated three phase voltage. The terminal voltage is regulated in spite of varying rotor speed and different load conditions. The proposed scheme does not require any real time computation for generating reference currents. This low cost high performance controller is suitable for constant voltage variable frequency loads. The digital simulation results show satisfactory operation of induction generators under the proposed control scheme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-17T08:00:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T12:55:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-17T08:00:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T12:55:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 21st International Telecommunications Energy Conference, Copenhagen, Denmark, 6-9 June 1999, 19/1-19/6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-5624-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/INTLEC.1999.794094</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/363</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>