<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10336</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Compatibilization of polypropylene and polybutylene terephthalate blends using reactive extrusion: Mechanical properties, morphological and rheological studies</dc:title><dc:creator>JAIN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>in-situ compatibilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>poly(butylene terephthalate)</dc:subject><dc:subject>glycidyl methacrylate</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactive extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>compatibilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>pp/pbt blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>rheology</dc:subject><dc:description>Reactively compatibilized blends of PP and PBT were investigated over a range of composition of PP and PBT using a GMA grafted PP (PP-g-GMA) component as a compatibilizing agent. The PP-g-GMA (gPP) was prepared by melt functionalization of PP with GMA in a twin-screw extruder. The PP-g-GMA was found to be miscible with PP and PBT due to potential reactivity of the epoxy group of GMA and carboxyl and hydroxyl endgroups of PBT during melt processing. The effect of level of PP-g-GMA and blend composition on the mechanical, morphological and rheological behaviour of the blends was explored. The impact strength, tensile strength and elongation at break of the blends were found to be strongly influenced by the amount of functionalized PP incorporated in the blends. Morphological studies by scanning electron microscopy reveal the presence of a two-phase morphology and a reduction in domain size with an increase in the level of compatibilizer in the blend. Compatibilized blends exhibit a higher viscosity at a low shear rate range and a narrower particle size distribution with an increase in the level of compatibilizer in the blend. The compatibilizing efficiency of PP-g-GMA can be attributed to the formation of PP-g-PBT copolymer at the interface that results in a stronger interfacial adhesion thereby reducing the interfacial tension and improving the interfacial thickness. These desired copolymers are able to reside at the interface and serve as efficient compatibilizer for this system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>OXFORD &amp; IBH PUBL CO PVT LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T11:28:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T11:28:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF POLYMER MATERIALS, 18(4), 341-353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0970-0838</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10336</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10336</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>