<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17680</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T14:03:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>An experimental and numerical investigation of heat transfer distribution of perforated plate burner flames impinging on a flat plate</dc:title><dc:creator>HINDASAGERI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNTIKANA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDULA, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>JETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Perforated plate burner</dc:subject><dc:subject>Local heat flux</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methane-air</dc:subject><dc:subject>Infrared thermography</dc:subject><dc:description>Heat transfer from perforated plate burner flame impinging on a flat plate finds importance in industrial (gas fired boiler) and domestic heating (household gas burner and commercial hotel gas burners) applications. A limited study on heat transfer distribution of this kind of burner plate is found in the literature. in the present work, high resolution heat flux is estimated by the inverse heat conduction (IHCP) technique based on use of analytical solution for semi-infinite medium for the impingement plate. Inline, star and staggered holes patterns with three different inter-hole distances (pitch) are considered in the present study. Methane air premixed flame of Reynolds number varying from 50 to 600 and an equivalence ratio varying from 0.6 to 1.2 is considered. The hole to impingement plate distance is varied from 3 to 7. From the experimental results, it is found that the inline and staggered patterns have the same heat flux averaged over an area of 50 mm x 50 mm for different Reynolds number. The intermediate pitch of 7 mm is the optimal pitch over the entire mixture flow range considered in the present study. The specific fuel consumption for the star pattern is less by 40-60% as compared with the inline pattern for p/d = 1.67, Re = 50-300 and z/d = 3-7. A numerical simulation is carried out using CFD software to explain the shift in the peak heat flux away from the geometric intended location. (C) 2015 Elsevier Masson SAS. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER FRANCE-EDITIONS SCIENTIFIQUES MEDICALES ELSEVIER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:03:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:03:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF THERMAL SCIENCES, 94,156-169</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1290-0729</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1778-4166</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2015.02.021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17680</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>