<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16003</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:55:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of different interpolation operators including nonlinear subdivision schemes in the simulation of particle trajectories</dc:title><dc:creator>BENSIALI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BODI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>CIRAOLO, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHENDRIH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIANDRAT, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>Interpolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subdivision schemes</dc:subject><dc:subject>PPH</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gibbs phenomenon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Edge plasma</dc:subject><dc:subject>Density structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Test particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROSTATIC TURBULENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, we compare different interpolation operators in the context of particle tracking with an emphasis on situations involving velocity field with steep gradients. Since, in this case, most classical methods give rise to the Gibbs phenomenon (generation of oscillations near discontinuities), we present new methods for particle tracking based on subdivision schemes and especially on the Piecewise Parabolic Harmonic (PPH) scheme which has shown its advantage in image processing in presence of strong contrasts. First an analytic univariate case with a discontinuous velocity field is considered in order to highlight the effect of the Gibbs phenomenon on trajectory calculation. Theoretical results are provided. Then, we show, regardless of the interpolation method, the need to use a conservative approach when integrating a conservative problem with a velocity field deriving from a potential. Finally, the PPH scheme is applied in a more realistic case of a time-dependent potential encountered in the edge turbulence of magnetically confined plasmas, to compare the propagation of density structures (turbulence bursts) with the dynamics of test particles. This study highlights the difference between particle transport and density transport in turbulent fields. (C) 2012 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:55:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:55:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COMPUTATIONAL PHYSICS, 236346-366</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcp.2012.11.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16003</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>