<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3918</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intramolecularly coordinated low-valent organotellurium complexes derived from 1-(dimethylamino) naphthalene</dc:title><dc:creator>MENON, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>JASINSKI, JM</dc:creator><dc:creator>JASINSKI, JP</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTCHER, RJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>molecular-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>chelate ring</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray</dc:subject><dc:subject>ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>pentacoordinate</dc:subject><dc:subject>telluride</dc:subject><dc:subject>derivatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>ditelluride</dc:subject><dc:subject>tribromide</dc:subject><dc:description>A series of low-valent intramolecularly coordinated organotellurium compounds incorporating the 8-(dimethylamino)-1-naphthyl group has been synthesized by the organolithium route. Insertion of elemental tellurium into the Li-C bond of RLi (2) affords the tellurolate RTeLi (3) (R = 8-(dimethylamino)-1-naphthyl). Oxidative workup of 3 gives dark red ditelluride 4 in moderate yield. Reaction of 2 with ''PhTeBr'' afforded telluride 5. Interestingly, the reaction of 2 with TeI2 afforded the stable tellurenyl iodide 6 instead of the expected telluride R(2)Te. Controlled bromination of ditelluride with bromine in chloroform gave stable tellurenyl bromide 7 whereas bromination with excess bromine leads to the isolation of tellurium(IV) tribromide 8. Ditelluride 4 was found to be inert to the reactions with diazomethane and reducing agents like NaBH4, NaH, and LiAIH(4). The compounds were characterized by elemental analysis, NMR (H-1, C-13, Te-125), and mass spectroscopic techniques. For three of these compounds R(2)Te(2) (4), RTePh (5), and RTeBr (7) the molecular structures in the solid state have been determined by X-ray diffraction studies. All the three complexes which have been structurally characterized have a T-shaped geometry around the central tellurium atom. Though there are weak Te ... N interactions in the solid state, in solution pyramidal inversion at the N-center is not blocked and as a result, the NMe(2) signals are observed as sharp singlets in the H-1 NMR spectra.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T09:20:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T09:20:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANOMETALLICS, 15(6), 1707-1712</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0276-7333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/om950841s</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3918</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3918</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>