<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15144</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:23:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>STABILITY ANALYSIS OF A SHALLOW DEPTH METRO TUNNEL: A NUMERICAL APPROACH</dc:title><dc:creator>MONJEZI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAHMANI, BN</dc:creator><dc:creator>TORABI, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Numerical modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil nailing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shield tunnelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Subsidence</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, an attempt has been made to use numerical modelling for simulating a long halt in construction process at a shallow depth metro tunnel and investigate the effects of soil nailing to increase the tunnel face strength. Finite difference software FLAC with high applicability in a continuum environment was adopted for this study. The tunnel is being excavated for Tehran metro project. Shield tunnelling with roadheader and back hoe cutting tools is applied in the excavation process. Mohr-Coulomb elasto-plastic constitutive law is considered to model the ground. After two months halting in excavation process, tunnel instability and ground subsidence were recorded in thirteen different monitoring points. Numerical simulation results showed a close approximation (11-16%) between measured and FLAC computed displacements of the tunnel crown in case of unsupported face, which is in close proximity and a proof indicates the reliability of simulation. Also, simulation results exhibit a significant reduction in the ground subsidence and tunnel instability in case of supported face by means of the soil nailing.</dc:description><dc:publisher>POLISH ACAD SCIENCES, STRATA MECHANICS RES INST</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:23:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:23:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ARCHIVES OF MINING SCIENCES, 57(3)535-545</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/v10267-012-0035-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15144</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>