<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17489</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:24:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Thermomechanical Treatment on the Environmentally Induced Cracking Behavior of AA7075 Alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENUGOPAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANKARAVELAYUDHAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GEORGE, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>STRESS-CORROSION CRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINUM-ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON-MICROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TREATMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>7075-T6</dc:subject><dc:subject>AA7075</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress corrosion cracking (SCC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermomechanical treatment</dc:subject><dc:description>The influence of thermomechanical treatment on the stress corrosion cracking behavior of AA7075 aluminum alloy forgings was examined in 3.5% NaCl solution by varying the extent of thermomechanical working imparted to each of the conditions. The results show that inadequate working during billet processing resulted in inferior corrosion and mechanical properties. However, more working with intermediate pre-heating stages also led to precipitation of coarse particles resulting in lowering of mechanical properties marginally and a significant reduction in the general/pitting corrosion resistance. The results obtained in the present study indicate that optimum working with controlled pre-heating levels is needed during forging to achieve the desired properties. It is also demonstrated that AA7075 in the over aged condition does not show any environmental cracking susceptibility in spite of the microstructural variations in terms of size and volume fraction of the precipitates. However, the above microstructural variations definitely affected the pitting corrosion and mechanical properties significantly and hence a strict control over the working and pre-heating stages during billet processing is suggested.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:24:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:24:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS ENGINEERING AND PERFORMANCE, 24(2)545-555</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1059-9495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1544-1024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11665-014-1311-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17489</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>