<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10197</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Laser Surface Treatment for Enhancing Intergranular Corrosion Resistance of AISI Type 304 Stainless Steel</dc:title><dc:creator>KAUL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAIN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANESH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>NATH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, RC</dc:creator><dc:subject>austenitic stainless-steels</dc:subject><dc:subject>boundary-character-distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitization</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactivation</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>cracking</dc:subject><dc:subject>304l</dc:subject><dc:subject>intergranular corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>laser surface treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitization</dc:subject><dc:subject>stainless steel</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel laser surface modification approach to suppress sensitization in AISI 304 (UNS S30400) austenitic stainless steel is described. Surface modification of austenitic stainless steel was carried out with a 10-kW carbon dioxide (CO2) laser in both continuous wave and pulse-modulated modes. After laser surface modification, the material was subjected to a sensitization heat treatment at 923 K for 9 h. The degree of sitization was determined by electrochemical potentiokinetic reactivation test while the susceptibility to intergranular corrosion was determined using the ASTM A262, practice B test. The results of the study demonstrated that the laser-melted surface exhibited significantly higher resistance against sensitization and intergranular corrosion than the base metal. The laser-melted surface, even after being subjected to severe sensitization heat treatment, developed comparable or even a lower degree of sensitization than the base metal in the asreceived condition. Enhanced immunity against sensitization of the laser-treated surface is attributed to its duplex microstructure and higher fraction of low-angle grain boundaries. The highlight of the investigation was that a laser surface melting treatment of unstabilized austenitic stainless steel brings about significant reduction in its Susceptibility to sensitization during subsequent exposure to a susceptible temperature region and to intergranular corrosion during service.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ASSOC CORROSION ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T02:37:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T02:37:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CORROSION, 64(10), 755-763</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0010-9312</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10197</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>