<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11960</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Competitive algorithms for layered graph traversal</dc:title><dc:creator>FIAT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>FOSTER, DP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARLOFF, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>RABANI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVID, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISHWANATHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>online algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>server</dc:subject><dc:subject>competitive analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>layered graphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>search strategies</dc:subject><dc:description>A layered graph is a connected graph whose vertices are partitioned into sets L-0 = {s}, L-1; L-2,..., and whose edges, which have nonnegative integral weights, run between consecutive layers. Its width is max{\L-i\}. In the on-line layered graph traversal problem, a searcher starts at s in a layered graph of unknown width and tries to reach a target vertex t; however, the vertices in layer i and the edges between layers i ? 1 and i are only revealed when the searcher reaches layer i ? 1. We give upper and lower bounds on the competitive ratio of layered graph traversal algorithms. We give a deterministic on-line algorithm which is O(9(w))-competitive on width-w graphs and prove that for no w can a deterministic on-line algorithm have a competitive ratio better than 2(w?2) on width-w graphs. We prove that for all w, w/2 is a lower bound on the competitive ratio of any randomized on-line layered graph traversal algorithm. For traversing layered graphs consisting of w disjoint paths tied together at a common source, we give a randomized on-line algorithm with a competitive ratio of O(log w) and prove that this is optimal up to a constant factor.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SIAM PUBLICATIONS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T04:41:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T04:41:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SIAM JOURNAL ON COMPUTING, 28(2), 448-463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0097-5397</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11960</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11960</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>