<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6296</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T04:59:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Large Igneous Provinces (LIPs)': Definition, recommended terminology, and a hierarchical classification</dc:title><dc:creator>SHETH, HC</dc:creator><dc:subject>deccan volcanic province</dc:subject><dc:subject>flood basalts</dc:subject><dc:subject>cenozoic basalts</dc:subject><dc:subject>oceanic-crust</dc:subject><dc:subject>lava flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>emplacement</dc:subject><dc:subject>magmatism</dc:subject><dc:subject>mantle</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>earth</dc:subject><dc:subject>large igneous province</dc:subject><dc:subject>magmatism</dc:subject><dc:subject>volcanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>nomenclature</dc:subject><dc:description>This article is an appeal for the adoption of a correct and appropriate terminology with respect to the so-called Large Igneous Provinces (LIPS). The term LIP has been widely applied to large basaltic provinces such as the Deccan Traps, and the term Silicic Large Igneous Province (SLIP) to volcanic provinces of dominantly felsic composition, such as the Whitsunday Province. However, neither term (LIP, SLIP) has been applied to the large granitic batholiths of the world (e.g., Andes) to which both terms are perfectly applicable. LIP has also not been applied to broad areas of contemporaneous basalt magmatism (e.g., Indochina, Mongolia) and sizeable layered mafic intrusions (e.g., Bushveld) which in many significant respects may also be considered to represent 'Large Igneous Provinces'. Here, I suggest that the term LIP is used in its broadest sense and that it should designate igneous provinces with outcrop areas : &gt;= 50,000 km(2). I propose a simple hierarchical classification of LIPS that is independent of composition, tectonic setting, or emplacement mechanism. I suggest that provinces such as the Deccan and Whitsunday provinces should be called Large Volcanic Provinces (LVPs), whereas large intrusive provinces (mafic-ultramafic intrusions, dyke/sill swarms, granitic batholiths) should be called Large Platonic Provinces (LPPs). LVPs and UPS thus together cover all LIPs, which can be felsic, mafic, or ultramafic, of sub-alkalic or alkalic affinity, and emplaced in continental or oceanic settings. LVPs are subdivided here into four groups: (i) the dominantly/wholly mafic Large Basaltic Provinces (LBPs) (e.g., Deccan, Ontong Java); (ii) the dominantly felsic Large Rhyolitic Provinces (LRPs) (e.g., Whitsunday, Sierra Madre Occidental); (iii) the dominantly andesitic Large Andesitic Provinces (LAPs) (e.g., Andes, Indonesia, Cascades), and (iv) the bimodal Large Basaltic-Rhyolitic Provinces (LBRPs) (e.g., Snake River-High Lava Plains). The intrusive equivalents of LRPs are the Large Granitic Provinces (LGPs) (e.g., the Andean batholiths), although an equivalent term for intrusive equivalents of LBPs is not necessary or warranted. The accuracy and usefulness of the termsflood basalt, plateau basalt, and trap are also examined. The largest LBP, LVP, and LIP is, of course, the bulk of the ocean floor. It is contended that the proposed LIP nomenclature and classification will lead to more accurate and precise terminology and hence better understanding of the wide variety of Large Igneous Provinces. (C) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T17:01:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T17:01:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTH-SCIENCE REVIEWS, 85(3-4), 117-124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0012-8252</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2007.07.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6296</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6296</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>