<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1668</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Light-trains: a cross-layer delivery mechanism for high bandwidth applications in moving metro-trains</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHENG, SQ</dc:creator><dc:subject>wireless networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>bandwidth</dc:subject><dc:subject>mass transportation</dc:subject><dc:subject>network protocols</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>time sharing programs</dc:subject><dc:description>Trains as a mass transport system are a strong application case for coarsely granular bandwidth-on-demand networking. Multiple trains time-sharing the same track, traveling at a significant speed and containing a large number of bandwidth savvy users represents a premier motivation for the merger of optical and wireless communications. Wireless delivery methods alone cannot suffice the need for such a large moving mass of bandwidth intensive users. We propose a method to efficiently integrate a wireless network over a flexible optical backbone. The proposed method is built upon the light-trails optical platform and involves a unique control layer that adapts to an overlaid wireless network. Here, we propose a cross-layer protocol that enables seamless communication for these "light-trains". We also show benefits in terms of throughput, end-to-end delay, bandwidth efficiency and scalability of such a scheme through a simulation study.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:58:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:58:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Communications (V 6), Istanbul, Turkey, 11-15 June 2006, 2648-2654</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0355-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICC.2006.255179</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1668</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1668</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>