<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3819</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Emission factors of carbon monoxide and size-resolved aerosols from biofuel combustion</dc:title><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, GUM</dc:creator><dc:subject>polycyclic aromatic-hydrocarbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>cooking devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>air-pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>cookstoves</dc:subject><dc:subject>exposure</dc:subject><dc:subject>efficiencies</dc:subject><dc:subject>countries</dc:subject><dc:description>This study reports emission factors of carbon monoxide and size-resolved aerosols from combustion of wood, dung cake, and biofuel briquette in traditional and improved stoves in India. Wood was the cleanest burning fuel, with higher emissions of CO from dung cake and particulate matter from both dung cake and briquette fuels. Combustion of dung cake, especially in an improved metal stove, resulted in extremely high pollutant emissions. Instead, biogas from anaerobic dung digestion should be promoted as a cooking fuel for public health protection. Pollutant emissions increased with increasing stove thermal efficiency, implying that thermal efficiency enhancement in the improved stoves was mainly from design features leading to increased heat transfer but not combustion efficiency. Compared to the traditional stove, the im proved stoves resulted in the lower pollutant emissions on a kW h(-1) basis from wood combustion but in similar emissions from briquette and dung cake. Stove designs are needed with good emissions performance across multiple fuels. Unimodal aerosol sire distributions were measured from biofuel combustion with mass median aerodynamic diameters of 0.5-0.8 mum, about a factor of 10 larger than those from fossil fuel combustion (e.g. diesel), with potential implications for lung deposition and health risk.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T01:10:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T01:10:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY, 35(10), 2100-2107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-936X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/es001603d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3819</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3819</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>