<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1364</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Frequency selective IR-filter produced by using EB-lithography</dc:title><dc:creator>KATHURIA, YP</dc:creator><dc:subject>transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>lithography</dc:subject><dc:subject>infra-red</dc:subject><dc:subject>cross diplexer</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper reports on the fabrication of Jerusalem cross diplexer by direct write electron beam (EB) lithography followed by reactive ion etching (RIE) on a phosphorus doped polished silicon wafer substrate. Such structures can be used as frequency selective components in visible, microwave and near infra-red wavelength region. Replication of the patterns is accomplished by micron or sub-micron order mould fabricated from the silicon (Si) master. Fourier transform infra-red reflectance (FT-IR) measurements were performed to characterize the structured patterns. The spectral reflectance from these patterns clearly show a reflection dip due to surface plasmon excitation in the near infra-red wavelength at about 1.42 and 2.5 mu m, respectively. Potential applications such as antireflection surface (ARS) can be realized. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:09:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:09:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED SURFACE SCIENCE,253(19)7826-7830</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0169-4332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2007.02.141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14695</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1364</dc:identifier><dc:source>Symposium on Photon-Assisted Synthesis and Processing of Functional Materials held at the 2006 EMRS Spring Meeting,Nice, FRANCE,MAY 29-JUN 02, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>