<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18054</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:30:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Surface defect rich ZnO quantum dots as antioxidants inhibiting alpha-amylase and alpha-glucosidase: a potential anti-diabetic nanomedicine</dc:title><dc:creator>ASOK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MORE, PA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOPADE, BA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, MN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>OXIDATIVE STRESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC-OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISIBLE PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIABETIC COMPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHARGE DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSULIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:description>Preventing chronic hyperglycaemia and associated oxidative stress is utmost important for the treatment and management of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus (T2DM). Here we report the role of different size surface defect rich ZnO quantum dots (D-QDs) for inhibiting metabolic enzymes and scavenging free radicals, which plays a key role in reducing hyperglycaemia and oxidative stress. Quantitative analysis of radical scavenging and metabolic enzyme inhibition activity of D-QDs demonstrates a size dependent behaviour, where D-QDs with a smaller diameter shows superior activity compared to larger size D-QDs. Considering the size dependence in surface defect formation, the increased surface defect density in smaller size D-QDs can be considered as the reason behind this enhancement. Detailed studies establishing the underlying mechanism behind potent free radical scavenging and enzyme inhibition provides an intense scientific rationale for considering D-QDs to design safe and effective nanomedicine for T2DM.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:30:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:30:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY B, 3(22)4597-4606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-750X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7518</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5tb00407a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18054</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>