<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17562</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:01:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spatial and temporal variability of ultrafine particles, NO2, PM2.5, PM2.5 absorbance, PM10 and PMcoarse in Swiss study areas</dc:title><dc:creator>EEFTENS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHULERIA, HC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEIER, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGUILERA, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>CORRADI, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAVEY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUCRET-STICH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>FIERZ, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GEHRIG, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>INEICHEN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEIDEL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>PROBST-HENSCH, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAGETTLI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHINDLER, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNZLI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>TSAI, MY</dc:creator><dc:subject>3 EUROPEAN AREAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPIDEMIOLOGIC EVIDENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NUMBER CONCENTRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIRBORNE PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEALTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPOSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCAPE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CITIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>URBAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAPALDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>NO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>Particulate matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>PM2.5</dc:subject><dc:subject>PM10</dc:subject><dc:subject>Absorbance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coarse particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>PNC</dc:subject><dc:subject>LDSA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Air pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Traffic</dc:subject><dc:description>Exposure to outdoor air pollutants remains an important concern in Europe, as limit values for NO2 and PM10 continue to be exceeded. Few studies have addressed the long-term spatial contrasts in PM2.5, PM absorbance, PM coarse coarse and especially ultrafine particles. This scarcity of data hampers the possibility to conduct epidemiological studies, assessing the health relevance of these markers of potentially harmful pollutants. Air pollution measurements were performed in eight geographically distinct areas of the Swiss Study on Air Pollution and Lung and Heart Diseases in Adults (SAPALDIA) in Switzerland. NO2 was measured in all eight areas at 40 sites per area, and PM2.5, PM2.5 absorbance, PM10 and ultrafine particles (particle number concentration (PNC) and lung deposited surface area (LDSA)) were measured in 4 of these areas, at a subset of 20 out of 40 sites. Each site was sampled three times during different seasons of the year, using the same equipment, sampling protocols and the same central facilities for analysis of samples. We assessed the spatial variability between areas and between individual sites, as well as pollution contrasts between the seasons and correlations between different pollutants. Within-area spatial contrasts (defined as the ratio between the 90th and 10th percentile) were highest for NO2 (3.14), moderate for PMcoarse (2.19), PNC (2.00) and PM2.5 absorbance (1.94), and lowest for LDSA (1.63), PM2.5 (1.50) and PM10 (1.46). Concentrations in the larger cities were generally higher than in smaller towns and rural and alpine areas, and were higher in the winter than in the summer and intermediate seasons, for all pollutants. Between-area differences accounted for more variation than within-area differences for all pollutants except NO2 and PMcoarse. Despite substantial within-area contrasts for PNC and LDSA, 74.7% and 83.3% of the spatial variance was attributed to between-area variability, respectively. Coefficients of determination between long-term adjusted pollutants were high (R-2&gt;0.70) between NO2, PM2.5 absorbance, PNC and LDSA and between PM2.5 and PM10. The measurement of spatial patterns for this large range of outdoor air pollutants will contribute to a highly standardized estimation of individual long-term exposure levels for SAPALDIA cohort participants. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:01:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:01:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT, 111,60-70</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1352-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2844</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2015.03.031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17562</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>