<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18424</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T11:07:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Vehicle Actuated Control for Heterogeneous Traffic Using Stop Line Detection</dc:title><dc:creator>NULI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, TV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Signal control</dc:subject><dc:subject>vehicle actuated</dc:subject><dc:subject>traffic responsive control</dc:subject><dc:description>Increasing road traffic congestion in major cities significantly undermines the mobility of urban areas around the globe. Since the space is constraint for construction of new roads for such urban areas, many efforts towards congestion relief are focused on better utilization of existing transportation facilities through the use of electronics and communication technologies. Advanced Transportation Management Systems (ATMS), a key component of the Intelligent Transportation Systems deals with such problems of urban traffic control. Traditional methods of signal control such as pre-timed or signal coordination works well when there is no fluctuations in the traffic i.e., saturated or over-saturated conditions. However, vehicle actuated (VA) controllers offer better signal time management especially when the traffic has fluctuations. VA controllers were implemented using upstream detectors in most of the developed countries, however their implementations in heterogeneous traffic poses greater challenges. These heterogeneous vehicles have diverse static and dynamic characteristics such as dimensions, acceleration and decelerations respectively. In addition, suchtraffic is characterized by heavy pedestrian movements, no lane discipline, and occasional violation of signals Modelling such traffic, present in several developing countries, is quite a difficult task. Therefore, developing a vehicle actuated control model to handle highly heterogeneous traffic is a challenging task. The challenge arises because of the difficulty in estimating the demand associated with each turning movement for computing signal timings. Such complex situations can be addressed by placing a detector at stop line rather than in-advance as in homogeneous traffic conditions. Therefore, the objective of this paper is to implement and evaluate proposed vehicle actuated control algorithm using stop line detector. To test the performance of the model atypical four-way four phase intersection with variable flow is simulated using a traffic simulator (VISSIM) and interfaced with the proposed model. The performance is compared with a traditional pre-timed control. The results using this approach shows significant improvement over traditional control, for both medium and high traffic.</dc:description><dc:publisher>UNIV STUDI TRIESTE, IST STUDIO TRASPORTI INTEGRAZIONE ECON EUROPEA-ISTIEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:07:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:07:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN TRANSPORT-TRASPORTI EUROPEI(57)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1825-3997</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18424</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>