<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15990</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:49:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>High Quality Al2O3 Dielectric Films Deposited by Pulsed-DC Reactive Sputtering Technique for High-k Applications</dc:title><dc:creator>BHAISARE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>WAIKAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOTTANTHARAYIL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>High-k Al2O3 Dielectric</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inter-Poly Dielectric (IPD)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reactive Sputtering</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pulse-DC Power Supply</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface Passivation for Silicon Solar Cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINUM-OXIDE FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>VAPOR-DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COATINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICON</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents high quality high-k Al2O3 dielectric films deposited by reactive sputtering technique with pulsed-DC (p-DC) power supply source. Process parameters are optimized to obtain Al2O3 dielectric film with high effective breakdown field (E-BD) of 18.07 MV/cm and dielectric constant (k) of 8.15 with an equivalent oxide thickness (EOT) of 8.59 nm, suitable for inter-poly dielectric (IPD) of floating gate flash memory applications. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) measurement is performed for films deposited with different gas flow ratios and it is observed that the film stoichiometry can be changed by varying the gas flow ratio. A low surface roughness of 3.2 angstrom is observed by atomic force microscopy (AFM) measurement on these films. Al2O3 films deposited at high power are found to be interesting for surface passivation of p-type silicon for solar cell applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:49:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:49:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY LETTERS, 4(6)645-650</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/nnl.2012.1362</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15990</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>