<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9074</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of a flexure-based, force-sensing microgripper for micro-object manipulation</dc:title><dc:creator>JAYARAM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the design and development of a flexure-based microgripper, accompanied with a real-time, vision-based force sensing system to handle objects of various sizes ranging from 100 mu m to 1 mm. A simulation-based design methodology is adopted to develop an initial microgripper design, which is then optimized using theoretical modeling. The final prototype developed generated a large stroke length of over 500 mu m with high-deflection magnification (ratio of the end deflection (output) to the input deflection) of 3.52. A spring system has been incorporated into the microgripper for easy measurement and control of the gripping forces. The web-camera-based visual system enables real-time force measurement with a resolution of 2.37 mN and can be operated in both manual and automatic modes to control the applied forces. The system has successfully demonstrated gripping of a variety of micro-objects including a 100 mu m human hair and a 1 mm steel rod with forces as small as 43 mN and 159 mN, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T15:21:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T15:21:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MICROMECHANICS AND MICROENGINEERING, 20(1), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-1317</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0960-1317/20/1/015001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9074</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9074</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>