<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1404</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Construction of linear time-invariant equivalent plants for nonlinear continuous-time and sampled-data systems</dc:title><dc:creator>NATARAJ, PSV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOTECHA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>feedback-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>interval arithmetic</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear control</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantitative feedback theory (qft)</dc:subject><dc:subject>robust control</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a technique is presented for constructing the so-called linear time-invariant equivalent (LTIE) plants used in the nonlinear quantitative feed back theory (QFT) approach. The proposed technique is applicable equally well to both continuous-time and sampled-data nonlinear plants described by nonlinear integro-differential equation and nonlinear autoregressive moving average with exogenous inputs (NARMAX) models, respectively. The technique uses inclusion function and interval integration tools of interval analysis. A nonlinear chemical reactor example is used to illustrate the procedure for both nonlinear continuous-time and sampled-data systems, and found to yield satisfactory results in both cases. Copyright (C) 2003 John Wiley Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T04:03:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T04:03:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ROBUST AND NONLINEAR CONTROL,13(7)657-673</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1049-8923</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/rnc.831</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14580</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1404</dc:identifier><dc:source>5th International Symposium on Quantitative Feedback Theory and Robust Frequency Domain Methods,PAMPLONA, SPAIN,AUG 23-24, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>