<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11194</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Preparation and characterization of mixed oxides obtained from various molar mixtures of beta-PbO2 and TiO2</dc:title><dc:creator>KRISHNA, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>xps</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoelectron spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical properties</dc:subject><dc:description>A detailed physical characterization of various mixed oxides obtained from 75 : 25, 65 : 35, 60 : 40, 50 : 50, 40 : 60, 35 : 65 and 25 : 75 molar mixtures of beta-PbO2 and TiO2 through solid state reaction has been made by using various analytical techniques like X-ray diffraction, UV-visible reflectance, scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive X-ray analysis, spin resonance spectroscopy and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. These studies reveal that the mixed oxides contain two phases: PbTiO3 with Pb1-xTixO and PbTiO3 with Ti1-xPbxO2 at the PbO2-rich and the TiO2-rich side of the PbO2-TiO2 system respectively. The 50 : 50 molar mixture produces a single phase PbTiO3 compound. It is also observed that incorporation of Ti into the PbO lattice restricts the phase transformation of tetragonal PbO to orthorhombic PbO on the PbO2-rich side of the system and incorporation of Pb into the TiO2 lattice makes the Pb4+ state stable even at high temperatures, in the TiO2-rich region of the system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T04:36:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T04:36:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS AND CHEMISTRY OF SOLIDS, 57(5), 615-626</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3697</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11194</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11194</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>