<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16316</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:06:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Scale-invariant entropy-based theory for dynamic ordering</dc:title><dc:creator>MAHULIKAR, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMARI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>SELF-ORGANIZATION PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>2ND LAW</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIFE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMODYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXISTENCE</dc:subject><dc:description>Dynamically Ordered self-organized dissipative structure exists in various forms and at different scales. This investigation first introduces the concept of an isolated embedding system, which embeds an open system, e.g., dissipative structure and its mass and/or energy exchange with its surroundings. Thereafter, scale-invariant theoretical analysis is presented using thermodynamic principles for Order creation, existence, and destruction. The sustainability criterion for Order existence based on its structured mass and/or energy interactions with the surroundings is mathematically defined. This criterion forms the basis for the interrelationship of physical parameters during sustained existence of dynamic Order. It is shown that the sufficient condition for dynamic Order existence is approached if its sustainability criterion is met, i.e., its destruction path is blocked. This scale-invariant approach has the potential to unify the physical understanding of universal dynamic ordering based on entropy considerations. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:06:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:06:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHAOS, 24(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1054-1500</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4892529</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16316</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>