<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1371</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Construction of interface for interactive multimedia</dc:title><dc:creator>POOVAIAH, BAR</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper looks at construction of interactive multimedia applications from the perspective of the communications designer, and tries to focus on issues that are of significance for a media-based communicator. There are many characteristics that are unique to this new media and these seem to offer creative opportunities to communicate with the media in radically different ways. To identify these, the construction of the interactive multimedia is conceived in discreet levels and the characteristics of each level explored for the potential choices it offers. It becomes obvious, therefore, that in order to gain proficiency in using this media, the design process in the construction of an interface for interactive multimedia needs to be conceived asa physical activity in terms of an interaction using our sensory capabilities; as a relational process that offers choices in terms of selection of information; and as an organisation of its various elements in terms of an arrangement across virtual space. This carts for new skills in understanding our ability to communicate in various sensory modes; of providing the user with various options; and of being able to visualise organisation of information in virtual space. It might even be essential to see these factors as relevant pedagogical inputs for those concerned with learning to work with this media.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ELECTRONICS TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T00:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T00:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IETE TECHNICAL REVIEW,13(6)317-322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-4602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14549</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1371</dc:identifier><dc:source>IETE International Conference on Multimedia Information Systems,NEW DELHI, INDIA,FEB 27-29, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>