<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16423</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:00:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improved electrochemical performance of SnO2-mesoporous carbon hybrid as a negative electrode for lithium ion battery applications</dc:title><dc:creator>SRINIVASAN, NR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>MESOPOROUS CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANODE MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SNO2 NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LI</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICA</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPEDANCE</dc:subject><dc:description>To utilize the high specific capacity of SnO2 as an anode material in lithium-ion batteries, one has to overcome its poor cycling performance and rate capability, which result from large volume expansion (similar to 300%) of SnO2 during charging-discharging cycles. Hence, to accommodate the volume change during cycling, SnO2 nanoparticles of 6 nm diameter were synthesized specifically only on the outer surface of the mesopores, present within mesoporous carbon (CMK-5) particles, resulting in an effective buffering layer. To that end, the synthesis process first involves the formation of 3.5 nm SnO2 nanoparticles inside the mesopores of mesoporous silica (SBA-15), the latter being used as a template subsequently to obtain SnO2-CMK-5 hybrid particles. SnO2-CMK-5 exhibits superior rate capabilities, e. g. after 30 cycles, a specific discharge capacity of 598 mA h g(-1), at a current density of 178 mA g(-1). Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy reveals that the SnO2-CMK-5 electrode undergoes a significant reduction in solid-electrolyte interfacial and charge transfer resistances, with a simultaneous increase in the diffusion coefficient of lithium ions, all these in comparison to an electrode made of only SnO2 nanoparticles. This enhances the potential of using the SnO2-CMK-5 hybrid as a negative electrode, in terms of improved discharge capacity and cycling stability, compared to other electrodes, such as only SnO2 or only CMK-5.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:00:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:00:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 16(14)6630-6640</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c3cp54492c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16423</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>