<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16317</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:07:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electron correlations and two-photon states in polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon molecules: A peculiar role of geometry</dc:title><dc:creator>ARYANPOUR, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKLA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAZUMDAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>VALENCE-BOND THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVEN-PARITY STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONJUGATED POLYMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL-EXCITATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINEAR POLYENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HUBBARD</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLY(PARA-PHENYLENEVINYLENE)</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRA</dc:subject><dc:description>We present numerical studies of one-and two-photon excited states ordering in a number of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon molecules: coronene, hexa-peri-hexabenzocoronene, and circumcoronene, all possessing D-6h point group symmetry versus ovalene with D-2h symmetry, within the Pariser-Parr-Pople model of interacting pi-electrons. The calculated energies of the two-photon states as well as their relative two-photon absorption cross-sections within the interacting model are qualitatively different from single-particle descriptions. More remarkably, a peculiar role of molecular geometry is found. The consequence of electron correlations is far stronger for ovalene, where the lowest spin-singlet two-photon state is a quantum superposition of pairs of lowest spin triplet states, as in the linear polyenes. The same is not true for D-6h group hydrocarbons. Our work indicates significant covalent character, in valence bond language, of the ground state, the lowest spin triplet state and a few of the lowest two-photon states in D-2h ovalene but not in those with D-6h symmetry. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:07:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:07:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 140(10)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7690</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4867363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16317</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>