<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1690</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improving the methodology for assessing natural hazard impacts</dc:title><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>impact assessment</dc:subject><dc:subject>natural hazards</dc:subject><dc:subject>vulnerability</dc:subject><dc:subject>tropical cyclones</dc:subject><dc:description>The impacts of natural hazards such as cyclones have been conventionally measured through changes in human, social and economic capital, typically represented by stock variables such as population, built property and public infrastructure, livestock, agricultural land, etc. This paper develops an alternative approach that seeks to detect and quantify impacts as changes in flow variables. In particular, we explore whether changes in annual agricultural output, when measured at an appropriate spatial level, could be used to measure impacts associated with tropical cyclones in coastal regions of India. We believe that such an approach may have a number of benefits from a policy perspective, particularly with regard to the debate between relief versus recovery as disaster management strategies. A focus on flow variables is also likely to be more relevant and useful in developing countries; the maintenance of economic activity directly affects livelihood and is perhaps of greater importance than loss of built property or other physical capital. (c) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T08:47:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T08:47:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>GLOBAL AND PLANETARY CHANGE,47,253-265</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-8181</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gloplacha.2004.10.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14858</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1690</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Young Scientists Global Change Conference 2003,Trieste, ITALY,NOV 16-19, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>