<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4039</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Role of capillary stresses in film formation</dc:title><dc:creator>TIRUMKUDULU, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RUSSEL, WB</dc:creator><dc:subject>organic coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>latex</dc:subject><dc:subject>evaporation</dc:subject><dc:description>Stresses generated during film formation were deduced from the deflection of a copper cantilever coated with a drying latex. Experiments with particles of varying radii and glass transition temperatures (T-g) focused on conditions for which capillary stresses normal to the film deform the particles to close the voids. Soft particles (low Tg) formed continuous films, but hard ones (high Tg) produced fascinating arrays of cracks. For both soft and rigid particles, the lateral stresses were tensile and scaled on the surface tension divided by the particle radius. Clearly, tensile stresses in the plane of the film responsible for cracking arise from the same capillary pressure that drives compression in the normal direction. Solving the model (Routh &amp; Russel 1996, 1999) for lateral flow of the fluid dispersion prior to close packing and deformation of the solid beyond close packing yields volume fraction, film thickness, and stress profiles for comparison with observations for both film-forming and film-cracking cases.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T18:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T18:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LANGMUIR, 20(7), 2947-2961</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0743-7463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/la0356250</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4039</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>