<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9510</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rheology, morphology, and crystallization Behavior of melt-mixed blends of polyamide6 and acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene: Influence of reactive compatibilizer premixed with multiwall carbon nanotubes</dc:title><dc:creator>BOSE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KODGIRE, PV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTSCHKE, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>nylon-6 abs blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>fractionated crystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>polypropylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>polycarbonate</dc:subject><dc:subject>agent</dc:subject><dc:subject>compatibilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>mwnt</dc:subject><dc:subject>pa6/abs blends</dc:subject><dc:description>Blends of polyamide6 (PA6) and acrylonitrile butadiene styrene (ABS) were prepared in presence or absence of up to 5 wt % of a reactive compatibilizer [styrene maleic anhydride copolymer (SMA) modified with 5 wt % multi wall carbon nanotubes (MWNT)] by melt-mixing using cortical twin screw microcompounder where the ABS content was varied from 20 to 50 wt %. The melt viscosity of the blends was significantly enhanced in presence of SMA modified by multiwall carbon nanotubes due to the reactive compatibilization, which leads to stabilized interphase in the blends. Furthermore, the presence of MWNT in the compatibilizer phase led to additional increase in viscosity and storage modulus. Morphological studies revealed the presence of either drop let-dispersed or cocontinuous type depending on the blend compositions. Further, reactive compatibilization led to a significant change in the morphology, namely a structure refining, which was enhanced by MWNT presence as observed from SEM micrographs. DSC crystallization studies indicated a delayed crystallization response of PA6 in presence of ABS presumably due to high melt viscosity of ABS. The crystallization temperature and the degree of crystallinity were strongly dependent on the type of morphology and content of reactive compatibilizer, whereas the presence of MWNT had an additional influence. SAXS studies revealed the formation of thinner and less perfect crystallites of PA6 phase in the blends, which showed cocontinuous morphology. A unique observation of multiple scattering maxima at higher q region has been found in the blends of cocontinuous morphology, which was observed to be successively broadened in presence of the compatibilizer. (c) 2007 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T13:17:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T13:17:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED POLYMER SCIENCE, 106(5), 3394-3408</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8995</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/app.27018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9510</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9510</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>