<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15104</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:29:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Substrate Temperature on the Electrical and Optical Properties of Pulsed Laser Deposited ZnO Thin Films</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Pulsed Laser Deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>X-Ray Diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scanning Electron Microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hall Measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAPPHIRE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPITAXY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOCVD</dc:subject><dc:description>This study investigated the effect of growth temperatures ranging from 400 to 800 degrees C on the structural, electrical, and optical properties of ZnO thin films deposited on &lt; 001 &gt; sapphire substrates using pulsed laser deposition. X-ray diffraction showed that the grown films were highly c-axis oriented &lt; 002 &gt;. SEM confirmed the growth of epitaxial films with some cracks caused by lattice strain. Van der Pauw Hall measurements showed a low carrier concentration of 1.49 x 10(18) cm(-3) and a corresponding Hall mobility of 24 cm(2) V-1 s(-1). Temperature-dependent PL spectra showed a dominant NBE emission around 3.36 eV at 8 K corresponding to the D degrees X peak, which thermally dissociates into the FX peak at higher temperatures. Deep-level peaks were also observed corresponding to the intrinsic defects in the ZnO films. The results show that ZnO films deposited at 650 degrees C show the best structural, electrical and optical quality The FX peak for this particular film was fitted using Varshni's equation, and the ZnO band gap was calculated to be 3.387 eV at 0 K.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:29:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:29:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSOR LETTERS, 11(8)1498-1503</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1546-198X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1546-1971</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/sl.2013.2836</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15104</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>