<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3910</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Integrated kinetics for the production of glucose in plant cells and the effect of temperature</dc:title><dc:creator>MEHTA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SENGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>ii reaction-center</dc:subject><dc:subject>photosynthetic electron-transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>chloroplast thylakoid membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>doped molecular-crystal</dc:subject><dc:subject>harvesting complex-i</dc:subject><dc:subject>density-matrix model</dc:subject><dc:subject>excitation-energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>photosystem-ii</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat-stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>theoretical determination</dc:subject><dc:description>We prepare a temperature-dependent formulation of the integrated kinetics for the overall process of photosynthesis in eukaryotic cells. To avoid complexity, the C-4 plants are chosen because their rate of photosynthesis is independent of the partial pressure of O-2. A systematically simplified but comprehensive scheme for both light and dark reactions is considered. The reaction rate per reaction center in the thylakoid membrane is related to the rate of exciton transfer between chlorophyll neighbors. An expression is formulated for the light reaction rate (R-1'). The NADPH formation rate is related to R-1' and the survival probability of the membrane. Rates of different steps in the simplified scheme can be related to each other by applying a few steady state conditions. The saturation probability of CO2 in a bundle sheath is also considered. The photochemical efficiency (phi) appears in terms of these probabilities. We find the glucose production rate as R-glucose = 0.8R(1)' phi g(T)([G3P]/[P-i](2)) exp(-Delta G(E)(S)/RT), where g(T) is the activation quotient of the involved enzymes, G3P and P-i represent glyceraldehyde-3-phosphate and inorganic phosphates, and Delta G(E)(S) is the free energy for the apparent equilibrium between G3P and glucose. This is the first time that such a comprehensive expression for R-glucose has been derived. The probabilities are generally given by sigmoid curves. The corresponding parameters can be easily determined. The quotient g(T) incorporates a Gaussian distribution for temperature dependence and a sigmoid function describing deactivation. The theoretical plots of photochemical efficiency and glucose production rate versus temperature are in excellent agreement with the experimental ones, thereby validating the formalism.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T08:33:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T08:33:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY B, 110(22), 10951-10961</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-6106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp0609075</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3910</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3910</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>