<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16734</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:18:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Schedulability Analysis of Deferrable Scheduling Algorithms for Maintaining Real-Time Data Freshness</dc:title><dc:creator>HAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHEN, DJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>XIONG, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAM, KY</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOK, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>Real-time database</dc:subject><dc:subject>real-time data</dc:subject><dc:subject>schedulability</dc:subject><dc:subject>temporal validity</dc:subject><dc:subject>real-time scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPORAL CONSISTENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DATABASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERIODS</dc:subject><dc:description>Although the deferrable scheduling algorithm for fixed priority transactions (DS-FP) has been shown to provide a better performance compared with the More-Less (ML) method, there is still a lack of any comprehensive studies on the necessary and sufficient conditions for the schedulability of DS-FP. In this paper, we first analyze the necessary and sufficient schedulability conditions for DS-FP, and then propose a schedulability test algorithm for DS-FP by exploiting the fact that there always exists a repeating pattern in a DS-FP schedule. To resolve the limitation of fixed priority scheduling in DS-FP, we then extend the deferrable scheduling to a dynamic priority scheduling algorithm called DS-EDF by applying the earliest deadline first (EDF) policy to schedule update jobs. We also propose a schedulability test for DS-EDF and compare its performance with DS-FP and ML through extensive simulation experiments. The results show that the schedulability tests are effective. Although the schedulability of DS-EDF is lower than DS-FP and the repeating patterns in DS-EDF schedules are longer than those in DS-FP due to the use of dynamic priority scheduling, the performance of DS-EDF is better than both DS-FP and ML in terms of CPU utilization and impact on lower priority application transactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:18:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:18:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON COMPUTERS, 63(4)979-994</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9956</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TC.2012.266</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16734</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>