<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14639</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:05:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>A multifunctional biphasic suspension of mesoporous silica encapsulated with YVO4:Eu-3(+) and Fe3O4 nanoparticles: synergistic effect towards cancer therapy and imaging</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRADHAN, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>SOL-GEL PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUG-DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTROLLED-RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DY3+</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUNCTIONALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHYSISORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONJUGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT</dc:subject><dc:description>Polyol mediated synthesized luminescent YVO4:Eu3+ nanoparticles (NPs) have been encapsulated in mesoporous silica nanoparticles (MSNs) using the sol-gel process. X-ray diffraction and Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy along with transmission electron microscopy confirm the encapsulation of the YVO4:Eu3+ NPs in the SiO2 matrix. N-2 adsorption/desorption analysis confirms the mesoporous nature of the MSNs and YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs. No significant quenching of the YVO4:Eu3+ luminescence is observed for YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs. This nanocomposite has been tested as a potential drug carrier. Efficient loading of doxorubicin hydrochloride (DOX), a typical anticancer drug, is observed which reaches up to 93% in 8 mg ml(-1) of YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs. pH sensitive release of DOX is observed, with 54% release for pH 4.3 and 31% in a physiological environment (pH 7.4). Both MSNs and YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs nanocomposites do not show accountable toxicity to two cell lines, i.e. HeLa and MCF-7. However, as desired, toxicity is observed when cells are incubated with DOX loaded YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs. Laser scanning confocal microscopy images confirm the uptake of the nanocomposite in both cell lines. The morphology of the cells (MCF-7) changes after incubation with DOX loaded YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs, indicating an interaction of DOX with the cells. More cytotoxicity to both cell lines with similar to 90% killing is observed due to the synergistic effect of magnetic fluid hyperthermia and chemotherapy using a biphasic suspension of superparamagnetic iron oxide magnetic nanoparticles and DOX loaded YVO4:Eu3+-MSNs. In addition, an AC magnetic field triggers an enhanced drug release.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:05:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:05:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 24(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/24/6/065101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14639</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>