<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17476</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:17:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interference-constrained coverage algorithms in the protocol and SINR models</dc:title><dc:creator>KAPADIA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAMANI, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>POWER-CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>VORONOI DIAGRAMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wireless coverage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computational geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Random sampling</dc:subject><dc:description>A wireless network's design must include the optimization of the area of coverage of its wireless transmitters-mobile and base stations in cellular networks, wireless access points in WLANs, or nodes on a transmit schedule in a wireless ad-hoc network. Furthermore, with increasing densities of wireless network deployments, paucity of spectrum, and new developments like whitespace devices and cognitive networks, there is a need to study the computational efficiency of managing interference and optimizing coverage. This work presents new algorithms for computing and optimizing interference-limited coverage of wireless networks under protocol and Signal-to-Interference-and-Noise Ratio (SINR) models. For the protocol model we demonstrate lower bounds on computation of the coverage area for an transmitter topology. We first show that any offline computation has a run-time of , and any dynamic update takes time to locate transmitters whose coverage is modified and time to update affected coverage regions. We then demonstrate an extension of an offline algorithm to a dynamic algorithm that achieves the lower bound. For coverage in the SINR model, we demonstrate the difficulty of geometric direct computation, and report a flexible coverage area estimation method. We then propose a Random Hill Climbing method for optimizing the coverage area measure, and demonstrate the efficacy of this method by experimental comparison with the Nelder-Mead and exhaustive search optimization methods.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:17:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:17:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WIRELESS NETWORKS, 21(4)1391-1409</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1022-0038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1572-8196</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11276-014-0832-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17476</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>