<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1321</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Monkman-Grant relation - analysis of first order kinetics of creep in AISI 304 stainless steel</dc:title><dc:creator>PHANIRAJ, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>NANDAGOPAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANNAN, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>RODRIGUEZ, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>fracture-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>rupture</dc:subject><dc:description>The transient creep behaviour in AISI 304 Stainless Steel at 873 and 973 K for different test conditions obeyed first order kinetics and it was shown that the validity of Monkman-Grant relation (MGR) is a consequence of first order kinetics. The analysis is extended to tertiary creep regime and the results are found to obey first order kinetics for all test conditions. A new relationship between steady state and tertiary creep is proposed as epsilon over dot ((sic)(s))'.t(t)/epsilon(t) = constant (where t(t) and epsilon(t) are time spent in tertiary and the limiting tertiary creep strain respectively); alpha' is found to be unity for all test conditions implying the validity of first order kinetics. Further, this relation (for alpha' = 1) is found to be identical to modified Monkman - Grant relation (MMGR; m' = 1 where m' is the exponent for epsilon over dot (s) in MMGR) for the conditions satisfying f = 1/lambda and it is postulated that validity of MMGR is also a consequence of first order kinetics. When first order kinetics is applicable, a generalised relationship between steady state creep rate and rupture life is formulated and is valid for the results at all test conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN INST METALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T21:13:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T21:13:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN INSTITUTE OF METALS,49(4)401-405</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-493X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14505</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1321</dc:identifier><dc:source>Workshop on the Phenomena of Creep, Fatigue, and Creep-Fatigue Interactions,KALPAKKAM, INDIA,FEB 15-17, 1995</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>