<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6196</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>PREDICTION OF ON-AXES ELASTIC PROPERTIES OF PLAIN WEAVE FABRIC COMPOSITES</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANESH, VK</dc:creator><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>woven fabric lamina</dc:subject><dc:subject>prediction</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-dimensional</dc:subject><dc:subject>plain weave</dc:subject><dc:subject>elastic constants</dc:subject><dc:description>Two fabric composite models are presented for the on-axes elastic analysis of two-dimensional orthogonal plain weave fabric lamina. These are two-dimensional models taking into account the actual strand cross-section geometry, possible gap between two adjacent strands and undulation and continuity of strands along both warp and fill directions. The shape functions considered to define the geometry of the woven fabric lamina compare well with the photomicrographs of actual woven fabric lamina cross-sections. There is a good correlation between the predicted results and the experimental values. Certain modifications are suggested to the simple models available in the literature so that these models can also be used to predict the elastic properties of woven fabric laminae under specific conditions. Some design studies have been carried out for graphite/epoxy woven fabric laminae. Effects of woven fabric geometrical parameters on the elastic properties of the laminae have been investigated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T10:27:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T10:27:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPOSITES SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, 45(2), 135-152</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0266-3538</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0266-3538(92)90036-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6196</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6196</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>