<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16713</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:08:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Road-RFSense: A Practical RF Sensing-Based Road Traffic Estimation System for Developing Regions</dc:title><dc:creator>SEN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAURYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHTA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALYANARAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>RF</dc:subject><dc:subject>Performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Model Training</dc:subject><dc:subject>Supervised Learning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wireless sensor networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>road traffic monitoring</dc:subject><dc:subject>RSSI</dc:subject><dc:subject>SVM</dc:subject><dc:description>An unprecedented rate of growth in the number of vehicles has resulted in acute road congestion problems worldwide, especially in many developing countries. In this article, we present Road-RFSense, a practical RF sensing-based road traffic estimation system for developing regions. Our first contribution is a new mechanism to sense road occupancy, based on variation in RF link characteristics, when line of sight between a transmitter-receiver pair is obstructed. We design algorithms to classify traffic states into two classes, free-flow versus congested, at timescales of 20 seconds with greater than 90% accuracy. We also present a traffic queue length measurement system, where a network of RF sensors can correlate the traffic state classification decisions of individual sensors and detect traffic queue length in real time. Deployment of our system on a Mumbai road gives correct estimates, validated against 9 hours of image-based ground truth. Our third contribution is a large-scale data-driven study, in collaboration with city traffic authorities, to answer questions regarding road-specific classification model training. Finally, we explore multilevel classification into seven different traffic states using a larger set of RF-based features and careful choice of classification algorithms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:08:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:08:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACM TRANSACTIONS ON SENSOR NETWORKS, 11(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-4859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-4867</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2560189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16713</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>