<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1419</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Resisting oxygen plasma damage in low-k hydrogen silsesquioxane films by hydrogen plasma treatment</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, SUNIL KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMBHAR, ALKA A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, RO</dc:creator><dc:subject>leakage currents</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen bonds</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasma theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>materials science</dc:subject><dc:description>Low-density materials, such as the commercially available hydrogen silsesquioxane (HSQ) offer a low dielectric constant. Thus, HSQ with a low value of k (not, vert, similar 2.85) can be spin-coated if the density of Si–H bonding is maintained at a high level and the formation of –OH bonds and absorption of water in the film is minimized. O2 plasma exposure on HSQ film increases leakage current. Also the dielectric constant shows a significant increase after O2 plasma exposure. Another consequence of the O2 plasma exposure is the significant decrease in the contact angle of the HSQ surface, which is not desirable. In this paper, we demonstrate that the surface passivation by hydrogen followed by oxygen plasma treatment of HSQ film for 30 min each leads to a regain of leakage current density and dielectric constant. These results show that the H2 plasma treatment is a promising technique to prevent the damage in the commercially available and highly applicable low-k materials and it also increases the visibility of its use at the 0.1-μm technology. The more hydrophilic nature of the HSQ surface after O2 plasma exposure leads to an increased moisture absorption with a subsequent increase in the dielectric constant.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-04T09:19:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:38:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-04T09:19:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:38:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Materials Letters  60(13-14), 1579-1581</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-577X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-577X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1419</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1419</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>