<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17954</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:39:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Exfoliated MoS2 Sheets and Reduced Graphene Oxide-An Excellent and Fast Anode for Sodium-ion Battery</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, TS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>LOW-COST</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPOROUS GRAPHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON-FIBERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH-CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LITHIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSPHERES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROLYTE</dc:subject><dc:description>Three dimensional (3D) MoS2 nanoflowers are successfully synthesized by hydrothermal method. Further, a composite of as prepared MoS2 nanoflowers and rGO is constructed by simple ultrasonic exfoliation technique. The crystallography and morphological studies have been carried out by XRD, FE-SEM, TEM, HR-TEM and EDS etc. Here, XRD study revealed, a composite of exfoliated MoS2 with expanded spacing of (002) crystal plane and rGO can be prepared by simple 40 minute of ultrasonic treatment. While, FE-SEM and TEM studies depict, individual MoS2 nanoflowers with an average diameter of 200 nm are uniformly distributed throughout the rGO surface. When tested as sodium-ion batteries anode material by applying two different potential windows, the composite demonstrates a high reversible specific capacity of 575 mAhg(-1) at 100 mAg(-1) in between 0.01V-2.6V and 218 mAhg(-1) at 50 mAg(-1) when discharged in a potential range of 0.4V-2.6V. As per our concern, the results are one of the best obtained as compared to the earlier published one on MoS2 based SIB anode material and more importantly this material shows such an excellent reversible Na-storage capacity and good cycling stability without addition of any expensive additive stabilizer, like fluoroethylene carbonate (FEC), in comparison to those in current literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:39:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:39:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, 5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2045-2322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep12571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17954</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>