<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2667</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optically tunable spiral inductor for RIF applications</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, AN</dc:creator><dc:description>The inductors are found in impedance matching networks, filters, tuned amplifiers and voltage controlled oscillators. The performance of these circuits is heavily depends on these passive components. Many researchers are working on improving the performance of passive components in particular inductors. A novel method of implementing the tunability in inductor is proposed. Tunability in this passive component gives better performance of RF front end circuits by adjusting the centre frequency of band pass filter. This work is based on improving the mutual impedance by increasing the length of the additional conductor without effecting the overall spiral length by optical switching. This method does not increase the resistance of the spiral inductor as we are not increasing the physical length of the spiral, but we are increasing the coupling.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T17:45:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T17:45:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2004 9TH IEEE SINGAPORE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS (ICCS),569-572</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8549-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16077</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2667</dc:identifier><dc:source>9th IEEE Singapore International Conference on Communication Systems (ICCS),Singapore, SINGAPORE,SEP 06-09, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>