<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8100</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>POLE-PARAMETER ANALYSIS - A NOVEL-APPROACH FOR THE DESIGN OF FILTERS</dc:title><dc:creator>PAI, KR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURTHY, KVV</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMACHANDRAN, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>pole parameter analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>filter design</dc:subject><dc:subject>transfer functions</dc:subject><dc:subject>identical section filters</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper introduces pole parameter analysis (PPA) as a novel approach useful in obtaining the realisable transfer functions to meet the prescribed specifications of a filter. Analytical expressions are obtained for the design parameters and performance indices, in terms of pole parameters omega(p) and theta(p) that are introduced as the basis of PPA. Details have been given for the second order case and extensions to higher order filters are indicated. Perspectives obtained through this approach indicate the possibilities of generating new families of transitional filters. A practically useful class of higher order filters which make use of (second order) identical section filters (ISFs) in cascade is studied in detail. ISFs are also desirable in limiting the component-spread in the fabrication using IC technology. The elegant manner in which the effect of component-spread can be incorporated at the design stages using the PPA approach is a so discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEE-INST ELEC ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T11:26:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T11:26:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEE PROCEEDINGS-CIRCUITS DEVICES AND SYSTEMS, 141(2), 121-128</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-2409</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/ip-cds:19949895</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8100</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>