<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11069</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>NEW ALGORITHMS FOR 3D SURFACE DESCRIPTION FROM BINOCULAR STEREO USING INTEGRATION</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:description>In this paper, we formulate and develop an approach which integrates different modules (feature extractor, matching and interpolation) involved in stereo. We study the integration process at the finest resolution when (i) the precomputed edge map is the only line filed driving the model, (ii) the line field are computed interactively by the feature extracting module of the model, and (iii) when both the interactive line field computation module and the precomputed line field modules are present. The integration process being computationally intensive, we develop a multiresolution stereo integration approach. The energy function for each module at different resolutions is constructed and minimized in an integrated manner yielding a dense disparity map. A new energy function for the matching module is proposed. Experimental results are presented to illustrate our approach.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T16:05:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T16:05:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE FRANKLIN INSTITUTE-ENGINEERING AND APPLIED MATHEMATICS, 331B(5), 531-554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-0032</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11069</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>