<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18078</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:42:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural and electronic properties of InN nanowire network grown by vapor-liquid-solid method</dc:title><dc:creator>BARICK, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RODRIGUEZ-FERNANDEZ, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>CANTARERO, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>INDIUM NITRIDE NANOWIRES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTORS</dc:subject><dc:description>Growth of InN nanowires have been carried out on quartz substrates at different temperatures by vapor-liquid-solid (VLS) technique using different thicknesses of Au catalyst layer. It has been found that a narrow window of Au layer thickness and growth temperature leads to multi-nucleation, in which each site acts as the origin of several nanowires. In this multi-nucleation regime, several tens of micrometer long wires with diameter as small as 20 nm are found to grow along [11 (2) over bar0] direction (a-plane) to form a dense network. Structural and electronic properties of these wires are studied. As grown nanowires show degenerate n-type behavior. Furthermore, x-ray photoemission study reveals an accumulation of electrons on the surface of these nanowires. Interestingly, the wire network shows persistence of photoconductivity for several hours after switching off the photoexcitation. (C) 2015 Author(s). All article content, except where otherwise noted, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AIP ADVANCES, 5(5)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2158-3226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4921946</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18078</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>