<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16418</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:58:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ultrafast FRET to Study Spontaneous Micelle-to-Vesicle Transitions in an Aqueous Mixed Surface-Active Ionic-Liquid System</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUCHLYAN, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANIK, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHORWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>FRET</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionic liquids</dc:subject><dc:subject>micelles</dc:subject><dc:subject>self-assembly</dc:subject><dc:subject>vesicles</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESONANCE ENERGY-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>1-BUTYL-3-METHYLIMIDAZOLIUM OCTYL SULFATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOINDUCED ELECTRON-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROTATIONAL-RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGGREGATION BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT DYES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORSTER THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLTEN-SALTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:description>The spontaneous micelle-to-vesicle transition in an aqueous mixture of two surface-active ionic liquids (SAILs), namely, 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium n-octylsulfate ([C(4)mim][C8SO4]) and 1-dodecyl-3-methylimidazoium chloride ([C(12)mim]Cl) is described. In addition to detailed structural characterization obtained by using dynamic light scattering, transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and cryogenic TEM techniques, ultrafast fluorescence resonance energy transfer (FRET) from coumarin 153 (C153) as a donor (D) to rhodamine 6G (R6G) as an acceptor (A) is also used to study micelle-vesicle transitions in the present system. Structural transitions of SAIL micelles ([C(4)mim][C8SO4] or [C(12)mim] Cl micelles) to mixed SAIL vesicles resulted in significantly increased D-A distances, and therefore, increased timescale of FRET. In [C(4)mim][C8SO4] micelles, FRET between C153 and R6G occurs on an ultrafast timescale of 3.3 ps, which corresponds to a D-A distance of about 15 angstrom. As [C(4)mim][C8SO4] micelles are transformed into mixed micelles upon the addition of a 0.25 molar fraction of [C(12)mim] Cl, the timescale of FRET increases to 300 ps, which suggests an increase in the D-A distance to 31 angstrom. At a 0.5 molar fraction of [C(12)mim] Cl, unilamellar vesicles are formed in which FRET occurs on multiple timescales of about 250 and 2100 ps, which correspond to D-A distances of 33 and 47 angstrom. Although in micelles and mixed micelles the obtained D-A distances are well correlated with their radius, in vesicles the obtained D-A distance is within the range of the bilayer thickness.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:58:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:58:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMPHYSCHEM, 15(16)3544-3553</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1439-4235</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1439-7641</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cphc.201402372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16418</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>