<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1340</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study on the variation of peak isometric strength and EMG activity in static field-simulated lifting postures</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITI, RINA</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, GG</dc:creator><dc:subject>construction industry</dc:subject><dc:subject>health risks</dc:subject><dc:subject>industrial management</dc:subject><dc:description>Peak isometric strength was measured from 10 adult Indian construction workers in eight different field-simulated (FS) postures. This peak-strength data in these FS postures were compared with symmetric postures. In symmetric postures, the vertical load positions were kept the same as FS postures and the points of force exertion were fixed at 40 cm distance in front of the subject. From both symmetric and FS static strength data, it was shown that the maximum peak strength occurred at medium vertical height level and decreased with both increase and decrease of the vertical height level. The maximum and minimum peak strengths were obtained in different FS postures as 222.85±61.15 N and 85.65±19.89 N, respectively. It was observed that the lifted weight in the field was 12.0 kg, which corresponds to 54.54% and 137.3% (i.e. &gt;100%) of these maximum and minimum peak-strength values. This result indicated the prevalence of high risk factors in the field. During this study, surface EMGs from four different muscles (i.e. trapezius, external oblique, rectus abdominis and erector spinae) were collected while exerting the peak isometric strength. From ANOVA analysis, it was shown that the erector spinae and trapezius activities were significantly (pless-than-or-equals, slant0.05) related to the peak-strength value, whereas external oblique and rectus abdominis activities were not. It was also observed that RMS of erector spinae activity increases with ipsi-lateral increase of asymmetry angle along with the decrease in maximum static peak-strength level in FS postures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-10T09:27:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:09:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-10T09:27:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:09:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>International Journal of Industrial Ergonomics 33(2), 109-122</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0169-8141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.ergon.2003.07.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1340</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>