<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16808</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:55:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Periplasmic glucose-binding protein from Pseudomonas putida CSV86-identification of the glucose-binding pocket by homology-model-guided site-specific mutagenesis</dc:title><dc:creator>MODAK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAUMIK, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>homology modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular docking</dc:subject><dc:subject>periplasmic binding protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pseudomonas</dc:subject><dc:subject>site-directed mutagenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON CATABOLITE REPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREFERENTIAL UTILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SECONDARY-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AROMATIC-COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRAP TRANSPORTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>AERUGINOSA</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECEPTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>CSV86</dc:subject><dc:description>Glucose transport in Pseudomonasputida CSV86 is mediated via a periplasmic glucose-binding protein (GBP)-dependent putative glucose ABC transporter. Here we describe a homology model and functional characterization of GBP from CSV86 (ppGBP). A whole-cell [C-14]-glucose uptake study revealed that glucose is transported by the high-affinity intracellular phosphorylative pathway. ppGBP was cloned, over-expressed in Escherichiacoli and purified to apparent homogeneity. The purified ppGBPs from both E.coli and CSV86 were found to be specific for glucose. A homology model of ppGBP was constructed that resembles the classII family of periplasmic binding proteins. The model showed highest structural similarity to GBP of Thermusthermophilus (ttGBP, rmsd 0.64 angstrom). Structural analysis and molecular docking studies predicted W35, W36, E41, K92, K339 and H379 of ppGBP as putative glucose-binding residues. Alanine substitution of these residues resulted in significantly reduced [C-14]-glucose binding activity. Analysis of the operonic arrangement and structural comparative studies suggested that ppGBP and ttGBP probably originated from a common ancestor. Structural adaptations that inhibit binding of di- or trisaccharides at the glucose-binding pocket of ppGBP were also identified.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FEBS JOURNAL, 281(1)365-375</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-464X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-4658</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/febs.12607</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16808</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>