<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12345</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-14T15:26:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of theta-alumina formation on the growth kinetics of alumina-forming superalloys</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASANNA, KMN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>QUADAKKERS, WJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>oxide scales</dc:subject><dc:subject>ods alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>yttrium</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>ods alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sims</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:description>Alumina-forming ODS superalloys are excellent oxidation-resistant materials. Their resistance relies upon the establishment of a stable, slow-growing, and adherent alpha-alumina. In the present investigation, these alloys exhibited unstable and relatively less adherent theta-alumina phase, which increased the oxidation rate in the transient stage and converted into alpha-alumina in the later part of the exposure. The oxide-growth process was found to depend upon various parameters such as temperature, time, and presence of an active element in the superalloy. Characterization carried out by XRD, SEM/EDAX, and AES on oxidized ODS and non-ODS alloys demonstrated a significant influence of the active element, Y on the transformation of theta- to alpha-alumina. SIMS analysis of two-stage oxidation at 900 degrees C for two different durations evidently showed that the change in the transport process is due to theta-to-alpha-alumina transformation. On the basis of these results, a new and consistent mechanism is proposed to explain the influence of theta-alumina and its transformation on growth kinetics and the effect of yttrium on the transformation leading to good scale adherence and oxidation resistance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER/PLENUM PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T14:08:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T14:08:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>OXIDATION OF METALS, 46(5-6), 465-480</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0030-770X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF01048641</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12345</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12345</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>