<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1486</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Process integration of organic Rankine cycle</dc:title><dc:creator>DESAI, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>working fluids</dc:subject><dc:subject>dry fluids</dc:subject><dc:subject>waste heat</dc:subject><dc:subject>power</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>recovery</dc:subject><dc:subject>targets</dc:subject><dc:subject>plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>process integration</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic rankine cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>regeneration</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbine bleeding</dc:subject><dc:subject>system optimization</dc:subject><dc:description>An organic Rankine cycle (ORC) uses an organic fluid as a working medium within a Rankine cycle power plant. ORC offers advantages over conventional Rankine cycle with water as the working medium, as ORC generates shaft-work from low to medium temperature heat sources with higher thermodynamic efficiency. The dry and the isentropic fluids are most preferred working. fluid for the ORC. The basic ORC can be modified by incorporating both regeneration and turbine bleeding to improve its thermal efficiency. In this paper, 16 different organic. fluids have been analyzed as a working medium for the basic as well as modified ORCs. A methodology is also proposed for appropriate integration and optimization of an ORC as a cogeneration process with the background process to generate shaft-work. It has been illustrated that the choice of cycle configuration for appropriate integration with the background process depends on the heat rejection pro. le of the background process (i.e., the shape of the below pinch portion of the process grand composite curve). The benefits of integrating ORC with the background process and the applicability of the proposed methodology have been demonstrated through illustrative examples. (C) 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T09:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T09:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY,34(10)1674-1686</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-5442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2009.04.037</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14635</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1486</dc:identifier><dc:source>11th Conference on Process Integration, Modelling and Optimisation for Energy Saving and Pollution Reduction,Prague, CZECH REPUBLIC,AUG, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>