<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1403</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biodegradation of diesel oil by an Arabian Sea sediment culture isolated from the vicinity of an oil field</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, SUPARNA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHEEJA, JAGADEVAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, GITA</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVINASH, VIJAY</dc:creator><dc:subject>trace elements</dc:subject><dc:subject>nutrients</dc:subject><dc:subject>denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sediments</dc:subject><dc:description>Laboratory scale batch studies were performed to test the diesel oil biodegradation ability of ES1 cultures isolated from Arabian Sea sediments obtained from the vicinity of an oil field. This culture could utilize diesel as the sole source of carbon and energy. Under aerobic conditions, 39% loss of diesel oil was observed over 8 days where 80% of the loss was due to aliphatic constituents. Under anoxic nitrate reducing conditions the rate and extent of degradation was significantly lower, i.e., 18% over 50 days. Salt acclimatized cultures could tolerate salinities up to 3.5% and demonstrated optimal performance at a salinity of 0.5%. The optimum N/P ratio for these cultures was found to be in the range of 2:1–5:1. Addition of two trace elemental substance formulations exhibited a significant inhibitory effect on culture growth. This culture has good potential for decontamination of oil-contaminated marine and subsurface environments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-01T09:01:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:30:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-01T09:01:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:30:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Bioresource Technology 95(3), 281-286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-8524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.biortech.2004.02.029</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1403</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1403</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>