<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15684</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:37:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Epitaxial Gd2O3 on strained Si1-xGex layers for next generation complementary metal oxide semiconductor device application</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>FISSEL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>OSTEN, HJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>SIGE ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOSFETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIELECTRICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GE</dc:subject><dc:description>Strained Si1-xGex (x = 0.1-0.4) layers were grown on Si(111) and Si(001) substrates using molecular beam epitaxy followed by the growth of epitaxial Gd2O3 thin films on Si1-xGex layers using same technique. Pt/Gd2O3/Si1-xGex/Si stacks fabricated by several in situ process steps exhibit excellent electrical properties. Surface and microstructural analysis of both Si1-xGex and Gd2O3 layers carried out by different in situ and ex situ tools reveal a relaxed epi-Gd2O3 layer on a strained Si1-xGex layer on both Si(111) and Si(001) substrates with sharp interfaces between the oxide and the SiGe layer. Standard electrical measurements, such as capacitance-voltage and leakage current analysis, demonstrate promising electrical properties for such metal oxide semiconductor capacitors. A capacitance equivalent thickness as low as 1.20 nm with associated leakage current density of 2.0 mA/cm(2) was obtained for devices with 4.5 nm thin oxide films where the density of interface trap (D-it) was only similar to 10(11) cm(-2) eV(-1). (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:37:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:37:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 103(15)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1077-3118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4824422</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15684</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>