<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1926</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance evaluation of working set scheme for location management in PCS networks</dc:title><dc:creator>PAWAR, PA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHNDIRATTA, SL</dc:creator><dc:description>To overcome drawbacks of existing centralized location management scheme, various approaches including message routing schemes based on a hierarchy of databases have been proposed previously by researchers in wireless network community. We have chosen working set idea, which is originally proposed for location management for mobile IP, to analyze its performance for PCS networks. Variants of working set idea have been developed for existing location management standard (HLR/VLR approach) and hierarchical approaches. Experimental analysis has been performed using a location management simulator with respect to bandwidth requirements, database requirements and time requirements for two real life mobility traces. Results obtained indicate that the working set scheme performs superior for real life traces at the cost of slightly higher penalty. Future work involves analyzing working set scheme in details for synthetic mobility models.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T15:30:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T15:30:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>HIGH PERFORMANCE COMPUTING - HIPC 2003,2913,418-427</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>3-540-20626-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15163</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1926</dc:identifier><dc:source>10th International Conference on High Performance Computing,HYDERABAD, INDIA,DEC 17-20, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>