<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-506</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance study on piezoelectric transformers</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOLE, AJAY M</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>equivalent circuits</dc:subject><dc:subject>operational amplifiers</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoelectric devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>power amplifiers</dc:subject><dc:subject>power transformers</dc:subject><dc:subject>switching convertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>transformers</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, performance study on multilayer Rosen-type piezoelectric transformer (PET) as a potential component for power electronic conversion is presented. The attractiveness of the smart piezoelectric technology is primarily due to its desirable features of miniaturization and the extreme simplicity of the resulting components compared to widely used wire wound conventional magnetics. As a result, recently much attention has been focused on application of PETs in high frequency switching power supplies as well as low profile inverters. PET equivalent circuit and impedance response is studied using impedance analyzer HP4192. The effects of load resistance on gain, efficiency and resonance characteristics are studied, using simulations and experimentally under sinusoidal excitation conditions. A sinusoidal source using common laboratory equipments and a power operational amplifier (POA) is fabricated. The details of this sinusoidal source designed and fabricated in laboratory are given.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-28T07:01:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T03:52:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-28T07:01:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T03:52:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 2nd International Conference on Power Electronics Systems and Applications, Hong Kong, 12-14 November 2006, 85-86.</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>962-367-544-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/PESA.2006.343075</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/506</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/506</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>