<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15428</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:25:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cyclopalladation of dimesityl selenide: synthesis, reactivity, structural characterization, isolation of an intermediate complex with C-H center dot center dot center dot Pd intra-molecular interaction and computational studies</dc:title><dc:creator>KOLAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>WADAWALE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISAN, HK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, VK</dc:creator><dc:subject>COUPLING REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALLADIUM(II)</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALLADACYCLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATINUM(II)</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRINUCLEAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DINUCLEAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATALYSTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of dimesityl selenide (Mes(2)Se) with either PdCl2(PhCN)(2) in toluene or PdCl2 in toluene-acetonitrile yields a chloro-bridged binuclear palladium complex, [Pd2Cl2(mu-Cl)(2)(Mes(2)Se)(2)] (1), whereas with Na2PdCl4 in refluxing ethanol, a cyclometallated palladium complex, [Pd-2(mu-Cl)(2){MesSeC(6)H(2)(Me-2)CH2} 2] (2) is afforded. 2 can also be obtained when 1 is refluxed in ethanol. On treatment with Pb(Epy)(2) in dichloromethane, 2 afforded the Epy-bridged binuclear complexes, [Pd-2(mu-Epy)(2){MesSeC(6)H(2)(Me-2)CH2} (2)] (3; E = S (3a) or Se (3b)). Treatment of 2 with PPh3 yields a bridge-cleaved monomeric complex, [PdCl{MesSeC(6)H(2)(Me-2)CH2}(PPh3)]. The molecular structures of 1-3 were established by X-ray diffraction analyses. All the complexes are dimeric, with the palladium atoms acquiring a distorted square planar configuration. There are intra-molecular C-H. Pd interactions (d(M-H): 2.75 angstrom and &lt;C-H center dot center dot center dot Pd: 111.23 degrees) in 1 which facilitate the activation of the C-H (sp(3)) bond leading to metallation. The optimized geometry of 1 obtained using the DFT(B3LYP) computational method identified a C-H center dot center dot center dot Pd contact distance of 2.78 angstrom. There are two independent molecules of 2 in the unit cell, which differ slightly in bond lengths, bond angles and torsion angles. The mechanism of formation of the dimeric species 2 is examined using DFT (B3LYP) computations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:25:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:25:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 42(30)10828-10837</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c3dt50935d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15428</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>