<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15259</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:53:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Preparation and characterization of lithium-titanate pebbles by solid-state reaction extrusion and spherodization techniques for fusion reactor</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYAMOORTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Lithium titanate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusion reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blanket</dc:subject><dc:subject>TiO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>Li2TiO3</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spherodization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solidstate reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>ITER</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESEARCH-AND-DEVELOPMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>LI2TIO3 PEBBLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEL METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLANKET</dc:subject><dc:subject>ITER</dc:subject><dc:description>For the development of TBM for fusion reactors, lithium containing ceramics as against the metal are preferred as tritium breeding material. Lithium titanate (Li2TiO3) is one such chosen ceramic tritium breeder. Li2TiO3 pebbles are conventionally prepared by sol-gel process and wet process. Solid state reaction of lithium carbonate with titanium dioxide is preferred route for the bulk production of Li2TiO3. Thermo-gravimetric and differential thermal analysis (TG-DTA) techniques have been used in the present study to understand the solid state reaction of intimate mixture of lithium carbonate and titanium dioxide. It was found out that single phase lithium titanate (Li2TiO3) is produced at 750 degrees C and the reaction is completed in 6 h. Fine powders of lithium titanate obtained after milling and classification were mixed with aqueous solution of PVA to prepare green pebbles of desired size and shape. The pebbles were subsequently sintered at 900 degrees C and the effect of sintering time on the properties of sintered pebbles was studied. The reaction mechanisms and the product qualities obtained by the solid state reaction, extrusion and spherodization techniques are discussed in this paper. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:53:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:53:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FUSION ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 87(1)7-12</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fusengdes.2011.08.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15259</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>