<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1721</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Computer analysis for the prediction of a strip profile in cold rolling</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHPANDE, DAS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURTHY, KS</dc:creator><dc:subject>cold rolling</dc:subject><dc:subject>strip</dc:subject><dc:subject>shape</dc:subject><dc:subject>profile</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present work, a software is developed on windows environment in C++ using analytical methods to predict the strip thickness distribution in the transverse direction For this purpose, the rolling equations are solved analytically along the length of arc of contact, while a numerical approach is used to determine the load distribution across the width. The procedure takes into account elastic deformations of work rolls and back-up rolls, the effect of roll flattening and the effect of work roll bending. It considers various situations, i.e., whether chamber is given or not to the work roll, back-up roll. Computations have been performed for various realistic ranges of rolling parameters. Using the data available from the literature regarding likely temperature distribution of the work roll, the program incorporates the expected thermal expansion of rolls and is capable of not only predicting the strip profile but also suggesting the magnitude of optimum camber, which would result in best possible flatness of strip under the given set of rolling conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T11:19:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T11:19:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS PROCESSING TECHNOLOGY,63,712-717</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0924-0136</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14887</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1721</dc:identifier><dc:source>3rd Asia Pacific Conference on Materials Processing,HONG KONG, HONG KONG,NOV 12-14, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>