<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17294</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:19:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Purification, crystallization and preliminary X-ray diffraction analysis of NADP-dependent glutamate dehydrogenase from Aspergillus niger</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAKASH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>WALVEKAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNEKAR, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAUMIK, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOSTERIC-REGULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECIFICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FAMILY</dc:subject><dc:description>Glutamate dehydrogenase (GDH) catalyzes the NAD-dependent or NADP-dependent oxidative deamination of l-glutamate to 2-oxoglutarate and ammonia. This important reversible reaction establishes the link between carbon and nitrogen metabolism. In this study, Aspergillus niger NADP-GDH (AnGDH) has been overexpressed and purified. Purified AnGDH, with a high specific activity of 631.1 units per milligram of protein, was crystallized and the crystal diffracted to 2.9 angstrom resolution using a home X-ray source. Preliminary analysis of the X-ray diffraction data showed that the crystal belonged to space group R32, with unit-cell parameters a = b = 173.8, c = 241.5 angstrom, alpha = beta = 90, gamma = 120 degrees. The crystals exhibited an unusually high solvent content (83.0%) and had only one molecule in the asymmetric unit. Initial phases were obtained by molecular replacement, and model building and structure refinement of AnGDH are in progress.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:19:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:19:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA CRYSTALLOGRAPHICA SECTION F-STRUCTURAL BIOLOGY COMMUNICATIONS, 701508-1512</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1744-3091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1107/S2053230X14021499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17294</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>