<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1567</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>GPS research for earthquake studies in India</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, MN</dc:creator><dc:subject>gps</dc:subject><dc:subject>national programme</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquakes</dc:subject><dc:subject>research permanent stations</dc:subject><dc:description>With the recent major earthquakes in the South East Asian reo ion. and the devastation caused by the tsunami effect. the importance of earthquake prediction has been re-emphasized. Monitoring the Geodynamics, including the crustal deformations, using advanced space geodetic techniques like the Global Positioning System (GPS) with the ultimate aim of predicting the natural disasters such as earthquakes. volcanic eruptions, landslides, avalanches, is one of the greatest challenges faced by the scientists in this century. In India, an extensive high precision Geodetic and Geophysical control network has been established by Survey of India (SOI). the national mapping agency ot'Govt. of India, For the primary purpose of national mapping, through dedicated efforts of over two centuries. More recently, various national organizations and institutions have taken up geodetic. geophysical and geological surveys for a variety of applications. The extensive horizontal and vertical geodetic and geophysical control network established through these collaborative efforts. and the huge amount of valuable data thus generate, has significant contribution towards monitoring the crustal dynamics of the Indian sub-continent. These efforts have now been augmented through an extensive National Prooramme on GPS and Geodetic Studies for Earthquake Hazard Estimation launched by the Department of Science &amp; Technology (DST), Government of India. since 1998. The programme, GPS network consisting of about 50 permanent, 700 semi-permanent and several hundreds of campaign mode field GPS stations, being implemented in a phased-manner by DST has now reached a significant stage. Several GPS research groups are en-aged in the study of specific regions under this national programme. An overview of the recent developments in this programme. along with the present status and future plans have been presented here. Two case studies, being carried out by the IIT Bombay GPS research group, under this National Programme: one in the Koyna region of central India, and the other in the Bhuj region of Gujarat, are also briefly described.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T16:04:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T16:04:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>VI HOTINE-MARUSSI SYMPOSIUM ON THEORETICAL AND COMPUTATIONAL GEODESY,132,88-93</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-540-74583-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0939-9585</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14937</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1567</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th Hotine-Marussi Symposium on Theoretical and Computational Geodesy,Wuhan, PEOPLES R CHINA,MAY 29-JUN 02, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>