<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12544</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling and predictive control of mimo nonlinear systems using Wiener-Laguerre models</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAN, SH</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VSR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, SC</dc:creator><dc:subject>2nd-order volterra models</dc:subject><dc:subject>identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>series</dc:subject><dc:subject>wiener models</dc:subject><dc:subject>laguerre filters</dc:subject><dc:subject>predictive control</dc:subject><dc:subject>ph control</dc:subject><dc:subject>input multiplicity</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, a Weiner-type nonlinear black box model was developed for capturing dynamics of open loop stable MIMO nonlinear systems with deterministic inputs. The linear dynamic component of the model was parameterized using orthogonal Laguerre filters while the nonlinear state output map was constructed either using quadratic polynomial functions or artificial neural networks. The properties of the resulting model, such as open loop stability and steady-state behavior, are discussed in detail. The identified Weiner-Laguerre model was further used to formulate a nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) scheme. The efficacy of the proposed modeling and control scheme was demonstrated using two benchmark control problems: (a) a simulation study involving control of a continuously operated fermenter at its optimum (singular) operating point and (b) experimental verification involving control of pH at the critical point of a neutralization process. It was observed that the proposed Weiner-Laguerre model is able to capture both the dynamic and steady-state characteristics of the continuous fermenter as well as the neutralization process reasonably accurately over wide operating ranges. The proposed NMPC scheme achieved a smooth transition from a suboptimal operating point to the optimum (singular) operating point of the fermenter without causing large variation in manipulated inputs. The proposed NMPC scheme was also found to be robust in the face of moderate perturbation in the unmeasured disturbances. In the case of experimental verification using the neutralization process, the proposed control scheme was found to achieve much faster transition to a set point close to the critical point when compared to a conventional gain-scheduled PID controller.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T02:17:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T02:17:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING COMMUNICATIONS, 191(8), 1083-1119</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-6445</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/0098644049276452</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12544</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12544</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>