<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17978</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:51:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mixed ligand copper(II) dicarboxylate complexes: the role of co-ligand hydrophobicity in DNA binding, double-strand DNA cleavage, protein binding and cytotoxicity</dc:title><dc:creator>LOGANATHAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANESHPANDIAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHUVANESH, NSP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALANIANDAVAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RIYASDEEN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>AKBARSHA, MA</dc:creator><dc:subject>BOVINE SERUM-ALBUMIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>DINUCLEAR PLATINUM(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENANTHROLINE BASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RED-LIGHT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL-BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>1,10-PHENANTHROLINE PHEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>RING PI,PI-INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTICANCER ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOINDUCED DNA</dc:subject><dc:description>A few water soluble mixed ligand copper(II) complexes of the type [Cu(bimda)(diimine)] 1-5, where bimda is N-benzyliminodiacetic acid and diimine is 2,2'-bipyridine (bpy, 1) or 1,10-phenanthroline (phen, 2) or 5,6-dimethyl-1,10-phenanthroline (5,6-dmp, 3) or 3,4,7,8-tetramethyl-1,10-phenanthroline (3,4,7,8-tmp, 4) and dipyrido[3,2-d: 2', 3'-f] quinoxaline (dpq, 5), have been successfully isolated and characterized by elemental analysis and other spectral techniques. The coordination geometry around copper(II) in 2 is described as distorted square based pyramidal while that in 3 is described as square pyramidal. Absorption spectral titrations and competitive DNA binding studies reveal that the intrinsic DNA binding affinity of the complexes depends upon the diimine co-ligand, dpq (5) &gt; 3,4,7,8-tmp (4) &gt; 5,6-dmp (3) &gt; phen (2) &gt; bpy (1). The phen and dpq co-ligands are involved in the p-stacking interaction with DNA base pairs while the 3,4,7,8-tmp/5,6-dmp and bpy co-ligands are involved in respectively hydrophobic and surface mode of binding with DNA. The small enhancement in the relative viscosity of DNA upon binding to 1-5 supports the DNA binding modes proposed. Interestingly, 3 and 4 are selective in exhibiting a positive induced CD band (ICD) upon binding to DNA suggesting that they induce B to A conformational change. In contrast, 2 and 5 show CD responses which reveal their involvement in strong DNA binding. The complexes 2-4 are unique in displaying prominent double-strand DNA cleavage while 1 effects only single-strand DNA cleavage, and their ability to cleave DNA in the absence of an activator varies as 5 &gt; 4 &gt; 3 &gt; 2 &gt; 1. Also, all the complexes exhibit oxidative double-strand DNA cleavage activity in the presence of ascorbic acid, which varies as 5 &gt; 4 &gt; 3 &gt; 2 &gt; 1. The ability of the complexes to bind and cleave the protein BSA varies in the order 4 &gt; 3 &gt; 5 &gt; 2 &gt; 1. Interestingly, 3 and 4 cleave the protein non-specifically in the presence of H2O2 as an activator suggesting that they can act also as chemical proteases. It is remarkable that 2-5 exhibit cytotoxicity against human breast cancer cell lines (MCF-7) with potency higher than the widely used drug cisplatin indicating that they have the potential to act as effective anticancer drugs in a time dependent manner. The morphological assessment data obtained by using Hoechst 33258 staining reveal that 3 and 4 induce apoptosis much more effectively than other complexes. Also, the alkaline single-cell gel electrophoresis study (comet assay) suggests that the same complexes induce DNA fragmentation more efficiently than others.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:51:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:51:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 44(22)10210-10227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4dt03879g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17978</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>