<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15961</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:34:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Time reversed Lamb wave for damage detection in a stiffened aluminum plate</dc:title><dc:creator>BIJUDAS, CR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUJUMDAR, PM</dc:creator><dc:subject>WAFER ACTIVE SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE PLATE</dc:subject><dc:description>According to the concept of time reversibility of the Lamb wave, in the absence of damage, a Lamb wave signal can be reconstructed at the transmitter location if a time reversed signal is sent back from the receiver location. This property is used for baseline-free damage detection, where the presence of damage breaks down the time reversibility and the mismatch between the reconstructed and the input signal is inferred as the presence of damage. This paper presents an experimental and a simulation study of baseline-free damage detection in a stiffened aluminum plate by time reversed Lamb wave (TRLW). In this study, single Lamb wave mode (A(0)) is generated and sensed using piezoelectric (PZT) transducers through specific transducer placement and amplitude tuning. Different stiffening configurations such as plane and T-stiffeners are considered. Damage cases of disbonding of stiffeners from the base plate, and vertical and embedded cracks in the stiffened plate, are studied. The results show that TRLW based schemes can efficiently identify the presence of damage in a stiffened plate.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:34:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:34:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS AND STRUCTURES, 22(10)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0964-1726/22/10/105026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15961</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>