<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9087</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Elastic scattering of electrons by polyatomic molecules in the energy range 300-1300 eV: CO, CO2, CH4, C2H4 and C2H6</dc:title><dc:creator>MAJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASAVARAJU, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARATHI, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHUSHAN, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHARE, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>differential cross-sections</dc:subject><dc:subject>intermediate energies</dc:subject><dc:subject>region</dc:subject><dc:subject>hcl</dc:subject><dc:subject>o2</dc:subject><dc:subject>h2</dc:subject><dc:description>Differential cross sections (DCS) for the elastic scattering of electrons have been measured by the crossed-beam technique for CO, CO2, CH4, C2H4 and C2H6 in the angular range 30 degrees-120 degrees and at impact energies of 300, 500, 700, 900, 1100 and 1300eV. The measurements were made with a view to test the validity of the independent atom model (IAM) for polyatomic molecules in this energy region. A comparison of experimental results with the IAM calculations indicates that the model is adequate for the linear molecules CO and CO2 in the energy region 900-1300 eV. The Born approximation for the evaluation of the atomic scattering amplitudes was found to be valid only at 1300 eV for all the molecules except for C2H6. A survey of the previous experimental and theoretical data based on different models shows that proper molecular wavefunctions have to be used for the evaluation of short-range potentials and that valence-bond distortion, absorption and non-adiabatic effects in the polarization potential have to be considered.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T16:34:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T16:34:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS B-ATOMIC MOLECULAR AND OPTICAL PHYSICS, 31(22), 4975-4990</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-4075</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-4075/31/22/009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9087</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>