<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9629</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental investigations on single stage, two stage and three stage conventional Savonius rotor</dc:title><dc:creator>KAMOJI, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEDARE, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>wind-tunnel tests</dc:subject><dc:subject>savonius rotor</dc:subject><dc:subject>single stage</dc:subject><dc:subject>two stage</dc:subject><dc:subject>three stage</dc:subject><dc:subject>coefficient of power (cp)</dc:subject><dc:subject>coefficient of torque (ct)</dc:subject><dc:subject>coefficient of static torque (cts)</dc:subject><dc:subject>rotor aspect ratio</dc:subject><dc:subject>stage aspect ratio</dc:subject><dc:description>The performance of single stage (rotor aspect ratio of 1.0), two stage Savonius rotor aspect ratios of 1.0 and 2.0 (stage aspect ratios of 0.50 and 1.0) and three stage Savonius rotor with rotor aspect ratios of 1.0 and 3.0 (stage aspect ratios of 0.33 and 1.0) are studied at different Reynolds numbers and compared at the same Reynolds number. The results show that the coefficient of power and the coefficient of torque increase with the increase in the Reynolds numbers for all the rotors tested. The coefficient of static torque is independent of the Reynolds number for all the rotors tested. The performance of two stage and three stage rotors remains the same even after increasing the stage aspect ratio and the rotor aspect ratio by a factor of two and three, respectively. For the same rotor aspect ratio of 1.0, by increasing the number of stages (stage aspect ratio decreases), the performance deteriorates in terms Cp and Ct. However, at the same stage aspect ratio of 1.0 and same Reynolds number, two and three stage rotors show the same performance in terms of coefficient of power and coefficient of torque. The variation in coefficient of static torque is lower for a three stage rotor when compared with the variation of coefficient of static torque for two stage or single stage rotor. Copyright (C) 2008 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T21:36:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T21:36:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ENERGY RESEARCH, 32(10), 877-895</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0363-907X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/er.1399</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9629</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9629</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>