<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14054</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:36:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>A sufficient condition for the existence of an anti-directed 2-factor in a directed graph</dc:title><dc:creator>DIWAN, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>FRYE, JB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PLANTHOLT, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIPNIS, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Anti-directed</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Directed graph</dc:subject><dc:description>Let D be a directed graph with vertex set V. arc set A, and order n. The graph underlying D is the graph obtained from D by replacing each arc (u. v) is an element of A by an undirected edge {u. v} land then replacing each double edge by a single edge. An anti-directed (hamiltonian) cycle H in D is a (hamiltonian) cycle in the graph underlying D such that no pair of consecutive arcs in H form a directed path in D. An anti-directed 2-factor in D is a vertex-disjoint collection of anti-directed cycles in D that span V. It was proved in Busch et al. (submitted for publication) [3] that if the indegree and the outdegree of each vertex of D is greater than 9/16 n then D contains an anti-directed Hamilton cycle. In this paper we prove that given a directed graph D, the problem of determining whether D has an anti-directed 2-factor is NP-complete, and we use a proof technique similar to the one used in Busch et al. (submitted for publication) [3] to prove that if the indegree and the outdegree of each vertex of D is greater than 24/46n then D contains an anti-directed 2-factor. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:36:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:36:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DISCRETE MATHEMATICS,311(21)2556-2562</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0012-365X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.disc.2011.07.033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14054</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>