<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15645</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:17:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Extending Light-Trails to Regional Networks: Multi-hop Light-Trails (MLT)-System Design and Performance</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAISHAMPAYAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, JP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOMANI, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>End-to-end delay</dc:subject><dc:subject>Light-trails</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metro optical networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multicast traffic</dc:subject><dc:subject>METRO OPTICAL NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:description>A light-trail is a generalization of a lightpath allowing multiple nodes to be able to communicate along the path, leading to all-optical spatial traffic grooming. A light-trail exhibits properties of dynamic bandwidth provisioning, optical multicasting and sub-wavelength grooming, and architecturally is analogous to a shared wavelength optical bus. Arbitration within the bus is conducted by an out-of-band control channel. The bus feature results in a node that has a large pass-through loss, restricting the size of a light-trail to metro environments. Due to this limitation, it is difficult to extend the light-trail concept to regional or core networks. In this paper we exhaustively investigate the concept of multi-hop light-trails (MLTs)-a method to provide multi-hop communication in light-trails, thus enhancing their reach. Node architecture and protocol requirements for creating MLTs are discussed. We then discuss design issues for MLTs in regional area networks through a problem formulation that is solved using convex optimization. The problem formulation takes into consideration issues such as routing MLTs as well as assigning connections (defined as sub-wavelength traffic requests) to MLTs. Two polynomial-time heuristic algorithms for creation of MLTs are presented. One of the algorithms is a static implementation, while the other is a dynamic implementation-with unknown traffic. A detailed delay analysis is also presented that enables computation of end-to-end delay over MLTs using different flow assignment algorithms. A simulation study validates the MLT concept.</dc:description><dc:publisher>OPTICAL SOC AMER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:17:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:17:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF OPTICAL COMMUNICATIONS AND NETWORKING, 4(12)1046-1061</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1364/JOCN.4.001046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15645</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>