<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12229</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-13T16:58:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling of spark erosion rate in microwire-EDM</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>wire-cut edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>wedm process</dc:subject><dc:subject>discharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>improvement</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>breakage</dc:subject><dc:subject>parts</dc:subject><dc:subject>microwire-edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>erosion rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>single-spark erosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>multi-spark erosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature distribution</dc:subject><dc:description>Micro-wire electro-discharge machining (WEDM) has been identified as a micromachining process for the fabrication of components of size down to the micrometer level. This process is derived from WEDM, and the principle of both the process is similar, yet due to significant scaling down of the micro-WEDM process, lots of modifications in the circuit design, wire diameter, stresses developed, and energy levels are needed. Hence, specific analysis and modeling of micro-WEDM process is required to understand its capability and limitations. Herein, a comprehensive mathematical model has been developed to incorporate plasma features, moving heat source characteristics, multispark phenomenon, and wire vibrational effect to predict the cathode erosion rate for a single-and multi-spark in micro-WEDM. The erosion rate evaluated by the model shows dependence on variables like voltage, wire diameter, number of sparks, and wire vibration but is independent of the wire velocity. The experimental validation of the model shows that the trends predicted by the model are logical and match fairly well with the experimental trends.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER LONDON LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T07:07:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T07:07:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ADVANCED MANUFACTURING TECHNOLOGY, 48(5-8), 581-596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-3768</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00170-009-2315-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12229</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12229</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>