<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2774</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of seepage on scour caused by impinging circular jets</dc:title><dc:creator>DUGAD, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANI, BS</dc:creator><dc:description>Circular jets impinging on a solid plane surface as well as the scour caused by it on a movable sand bed have been studied in the past. However, the effect of seepage on scour has not been included though it is important for many hydraulic structures. Hence, experimental investigations were undertaken to study the effect of upward seepage on the scour caused by an impinging circular submerged jet for a range of exit hydraulic gradients. The role of impingement height, velocity of jet and the time of scour were also investigated. The maximum scour depth produced by a jet in the presence of upward seepage is found to be somewhat less than that without seepage. The maximum scour depth is found to decrease with an increase in the value of exit gradient of seepage. For the range of investigations, the maximum scour depth is found to increase with an increase in the impingement height.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T23:36:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T23:36:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN HYDRAULICS AND WATER ENGINEERING, VOLS 1 AND 2, PROCEEDINGS,276-279</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>981-238-090-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16166</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2774</dc:identifier><dc:source>13th Congress of the Asia/Pacific Division of the International-Association-of-Hydraulic-Engineering-and-Research,SINGAPORE, SINGAPORE,AUG 06-08, 2002</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>