<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2697</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Priority scheduling in parallel I/O systems</dc:title><dc:creator>VENUGOPAL, CR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, SSSP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>priority queues</dc:subject><dc:subject>i/o systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>event-driven simulator</dc:subject><dc:subject>analytical model</dc:subject><dc:subject>priority scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>skewness</dc:subject><dc:description>Performance of I/O intensive applications on a multiprocessor system depends mostly on the variety of disk access delays encountered in the I/O system. With increasing processor speeds and multiprocessor organization, the demands on the I/O subsystem have been steadly growing. To obtain a better system performance it is necessary to improve the I/O performance. An event-driven parallel I/O simulator has been developed to evaluate the impact of delays in the parallel I/O system. Many I/O intensive applications have more read access than the write. We have proposed read priority I/O scheduling algorithm to such application programs. We have found 3% to 10% improvement in the I/O system performance. The results of the I/O simulator has been validated by an analytical model that we have developed. Analytical model results fairly agrees with simulator. Our results indicated that priority based I/O scheduling could be benificial to overall performance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>C S R E A PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T09:04:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T09:04:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PARALLEL AND DISTRIBUTED PROCESSING TECHNIQUES AND APPLICATIONS, VOLS I-V, PROCEEDINGS,2554-2560</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-892512-15-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16244</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2697</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Parallel and Distributed Processing Techniques and Applications (PDPTA 99),LAS VEGAS, NV,JUN 28-JUL 01, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>