<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12100</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Higher Himalayan Shear Zone, Sutlej section: structural geology and extrusion mechanism by various combinations of simple shear, pure shear and channel flow in shifting modes</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOYI, HA</dc:creator><dc:subject>main central thrust</dc:subject><dc:subject>south tibetan detachment</dc:subject><dc:subject>inverted metamorphism example</dc:subject><dc:subject>nepal himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>ductile shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>collision tectonics</dc:subject><dc:subject>manaslu leukogranite</dc:subject><dc:subject>zanskar himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>western zanskar</dc:subject><dc:subject>everest massif</dc:subject><dc:subject>higher himalayan shear zone</dc:subject><dc:subject>extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>ductile shearing</dc:subject><dc:subject>channel flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>brittle shearing</dc:subject><dc:subject>detachment</dc:subject><dc:description>The Higher Himalayan Shear Zone (HHSZ) in the Sutlej section reveals (1) top-to-SW ductile shearing, (2) top-to-NE ductile shearing in the upper- and the lower strands of the South Tibetan Detachment System (STDS(U), STDS(L)), and (3) top-to-SW brittle shearing corroborated by trapezoid-shaped minerals in micro-scale. In the proposed extrusion model of the HHSZ, the E(1)-phase during 25-19 Ma is marked by simple shearing of the upper sub-channel defined by the upper strand of the Main Central Thrust (MCT(U)) and the top of STDS(U) as the lower- and the upper boundaries, respectively. Subsequently, the E(2a)-pulse during 15-14 Ma was characterized by simple shear, pure shear, and channel flow of the entire HHSZ. Finally, the E(2b)-pulse during 14-12 Ma observed simple shearing and channel flow of the lower sub-channel defined by the lower strand of the Main Central Thrust (MCT(L)) and the top of the STDS(L) as the lower- and the upper boundaries, respectively. The model explains the constraints of thicknesses of the STDS(U) and the STDS(L) along with spatially variable extrusion rate and the inverted metamorphism of the HHSZ. The model predicts (1) shear strain after ductile extrusion to be maximum at the boundaries of the HHSZ, which crudely matches with the existing data. The other speculations that cannot be checked are (2) uniform shear strain from the MCT(U) to the top of the HHSZ in the E(1)-phase; (3) fastest rates of extrusion of the lower boundaries of the STDS(U) and the STDS(L) during the E(2a)- and E(2b)-pulses, respectively; and (4) variable thickness of the STDS(L) and rare absence of the STDS(U). Non-parabolic shear fabrics of the HHSZ possibly indicate heterogeneous strain. The top-to-SW brittle shearing around 12 Ma augmented the ductile extruded rocks to arrive a shallower depth. The brittle-ductile extension leading to boudinage possibly did not enhance the extrusion.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T13:49:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T13:49:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES, 99(6), 1267-1303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1437-3254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00531-009-0459-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12100</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>