<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9263</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of thermal and mechanical processing on room temperature mechanical properties of nickel free high nitrogen austenitic stainless steels</dc:title><dc:creator>BALACHANDRAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATIA, ML</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALLAL, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>nickel free austenitic stainless steels</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrogen steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>hall-petch relation</dc:subject><dc:subject>work-hardening</dc:subject><dc:subject>dbtt</dc:subject><dc:description>Nickel free high nitrogen austenitic stainless steels with a base composition around 18%Cr-18%Mn and varying in C and N contents and processing conditions were evaluated for their mechanical behaviour. A range of mechanical properties from high strengths to ultra high strength levels could be obtained. The steels develop ultra high strength levels in the as-hot worked condition, hot work+cold work condition and solution treated+cold worked conditions. They show high strength levels with very good ductility and impact roughness levels in the solution annealed condition. The Hall-Fetch parameters and DBTT obtained in the solution annealed condition were found to be influenced by the carbon content of the steel. The work hardening behaviour of the steels have been examined at various processing conditions. Nitrogen steels with high carbon content show good mechanical properties in the solution treated and subsequently cold rolled conditions. In the as-formed condition, the high carbon steels show inferior ductility due to grain boundary lamellar nitride precipitation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IRON STEEL INST JAPAN KEIDANREN KAIKAN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T05:52:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T05:52:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ISIJ INTERNATIONAL, 40(5), 501-510</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0915-1559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2355/isijinternational.40.501</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9263</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>