<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5651</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>PERIODIC OPERATION OF TRANSPORT REACTORS FOR CATALYTIC REACTIONS</dc:title><dc:creator>MIDHA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHIDAMBARAM, M</dc:creator><dc:description>The behaviour of a transport reactor is analyzed for an adsorption/desorption model with Langmuir-Hinshelwood surface kinetics for a reaction A + 2B --&gt; 3C and for a consecutive reaction A--&gt;k1B--&gt;k2C taking place on a bifunctional catalyst with series or parallel type poisoning. A square wave input in inlet concentration is considered. The effects of reaction rate constants, deactivation rate constants, and inlet feed mean concentration of the reactant on the yield of product are evaluated. For the reaction A + 2B --&gt; 3C, a significant improvement in the yield is obtained under periodic operation. The series reaction on a bifunctional catalyst, with a parallel poisoning and with a second order reaction with respect to reactant A, gives a significant improvement in the yield of product C. No significant improvement in the yield is obtained for series type poisoning, particularly for a lower value of K2. For a second order reaction with respect to B, both types of poisoning give a significant improvement in the yield.</dc:description><dc:publisher>COUNCIL SCIENTIFIC INDUSTRIAL RESEARCH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-20T21:09:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-20T21:09:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY, 2(1), 11-17</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-457X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5651</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5651</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>