<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3584</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>On quotients of posets, with an application to the q-analog of the hypercube</dc:title><dc:creator>SRINIVASAN, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>theorem</dc:subject><dc:subject>chains</dc:subject><dc:subject>order</dc:subject><dc:subject>sperner theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>group actions</dc:subject><dc:subject>quotients of posets</dc:subject><dc:subject>fixed points</dc:subject><dc:description>Let G be a finite group having an order preserving and rank preserving action on a finite ranked poset P. Let P/G denote the quotient poset. A well known result in algebraic Sperner theory asserts that an order raising G-linear map on V(P) (the complex vector space with P as basis) satisfying the full rank property induces an order raising linear map on V(P/G), also satisfying the full rank property. In this paper we prove a kind of converse result that has applications to Boolean algebras and their cubical and q-analogs. For a finite ranked poset P, let L denote the Lefschetz order raising map taking an element to the sum of the elements covering it and let P-i, 0 less than or equal to i less than or equal to n, where n = rank(P), denote the set of elements of rank i. We say that P is unitary Peck (respectively, unitary semi-Peck) if the map Ln-2i : V(P-i) --&gt; V(Pn-i), i &lt; n/2 is bijective (respectively, injective). We show that the q-analog of the n-cube is unitary semi-Peck. (C) 2003</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF COMBINATORICS, 25(5), 675-683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0195-6698</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ejc.2003.09.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3584</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3584</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>