<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15340</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:30:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Exploration of CH center dot center dot center dot pi mediated stacking interactions in saccharide: aromatic residue complexes through conformational sampling</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMARI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAJI, PV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Carbohydrates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Conformational analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Molecular mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Potential energy surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apolar patch</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saccharide specificity</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANALOG COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-SOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING-SITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BENZENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNITUDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLUCOSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORCE</dc:subject><dc:description>Saccharides interact with aromatic residues mostly through CH center dot center dot center dot pi mediated stacking interactions. The energetics of such interactions depends upon the mutual position-orientations (POs) of the two moieties. The POs found in the crystal structures are only a subset of the various possible ways of interaction. Hence, potential energy surfaces of saccharide-aromatic residue complexes have been explored by mixed Monte Carlo multiple minimum/low mode sampling. The saccharides considered in this study are alpha/beta-D-glucose, beta-D-galactose, alpha-D-mannose, and alpha/beta-L-fucose. p-Hydroxytoluene, toluene, and 3-methylindole were used as analogs of tyrosine, phenylalanine, and tryptophan, respectively. The saccharides interact from either above or below the pi-cloud of an aromatic ring but not along the edges. The POs preferred by different saccharides, both in the preferred chair and skew-boat forms, for interacting with different aromatic amino acid residue analogs have been identified. Aromatic residues can interact with the same -CH group in many POs but not so with the -OH groups. Changes in the configurations of pyranose ring carbon atoms cause remarkable changes in stacking preferences. beta-D-Galactose and beta-L-fructose interact only through their a- and b-faces, respectively. Saccharides use a wide variety of apolar patches for stacking against aromatic residues and these have been analyzed in detail. As many as four -CH groups can simultaneously participate in CH center dot center dot center dot pi interactions, especially with 3-methylindole owing to its larger surface area. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:30:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:30:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CARBOHYDRATE RESEARCH, 361133-140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.carres.2012.08.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15340</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>