<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12112</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interlaminar fracture characterization for plain weave fabric composites</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEDURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJU, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, PD</dc:creator><dc:creator>AZAD, SNM</dc:creator><dc:creator>OGDE, PA</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, BCK</dc:creator><dc:subject>mode</dc:subject><dc:subject>toughness</dc:subject><dc:subject>apparatus</dc:subject><dc:description>For the analysis of laminated composite plates under transverse loading and drilling of composites, all the elastic, strength and fracture properties of the composite plates are essential. Interlaminar critical strain energy release rate properties in mode I, mode II, mixed mode I/II and mode III have been evaluated for two types of plain weave fabric E-glass/epoxy laminates. The double cantilever beam test and the end notch flexure test have been used for mode I and mode II loading. The mixed mode bending test and split cantilever beam test have been used for mixed mode I/II and mode III loading. It is observed that the plain weave fabric composite with lesser strand width has higher interlaminar fracture properties compared to the plain weave fabric composite with more strand width. Further, crack length versus crack growth resistance plots have been presented for mode III loading. In general, it is observed that total fracture resistance is significantly higher than the critical strain energy release rate. (C) 2002 Kluwer Academic Publishers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T14:41:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T14:41:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 37(14), 2983-2987</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-2461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1016025232102</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12112</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12112</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>