<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10049</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Creation of English and Hindi Verb Hierarchies and their Application to Hindi WordNet Building and English-Hindi MT</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, P</dc:creator><dc:description>Verbs form the pivots of sentences. However, they have not received as much attention as nouns did in the ontology and lexical semantics research. The classification of verbs and placing them in a structure according to their selectional preference and other semantic properties seem essential in most text information processing tasks like machine translation, information extraction etc. The present paper describes the construction of a verb hierarchy using Beth Levin's verb classes for English, the hypernymy hierarchy of the WordNet and the constructs and the knowledge base of the Universal Networking Language (UNL) which is a recently proposed interlingua. These ideas have been translated into the building of a verb hierarchy for Hindi. The application of this hierarchy to the construction of the Hindi WordNet is discussed. The overall motivation for this work is the task of machine translation between English and Hindi.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MASARYKOVA UNIV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T14:35:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T14:35:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GWC 2004: SECOND INTERNATIONAL WORDNET CONFERENCE, PROCEEDINGS, (), 83-90</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10049</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10049</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>