<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9680</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Response of SDOF system to non-stationary earthquake excitation</dc:title><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>duration</dc:subject><dc:subject>motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>sdof system</dc:subject><dc:subject>non-stationary</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>modulating function</dc:subject><dc:description>Earthquake excitation is often modelled by non-stationary random process (i.e. uniformly modulated broad-band excitation) for analysis of structural safety subjected to seismic hazards. In this paper, the non-stationary response of a single-degree-of-freedom (SDOF) system to non-stationary earthquake motion is investigated for different shapes of modulating functions. The evolutionary power-spectral density function (PSDF) of the displacement of the SDOF system is obtained using the time-varying frequency response function and the PSDF of the earthquake excitation. The close form expressions for time-varying frequency response function are derived for different shapes of the modulating functions. In order to study the effects of the shape of the modulating function, a comparison of the non-stationary earthquake response of the SDOF system is also made for different modulating functions having the same energy content. Copyright (C) 2004 John Wiley Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T00:32:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T00:32:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING &amp; STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS, 33(15), 1417-1428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-8847</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/eqe.409</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9680</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9680</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>