<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1558</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of paclitaxel penetration in normal and cancerous cervical model monolayer membranes</dc:title><dc:creator>PREETHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HUILGOL, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>physiological models</dc:subject><dc:subject>langmuir blodgett films</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug products</dc:subject><dc:subject>tumors</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of the present study was to evaluate the penetration of paclitaxel in normal as well as cancerous human cervical monolayer membranes and to compare these results with the paclitaxel penetration in a model dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC) monolayer. At physiologically relevant surface pressures of 30 mN/m, equilibrium drug penetration was observed in DPPC model membrane, whereas in cervical lipid model membranes exclusion of the drug and destabilization of the membrane was observed. The maximum surface pressure increment due to penetration (Δπmax) of 600 nM paclitaxel, for DPPC monolayer was found to be 3.6, 5.4 and 5.0 times higher than those for penetration in the cancerous monolayer at surface pressures 10, 20 and 30 mN/m, respectively. At initial surface pressure 10 mN/m, the maximum surface pressure increment, for 600 nM paclitaxel penetration, of normal cervical lipid membrane was double that of the cancerous cervical lipid membrane. At 30 mN/m initial surface pressure the representative IC50 concentration of the drug produced negligible drug penetration and significant membrane destabilization in cervical lipid model membranes. The difference in penetration profile could be due to differences in composition of the model membranes. The cholesterol level in cancerous cervical membrane was 1.5-folds higher than that in the normal cervical membrane. Apart from PC, another constituent present in 20-32% in cancerous and normal membranes is sphingomyelin (SM). Introduction of 70% SM to the DPPC monolayer decreased the Δπmax from 4.7 to 1.1 mN/m, revealing the rigidifying effect of SM which was directly proportional to the amount of SM added. Modulation of fluidity of the membranes can alter the penetration of paclitaxel in biological membranes and hence its toxicity profile.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-22T04:42:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:13:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-22T04:42:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:13:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Colloids and Surfaces B: Biointerfaces 53(2), 179-186</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>09277765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.colsurfb.2006.09.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1558</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>