<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17955</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:39:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Autoantibody Profiling of Glioma Serum Samples to Identify Biomarkers Using Human Proteome Arrays</dc:title><dc:creator>SYED, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHARY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDALA, NG</dc:creator><dc:creator>ATAK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RICHHARIA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANUBHAI, KP</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHU, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>EPARI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NORONHA, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOIYADI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>TOLL-LIKE RECEPTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOCAL ADHESION KINASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLIOBLASTOMA-MULTIFORME</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMMUNOGLOBULIN-G</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBVENTRICULAR ZONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MALIGNANT GLIOMAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELL-MIGRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUMOR-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURVIVAL</dc:subject><dc:description>The heterogeneity and poor prognosis associated with gliomas, makes biomarker identification imperative. Here, we report autoantibody signatures across various grades of glioma serum samples and sub-categories of glioblastoma multiforme using Human Proteome chips containing similar to 17000 fulllength human proteins. The deduced sets of classifier proteins helped to distinguish Grade II, III and IV samples from the healthy subjects with 88, 89 and 94% sensitivity and 87, 100 and 73% specificity, respectively. Proteins namely, SNX1, EYA1, PQBP1 and IGHG1 showed dysregulation across various grades. Sub-classes of GBM, based on its proximity to the sub-ventricular zone, have been reported to have different prognostic outcomes. To this end, we identified dysregulation of NEDD9, a protein involved in cell migration, with probable prognostic potential. Another subcategory of patients where the IDH1 gene is mutated, are known to have better prognosis as compared to patients carrying the wild type gene. On a comparison of these two cohorts, we found STUB1 and YWHAH proteins dysregulated in Grade II glioma patients. In addition to common pathways associated with tumourigenesis, we found enrichment of immunoregulatory and cytoskeletal remodelling pathways, emphasizing the need to explore biochemical alterations arising due to autoimmune responses in glioma.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:39:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:39:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, 5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2045-2322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep13895</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17955</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>