<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11214</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>RAPID SOLIDIFICATION FOLLOWING LASER MELTING OF PURE METALS .1. STUDY OF FLOW FIELD AND ROLE OF CONVECTION</dc:title><dc:creator>BASU, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATE, AW</dc:creator><dc:subject>steady-state</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat-transfer</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper is concerned with the numerical predictions of characteristics of rapid solidification following laser melting. The numerical model is based on the enthalpy formulation to account for the latent heat release during solidification and the momentum equations are solved by the SIMPLE algorithm in the liquid domain only. With different laser powers (10(8) and 10(9) W m-2) and interaction times, the flow field and the temperature distribution within the liquid pool during rapid solidification are studied for aluminium and steel. The flow field is observed to die out very soon after the laser beam is removed. At higher power, the liquid pool remains very deep in the case of aluminium for a relatively long time due to a large secondary vortex formed during melting. Although the shape of the interface is different, there is a marginal difference in the total solidification times with and without convection for both the metals.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T05:50:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T05:50:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 35(5), 1049-1058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0017-9310(92)90165-O</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11214</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11214</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>