<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10711</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Determination of influence of various parameters on thermal properties of soils</dc:title><dc:creator>KRISHNAIAH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>heat-pulse method</dc:subject><dc:subject>probe</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistivity</dc:subject><dc:description>Determination of thermal properties of soils such as diffusivity, thermal resistivity and specific heat is important for various civil and electrical engineering applications such as heat loss from basements of buildings, underground soil heating, nuclear waste facilities and design of buried cables etc. These properties are also required for estimating transport of heat through the soil mass. With this in view a device, termed as thermal property detector, which can be used to determine thermal properties of various soils has been developed and its details are presented in this paper. The efficiency of this device has been established by comparing the results obtained by using the response of the laboratory thermal probe (single probe method). Based on rigorous experimentation, attempts have been made to demonstrate the influence of various parameters on thermal properties of soils such as their type, the dry density, the total density and the moisture content. (C) 2003 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T01:12:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T01:12:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL COMMUNICATIONS IN HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 30(6), 861-870</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0735-1933</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0735-1933(03)00134-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10711</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10711</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>