<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14181</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:28:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>An analysis of beta type Stirling engine with rhombic drive mechanism</dc:title><dc:creator>SHENDAGE, DJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEDARE, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAPAT, SL</dc:creator><dc:subject>Stirling engine</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rhombic drive</dc:subject><dc:subject>Overlapping volume</dc:subject><dc:description>Stirling engine system is one of the options for electrifying a remote community not serviceable by the grid, which can operate on energy input in the form of heat. Major hurdle for the wide-spread usage of rhombic drive beta type Stirling engine is complexity of the drive and requirement of tight tolerances for its proper functioning. However, if the operating and geometrical constraints of the system are accounted for, different feasible design options can be identified. In the present work, various aspects that need to be considered at different decision making stages of the design and development of a Stirling engine are addressed. The proposed design methodology can generate and evaluate a range of possible design alternatives which can speed up the decision making process and also provide a clear understanding of the system design considerations. The present work is mainly about the design methodology for beta type Stirling engine and the optimization of phase angle, considering the effect of overlapping volume between compression and expansion spaces. It is also noticed that variation of compression space volume with phase angle remains sinusoidal for any phase difference. The aim of the present work is to find a feasible solution which should lead to a design of a single cylinder, beta type Stirling engine of 1.5 kW(e) capacity for rural electrification. (c) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:28:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:28:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RENEWABLE ENERGY,36(1)289-297</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-1481</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2010.06.041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14181</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>