<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-326</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>A low-power and compact analog CMOS processing chip for portable ECG recorders</dc:title><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAL, RAKESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:subject>cmos analogue integrated circuit</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrocardiography</dc:subject><dc:subject>image recording</dc:subject><dc:subject>low pass filters</dc:subject><dc:subject>signal processing</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a three-channel low-power and compact analog processor including a test chip, fabricated in TSMC 0.35mum mixed-mode CMOS process, for portable electrocardiogram (ECG) monitoring devices. The chip highlights integrating CMOS instrumentation amplifiers based on current balancing technique to implement more analog signal conditioning functions at instrumentation amplifiers. First order low-pass filtering as well as programmable high-pass filtering has been included in each instrumentation amplifier. Experimental results show that each channel draws 22muA from a 3.3V battery. Measurement results satisfy recommended specifications for portable ECG recorders. The programmable test board designed using the chip, records three-leads ECG with frontal plane and precordial leads. Analog signal conditioning circuit, measurement results and recorded ECGs are given in this paper.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-15T10:38:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T12:52:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-15T10:38:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T12:52:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Asian Solid-State Circuits Conference, Hsinchu, Taiwan, 1-3 November 2005, 473-476</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-9163-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ASSCC.2005.251768</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/326</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/326</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>