<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5977</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>An analytical approach for predicting fin performance of triangular fins subject to simultaneous heat and mass transfer</dc:title><dc:creator>KUNDU, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BARMAN, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEBNATH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat exchanger</dc:subject><dc:subject>dehumidification</dc:subject><dc:subject>air</dc:subject><dc:subject>finned tube</dc:subject><dc:subject>geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>fin</dc:subject><dc:subject>modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:description>The present model established analytically analyzes the performance of a triangular fin under dehumidifying conditions satisfying a cubic polynomial relationship between specific humidity and the corresponding saturation temperature. A differential transform method has been adopted for solving the nonlinear governing differential equation of fully wet fins. The result obtained from the present model has been compared with that from the previous model, and a significant difference in results has been noticed. From the present result, it can also be highlighted that the fin performance of wet fins is almost independent on the relative humidity. In comparison with the previous model, the present model shows always better results while analyzing the wet fin irrespective of any design condition. However, this superiority in results decreases with the decrease in both relative humidity and difference in temperature between the dew point and that at the base of the fin. (C) 2008 Elsevier Ltd and IIR. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T20:10:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T20:10:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF REFRIGERATION-REVUE INTERNATIONALE DU FROID, 31(6), 1113-1120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0140-7007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijrefrig.2008.01.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5977</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5977</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>