<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2192</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Co-relation between capacitance-voltage, conductance-voltage and photoconductive properties of the as-deposited and annealed a-Si/SIN(X) multilayer films prepared using hot-wire cvd</dc:title><dc:creator>PANCHAL, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAI, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:description>In this paper, the electrical properties of the as-deposited and the annealed a-Si/SiN(X) multilayer (ML) films are compared. The a-Si/SiN(X) ML films are prepared at 250 degrees C using hot-wire chemical vapor deposition (HWCVD) technique. Silicon quantum dots (Si-QDs) are formed in the a-Si layers of ML films upon annealing at 850 degrees C. Metal insulator semiconductor (MIS) structures containing the ML films are characterized with high frequency capacitance-voltage (C-V), conductance-voltage (G-V) and photo-current measurements. These characterizations show that the annealed ML films have high defects centers than the as-deposited ML films. A shift in the C-V plot and a peak shift in the G-V plot for the annealed ML film are due to the charge storage in the defects centers and the quantized states of Si-QDs. The defect centers introduced low photo-response for the annealed ML film (Si-QD structure) than the as-deposited ML films.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T07:16:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T07:16:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>35TH IEEE PHOTOVOLTAIC SPECIALISTS CONFERENCE,</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-5891-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0160-8371</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15642</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2192</dc:identifier><dc:source>35th IEEE Photovoltaic Specialists Conference,Honolulu, HI,JUN 20-25, 2010</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>