<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10095</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Recent trends in coatings for high temperature applications</dc:title><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATTANAIK, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>mild-steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrosion behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>stainless-steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>chromium</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel</dc:subject><dc:description>Many components operating at high temperatures need additional protection to resist the aggressive environment This is usually provided by coatings which impart excellent corrosion resistance by forming a protective alumina, chromia or silica scales. The requirement of coating varies from one application to the other, depending upon the environment, whether it is oxidising, sulphidizing or in the presence of salt deposits. The coatings at high temperatures. must have low reaction rates with the environment, and also remain adherent and form protective oxides at the temperature of operation. Most of these coatings are divided into three main categories, conventional coatings, modified coatings and advanced coatings. Conventional coatings such as aluminide, silicides very commonly fail in aggressive environments. Advanced coatings are by vacuum plasma method, HVOF, laser surface alloying, plasma powder welding and ion beam assisted coatings. Laser surface alloying is being considered as the most versatile technique which can be used to make high performance surface alloys. This helps in saving huge cost of costly materials, which are un-necessarily used in bulk alloying as well as the processing does not interfere with the bulk properties.</dc:description><dc:publisher>METAL FINISHERS ASSOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T18:06:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T18:06:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE METAL FINISHERS ASSOCIATION OF INDIA, 6(3), 187-205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-5304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10095</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10095</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>