<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17075</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T18:11:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic Loss Inclusion in the Jiles-Atherton (JA) Hysteresis Model Using the Original JA Approach and the Field Separation Approach</dc:title><dc:creator>BAGHEL, APS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Dynamic losses</dc:subject><dc:subject>field separation approach (FSA)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jiles-Atherton (JA) model</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERROMAGNETIC HYSTERESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOOPS</dc:subject><dc:description>Magnetic materials exhibit non-linear, hysteretic, and dynamic characteristics due to presence of classical eddy and anomalous losses. Various dynamic models based on the original Jiles-Atherton (JA) approach have been reported in the literature but they show a physical uncertainty about their energy considerations. These models show some non-physical situations in the form of vertical lengthening of hysteresis loops. This paper presents two inverse dynamic models based on the JA approach and the field separation theory. It explains the energy aspects of the JA model and suggests an alternative approach based on the field separation for inclusion of dynamic losses. Comparisons of performances of the two models on measured dynamic hysteresis loops for non-oriented and grain-oriented materials are given. The model based on the field separation theory is shown to give physically correct loop shapes for both materials.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:11:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:11:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON MAGNETICS, 50(2)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9464</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1941-0069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TMAG.2013.2284381</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17075</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>