<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2792</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Three dimensional finite element analysis of laterally loaded pile group</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEWAIKAR, DM</dc:creator><dc:description>A three dimensional finite element analysis is proposed for studying the response of pile groups embedded in homogenous clays, subjected to lateral load. Two ways of carrying out finite element analysis are suggested-one by finite element formulation and other by using the finite element analysis software ANSYS. Analysis is carried out for two as well as three pile groups. A parametric study of the pile group is carried out by varying the spacing and arrangement of piles in the group. The results show that the lateral load resistance of the pile group increases with increase in the spacing of piles. Also, the parallel arrangement of piles have greater lateral load resistance than piles in series. Results obtained by finite element formulation as well as by ANSYS are consistent and show agreement with the field behaviour of pile groups.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A A BALKEMA PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T01:16:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T01:16:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOSHORE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON OFFSHORE AND NEARSHORE GEOTECHNICAL ENGINEERING,315-319</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-5809-211-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16192</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2792</dc:identifier><dc:source>Geoshore International Conference on Offshore and Nearshore Geotechnical Engineering,PANVEL, INDIA,DEC 02-03, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>