<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17453</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:05:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Quotations in Grammatical Texts and the Tradition of Manuscript Transmission of the Kasikavrtti</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Kasikavrtti</dc:subject><dc:subject>Text of the Astadhyayi</dc:subject><dc:subject>Later Paninian grammatical tradition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manuscript transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>Textual reuse</dc:subject><dc:description>The Kasikavrtti, the oldest available complete commentary on Panini's grammar, the Astadhyayi, is found quoted often in the later Paninian grammatical tradition. These quotations throw light on a number of aspects of the text of the Kasikavrtti. This paper focuses on how this later Paninian grammatical tradition views the modifications in the text of the Adyadhyayi (generally ascribed to the text of Kasikavrtti by modern scholarship) and concludes that also the tradition ascribes these modifications to the Kasikavrtti. Further, this paper also attempts to show that these quotations can be shown to have interacted with the manuscript tradition of the Kasikavrtti and indeed with the help of these quotations it becomes easier to better understand the manuscript transmission of the Kasikavrtti. Thus, this article focuses on one of the applications of the study of quotations: through an analysis of the content of the quoted passages of the Kasikavrtti (hereafter KV) in later Grammatical literature, it discusses the history of the transmission of the KV and of the text it comments upon, i.e., Panini's Astadhyayi. It also shows how a study of quotations is an unavoidable complement of the analysis of manuscripts for scholars aiming at the reconstruction of texts so remote in time.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:05:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:05:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF INDIAN PHILOSOPHY, 43(42038SI)183-190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-1791</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-0395</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10781-014-9236-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17453</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>