<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4963</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Uncertainties in Geologic Profiles versus Variability in Pile Founding Depth</dc:title><dc:creator>ZHANG, LM</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASAKA, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>driven piles</dc:subject><dc:subject>weathered soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>construction</dc:subject><dc:subject>geology</dc:subject><dc:subject>pile foundations</dc:subject><dc:subject>pile driving</dc:subject><dc:subject>reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>site investigation</dc:subject><dc:subject>spatial analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>uncertainty principles</dc:subject><dc:description>How the design and actual founding depths of foundations correspond to the variability of geological conditions has long been a concern. This paper evaluates the spatial variability characteristics of as-built and estimated founding depths of driven steel H piles with reference to the spatial variability characteristics of geologic profiles at a weathered soil site in Hong Kong. Spatial variability characteristics are evaluated in terms of variance and scale of fluctuation. The variability of three founding depth indicators, i.e., the depth of Grade-III bedrock, the depth of standard penetration test blow count "N" of 200 blows/0.3 m (SPT-200), and the depth of completely decomposed granite over the site was estimated. It is found that pile founding depths exhibit greater variations than those of the geologic profiles due to the presence of design model errors, judgment errors, and construction effects. The as-built founding depths are mostly between the SPT-200 profile and the Grade-III bedrock profile. The variances of as-built pile length are similar to those with depth of SPT-200 but less than those with depth of Grade-III bedrock. The scale of fluctuation of as-built pile length is on the order of 20 m when kriging is used and 10 m when kriging is not used, which are less than those with depths of SPT-200 and Grade-III bedrock.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T15:10:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T15:10:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEOTECHNICAL AND GEOENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEERING, 136(11), 1475-1488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1090-0241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)GT.1943-5606.0000364</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4963</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4963</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>