<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1071</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis and spectral properties of N4, N3S, and N2S2 porphyrins containing one, two, three, and four meso-furyl groups</dc:title><dc:creator>SANTOSH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>porphyrins</dc:subject><dc:subject>meso-furyl</dc:subject><dc:description>Porphyrins with N4, N3S, and N2S2 cores having one, two, three, and four furyl groups at the meso-positions were synthesized by following various methodologies and characterized by using mass spectrometry, NMR spectroscopy, elemental analysis, absorption, and fluorescence spectroscopic techniques. NMR studies indicated that by replacing the meso-aryl groups with meso-furyl groups, the β-pyrrole and β-thiophene protons of porphyrins experienced considerable downfield shifts, supporting the alteration of π-delocalization of porphyrins on the introduction of meso-furyl groups. The absorption and emission bands of porphyrins experienced red shifts on the introduction of meso-furyl groups and the magnitude of red shifts vary linearly with the number of meso-furyl groups. Thus, the spectral studies supported a systematic alteration in spectral properties on successive introduction of meso-furyl groups.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-23T05:13:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-23T05:13:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Tetrahedron 63(33), 7833-7844</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-4020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tet.2007.05.099</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1071</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1071</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>