<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15094</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:23:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Lithological discrimination of the Phenaimata felsic-mafic complex, Gujarat, India, using the Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER)</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>IMAGING SPECTROMETER DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMBA DONGAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROCKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENHANCEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>INFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSTRUMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOUNTAINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUSTRALIA</dc:subject><dc:description>This study deals with an evaluation of the efficacy of an Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER) image for lithological mapping. ASTER level-1B data in the visible near-infrared (VNIR), short wave infrared (SWIR) and thermal infrared (TIR) regions have been processed to generate a lithological map of the study area in and around the Phenaimata igneous complex, in mainland Gujarat, India. ASTER band combinations, band ratio images and spectral angle mapper (SAM) processing techniques were evaluated for mapping various lithologies. The reflectance and emissivity spectra of rock samples collected from the study area were obtained in the laboratory and were used as reference spectra for ASTER image analysis. The original data in the scaled digital number (DN) values were converted to radiance and then to relative reflectance by using a scene-derived correction technique prior to SAM classification. The SAM classification in the VNIR-SWIR region is found to be effective in differentiating felsic and mafic lithologies. The relative band depth (RBD) images were generated from the continuum-removed images of ASTER VNIR-SWIR bands. Four RBD combinations (3, 5, 6 and 8) were used to identify Al-OH (aluminium hydroxide), Fe-OH (iron hydroxide), Mg-OH (magnesium hydroxide) and CO(3) (carbonate) absorption from various lithological components. ASTER TIR spectral emittance data and the laboratory emissivity measurements show the presence of a number of discrete Si-O spectral features that can differentiate mafic and felsic rock types reflecting the lithological diversity around the regions of Phenaimata igneous complex. SAM classification using emittance data failed to distinguish the felsic and mafic lithology due to the wider spectral bandwidth. The felsic class comprises the granitoid composition of rocks. RBD12 and 13 images in the TIR region were used to derive the mafic index (MI) and the silica index (SI). The MI shows the highest value in regions of gabbro-basalt occurrence, while the SI indicates regions of high silica content. The MI is lowest in regions where granophyres occur. The complimentary attributes based on the spectral reflectance and emittance data resulted in the discrimination of silica-rich and silica-poor lithologies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:23:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:23:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF REMOTE SENSING, 33(1)198-219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2011.591441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15094</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>