<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10127</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic Performance of Benchmark Highway Bridge with Variable Friction Pendulum System</dc:title><dc:creator>MADHEKAR, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>structural control-problem</dc:subject><dc:subject>benchmark highway bridge</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic isolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>friction pendulum system</dc:subject><dc:subject>friction coefficient</dc:subject><dc:subject>variable friction pendulum system</dc:subject><dc:description>Dynamic response of a benchmark highway bridge isolated with variable friction pendulum system (VFPS) is investigated under six earthquake motions. The study is based on the finite-element model of the benchmark highway bridge in California. The seismic response of bridge isolated with VFPS is compared with the conventional friction pendulum system (FPS). A parametric study is carried out to study the effects of the maximum coefficient of friction, initial time period and isolation period of VFPS. The response of bridge is also compared with the corresponding uncontrolled case, with FPS, and that controlled by alternate sample control strategies. It is concluded that with the installation of VFPS, the seismic response of the bridge under near-fault motions can be controlled significantly. The VFPS is quite effective in reducing the peak response quantities of the bridge to a level comparable to / better than that of the sample controllers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MULTI-SCIENCE PUBL CO LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T20:36:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T20:36:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN STRUCTURAL ENGINEERING, 13(4), 561-589</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1369-4332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10127</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10127</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>