<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12219</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T03:26:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>A case-based and practical approach for multivariate modeling of grinding process</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>neural-network approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>working-conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>process parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface-roughness</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>operations</dc:subject><dc:subject>selections</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>grinding</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiresponse</dc:subject><dc:subject>multivariate modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>multivariate regression</dc:subject><dc:subject>artificial neural network</dc:subject><dc:description>Grinding process is claimed to be the only possible cost-effective means of shaping engineering part(s) or component(s) into finished products with required surface topology. However, because of the complicated relationship(s) between several phenomena and entities involved in a grinding process, determining functional relationship between relevant input(s), in-process variable(s), and output quality characteristic [or response] remains a critical and difficult task for researchers and practitioners. The complexity of the problem further increases as number of responses considered for modeling is more than one, and the situation is so-called multivariate or multiresponse surface modeling. Although various mechanistic and empirical modeling approaches have been proposed in literature, they are found to be of limited validity, with applied functional approximation and simplistic assumption(s). In addition, empirical models are sometimes based on off-line designed experimental data, which are expensive or uneconomical in many line layout type mass-manufacturing situations. This paper attempts to provide a case-based practical approach for practitioners, with detailed steps involved in multivariate modeling, based on conventional regression technique, and unconventional artificial neural network-based technique, using real-time production data. The two case examples selected to verify the approaches are from an automobile engine manufacturing unit located in eastern India.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER LONDON LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T06:27:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T06:27:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ADVANCED MANUFACTURING TECHNOLOGY, 45(3-4), 245-260</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-3768</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00170-009-1977-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12219</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>