<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3985</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimum Design of Battery-Integrated Diesel Generator Systems Incorporating Demand Uncertainty</dc:title><dc:creator>ARUN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>heat-exchanger design</dc:subject><dc:subject>power-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>space</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>cost</dc:subject><dc:description>A diesel generator system, integrated with battery, is one of the options for decentralized power production in remote locations. The principles of process system engineering along with the concept of design space approach for system design have been employed to optimize a battery integrated diesel generator system. The design space is the set of all feasible design options, generated using time series simulation of the entire system. In this paper, a methodology is proposed to appropriately size a battery integrated diesel generator system incorporating uncertainty associated with the demand. Chance constrained programming approach is combined with the design space approach to incorporate the demand uncertainty at the design stage. With a known distribution of the demand, the proposed methodology helps in identifying a sizing curve on the diesel generator rating versus storage capacity diagram for a specified reliability level. The system reliability values given by the proposed approach are validated using sequential Monte Carlo simulation approach through illustrative examples. Sets of sizing curves may be generated for different confidence levels as required by the designer. However, under the simplified assumption of a constant coefficient of variation for the demand, these sizing curves can be combined into a single curve. The cost of energy of the system is minimized to select the optimum configuration for different reliability levels.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T14:40:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T14:40:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 48(10), 4908-4916</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie8014236</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3985</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3985</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>