<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15707</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:49:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Observation of Ferromagnetic Exchange, Spin Crossover, Reductively Induced Oxidation, and Field-Induced Slow Magnetic Relaxation in Monomeric Cobalt Nitroxides</dc:title><dc:creator>GASS, IA</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAFADY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHILTON, NF</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARTSHORE, CJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASADI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LUPTON, DW</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOUBARAKI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOND, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOAS, JF</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUO, SX</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURRAY, KS</dc:creator><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEUTRON-SCATTERING SPECTRA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE MAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAUSSIAN-BASIS SETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON DELOCALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIS(NITROXYL) ADDUCTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITED-STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY-LEVELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHAIN MAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATOMS LI</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of [Co-II(NO3)(2)]center dot 6H(2)O with the nitroxide radical, 4-dimethyl-2,2-di(2-pyridyl) oxazolidine-N-oxide (L-center dot), produces the mononuclear transition-metal complex [Co-II(L-center dot)(2)](NO3)(2) (1), which has been investigated using temperature-dependent magnetic susceptibility, electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy, electrochemistry, density functional theory (DFT) calculations, and variable-temperature X-ray structure analysis. Magnetic susceptibility measurements and X-ray diffraction (XRD) 'analysis reveal a central low-spin octahedral Co2+ ion with both ligands in the neutral radical form (L-center dot) forming a linear L-center dot center dot center dot center dot Co(II)center dot center dot center dot L-center dot arrangement. This shows a host of interesting magnetic properties including strong cobalt-radical and radical-radical intramolecular ferromagnetic interactions stabilizing a S = 3/2 ground state, a thermally induced spin crossover transition above 200 K and field-induced slow magnetic relaxation. This is supported by variable-temperature EPR spectra, which suggest that 1 has a positive D value and nonzero E values, suggesting the possibility of a field-induced transverse anisotropy barrier. DFT calculations support the parallel alignment of the two radical pi*No orbitals with a small orbital overlap leading to radical-radical ferromagnetic interactions while the cobalt-radical interaction is computed to be strong and ferromagnetic. In the high-spin (HS) case, the DFT calculations predict a weak antiferrornagnetic cobalt-radical interaction, whereas the radical-radical interaction is computed to be large and ferromagnetic. The monocationic complex [Co-III(L-)(2)](BPh4) (2) is formed by a rare, reductively induced oxidation of the Co center and has been fully characterized by X-ray structure analysis and magnetic measurements revealing a diamagnetic ground state. Electrochemical studies on 1 and 2 revealed common Co-redox intermediates and the proposed mechanism is compared and contrasted with that of the Fe analogues.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:49:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:49:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 52(13)7557-7572</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic400565h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15707</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>