<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1888</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Towards a characterisation of finite-state message-passing systems</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKUND, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, KN</dc:creator><dc:creator>RADHAKRISHNAN, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOHONI, M</dc:creator><dc:description>We investigate an automata-theoretic model of distributed systems which communicate via message-passing. Each node in the system is a finite-state device. Channels are assumed to be reliable but may deliver messages out of order. Hence, each channel is modelled as a set of counters, one for each type of message. These counters may not be tested for zero. Though each node in the network is finite-state, the overall system is potentially infinite-state because the counters are unbounded. We work in an interleaved setting where the interactions of the system with the environment are described as sequences. The behaviour of a system is described in terms of the language which it accepts--that is, the set of valid interactions with the environment that are permitted by the system. Our aim is to characterise the class of message-passing systems whose behaviour is finite-state. Our main result is that the language accepted by a message-passing system is regular if and only if both the language and its complement are accepted by message-passing systems. We also exhibit an alternative characterisation of regular message-passing languages in terms of deterministic automata.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:50:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:50:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN COMPUTING SCIENCE-ASIAN' 98,1538,282-299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>3-540-65388-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1888</dc:identifier><dc:source>4th Asian Computing Science Conference (ASIAN 98),MANILA, PHILIPPINES,DEC 08-10, 1998</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>