<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8286</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design of simultaneously stabilizing controllers and its application to fault-tolerant lane-keeping controller design for automated vehicles</dc:title><dc:creator>SURYANARAYANAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOMIZUKA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUZUKI, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>time-invariant plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>automated highways</dc:subject><dc:subject>fault tolerance</dc:subject><dc:subject>h-infinity control</dc:subject><dc:subject>linear matrix inequality (lmi)</dc:subject><dc:subject>simultaneous stability</dc:subject><dc:description>Simultaneous stabilization deals with the following question: given a finite number of LTI plants P-1, P-2, (.) (.) (.), P-k does there exist a single LTI controller C such that each of the feedback interconnections (P-i, C) (i = 1, 2, (. . .) , k) is internally stable? This paper presents a new methodology for the design of simultaneously stabilizing controllers for two or more plants that satisfy a sufficient condition. A classic result from simultaneous-stability theory is invoked to cast the sufficient condition as a linear matrix inequality (LMI). It is shown that in this setting, the problem of design of simultaneously stabilizing controllers can be reduced to that of a standard H-infinity control problem. The technique developed is applied to the design of a fault-tolerantcontroller for lane-keeping control of automated vehicles. The controller makes the system insensitive to a failure in either one of two lateral error measuring sensors used for lane-keeping control. Experimental results confirm the efficacy of the design and reinforce analytical predictions of performance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T00:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T00:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON CONTROL SYSTEMS TECHNOLOGY, 12(3), 329-339</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1063-6536</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TCST.2004.825130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8286</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>