<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17967</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:45:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of non-covalent modification of multiwalled carbon nanotubes on the crystallization behaviour of binary blends of polypropylene and polyamide 6</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANWAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>ACRYLONITRILE-BUTADIENE-STYRENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO-CONTINUOUS BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISOTACTIC POLYPROPYLENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-MODIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRACTIONATED CRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RHEOLOGICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPATIBILIZED BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MELTING BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:description>Blends of polypropylene (PP) and polyamide 6 (PA6) with multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) were prepared using different processing strategies in a twin-screw micro-compounder. The effect of MWNTs on the crystallization behaviour of the PP phase and the PA6 phase of the blend has been investigated through non-isothermal crystallization studies by differential scanning calorimetric analysis. Furthermore, the effect of the addition of the compatibilizer (PP-g-MA) and the modification of MWNTs (m-MWNTs) with a non-covalent organic modifier (Li-salt of 6 amino hexanoic acid, Li-AHA) has also been studied in context to the crystallization behaviour of the PP and PA6 phase in the blend. The crystallization studies have indicated a significant increase in bulk crystallization temperature of the PP phase in the blend in the presence of MWNTs. Moreover, the formation of 'trans-lamellar crystalline' structure consisting of PA6 'trans-crystalline lamellae' on MWNTs surface was facilitated in the case of blends prepared via 'protocol 2' as compared to the corresponding blends prepared via 'protocol 1'. Wide angle X-ray diffraction analysis has showed the existence of a beta-polymorph of the PP phase due to incorporation of the PA6 phase in the blend. Addition of MWNTs in the blends has facilitated further beta-crystalline structure formation of the PP phase. In the presence of m-MWNTs, a higher beta-fraction was observed in the PP phase as compared to the blend with pristine MWNTs. Addition of PP-g-MA has suppressed the beta-phase formation in the PP phase in the blend. X-ray bulk texture analysis revealed that incorporation of PA6 as well as pristine/modified MWNTs has influenced the extent of orientation of the PP chains towards specific crystalline planes in various blend compositions of PP and PA6.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:45:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:45:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 17(6)4293-4310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4cp05060f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17967</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>