<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1653</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimization of fenton-biological treatment scheme for the treatment of aqueous dye solutions</dc:title><dc:creator>LODHA, BHARAT</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, SANJEEV</dc:creator><dc:subject>azo dyes</dc:subject><dc:subject>biological system</dc:subject><dc:subject>hazardous materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>amines</dc:subject><dc:subject>bioactivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>fenton treatment</dc:subject><dc:description>Degradation of dyes especially, azo dyes are difficult due to their complex structure and synthetic nature. The main objective of this study was to evaluate the Fenton-biological (aerobic) treatment train for decolorization and mineralization of azo dyes viz. Reactive Black 5 (RB5), Reactive Blue 13 (RB13) and Acid Orange 7 (AO7). The objective of Fenton treatment was only to decolorize the dyes (breakage of –Ndouble bond; length as m-dashN–), as it was considered that after breakage of –Ndouble bond; length as m-dashN–, the dyes will become amenable to biodegradation and can be further treated in aerobic biological system. Hence studies were carried out to optimize the lower Fenton's doses for decolorization of dyes. The optimum doses for decolorization (&gt;95%) of all the three dyes were found out to be 15 mg L−1 of Fe2+ (0.27 mM) and 50 mg L−1 (1.47 mM) of H2O2 dose at optimum pH 3. Further it was also investigated that at lower doses, the main problem of Fenton process (sludge generation) can also be minimized. Later the mineralization of the dye (removal of aromatic amines) was achieved in the aerobic biological treatment system. Overall reduction of 64, 89 and 75% in the aromatic amines (at 254 nm), 88, 95 and 78% in naphthalene ring associated compounds (near 310 nm) and 49, 89 and 91% reduction in benzene ring associated compounds (near 226 nm) were observed for RB5, RB13 and AO7, respectively. Thus this treatment system seems to be quite effective and economical option for the treatment of recalcitrant compounds like dyes, as the cost in the chemical treatment is considered mainly due to chemicals thus at lower doses the operational cost is saved. Further, as the sludge generation was almost negligible at lower doses, thus the savings in cost of handling and disposal of hazardous sludge also adds to economy of treatment.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-19T08:36:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:32:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-19T08:36:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:32:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Hazardous Materials 148(1-2), 459-466</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2007.02.061</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1653</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1653</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>