<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1977</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Projection onto convex sets with watermarking for error concealment</dc:title><dc:creator>NAYAK, CK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAYALAKSHMI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>image</dc:subject><dc:description>Transmission of images and video over unreliable channels produces visual artifacts due to either loss or corruption of bit streams. Error concealment schemes aim at reducing such degradation and improving the visual quality. Error concealment schemes usually conceal errors of a specific type. This points towards the possibility of combining more than one scheme, for efficient error concealment and better visual effects. In this paper, we propose a scheme for error concealment using a combination of watermarking and Projection Onto Convex Sets (POCS). Watermarking an image using the information derived from the host data itself conceals errors initially and those which are prominent even after this stage are concealed through POCS. The proposed method can be used for concealing errors in images and intra coded video by preserving average values through watermarking and edge information through POCS. Simulation results of POCS, watermarking and watermarking with POCS are given in the paper to show the advantage of combining both the methods.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T23:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T23:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PATTERN RECOGNITION AND MACHINE INTELLIGENCE, PROCEEDINGS,4815,119-127</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-540-77045-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15260</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1977</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Conference on Pattern Recognition and Machine Intelligence,Calcutta, INDIA,DEC 18-22, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>