<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13963</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:25:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Do Two Flavour Oscillations Explain both KamLAND Data and the Solar Neutrino Spectrum?</dc:title><dc:creator>KORANGA, BS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANKAR, SU</dc:creator><dc:subject>MATTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solar neutrino spectrum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neutrino oscillation</dc:subject><dc:description>The recent measurement of Delta (sol) by the KamLAND experiment with very small errors, makes definitive predictions for the energy dependence of the solar neutrino survival probability P (ee) . We fix Delta (sol) to be the KamLAND best fit value of 8x10(-5) eV(2) and study the energy dependence of P (ee) for solar neutrinos, in the framework of two flavour oscillations and also of three flavour oscillations. For the case of two flavour oscillations, P (ee) has a measurable slope in the 5-8 MeV range but the solar spectrum measurements in this range find P (ee) to be flat. The predicted values of P (ee) , even for the best fit value of theta (sol) , differ by 2-3 sigma from the Super-K measured values in each of the three energy bins of the 5-8 MeV range. If future measurements of solar neutrinos by Super-K and SNO find a flat spectrum with reduced error bars (by a factor of 2), it will imply that two flavour oscillations can no longer explain both KamLAND data and the solar spectrum. However a flat solar neutrino spectrum and the Delta (sol) measured by KamLAND can be reconciled in a three flavour oscillation framework with a moderate value of theta (13) approximate to 13 degrees.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER/PLENUM PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:25:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:25:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF THEORETICAL PHYSICS,50(5)1515-1521</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10773-010-0660-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13963</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>