<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18269</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:37:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>BT-benzo-29 inhibits bacterial cell proliferation by perturbing FtsZ assembly</dc:title><dc:creator>RAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JINDAL, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNAL, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUROLIA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>SMALL-MOLECULE INHIBITORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIVISION PROTEIN FTSZ</dc:subject><dc:subject>BACILLUS-SUBTILIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MYCOBACTERIUM-TUBERCULOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>TARGETING FTSZ</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYTOKINESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMBRANE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacterial cell division</dc:subject><dc:subject>cytokinesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>membrane integrity</dc:subject><dc:subject>membrane potential</dc:subject><dc:description>We have identified a potent antibacterial agent N-(4-sec-butylphenyl)-2-(thiophen-2-yl)-1H-benzo[d]imidazole-4-carboxamide (BT-benzo-29) from a library of benzimidazole derivatives that stalled bacterial division by inhibiting FtsZ assembly. A short (5 min) exposure of BT-benzo-29 disassembled the cytokinetic Z-ring in Bacillus subtilis cells without affecting the cell length and nucleoids. BT-benzo-29 also perturbed the localization of early and late division proteins such as FtsA, ZapA and SepF at the mid-cell. Further, BT-benzo-29 bound to FtsZ with a dissociation constant of 24 +/- 3 m and inhibited the assembly and GTPase activity of purified FtsZ. A docking analysis suggested that BT-benzo-29 may bind to FtsZ at the C-terminal domain near the T7 loop. BT-benzo-29 displayed significantly weaker inhibitory effects on the assembly and GTPase activity of two mutants (L272A and V275A) of FtsZ supporting the prediction of the docking analysis. Further, BT-benzo-29 did not appear to inhibit DNA duplication and nucleoid segregation and it did not perturb the membrane potential of B. subtilis cells. The results suggested that BT-benzo-29 exerts its potent antibacterial activity by inhibiting FtsZ assembly. Interestingly, BT-benzo-29 did not affect the membrane integrity of mammalian red blood cells. BT-benzo-29 bound to tubulin with a much weaker affinity than FtsZ and exerted significantly weaker effects on mammalian cells than on the bacterial cells indicating that the compound may have a strong antibacterial potential.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:37:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:37:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FEBS JOURNAL, 282(20)4015-4033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-464X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-4658</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/febs.13403</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18269</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>