<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16005</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:56:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Early Bartonian orthophragminids (Foraminiferida) from Reineche Limestone, north African platform, Tunisia: taxonomy and paleobiogeographic implications</dc:title><dc:creator>BEN ISMAIL-LATTRACHE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>OZCAN, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOUKHALFA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARASWATI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOUSSI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOVANE, L</dc:creator><dc:subject>orthophragminids</dc:subject><dc:subject>taxonomy</dc:subject><dc:subject>paleobiogeography</dc:subject><dc:subject>early Bartonian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reineche Limestone</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tunisia</dc:subject><dc:subject>LARGER FORAMINIFERA</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN TETHYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHALLOW-MARINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>THRACE BASIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>NW TURKEY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EOCENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIDDLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOSTRATIGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BOUNDARY</dc:subject><dc:description>The orthophragminids in lower Bartonian Reineche Limestone member, a fossiliferous shallow-marine unit exposed in Cap Bon peninsula in Tunisia, are represented by 17 species assigned to Discocyclinidae Galloway 1928 and Orbitoclypeidae Bronnimann 1946. These taxa, associated with nummulitids and alveolinids, belong to the lineages of Discocyclina Gumbel 1870, Nemkovella, 1987, Orbitoclypeus Silvestri 1907, and Asterocyclina Gumbel 1870, described for the first time from north Africa lying at the southern margin of Tethyan ocean during Paleogene. We identified Nemkovella evae, previously not recorded in upper Lutetian/lower Bartonian and younger Eocene deposits of northern Tethyan platforms, and erected a new subspecies, N. evae reinechensis n. ssp. A comparison of Reineche orthophraminids, assigned to orthophragmines zone (OZ) 12 and shallow benthic zone (SBZ 17), to the well-described coeval assemblages at northern Tethyan platforms in Italy, Hungary, Turkey, and to those in Kutch Basin in the Indian subcontinent suggests that some species are confined to certain paleogeographic domains. Orbitoclypeus haynesi, the only orbitoclypeid and the most abundant orthophragminid in lower Bartonian deposits in Kutch, appears to be the most common orbitoclypeid in Reineche Limestone. In Europe, this species is not known and is replaced by Orbitoclypeus varians, the most common orbitoclypeid in middle Eocene of central Europe. Both species occur in varying proportions in marine successions in Turkey. Asterocyclina sireli, identified so far only in Turkey, occurs in Reineche Limestone and in lower Bartonian deposits in Kutch. This species is recorded for the first time in the Indian subcontinent. Relying on present study, as well as our recent studies in Kutch Basin, we conclude that the generic and specific diversity of orthophragminids decreases eastward from the peri-Mediterranean region to Indian subcontinent and to the western Pacific.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEODINAMICA ACTA, 26(1-2)94-121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0985-3111</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1778-3593</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09853111.2013.858950</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16005</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>