<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15714</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:52:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Probabilistic assessment of flood risks using trivariate copulas</dc:title><dc:creator>GANGULI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, MJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>BIVARIATE FREQUENCY-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTREME-VALUE DISTRIBUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROLOGICAL APPLICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NONPARAMETRIC-ESTIMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARCHIMEDEAN COPULAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TAIL-DEPENDENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISTRIBUTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TESTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a copula-based methodology is presented for probabilistic assessment of flood risks and investigated the performance of trivariate copulas in modeling dependence structure of flood properties. The flood is a multi-attribute natural hazard and is characterized by mutually correlated flood properties peak flow, volume, and duration of flood hydrograph. For assessing flood risk, many studies have used bivariate analysis, but a more effective assessment can be possible considering all three mutually correlated flood properties simultaneously. This study adopts trivariate copulas for multivariate analysis of flood risks, and applied to a case study of flood flows of Delaware River basin at Port Jervis, NY, USA. On evaluation of various probability distributions for representation of flood variables, it is found that the flood peak flow and volumes can be best represented by Fr,chet distribution, whereas flood duration by log-normal distribution. The joint distribution is modeled using four trivariate copulas, namely, three fully nested form of Archimedean copulas: Clayton, Gumbel-Hougaard, Frank copulas; and one elliptical copula: Student's t copula. Based on distance-based performance measures, graphical tests, and tail-dependence measures, it is found that the Student's t copula best representing the trivariate dependence structure of flood properties as compared to the other copulas. Similar results are found for bivariate copula modeling of flood variables pairs, where Student's t copula performed better than the other copulas. The obtained copula-based joint distributions are used for multivariate analysis of flood risks, in terms of primary and secondary return periods. The resultant trivariate return periods are compared with univariate and bivariate return periods, and addressed the necessity of multivariate flood risk analysis. The study concludes that the trivariate copula-based methodology is a viable choice for effective risk assessment of floods.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER WIEN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:52:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:52:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>THEORETICAL AND APPLIED CLIMATOLOGY, 111(1-2)341-360</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00704-012-0664-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15714</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>