<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1159</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>A multi-wavelength optical source for synchronous and asynchronous data transfer at a minimum of 16×10 Gbps</dc:title><dc:creator>SHAH, DD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DIXIT, NIMISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>wavelength division multiplexing</dc:subject><dc:subject>spread spectrum communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>demultiplexing</dc:subject><dc:description>Numerical calculations have been carried out to study the characteristics of a multi-channel optical source capable of delivering (i) picosecond pulses with 10 GHz repetition rate at 16 different wavelengths and (ii) at least 16 channel multi-wavelength single mode CW output with precise 40 GHz channel spacing for application to fiber communication. In the first scheme, the pulse characteristics like power variation, pulse width and de-synchronization across the 16 demultiplexed channels are numerically investigated. The pulse width is observed to be almost constant (~13 ps) in all the channels. The suitability of dispersion flattened fiber and dispersion shifted fiber as supercontinuum fiber is analyzed from the viewpoint of power variation and de-synchronization. In the second scheme a negligible power variation is observed across the 16 CW channels. The advantage of the proposed scheme lies in obtaining easy up-gradation with ultra-stable pulse train. The first scheme is suitable only for synchronous data transfer while the second scheme can be used also for asynchronous data transfer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-09T04:33:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:52:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-09T04:33:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:52:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Optical Fiber Technology 9(3), 149-158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1068-5200</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1068-5200(03)00018-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1159</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1159</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>