<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14902</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:26:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Standalone PV-diesel system vs. PV-H-2 system: An economic analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJ, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, PC</dc:creator><dc:subject>PV-DG system</dc:subject><dc:subject>PV-H-2 system</dc:subject><dc:subject>Long-term storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Life cycle cost</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR ENERGY-STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERATOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDRIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>WIND</dc:subject><dc:description>Hydrogen as a long-term storage medium in photovoltaic systems has been a subject of interest in recent years. Such a system uses an electrolyser - H-2 storage - fuel cell combination along with battery as short-term storage to minimize the loss of load probability. Conventionally, the same goal is achieved including a diesel generator (DG) in the photovoltaic (PV) systems. In present work, an economic comparison is carried out between DG based system and various possible configurations of H-2 based systems suitable for standalone application in the range of 5 kW. Both the systems are compared with the help of boundary curve obtained from life cycle cost analysis and excess energy available in the PV-DG system. Boundary curve enables in determining cost-effective system for a site, specified by on-site fuel cost including transportation cost and seasonal solar energy difference. It is found, a system with unitized regenerative fuel cell (URFC) and metal hydride storage offers most cost-effective solution. Further, the scope of the PV-H-2 system is enhanced if the salvage value of the fuel cell is considered. With steeply rising fossil fuel prices and developments in H-2 technology, globally more regions will be cost-effective for PV-H-2 systems. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:26:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:26:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY, 42(1)270-280</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2012.03.059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14902</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>