<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2394</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Selectivity engineering with reactive distillation : attainable region for complex reactions</dc:title><dc:creator>AMTE, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALIK, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactive distillation</dc:subject><dc:subject>attainable region</dc:subject><dc:subject>van de vusse reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>composition vector</dc:subject><dc:description>Reactive Distillation (RD) is by now a well established operation that combines reaction and distillation in a single unit to offer enhancement in the overall performance of the process. It leads to enhancement in conversion for reversible reactions and selectivity or yield improvement in the case of multiple reaction schemes. The main underlying principle in application of RD for selectivity engineering is to facilitate the separation of selected components and favorably manipulate the composition profiles in the reactive zone to expedite the desired reaction. In this work, a geometric approach of attainable region (AR), which is already developed for conventional reactor network, is extended further to include representative RD configurations. A model reaction with Van de Vusse scheme (A -&gt; B -&gt; C and 2A -&gt; D) was studied and an algorithm is developed to obtain the attainable reaction for the given kinetics, feed composition and relative volatilities. The AR should be convex with newly defined RD composition vectors on the boundaries should always point inward. The RD vectors emphasize on the need of RD model networking to enlarge the set of attainable compositions until no further enlargement is seen. The results obtained through the algorithm developed above are verified with independent simulation for maximization of selectivity. In almost all different cases of kinetic regime and relative volatilities, RD models perform better than conventional reactors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD ACAD UNION-WORLD ACAD PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T13:58:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T13:58:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF 2010 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON CHEMICAL ENGINEERING AND APPLICATIONS,220-224</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-84626-023-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15739</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2394</dc:identifier><dc:source>2010 International Conference on Chemical Engineering and Applications,Singapore, SINGAPORE,FEB 26-28, 2010</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>