<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9329</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>An optimal strategy to model microbial growth in a multiple substrate environment</dc:title><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOSHI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RENGASWAMY, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>metabolic-regulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>flux towards growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>e-coli k12</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple substrate</dc:subject><dc:description>A comprehensive moel is developed based on an optimal strategy describing varied microbial growth phenomenon involving sequential and simultaneous utilization of substrate. The model mimics the complex regulatory process of a cell which results in diverse growth process with the help of simple multi-variable constrained optimization, which aims at maximizing the specific cell growth. The metabolic processes of a cell are represented by simple flux balance equations. The different growth phenomenon exhibited by a microorganism are attributed to different levels of control present inside the cell. Provision is made in the model for these controls, in the form of constraints in the optimization formulation. The model prediction matches well with the experimental data of simultaneous growth of E. coli K12 on a mixture of glucose and organic acids like lactate, pyruvate, and acetate. Moreover, the model predictions are well in agreement with earlier published experimental data for the growth of E. coli K12 on other organic acids like fumarate, alpha-ketoglutarate, and succinate. (C) 1997 , Inc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T10:24:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T10:24:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOTECHNOLOGY AND BIOENGINEERING, 56(6), 635-644</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-3592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-0290(19971220)56:6&lt;635::AID-BIT6&gt;3.3.CO;2-E</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9329</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9329</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>