<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15131</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:17:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparing the performance of neural networks developed by using Levenberg-Marquardt and Quasi-Newton with the gradient descent algorithm for modelling a multiple response grinding process</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROUTROY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Back propagation neural network</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gradient descent algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>Levenberg-Marquardt algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiple response</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quasi-Newton algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE-ROUGHNESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>METHODOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPERATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>WEAR</dc:subject><dc:description>Monitoring and control of multiple process quality characteristics (responses) in grinding plays a critical role in precision parts manufacturing industries. Precise and accurate mathematical modelling of multiple response process behaviour holds the key for a better quality product with minimum variability in the process. Artificial neural network (ANN)-based nonlinear grinding process model using backpropagation weight adjustment algorithm (BPNN) is used extensively by researchers and practitioners. However, suitability and systematic approach to implement Levenberg-Marquardt (L-M) and Boyden, Fletcher, Gold-farb and Shanno (BFGS) update Quasi-Newton (Q-N) algorithm for modelling and control of grinding process is seldom explored. This paper provides L-M and BEGS algorithm-based BPNN models for grinding process, and verified their effectiveness by using a real life industrial situation. Based on the real life data, the performance of L-M and BFGS update Q-N are compared with an adaptive learning (A-L) and gradient descent algorithm-based BPNN model. The results clearly indicate that L-M and BEGS-based networks converge faster and can predict the nonlinear behaviour of multiple response grinding process with same level of accuracy as A-L based network. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:17:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:17:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERT SYSTEMS WITH APPLICATIONS, 39(3)2397-2407</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2011.08.087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15131</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>