<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1326</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Processing and room temperature properties of nickel free high nitrogen austenitic stainless steels</dc:title><dc:creator>BALACHANDRAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATIA, ML</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALLAL, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, PK</dc:creator><dc:description>Nickel free high nitrogen austenitic stainless steels based on chromium, manganese and nitrogen are technologically important materials, widely being explored for several potential applications. Empirical equations to find the minimum nitrogen content to form austenite phase with respect to alloy design principles is presented. In addition, large-scale melting of nitrogen steel ingot using electro slag refining (ESR) process at normal atmosphere, using ingot withdrawal method has been studied. Investigations on solid state nitriding of thin strips of nitrogen steel has also been examined. The property level of these steels under varying processing conditions show, a versatile range of properties from high strength to ultra high strength, by appropriate choice of nitrogen and carbon contents and processing condition. Empirical equations for determination of strength as a function of composition, grain size and cold working and have been evolved. Further, the formation of detrimental precipitation at various processing conditions was examined and the scope for circumventing some of the detrimental properties in the steel has been assessed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN INST METALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T21:26:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T21:26:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN INSTITUTE OF METALS,55(4)149-159</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-493X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1326</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th International Conference on High Nitrogen Steels (HNS 2002),CHENNAI, INDIA,FEB 21-24, 2002</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>