<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1341</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of pyrolytic carbon coated zirconia pebbles in a high temperature spouted bed</dc:title><dc:creator>SATHIYAMOORTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VG</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, PT</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOLLICK, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>pyrocarbon coating</dc:subject><dc:subject>zirconia particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical vapor deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>spouted bed reactor</dc:subject><dc:description>Pyrocarbon (PyC) coating is deposited on spherical zirconia particles (size 480 mu m, density 6300 kg/m(3)). The coating is carried out at 1350 +/- 1 degrees C in a spouted bed reactor (height 0.3 m, dia 0.06 m) using acetylene and argon gas mixture. The PyC coating is uniformly deposited by chemical vapor deposition (CVD) on the surface of the pebbles where the precursor (acetylene) undergoes chemical bond dissociation. The spouted bed reactor is characterized for its stable solid circulation which is responsible to enhance heat and mass transfer. Therefore, it is expected that the properties of the coated layer should be affected by critical parameters of the bed during its high temperature operations. It was found that both the thickness and density of PyC coated layer change with static height of the bed as well as with the spouting gas velocity. With the increase in spouting gas velocity the coating thickness decreased whereas, the density of the coated material increased. On the other hand it is found that up to a critical static bed height the coating rate increased beyond which it started decreasing and the coating density remains almost unchanged up to that critical static bed height and marginally decreased beyond this height. This paper discusses the issues that affect spouted bed performance with respect to its stability during PyC coating by CVD.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION-NISCAIR</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T22:23:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T22:23:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF ENGINEERING AND MATERIALS SCIENCES,17(5)349-352</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-4588</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14521</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1341</dc:identifier><dc:source>First Asian Carbon Conference (FACC),New Delhi, INDIA,NOV 25-27, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>