<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14524</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:05:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dielectrophoresis and deformation of a liquid drop in a non-uniform, axisymmetric AC electric field</dc:title><dc:creator>THAOKAR, RM</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTROHYDRODYNAMIC DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER DROPS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEADY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPE</dc:subject><dc:description>Analytical theory for the dielectrophoresis and deformation of a leaky dielectric drop, suspended in a leaky dielectric medium, subjected to non-uniform, axisymmetric Alternating Current (AC) fields is presented in the small deformation limit. The applied field is assumed to be a combination of a uniform part and a quadrupole component. The analysis shows that the magnitude and the sign of the steady and time-periodic dielectrophoretic velocity depend upon the frequency of the applied voltage. The frequency of oscillatory motion is twice that of the applied frequency and the phase lag is a consequence of charge dynamics. A deformed drop under non-uniform axisymmetric AC fields admits Legendre modes l = 2, 3, 4. The deformation has a frequency-dependent steady and time-periodic parts due to charge and interface dynamics. The steady deformation can be zero at a certain critical frequency in leaky dielectric systems. The time-periodic deformation also has a frequency which is twice the frequency of the applied voltage. In perfect dielectric systems, unlike the steady state deformation which is a balance of Maxwell and curvature stresses, the time-periodic deformation additionally includes viscous stresses associated with the oscillatory shape changes of the drop. A consequence of this effect is a phase lag that is dependent on the charge and interface hydrodynamics and a lag of pi/2 at high frequencies. It also results in vanishing amplitude of the oscillatory deformation at high frequencies. The study should lead to a better understanding of dielectrophoresis under non-uniform axisymmetric AC fields and better electrode design to affect drop breakup.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:05:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:05:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN PHYSICAL JOURNAL E, 35(8)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epje/i2012-12076-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14524</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>