<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4469</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-05T09:02:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structure and magnetocaloric properties of the Fe-doped HoTiGe alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>PROVENZANO, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAUMGOLD, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHULL, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAPIRO, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOYAMA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>WATANABE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALIK, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>magnetic-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>gd-5(si2ge2)</dc:subject><dc:description>The structure and magnetocaloric properties of the Fe-doped HoTiGe compound were investigated by means of scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy dispersive spectroscopy, x-ray diffraction, magnetometry, and calorimetry. As with the early studies on the undoped compound, the Fe-containing alloy exhibited an antiferromagnetic-to-paramagnetic transition and a magnetocaloric effect peak at 90 K. The magnetization (M) versus temperature (T) data showed peaks at 10 and 90 K, while M versus field (H) curves showed the presence of a field-induced transition for all T &lt; 120 K; additionally, for all T &lt; 60 K, open hysteresis loops at the magnetic transitions were observed. XRD measurements between 10 and 60 K under various magnetic fields up to 3184 kA/m (40 kOe) showed that the hysteresis was not accompanied by any change in crystallography. The magnetization derived entropy change -Delta S-m vs T plot also showed the presence of two peaks, at 20 and 90 K; but below 15 K, -Delta S-m increased steeply with decreasing temperature. It is believed that the minor phases in the Fe-doped alloy give rise to the magnetization-derived -Delta S-m peak at 20 K. The heat-capacity-derived -Delta S-m vs T plot for the Fe-doped alloy also showed the presence of two peaks at 20 and 90 K. However, the heat-capacity-derived -Delta S-m did not show a rapid rise with decreasing temperature below 15 K. (C) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T16:22:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T16:22:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 99(8), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.2159396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4469</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4469</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>