<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13886</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T03:40:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Melt-Mixed Polypropylene/Acrylonitrile-Butadiene-Styrene Blends with Multiwall Carbon Nanotubes: Effect of Compatibilizer and Modifier on Morphology and Electrical Conductivity</dc:title><dc:creator>KHARE, RA</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>IMMISCIBLE POLYMER BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PP/ABS BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISPERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLACK</dc:subject><dc:subject>blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiwall carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>polypropylene (PP)</dc:subject><dc:description>Cocontinuous blends of 45/55 polypropylene (PP)/acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene (ABS) with multi-wall carbon nanotubes (MWNT) were prepared by melt-mixing in a conical twin-screw microcompounder. PP-grafted-maleic anhydride (PP-g-MA) and styrene MA were used as compatibilizers for PP/ABS blends. Scanning electron microscopic observations showed phase segregation of PP-g-MA in the blends. State of dispersion of MWNT in the presence or absence of the compatibilizers was assessed through AC electrical conductivity measurements and crystallization studies of the blends. An improvement in AC electrical conductivity was observed in blends in presence of either styrene MA or dual compatibilizers. The lowest electrical percolation threshold was achieved at 0.1 wt % of MWNT using sodium salt of 6-amino hexanoic acid-modified MWNT. Significant increase in crystallization temperature of PP phase of blends with MWNT was observed in the presence of compatibilizers as compared to blends without compatibilizers. An attempt has been made to address the complex issues of phase segregation, compatibilization, and dispersion of MWNT in cocontinuous blends of PP/ABS. (C) 2011 Wiley Periodicals, Inc. J Appl Polym Sci 120: 2663-2672, 2011</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T03:40:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T03:40:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED POLYMER SCIENCE,120(5)2663-2672</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8995</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/app.33371</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13886</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>