<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11825</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>SUBSTITUTION OF AL IN THE ALPO4-5 AND ALPO4-11 FRAMEWORKS BY SI AND FE - A STUDY BY MOSSBAUER, MAGIC-ANGLE-SPINNING NUCLEAR-MAGNETIC-RESONANCE AND ELECTRON-PARAMAGNETIC RESONANCE SPECTROSCOPIES AND CHEMICAL PROBES</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATYANARYANA, CVV</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTY, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PIRAMANAYAGAM, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHRINGI, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>crystalline inorganic solids</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicoaluminophosphate molecular-sieves</dc:subject><dc:subject>nmr</dc:subject><dc:subject>sapo-5</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolites</dc:subject><dc:subject>al-27</dc:subject><dc:subject>p-31</dc:subject><dc:description>Substitution of Al by Fe and Si in the AlPO4-5 and AIPO4-11 frameworks has been investigated by a number of experimental methods such as electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR), Mossbauer and magic-angle-spinning nuclear magnetic resonance (MASNMR) spectroscopies and temperature-programmed desorption of ammonia. There are indications that Fe(III) replaces Al(III) and the extent of substitution increases with time of reaction. The FAPO-n formed, however, is contaminated with an amorphous phase containing Fe(III). Silicon replaces phosphorus in the framework only to a limited extent and in those cases when the synthesis gel had a higher amount of silicon, the product was contaminated with an amorphous silica-containing phase. No evidence tor silicon removing a phosphorus-aluminium pair has been found. The conclusions are also supported by the results of acidity measurements and the alkylation of toluene with methanol on these molecular sieve samples.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T19:23:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T19:23:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE CHEMICAL SOCIETY-FARADAY TRANSACTIONS, 88(21), 3255-3261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0956-5000</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/ft9928803255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11825</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11825</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>