<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5315</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T02:32:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Reactivity of nano-size particles vis-a-vis large particles and their applications</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAL, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>photocatalytic degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic pollutants</dc:subject><dc:subject>tio2</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoelectrochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>photochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecules</dc:subject><dc:subject>reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>nano size particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoelectrochemical reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>photo imaging</dc:subject><dc:description>Reactivity of a solid in a heterogeneous type of reaction, is mainly controlled by electronic structure of the interface formed between the two phases e.g. solid and electrolyte. The electronic structure and hence its property depends upon the particle size constituting the solid electrolyte interface. Upto certain diameter of the particle size, its interfacial behaviour is almost independent of the particle, but when its diameter is decreased to a value around 100 Angstrom or less, such that the particles contain around 10(4) molecules or less, then the interfacial property abruptly shows a very distinctly different reactivity. The object of this article is to understand this behaviour by correlating the size of the particle with interfacial charge distribution. Moreover It is also observed that the band gap of the material increases with decrease in diameter of the particle and is maximum when its diameter is around 15-50 Angstrom. The latter type of particles are classified as nano size particles. A model is developed to understand the reasons for showing these two distinct properties by particles. applications depending upon the large macro size particles as well as nano size material are briefly discussed. These include applications like selective photoelectrochemical reactions, photography memory devices, detoxification of drinking water, killing of water borne bacteria, cancer cells etc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CENTRAL ELECTROCHEM RES INST</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T13:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T13:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF ELECTROCHEMISTRY, 12(3-4), 219-233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-1654</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5315</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5315</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>