<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12200</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling of a jointed rock mass under triaxial conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>compression</dc:subject><dc:subject>fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>flac(3d)</dc:subject><dc:subject>jointed rock</dc:subject><dc:subject>failure behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>principal stresses</dc:subject><dc:description>One of the most important aspects of designing a structure on or in a rock mass is based on the strength response of a jointed rock mass. Understanding this important aspect, the present study was undertaken to understand the strength response of a jointed rock mass with the help of a finite difference package FLAC(3D). In the present work, an attempt has been made to understand the effect of discontinuity angle on the failure mode and strength of the rock mass. For this purpose, stress and displacement in the model were studied and various stress-strain histories were recorded at constant strain loading rate. Rock discontinuity plays a critical and vital role to understand physico-mechanical characteristics of a rock mass. It has wider application in the rock excavation engineering, e. g., caverns, tunnels, slope stability, dams, etc. Simulated rock results are compared with the analytically calculated results of the jointed rock mass and found in good agreement.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T05:00:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T05:00:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ARABIAN JOURNAL OF GEOSCIENCES, 3(1), 91-103</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1866-7511</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-009-0063-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12200</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12200</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>