<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7812</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mode II stable crack growth</dc:title><dc:creator>MOURAD, AHI</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>mixed-mode</dc:subject><dc:subject>fracture-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>brittle-fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminum-alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite-element</dc:subject><dc:subject>toughness</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>specimen</dc:subject><dc:subject>steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>mode ii crack growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>crack opening criterion</dc:subject><dc:subject>plastic zones</dc:subject><dc:subject>d16at (2024-t3) aluminum alloy</dc:subject><dc:description>Mode II stable crack extension has been examined for an aircraft grade aluminium alloy D16AT. Both theoretical and experimental results are presented. The experimental observations include load displacement diagrams, plastic wake, crack front tunnelling and scanning electron micrographs of the fracture surfaces. The crack shows a tendency for in-plane extension, and the fracture surface is very Bat, smooth and free of any dimples. The crack front advances with negligible tunnelling at all stages of extension. The span of mode II stable crack growth (SCG) is longer than in the case of mode I SCG reported earlier for the same material and there is also more extensive plastic deformation. In the presence of a slight mode I load, the crack grows out-of-plane and the fractured surface facets resemble that of a mode I or mixed-mode dimpled fracture. The theoretical study is based on a finite element analysis using small deformation theory and incremental plasticity. Some of the experimental results have been theoretically predicted using the COA criterion as the governing criterion. The theoretical results include load-displacement diagrams, crack edge displacement curves, plastic zones and the J resistance curves. There is good agreement between the load-displacement diagrams. The initiation and maximum loads differ by less than 15%. The J resistance curve has a constant slope over the whole span of stable crack growth.</dc:description><dc:publisher>FATIGUE &amp; FRACTURE ENGINEERINGMATERIALS STRUCTURES LIMITED</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T19:54:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T19:54:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FATIGUE &amp; FRACTURE OF ENGINEERING MATERIALS &amp; STRUCTURES, 19(1), 75-84</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>8756-758X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7812</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7812</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>