<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1555</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-26T06:34:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Machinery condition monitoring system selection - A multi-objective decision approach using GA</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMESH, PG</dc:creator><dc:subject>process engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>decision support system</dc:subject><dc:subject>maintainability</dc:subject><dc:subject>industrial engineering</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a framework for Condition Based Maintenance (CBM) of large engineering systems has been suggested to address the need to optimize the characteristics of both the condition monitoring system and the plant that is being maintained at a macro level. CBM for large engineering systems has been modeled using Markov process. The issues which are critical to CBM, namely, predictability, detectability as well as implications of availability and cost have been considered in the framework to provide effective decision support. The application of the framework has been demonstrated using a numerical example. The trade offs between the Pareto optimal solutions of various objectives have been studied and the effects of variation of the maintenance objective function values with detectability and predictability have been brought out.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-22T04:37:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:28:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-22T04:37:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:28:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 1st International Conference on Emerging Trends in Engineering and Technology,  Nagpur, Maharashtra, India, 16-18 July 2008, 787-792</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>9780769532677</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICETET.2008.127</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1555</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1555</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>