<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1462</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>A reliability based analysis of generation/transmission system incorporating TCSC using fuzzy set theory</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATKAR, MV</dc:creator><dc:subject>set theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric power transmission network</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>reliability theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuzzy sets</dc:subject><dc:description>Flexible AC transmission system technology is an important tool for permitting existing transmission facilities to be loaded at least under contingency situations up to their permissible limits without violating security constraints. In power system reliability studies the parameters such as failure and repair rates used in the probabilistic models have considerable data uncertainty. The theory of fuzzy sets has been recognized as a potential tool to include data uncertainty in normal calculations. This paper presents the reliability based analysis of generation /transmission system by incorporating TCSC using fuzzy set theory. Fuzzy availability analysis of Thyristor-Controlled Series Capacitor (TCSC),a FACTS controller, is also presented using Markov model. The state probabilities of the components are represented as a fuzzy number. The system load is also considered as a fuzzy to investigate the reliability index as fuzzy LOLE. Impact of system peak load (fuzzy) and TCSC on the power system is investigated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-11T04:08:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:12:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-11T04:08:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:12:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Industrial Technology, Mumbai, India, 15-17 December 2006, 2779-2784</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1424407265</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICIT.2006.372655</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1462</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1462</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>