<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18313</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:59:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Butterfly-Inspired 2D Periodic Tapered-Staggered Subwavelength Gratings Designed Based on Finite Difference Time Domain Method</dc:title><dc:creator>WANG, HX</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHOU, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>LI, EP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOTE, RG</dc:creator><dc:subject>PHOTONIC PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL COLOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>WING SCALES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARCHITECTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILM</dc:subject><dc:subject>COATINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:description>The butterfly-inspired 2D periodic tapered-staggered subwavelength gratings were developed mainly using finite difference time domain (FDTD) method, assisted by using focused ion beam (FIB) nanoscale machining or fabrication. The periodic subwavelength structures along the ridges of the designed gratings may change the electric field intensity distribution and weaken the surface reflection. The performance of the designed SiO2 gratings is similar to that of the corresponding Si gratings (the predicted reflectance can be less than around 5% for the bandwidth ranging from 0.15 mu m to 1 mu m). Further, the antireflection performance of the designed x-unspaced gratings is better than that of the corresponding x-spaced gratings. Based on the FDTD designs and simulated results, the butterfly-inspired grating structure was fabricated on the silicon wafer using FIB milling, reporting the possibility to fabricate these FDTD-designed subwavelength grating structures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>HINDAWI PUBLISHING CORPORATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:59:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:59:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOMATERIALS</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1687-4110</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1687-4129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/740984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18313</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>