<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17444</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:01:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Decadal changes in the land use/land cover and shoreline along the coastal districts of southern Gujarat, India</dc:title><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAJI, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>URBAN-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLASSIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELTA</dc:subject><dc:subject>AREA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Band ratios</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hybrid classification</dc:subject><dc:subject>LULC changes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coastal erosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shoreline change</dc:subject><dc:subject>Southern Gujarat</dc:subject><dc:description>The coastal zone along the districts of Surat, Navsari, and Valsad in southern Gujarat, India, is reported to be facing serious environmental challenges in the form of shoreline erosion, wetland loss, and man-made encroachments. This study assesses the decadal land use/ land cover (LULC) changes in these three districts for the years 1990, 2001, and 2014 using satellite datasets of Landsat TM, ETM, and OLI. The LULC changes are identified by using band ratios as a preclassification step, followed by implementation of hybrid classification (a combination of supervised and unsupervised classification). An accuracy assessment is carried out for each dataset, and the overall accuracy ranges from 90 to 95 %. It is observed that the spatial extents of aquaculture, urban built-up, and barren classes have appreciated over time, whereas the coverage of mudflats has depreciated due to rapid urbanization. The changes in the shoreline of these districts have also been analyzed for the same years, and significant changes are found in the form of shoreline erosion. The LULC maps prepared as well as the shoreline change analysis done for this study area will enable the local decision makers to adopt better land-use planning and shoreline protection measures, which will further aid in sustainable future developments in this region.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:01:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:01:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING AND ASSESSMENT, 187(7)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-6369</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-2959</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10661-015-4684-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17444</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>