<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17287</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:16:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Looping and reconfiguration dynamics of a flexible chain with internal friction</dc:title><dc:creator>SAMANTA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>END-TO-END</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNFOLDED POLYPEPTIDE-CHAINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIFFUSION-CONTROLLED REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPENDENT SURVIVAL PROBABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER-CHAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTRAMOLECULAR DIFFUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMIFLEXIBLE POLYMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORMATION KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:description>In recent past, experiments and simulations have suggested that apart from the solvent friction, friction arising from the protein itself plays an important role in protein folding by affecting the intra-chain loop formation dynamics. This friction is termed as internal friction in the literature. Using a flexible Gaussian chain with internal friction we analyze the intra-chain reconfiguration and loop formation times for all three topology classes namely end-to-end, end-to-interior and interior-to-interior. In a nutshell, bypassing expensive simulations we show how simple models like that of Rouse and Zimm can support the single molecule experiment and computer simulation results on intra-chain diffusion coefficients, looping time and even can predict the effects of tail length on the looping time. (C) 2014 Author(s). All article content, except where otherwise noted, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:16:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:16:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AIP ADVANCES, 4(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2158-3226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4881416</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17287</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>