<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13920</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T04:57:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>The Role of Specific Interaction and Selective Localization of Multiwall Carbon Nanotubes on the Electrical Conductivity and Phase Morphology of Multicomponent Polymer Blends</dc:title><dc:creator>BOSE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHARE, RA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAMATH, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>ACRYLONITRILE-BUTADIENE-STYRENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO-CONTINUOUS BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLIZATION BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILLED POLYCARBONATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PA6/ABS BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYETHYLENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISPERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYAMIDE-6</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLACK</dc:subject><dc:description>Multicomponent polymer blends involving polyamide6 (PA6), polypropylene (PP), acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene (ABS) and high density polyethylene (HDPE) with multiwall carbon nanotubes (MWNT) were prepared by melt mixing technique to achieve conducting composites. MWNT were either compounded directly or by employing a masterbatch dilution approach in binary (PA6/ABS), ternary (PA6/PP/ABS) and quaternary (PA6/PP/ABS/HDPE) blends. To facilitate "network-like" structure MWNT were pretreated with either sodium salt of 6-aminohexanoic acid or octadecyl tri-phenyl phosponium bromide. Multicomponent blends with pretreated MWNT utilizing masterbatch dilution approach showed significant improvements in the bulk electrical conductivity as compared to blends prepared by direct addition approach at 2 wt % MWNT content. Phase morphology of these blends revealed co-continuous type of morphology wherein MWNT were found to be selectively localized in the PA6 phase. The hetero-nucleating action of MWNT was manifested in increased crystallization temperature of mainly PA6 phase of the blends indicating preferential localization of MWNT in the PA6 phase. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 51:1987-2000, 2011. (C) 2011 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:57:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:57:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE,51(10)1987-2000</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.21998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13920</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>