<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1203</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic response of isolated bridges with soil-structure interaction</dc:title><dc:creator>TONGAONKAR, NP</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>elastomers</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic prospecting</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>time domain analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>The modern transportation facilities demand that the bridges are to be constructed across the gorges that are located in seismically active areas and at the same time the site conditions compel the engineers to rest the pier foundation on soil. The purpose of this study is to assess the effects of soil–structure interaction (SSI) on the peak responses of three-span continuous deck bridge seismically isolated by the elastomeric bearings. The emphasis has been placed on gauging the significance of physical parameters that affect the response of the system and identify the circumstances under which it is necessary to include the SSI effects in the design of seismically isolated bridges. The soil surrounding the foundation of pier is modelled by frequency independent coefficients and the complete dynamic analysis is carried out in time domain using complex modal analysis method. In order to quantify the effects of SSI, the peak responses of isolated and non-isolated bridge (i.e. bridge without isolation device) are compared with the corresponding bridge ignoring these effects. A parametric study is also conducted to investigate the effects of soil flexibility and bearing parameters (such as stiffness and damping) on the response of isolated bridge system. It is observed that the soil surrounding the pier has significant effects on the response of the isolated bridges and under certain circumstances the bearing displacements at abutment locations may be underestimated if the SSI effects are not considered in the response analysis of the system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-22T09:01:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:14:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-22T09:01:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:14:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Soil Dynamics and Earthquake Engineering 23(4), 287-302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0267-7261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0267-7261(03)00020-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1203</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>