<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18018</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:11:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Switching the orientation of Jahn-Teller axes in oxime-based Mn-III dimers and its effect upon magnetic exchange: a combined experimental and theoretical study</dc:title><dc:creator>COMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJESHKUMAR, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>NICHOL, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PITAK, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>COLES, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRECHIN, EK</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE MAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAUSSIAN-BASIS SETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERROMAGNETIC EXCHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COUPLING-CONSTANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MN-2(III) DIMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROUND-STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATOMIC-SCALE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFERENCE</dc:subject><dc:description>A family of Mn-III dimers of general formula [Mn-2(III)(R-sao)(2)(dpa)(2)](ClO4)(2) (1-5) has been synthesised using derivatised phenolic oximes (R-saoH(2), where R = H, Me, Et, Ph) in combination with di-(2-picolyl)-amine (dpa). Their structures reveal a double-oxime bridged [Mn-III(NO)](2) magnetic core in which the Jahn-Teller axes lie perpendicular to the bridging plane, in contrast to two previously reported family members (6, 7). The switch in the orientation of the Jahn-Teller axes is enforced through the use of the chelating ligand which is present in 1-5 and absent in 6-7. Dc magnetic susceptibility measurements reveal that the exchange interactions between the MnIII metal centres in 1-5 are antiferromagnetic in contrast to that observed for 6 and 7 which are ferromagnetic. DFT calculations performed on complexes 1-6 reproduce both the sign and strength of the J values found experimentally. Molecular orbital analysis unlocks a common mechanism of magnetic coupling based upon the orientation of the Jahn-Teller axis, with the magneto-structural correlation also dependent upon the Mn-N-O-Mn angles - with ferromagnetic interactions at smaller dihedral angles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 44(46)19805-19811</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5dt03615a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18018</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>