<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3145</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Protection against peroxynitrite-mediated nitration reaction by intramolecularly coordinated diorganoselenides</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>WOLMERSHAUSER, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>synthetic organoselenium compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>glutathione-peroxidase activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>free-radical synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>dot-n interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitric-oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen-peroxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>organotellurium compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>antioxidant activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>ebselen derivatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>remarkable activity</dc:subject><dc:description>A series of intramolecularly Se center dot center dot center dot X (X = N, O) coordinated diorganoselenides and sulfides are synthesized by using the heteroatom-directed lithiation route and characterized by multinuclear (H-1, C-13, Se-77) NMR, IR spectroscopy, and electrospray mass spectrometry (ES-MS). The intramolecular Se center dot center dot center dot O interactions in diorganoselenides 26-31 have been studied by multinuclear NMR studies in solution and in the solid state by single-crystal X-ray crystallography. The protection against peroxynitrite-mediated nitration reaction (PN assay) by diorganoselenides/-sulfides (with and without intramolecular coordination) has been evaluated. The PN assay data of diorganoselenides reveal that the selenides 20-22, having a basic amino group (sp(3)-N donor) in close proximity of selenium, are more active compared to the diorganoselenides 16-19, having an imino group (sp(2)-N donor), and also show much higher protective action than the unsubstituted diorganoselenides 14 and 15. The diorganoselenides 16-31 were oxidized to corresponding selenoxides 44-59. The redox properties of the selenoxides 13 and 44-59 have been investigated by cyclic voltammetry and potentiometric titration experiments. Two redox potentials for in situ-generated ferrocenyl selenoxides (50, 54-59) were observed. The reduction of selenoxides 13 and 48 to ebselen (2) and selenide 20 with benzenethiol (PhSH) was monitored by ES-MS.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-15T07:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-15T07:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANOMETALLICS,25(2)382-393</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0276-7333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/om050353c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13953</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3145</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>