<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15804</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:38:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Lower Rim 1,3-Di{4-antipyrine}amide Conjugate of Calix[4]arene: Synthesis, Characterization, and Selective Recognition of Hg2+ and Its Sensitivity toward Pyrimidine Bases</dc:title><dc:creator>DESSINGOU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>TABBASUM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>MERCURY(II)</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEAD(II)</dc:subject><dc:description>The structurally characterized lower rim 1,3-di{4-antipyrine}amide conjugate of calix[4]arene (L) exhibits high selectivity toward Hg2+ among other biologically important metal ions, viz., Na+, K+, Ca2+, Mg2+, Mn2+, Fe2+, Co2+, Ni2+, Zn2+, Cd2+, Hg2+, Pb2+, and Ag+ as studied by fluorescence, absorption, and ES1 MS. L acts as a sensor for Hg2+ by switch-off fluorescence and exhibits a lowest detectable concentration of 1.87 +/- 0.1 ppm. The complex formed between L and Hg2+ is found to be 1:1 on the basis of absorption and fluorescence titrations and was confirmed by ESI MS. The coordination features of the mercury complex of L were derived on the basis of DFT computations and found that the Hg2+ is bound through an N2O2 extending from both the arms to result in a distorted octahedral geometry with two vacant sites. The nanostructural features such as shape and size obtained using AFM and TEM distinguishes L from its Hg2+ complex and were different from those of the simple mercuric perchlorate. L is also suited to sense pyrimidine bases by fluorescence quenching with a minimum detection limit of 1.15 +/- 0.1 ppm in the case of cytosine. The nature of interaction of pyrimidine bases with L has been further studied by DFT computational calculations and found to have interactions through a hydrogen bonding and NH-pi interaction between the host and the guest.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:38:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:38:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 77(3)1406-1413</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo2022372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15804</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>