<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16269</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T09:19:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Power and efficiency analysis of a realistic resonant tunneling diode thermoelectric</dc:title><dc:creator>AGARWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURALIDHARAN, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>QUANTUM-DOT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIGURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MERIT</dc:subject><dc:description>Low-dimensional systems with sharp features in the density of states have been proposed as a means for improving the efficiency of thermoelectric devices. Quantum dot systems, which offer the sharpest density of states achievable, however, suffer from low power outputs while bulk (3-D) thermoelectrics, while displaying high power outputs, offer very low efficiencies. Here, we analyze the use of a resonant tunneling diode structure that combines the best of both aspects, that is, density of states distortion with a finite bandwidth due to confinement that aids the efficiency and a large number of current carrying transverse modes that enhances the total power output. We show that this device can achieve a high power output (similar to 0.3 MW/m(2)) at efficiencies of similar to 40% of the Carnot efficiency due to the contribution from these transverse momentum states at a finite bandwidth of kT/2. We then provide a detailed analysis of the physics of charge and heat transport with insights on parasitic currents that reduce the efficiency. Finally, a comparison between the resonant tunneling diode and a quantum dot device with comparable bandwidth reveals that a similar performance requires ultra-dense areal quantum dot densities of similar to 10(12)/cm(2). (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:19:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:19:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 105(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1077-3118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4888859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16269</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>