<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3009</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Chemistry of biological photoreceptors based on linear polyenes</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOTA, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>photoreceptors</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoactive proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>rhodopsins</dc:subject><dc:subject>inear polyences</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanotechnology</dc:subject><dc:subject>excited-state properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>donor-acceptor diarylbutadienes</dc:subject><dc:subject>alpha-chymotrypsin activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>retinylidene schiff-base</dc:subject><dc:subject>point-charge model</dc:subject><dc:subject>visual pigments</dc:subject><dc:subject>hula-twist</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacteriorhodopsin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>wavelength regulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>angstrom resolution</dc:subject><dc:description>Many biological processes like vision, microbial phototxis and proton pump are mediated by photoreceptors that are mde of a proton pump are mediated by photoreceptors that are made of a protein covalently bound to a linear polyene like retinal (vitamin A aldehyde). Recent years have witnessed extensive multidisciplinary inquiry into the molecular details of the structure, excited state dynamics and mechanism of functions of these photoreceptors, and a great deal of information is now available. These photoreceptor proteins exhibit unique electro-optical features, and constitute properties of a multiple cycle photoswitch. Hence, these arc being considered for applications as photoactive element in molecular electronic/ nanotechnological devices, particularly in optical information processing. Attempts are also being made to enhance the performance of these proteins for such applications. Additionally, semi-synthetic photoswitches based on some of the photoreceptors arc also being developed. The subject of photobiomolecular switches presents challenge and indeed an unique opportunity to chemists for not only unraveling the basic principles underlying the functioning of these systems but also for developing improved quality photoswitches that can find various applications. Basic studies of their chemistry, excited state properties of the chromophores, model studies, development of semi-synthetic systems, and enhancement of their performance by various physical, chemical, and biochemical means can lead to more exciting usage of these unique photon-powered molecular machines. The coming years are expected to witness increased multidisciplinary endeavours with a goal for better understanding of the excited state structure and dynamics of the chromophores and also for construction of nanotechnological devices based on these photoactive proteins and/or their analogues. A brief account of the structure and mechanism of functions of some of the photoreceptors is given in this article. The literature on the subject is indeed very vast and it is:not possible to cite all the literature because of the nature of this article. Only a few representative citations are given, and wherever possible citation of review articles has been made.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ACAD SCIENCES INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T19:25:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T19:25:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATIONAL ACADEMY SCIENCE LETTERS-INDIA,29,231-252</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-541X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13828</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3009</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>