<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4475</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synchronization of an ensemble of oscillators regulated by their spatial movement</dc:title><dc:creator>SARKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARMANANDA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>lasers</dc:subject><dc:subject>chaos</dc:subject><dc:description>Synchronization for a collection of oscillators residing in a finite two dimensional plane is explored. The coupling between any two oscillators in this array is unidirectional, viz., master-slave configuration. Initially the oscillators are distributed randomly in space and their autonomous time-periods follow a Gaussian distribution. The duty cycles of these oscillators, which work under an on-off scenario, are normally distributed as well. It is realized that random hopping of oscillators is a necessary condition for observing global synchronization in this ensemble of oscillators. Global synchronization in the context of the present work is defined as the state in which all the oscillators are rendered identical. Furthermore, there exists an optimal amplitude of random hopping for which the attainment of this global synchronization is the fastest. The present work is deemed to be of relevance to the synchronization phenomena exhibited by pulse coupled oscillators such as a collection of fireflies. (C) 2010  [doi:10.1063/1.3496399]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T17:07:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T17:07:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHAOS, 20(4), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1054-1500</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3496399</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4475</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4475</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>