<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16355</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:26:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Negative differential conductivity and carrier heating in gate-all-around Si nanowire FETs and its impact on CMOS logic circuits</dc:title><dc:creator>NAYAK, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJAJ, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KONAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>OLDIGES, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>IWAI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURALI, KVRM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTOR-DEVICE SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICON NANOWIRES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHONON TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAND-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOSFETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HOT</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we present a fully-coupled and self-consistent continuum based three-dimensional numerical analysis to understand hot carrier and device self-heating effects for device-circuit co-optimization in Si gate-all-around nanowire FETs. We employ three-moment based energy transport formulations and two-dimensional quantum confinement effects to demonstrate negative differential conductivity in Si nanowire FETs and assess its impact on a CMOS inverter and three-stage ring oscillator. We show that strong two-dimensional quantum confinement yields volume inversion conditions in Si nanowire FETs and surround gate geometry enables better short-channel effect control. We find that hot carrier and self-heating effects can degrade ON-state current in Si nanowire FETs and severely limit the logic circuit performance due to the introduction of higher signal propagation delays. (C) 2014 The Japan Society of Applied Physics</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:26:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:26:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JAPANESE JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 53(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-4922</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1347-4065</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.7567/JJAP.53.04EC16</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16355</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>