<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7795</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Turbulent mixing enhancement with a 10 degrees chute mixer</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMED, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, SD</dc:creator><dc:subject>central-lobed mixer</dc:subject><dc:subject>coaxial jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>velocity-measurements</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulence</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulent flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>aircraft engines</dc:subject><dc:description>Purpose - Turbulent mixing of two co-axial jets having a low annular to core area ratio is enhanced by employing a chute mixer directing part of the annular stream at 10 degrees towards the core region. Aims to present results from measurements of time-averaged and fluctuating components of velocity under cold flow conditions, Design/methodology/approach - Experiments were conducted at a bypass ratio of 0.47 which is a typical value for low bypass turbofan engines. Contours of time-averaged velocity and streamwise and transverse turbulence intensities were obtained by making detailed measurements close to the chutes. Distributions of time-averaged velocity and turbulence intensity were obtained at different axial locations downstream of the chute mixer. Total and static pressure measurements were also performed. Findings - The high velocity annular stream was found to quickly diffuse after entering through the chutes and mix with the core stream due to high turbulence generation. A strong transverse turbulence component enhanced the mixing of the streams. With the aid of the chute mixer, nearly complete mixing is achieved over a length of 5 duct radii. A higher total pressure loss of about 1.38 percent is the penalty paid for the enhanced mixing. Originality/value - Provides results from experiments into the process of turbulent mixing of co-axial jets.</dc:description><dc:publisher>EMERALD GROUP PUBLISHING LIMITED</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T18:45:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T18:45:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AIRCRAFT ENGINEERING AND AEROSPACE TECHNOLOGY, 77(5), 404-414</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0002-2667</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/00022660510617149</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7795</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7795</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>