<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3920</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>IR-UV double resonance spectroscopic investigation of phenylacetylene-alcohol complexes. Alkyl group induced hydrogen bond switching</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, PC</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:subject>vibrational-spectra</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzene</dc:subject><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorobenzene</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>shifts</dc:subject><dc:description>The electronic transitions of phenylacetylene complexes with water and trifluoroethanol are shifted to the blue, while the corresponding transitions for methanol and ethanol complexes are shifted to the red relative to the phenylacetylene monomer. Fluorescence dip infrared (FDIR) spectra in the O-H stretching region indicate that, in all the cases, phenylacetylene is acting as a hydrogen bond acceptor to the alcohols. The FDIR spectrum in the acetylenic C-H stretching region shows Fermi resonance bands for the bare phenylacetylene, which act as a sensitive tool to probe the intermolecular structures. The FDIR spectra reveal that water and trifluoroethanol interact with the pi electron density of the acetylene C-C triple bond, while methanol and ethanol interact with the pi electron density of the benzene ring. It can be inferred that the hydrogen bonding acceptor site on phenlacetylene switches from the acetylene pi to the benzene pi with lowering in the partial charge on the hydrogen atom of the OH group. The most significant finding is that the intermolecular structures of water and methanol complexes are notably distinct, which, to the best of our knowledge, this is first such observation in the case of complexes of substituted benzenes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T09:25:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T09:25:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 112(23), 5121-5125</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp800968g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3920</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3920</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>