<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7187</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of spanwise pitch on local heat transfer distribution for in-line arrays of circular jets with spent air flow in two opposite directions</dc:title><dc:creator>KATTI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>staggered arrays</dc:subject><dc:subject>impinging jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>cross-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>reynolds-number</dc:subject><dc:subject>mach number</dc:subject><dc:subject>impingement</dc:subject><dc:subject>visualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>spacings</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>plate</dc:subject><dc:subject>jet impingement cooling</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple jets</dc:subject><dc:description>Effect of spanwise jet-to-jet spacing on local heat transfer distribution due to an in-line rectangular array of confined multiple circular air jets impinging on a surface parallel to the jet plate are studied experimentally. Length-to-diameter ratio of nozzles of the jet plate is 1.0. The flow. after impingement, is constrained to exit in two opposite directions from the confined passage formed betweenjet plate and target plate. Mean jet Reynolds numbers based on the nozzle exit diameter (d) covered are 3000, 5000, 7500 and 10,000 and jet-to-plate spacings studied are d, 2d and 3d. Spanwise pitches considered are 2d, 4d and 6d in steps of 2d keeping the streamwise pitch at 5d. For all the configurations, the jet-plates have ten spanwise rows in streamwise direction and six jets in each spanwise row. Flat heat transfer surface is made of thin stainless steel metal foil. Local temperature distribution on a target plate is measured using thermal infrared camera. Wall static pressure on the target plate is measured in the streamwise direction to estimate crossflow velocities and individual jet velocities. Heat transfer characteristics are explained on the basis of the flow distribution. A simple correlation to predict streamwise distribution of heat transfer coefficients averaged over each spanwise strip resolved to one jet hole is developed. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T09:40:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T09:40:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTAL THERMAL AND FLUID SCIENCE, 33(1), 84-95</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0894-1777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2008.07.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7187</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7187</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>