<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17036</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:51:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel concept to estimate the steady state heat flux from impinging premixed flame jets in an enclosure by numerical IHCP technique</dc:title><dc:creator>HINDASAGERI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDULA, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Enclosure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flame jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>IHCP</dc:subject><dc:subject>Local heat flux</dc:subject><dc:subject>Infrared thermography</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS</dc:subject><dc:description>Most of the flame jet impingement in industrial and domestic applications is carried out in an enclosure. However, no data is available in the literature for impinging flame jets in an enclosure. The present experimental study proposes a novel concept for obtaining the heat flux distribution using numerical IHCP technique. The heat flux evaluated by the present method has high spatial resolution, requires short time and is found to be reasonably accurate. The heat transfer distribution of a single flame jet from tube burner of 7.5 mm diameter is studied at Reynolds number varying from 500 to 900 with and without enclosure. The heat transfer distribution of three circular tube burners of diameter 7.5 mm is studied at Reynolds number varying from 500 to 900 with and without enclosure. The ratio of distance from the burner tip to the impingement plate to the burner diameter is varied from 1.9 to 5.1. A comparison of average heat flux distribution of three tube burner pair (7.5 mm diameter) with two tube burner pair (11.25 mm diameter) is carried out for similar conditions. The presence of enclosure has negligible effect on the heat transfer distribution from flame jets for both single and multiple jets. It is found that two tube burner pair has higher (8% to 18%) average heat flux distribution and more uniformity as compared to three tube burner pair. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:51:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:51:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 79342-352</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-2189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2014.08.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17036</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>