<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17502</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:30:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization of electroless nickel as a seed layer for silicon solar cell metallization</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVAL, MC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:subject>PHOSPHORUS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTACT</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ni-Cu metallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>electroless nickel</dc:subject><dc:subject>contact resistivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel silicide</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel phosphides</dc:subject><dc:description>Electroless nickel plating is a suitable method for seed layer deposition in Ni-Cu-based solar cell metallization. Nickel silicide formation and hence contact resistivity of the interface is largely influenced by the plating process and annealing conditions. In the present work, a thin seed layer is deposited from neutral pH and alkaline electroless nickel baths which are annealed in the range of 400-420(a similar to)C for silicide morphology and contact resistivity studies. A minimum contact resistivity of 7 m Omega cm(2) is obtained for seed layer deposited from alkaline bath. Silicide formation for Pd-activated samples leads to uniform surface morphology as compared with unactivated samples due to non-homogeneous migration of nickel atoms at the interface. Formation of nickel phosphides during annealing and the presence of SiO2 at Ni-Si interface creates isolated Ni2Si-Si interface with limited supply of silicon. Such an interface leads to the formation of high resistivity metal-rich Ni3Si silicide phase which limits the reduction in contact resistivity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:30:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:30:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 38(1)197-201</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-4707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-7669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12034-014-0828-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17502</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>