<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1606</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Relationship between interplanetary (IP) parameters and geomagnetic indices during IP shock events of 2005</dc:title><dc:creator>RATHOD, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAM, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALYANA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, AC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, CG</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, MYS</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTH, AG</dc:creator><dc:subject>magnetic clouds</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar-wind</dc:subject><dc:subject>field</dc:subject><dc:subject>ip parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>ip shocks</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar-terrestrial relationship</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, we investigate the possible relationship of IP parameters of solar wind and interplanetary magnetic field with ground-based geomagnetic indices. To carry out the study, we take all the IP shock events listed by Proton Monitor onboard Solar and Heliospheric Observatory (SOHO) during 2005, and plot the time variations of all the IP parameters and geomagnetic parameters (+/-5 days), centered at the shock arrival time. Next, we obtain scatter plots of absolute values of solar wind parameters such as Vsw, Nsw and Interplanetary Magnetic Field (IMF) components Bx, By, Bz and total B with the values of geomagnetic parameters such as Dst, Kp indices, dayside Magnetopause (MP) distance and Cosmic-Ray Neutron Monitor count (CRNM). The scatter plots show that before the IP shock, the pattern is random with no clear relationship. Following the shock, a clear pattern emerges with a type of relationship being seen - clear for SHARP shocks and less clear for DIFFUSE shocks. A total of 10 shock events for 2005 have been studied. Typical examples of this behaviour are the shock events of January 21, 2005 and May 15, 2005. Our study suggests a definite correlation between changes in the solar wind and interplanetary magnetic field parameters and ground-based geomagnetic response. We are trying to obtain quantitative relationships between these for shock events of 2005.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T04:16:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T04:16:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ASTROPHYSICS AND ASTRONOMY,29,293-302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-6335</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12036-008-0039-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14817</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1606</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Challenges for Solar Cycle 24,Ahmedabad, INDIA,JAN 22-25, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>