<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18033</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:19:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Steric group enforced aromatic cyclic trimer conformer in tripodal molecules</dc:title><dc:creator>SATHIYASHIVAN, SD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANKAR, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJAKANNU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISHNOI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MASRAM, DT</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYENDIRAN, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>SMALL BENZENE CLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PI-INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TETRAMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMOCHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BENZIMIDAZOLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:description>A family of tripodal molecules (1-6) with/without steric ethyl groups at the central benzene scaffold and with furan/thiophene/pyridyl group at the 2-position of the benzimidazolyl unit was synthesised. Compounds 1-6 were characterized by elemental analysis and NMR spectroscopy. Compounds 1, 3, and 5 were further characterized by single crystal X-ray diffraction analysis. The molecular structures of 1 and 4 were optimized using density functional theory (DFT) calculations. X-ray and H-1 NMR studies reveal that the introduction of three ethyl groups into a central benzene scaffold of furan/thiophene/pyridyl substituted benzimidazolyl based tripodal molecules enhances the edge-to-face C-H/p interactions, thereby favouring the aromatic cyclic trimer motif, in solution and the solid state. The unsubstituted central benzene scaffold allows the furan/thiophene substituted benzimidazolyl units in the tripodal molecules to move freely thereby weakening the edge-to-face C-H/p interactions between the aromatic cyclic trimer motif. Molecular modelling calculations indicate that the energy minimized structures of the tripodal molecules adopt a symmetric cyclic aromatic motif conformation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:19:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:19:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 5(91)74705-74711</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5ra05151g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18033</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>