<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12039</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>An efficient algorithm for range computation of polynomials using the Bernstein form</dc:title><dc:creator>RAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NATARAJ, PSV</dc:creator><dc:subject>global optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>filled functions</dc:subject><dc:subject>bernstein polynomials</dc:subject><dc:subject>global optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>interval analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>polynomial optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>range computation</dc:subject><dc:description>We present a novel optimization algorithm for computing the ranges of multivariate polynomials using the Bernstein polynomial approach. The proposed algorithm incorporates four accelerating devices, namely the cut-off test, the simplified vertex test, the monotonicity test, and the concavity test, and also possess many new features, such as, the generalized matrix method for Bernstein coefficient computation, a new subdivision direction selection rule and a new subdivision point selection rule. The features and capabilities of the proposed algorithm are compared with those of other optimization techniques: interval global optimization, the filled function method, a global optimization method for imprecise problems, and a hybrid approach combining simulated annealing, tabu search and a descent method. The superiority of the proposed method over the latter methods is illustrated by numerical experiments and qualitative comparisons.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T09:15:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T09:15:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GLOBAL OPTIMIZATION, 45(3), 403-426</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-5001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10898-008-9382-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12039</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>