<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-801</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Generation of multi-block topology for discretisation of three-dimensional domains</dc:title><dc:creator>SHIRSAT, AMIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SANDEEP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHEVARE, GOPAL R</dc:creator><dc:subject>computational geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesh generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>digital simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>Simulations of field equations in science and engineering require tessellation of space. In the parlance of computational mechanics, this is called mesh generation or grid generation. It refers to the creation of discrete points and their connectivity (neighbourhood information) so as to input the geometry of the domain to the simulation codes. Different methods require different kinds of neighbourhood information. If a simulation method accepts triangulated surface patches in two dimensions and tetrahedra in three dimensions a great amount of automation is possible. But if a method 
demands a set of curvilinear coordinates typified by a two or three-dimensional array of points, a lot of human interaction is needed. This interaction happens to be mostly in the creation of sub-domains called blocks, in which these points are generated. The present paper proposes to make the blocks with a view to minimise user interaction.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-27T11:07:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:01:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-27T11:07:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:01:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computers &amp; Graphics 23(1), 45-57</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0097-8493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0097-8493(98)00115-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/801</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/801</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>