<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1182</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:09:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of optical properties of swift heavy ion irradiated gallium antimonide</dc:title><dc:creator>DUBEY, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUBEY, RL</dc:creator><dc:creator>YADAV, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>JADHAV V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHANTY, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANJILAL, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>gasb</dc:subject><dc:subject>high-energy ion irradiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>gallium antimonide</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>ftir</dc:subject><dc:subject>defects</dc:subject><dc:subject>annealing</dc:subject><dc:description>Gallium antimonide (GaSb) which is a narrow band gap compound semiconductor has received attention because of its potential applications in optoelectronic devices. In the present work, p-type GaSb wafers of &lt; 100 &gt; orientation were irradiated with 70 MeV (56)Fe ions at fluences varying from 1 x 10(12) to 1 x 10(14) ions cm(-2). Mid-infrared and Far-infrared Fourier Transform (FT) measurements were carried out to investigate the optical properties of as irradiated and vacuum annealed samples. Mid-infrared Fourier Transform study revealed that the optical absorption of the irradiated samples increases with increasing ion fluence due to increase in irradiation-induced defects. The band gap energy determined from the infrared spectra was found to change from 0.65 to 0.62 eV while for non-irradiated GaSb wafer the corresponding estimate was 0.67 eV. The density of the carrier estimated from the plasma frequency (omega(p)) was found to vary from 2.05 x 10(18) to 1.9 x 10(18) cm(-3). The samples annealed in vacuum (10(-6) mb) over the temperature range 100-600 degrees C showed the significant damage recovery. Crown Copyright (c) 2005 Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T08:58:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T08:58:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION B-BEAM INTERACTIONS WITH MATERIALS AND ATOMS,244(1)141-144</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-583X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nimb.2005.11.131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14377</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1182</dc:identifier><dc:source>Indo German Workshop on Synthesis and Modifications of Nano-Structured Materials by Energetic Ion Beams,New Delhi, INDIA,FEB 20-24, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>