<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17634</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:37:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel multistage decision fusion for cognitive sensor networks using AND and OR rules</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>RADIO NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AND</dc:subject><dc:subject>OR</dc:subject><dc:subject>Radix-2 multistage decision fusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Correct decision probability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cooperative spectrum sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computational complexity</dc:subject><dc:description>We propose a centralized radix-2 multistage decision fusion strategy comprising simple AND and OR rules for cooperative spectrum sensing in cognitive sensor networks. Earlier works on centralized decision fusion show the half-voting and majority rules to be optimum in many spectrum sensing scenarios in terms of minimizing the decision error (or equivalently maximizing the probability of correct decision). We consider a commonly occurring case in spectrum sensing in which the detection probability of a cognitive radio enabled sensor node is greater than its false-alarm probability. For this case, we consider five scenarios and demonstrate that the proposed method either performs better than half-voting and majority rules or exhibits a comparable performance. In this context, we also establish a criterion to make a choice between the AND and OR rules and compute the optimum number of nodes participating in cooperative spectrum sensing for these rules to maximize the correct decision probability. (c) 2015 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:37:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:37:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING, 42,27-34</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1051-2004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1095-4333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.dsp.2015.04.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17634</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>