<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8866</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assessment of geo-coding and height accuracy of the DEM derived from preliminary data sets of X-band SRTM</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALKE, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARUP, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>AL-JASSAR, HK</dc:creator><dc:description>The first data set of X-band Digital Elevation Model (DEM), derived from Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM), of GuJarat Earthquake affected area was processed to assess the geo-coding and height accuracy. A detailed Survey of the Study area was carried out using Differential-GPS systems to get accurate control points. Though, it is the first data set processed without Attitude and Orbit Determination Avionics, the geo-coding and height accuracy is good. It is observed that there is an average shift of -1.5 pixels in Latitude and 2.5 pixels in Longitude with 1.5 pixels Standard Deviation (STD). A comparison of SRTM and Ditferential-GPS heights indicates that there is a bias of 7.4 m with STD of 3.4 m. This is in agreement with the height errors reported by the Deutschen Zentrums fur Luft- Lind Raumfahrt (DLR) in Height Error Map (HEM) data set.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN SOCIETY  REMOTE SENSING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T16:27:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T16:27:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHOTONIRVACHAK-JOURNAL OF THE INDIAN SOCIETY OF REMOTE SENSING, 34(4), 369-375</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0255-660X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8866</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8866</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>