<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16915</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:43:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Glucose oxidase enzyme immobilized porous silica for improved performance of a glucose biosensor</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, AY</dc:creator><dc:creator>NORONHA, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Biocatalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biosensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Enzyme activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Immobilized enzymes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mesoporous silica</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glucose oxidase</dc:subject><dc:subject>MESOPOROUS MOLECULAR-SIEVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SBA-15</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENCAPSULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSPHERES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LYSOZYME</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:description>High activity of glucose oxidase (GOD) enzyme (immobilized in porous silica particles) is desirable for a better glucose biosensor. In this work, effect of pore diameter of two porous hosts on enzyme immobilization, activity and glucose sensing was compared. The hosts were amine functionalized: (i) microporous silica (NH2-MS) and (ii) mesoporous silica (NH2-SBA-15). Based on whether the dimension of GOD is either larger or smaller than the pore diameter, GOD was immobilized on either external or internal surface of NH2-MS and NH2-SBA-15, with loadings of 512.5 and 634 mg/g, respectively. However, GOD in NH2-SBA-15 gave a higher normalized absolute activity (NAA), which led to an amperometric sensor with a larger linear range of 0.4-13.0 mM glucose. In comparison, GOD in NH2-MS had a lower NAA and a smaller linear range of 0.4-3.1 mM. In fact, the present GOD-NH2-SBA-15 electrode based sensor was better than other MS and SBA-15 based electrodes reported in literature. Thus, achieving only a high GOD loading (as in NH2-MS) does not necessarily give a good sensor performance. Instead, a host with a relatively larger pore than enzyme, together with optimized electrode composition ensures the sensor to be functional in both hyper- and hypoglycemic range. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:43:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:43:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHEMICAL ENGINEERING JOURNAL, 9178-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1369-703X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-295X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bej.2014.07.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16915</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>