<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4073</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spectroscopy and Microscopy Studies of the Recognition of Amino Acids and Aggregation of Proteins by Zn(II) Complex of Lower Rim Naphthylidene Conjugate of Calix[4]arene</dc:title><dc:creator>CHINTA, JP</dc:creator><dc:creator>ACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>bovine serum-albumin</dc:subject><dc:subject>zinc(ii) complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>gas-phase</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrosprayed ions</dc:subject><dc:subject>cysteine</dc:subject><dc:subject>fragmentations</dc:subject><dc:subject>homocysteine</dc:subject><dc:subject>histidine</dc:subject><dc:subject>zwitterions</dc:subject><dc:subject>selectivity</dc:subject><dc:description>A lower rim naphthylidene conjugate of calix[4]arene [L] has been synthesized and characterized, and the structure has been established on the basis of single crystal XRD. The L has been found to be selective toward Zn(2+), which induces appropriate changes in the arms of L so that the N(2)O(2) coordination results in the formation of a tetrahedral complex; namely, [ZnL]. [ZnL] recognizes Asp, Cys, His, and Glu from among the naturally occurring amino acids owing to the protonation and chelating ability of the amino acid and the pi-pi interaction ability of the side chain of the amino acid with [ZnL]. All of these features have been demonstrated oil the basis of fluorescence, absorption, and lifetime measurements. The rechelation of Zn(2+) by the amino acid used in the titration has been demonstrated on the basis of ESI-MS studies in the case of Cys to result in a Zn(2+) complex having either 5- or 6-coordination. [ZnL] has also been shown to be selective toward glutathione and glutathione oxidized, The amino acids present in the proteins also interact with [ZnL], resulting in dechelation of [ZnL] as well as aggregation of the protein, as demonstrated on the basis of absorption and fluorescence spectroscopy and atomic force microscopy. The alpha-helical proteins (namely, albumins) exhibit greater conformational changes, as compared to the beta-sheet proteins (namely, lectins), as studied oil the basis of CD spectroscopy, The aggregation of the proteins when treated with [ZnL] follows a trend: peanut agglutinin &lt; bovine serum albumin &lt; jacalin &lt; human serum albumin. The present studies clearly demonstrated the recognition features of [ZnL] toward Asp, Cys, His, and Glu, and the peptides and proteins containing these by spectroscopy and microscopy studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T21:25:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T21:25:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY B, 113(35), 12075-12083</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-6106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp903099b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4073</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4073</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>