<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12214</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Glauconites from the Late Palaeocene - Early Eocene Naredi Formation, Western Kutch and their Genetic Implications</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATTORAJ, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARASWATI, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>penganga group</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>framework</dc:subject><dc:subject>origin</dc:subject><dc:subject>glauconite</dc:subject><dc:subject>subtidal</dc:subject><dc:subject>pellets</dc:subject><dc:subject>feldspar</dc:subject><dc:subject>authigenic</dc:subject><dc:subject>palaeogene</dc:subject><dc:subject>western kutch</dc:subject><dc:description>Glauconitic minerals are considered as one of the valuable input parameters in sequence stratigraphic analysis of a basin. In the present study glauconitic minerals are reported from subtidal green shale facies in the lower part of the Late Paleocene-Early Eocene Naredi Formation of western Kutch. On the basis of the foraminiferal assemblage the glauconite hearing beds are interpreted to have formed in a mid shelf depositional settings of an unstable marine conditions. XRD studies confirm the glauconite mineralogy of the green pellets and provide an estimation of glauconite maturity. Textural attributes of the glauconites confirm their derivation by different degrees of alteration of precursor feldspar grains. Because of the authigenic origin and autochthonous nature, these glauconites hold promise for understanding sequence stratigraphy of the Palaeogene succession of the western Kutch.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T05:55:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T05:55:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 73(4), 567-574</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12214</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12214</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>