<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12162</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Single reservoir operating policies using genetic algorithm</dc:title><dc:creator>JOTHIPRAKASH, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANTHI, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>multireservoir systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>multi-purpose reservoir operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>operating rule curves</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>uniform cross over</dc:subject><dc:subject>modified mutation</dc:subject><dc:description>To obtain optimal operating rules for storage reservoirs, large numbers of simulation and optimization models have been developed over the past several decades, which vary significantly in their mechanisms and applications. As every model has its own limitations, the selection of appropriate model for derivation of reservoir operating rule curves is difficult and most often there is a scope for further improvement as the model selection depends on data available. Hence, evaluation and modifications related to the reservoir operation remain classical. In the present study a Genetic Algorithm model has been developed and applied to Pechiparai reservoir in Tamil Nadu, India to derive the optimal operational strategies. The objective function is set to minimize the annual sum of squared deviation form desired irrigation release and desired storage volume. The decision variables are release for irrigation and other demands (industrial and municipal demands), from the reservoir. Since the rule curves are derived through random search it is found that the releases are same as that of demand requirements. Hence based on the present case study it is concluded that GA model could perform better if applied in real world operation of the reservoir.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T18:44:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T18:44:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESOURCES MANAGEMENT, 20(6), 917-929</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0920-4741</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11269-005-9014-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12162</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12162</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>