<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12081</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of volume fraction of primary alpha(2) on the trigger stress for stress-induced martensitic transformation in two-phase Ti-Al-Nb alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>PARADKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAMAT, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOGIA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>tensile properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium-alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>ti-10v-2fe-3al</dc:subject><dc:subject>niti</dc:subject><dc:description>Ti-Al-Nb alloys in the composition range studied in the present investigation were found to undergo stress-induced martensitic transformation (SIMT) in alpha(2) + beta heat-treated (two-phase) condition under tensile loading. The effect of different volume fractions of primary alpha(2) on trigger stress for SIM transformation in these alloys was investigated. The trigger stress required for SIM transformation decreased initially when the volume fraction of primary alpha(2) was increased from 0 to 5 pct. However, subsequently, the trigger stress was found to increase with further increase in volume fraction of primary alpha(2) from 5 to 40 pct in all three alloys. An increase in the volume fraction of primary alpha(2) is achieved by changing the solution treatment temperatures, which also results in a change in the beta composition and beta grain size. The observed variation of trigger stress with the volume fraction of primary alpha(2) from 5 to 40 pct was then explained on the basis of the effect of composition and grain size of the beta phase on trigger stress required for stress-induced transformation of beta to martensite.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T12:26:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T12:26:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 39A(9), 2086-2094</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-008-9560-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12081</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12081</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>