<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15681</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:36:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Lack of uniform trends but increasing spatial variability in observed Indian rainfall extremes</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAO, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>PRECIPITATION EXTREMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLIMATE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL SIMULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTENSITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent studies disagree on how rainfall extremes over India have changed in space and time over the past half century'', as well as on whether the changes observed are due to global warming(5,6) or regional urbanization(7). Although a uniform and consistent decrease in moderate rainfall has been reported, a lack of agreement about trends in heavy rainfall may be due in part to differences in the characterization and spatial averaging of extremes. Here we use extreme value theory(8-15) to examine trends in Indian rainfall over the past half century in the context of long-term, low-frequency variability. We show that when generalized extreme value theory(8,16-18) is applied to annual maximum rainfall over India, no statistically significant spatially uniform trends are observed, in agreement with previous studies using different approaches(2-4). Furthermore, our space-time regression analysis of the return levels points to increasing spatial variability of rainfall extremes over India. Our findings highlight the need for systematic examination of global versus regional drivers of trends in Indian rainfall extremes, and may help to inform flood hazard preparedness and water resource management in the region.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:36:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:36:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURE CLIMATE CHANGE, 2(2)86-91</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/NCLIMATE1327</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15681</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>