<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1605</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Distributed inter-domain lightpath provisioning in the presence of wavelength conversion</dc:title><dc:creator>LIU, Q</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, NSV</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARCIA, ML</dc:creator><dc:subject>optical wavelength conversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>fiber optic networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>switching networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>scalability</dc:subject><dc:description>Dense wavelength division multiplexing (DWDM) has become the dominant transport layer technology for next-generation backbone networks due to its unprecedented capacity scalability. As a result, there is a pressing need to investigate lightpath provisioning in multi-domain DWDM networks. Although inter-domain provisioning has been well-studied for packet/cell-switching networks, the wavelength dimension (along with wavelength conversion) presents many added challenges. To address these concerns, a detailed GMPLS-based hierarchical routing framework for provisioning transparent/translucent/opaque multi-domain DWDM networks is presented. The scheme adapts topology abstraction to hide internal domain state so as to resolve routing scalability and security issues. Specifically a novel full-mesh topology abstraction scheme is developed for full wavelength conversion domains, i.e., to disseminate additional wavelength converter state. Related inter-domain lightpath RWA and signaling schemes are also tabled. Performance analysis results are then presented to demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed mechanisms along with directions for future research work.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-07-18T05:36:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:10:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-07-18T05:36:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:10:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computer Communications 30(18), 3662-3675</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0140-3664</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.comcom.2007.07.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1605</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1605</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>