<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17522</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:40:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Discrete element modelling of conceptual deep geological repository for high-level nuclear waste disposal</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAUTAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJPAI, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>STRESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>High-level waste</dc:subject><dc:subject>Discrete element</dc:subject><dc:subject>Granite</dc:subject><dc:subject>DGR</dc:subject><dc:description>The long-lived high-level spent nuclear has to be isolated from environment for the protection of ecosystem. One of the methods suggested to isolate the nuclear waste from ecosystem is its burial in deep underground repository. In this paper, discrete element method is used to disposal of spent fuel on stability of underground space and its surrounding rock strata. Effect of temperature increment on stresses-strains and temperature variation of surrounding rockmass due to heat generated by nuclear waste is studied and discussed. Simulation was performed on both strong and jointed granite rock in which tunnel is excavated. Bentonite is used as buffer because of its high sorptivity, longevity and low permeability. It has been found that both temperature and stresses at any point in the rock mass is below the design criteria which are 100 A degrees C for temperature over a time period of 16 years.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:40:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:40:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ARABIAN JOURNAL OF GEOSCIENCES, 8(10)8027-8038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1866-7511</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1866-7538</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-014-1762-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17522</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>