<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14151</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:36:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microstructure and microtextural studies of friction stir welded aluminium alloy 5052</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMBHAR, NT</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHOO, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANUMURTHY, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRECIPITATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HARDNESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFECTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>JOINTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOOL</dc:subject><dc:description>The present investigation presents a composite picture of the microstructural developments in a friction stir welded (FSW) AA5052. Optimized, defect free and chemically homogeneous, FS weld was generalized in four regions - base material (BM), nugget, advancing side (AS) and retreating side (RS), using standard nomenclatures. Each region had its signature of microstructural features. AS had clear indications of shear and of grain fragmentation. The nugget region, on the other hand, had nearly equiaxed grains, with strong in-grain misorientation and presence of grain-interior dislocation structure ruling out contributions from static recrystallization. Equiaxed grains of the nugget region had typical onion ring structure - each ring did approximately correspond to one dominant family of orientation. Microstructural developments, as obtained from relative grain refinement, in-grain misorientation development, relative banding, etc., were most significant in nugget followed by AS and then by RS. Heterogeneous plastic deformation and thermal activation through localized heating/friction were the apparent causes. Most of the friction stir welded specimen fractured away from the nugget and showed ductile mode of failure. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:36:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:36:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS &amp; DESIGN,32(3)1657-1666</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0261-3069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2010.10.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14151</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>