<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10822</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>EXPERIMENTAL AND FINITE-ELEMENT STUDY ON MODE-I STABLE CRACK-GROWTH IN SYMMETRICALLY STIFFENED COMPACT TENSION SPECIMEN</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAVLA, PD</dc:creator><dc:subject>stress intensity factors</dc:subject><dc:subject>panels</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:description>Mode I stable crack growth results are presented under static loading through a symmetrically stiffened compact tension specimen of an aircraft grade aluminium alloy (D16AT). The results include load-deflection diagrams, J integrals, plastic zones, tunnelling (or crack front curving), etc. During experiments tunnelling is observed, the extent of which increases as the extension progresses. The maximum to initiation load ratio is about 1.60 in the observed range. From the finite element analysis it is observed that the J integral increases as the crack extends. The plastic zone also grows as the stable extension progresses; the growth is more or less maximum along the line of stable crack extension. The load-displacement diagram can be predicted reasonably accurately using the criterion of crack opening angle (or crack opening displacement at a finite distance behind the crack tip), irrespective of whether the specimen is stiffened or not.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:36:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:36:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 44(5), 721-733</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0013-7944(93)90201-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10822</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10822</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>