<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-231</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Small signal characteristics of thin film single halo SOI MOSFET for mixed mode applications</dc:title><dc:creator>NAJEEB-UD-DIN HAKIM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMGOPAL RAO, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>mosfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>doping profiles</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon-on-insulator</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor device models</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed analogue digital</dc:subject><dc:subject>integrated circuits</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we report a study on the small signal characterization and simulation of single halo (SH) thin film silicon-on-insulators (SOI) nMOSFETs for analog and mixed signal applications. The single halo structure has a high pocket impurity concentration near the source end of the channel and low impurity concentration in the rest of the channel. Besides excellent DC output characteristics, the experimental characterization results of these devices show better Vth-L roll-off, low DIBL, higher breakdown voltages and kink free operation. Small signal characterization of these devices shows higher AC transconductance, higher output resistance and better dynamic intrinsic gain (gmRo) in comparison with the conventional (CON) homogeneously doped SOI MOSFETs. Also, the low drain junction capacitance as a result of low impurity concentration near the drain region is beneficial for improved circuit performance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-08T09:14:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T18:22:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-08T09:14:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T18:22:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 16th International Conference on VLSI Design, Calcutta, India, 4-8 January 2003, 110-115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-1868-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICVD.2003.1183123</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/231</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>