<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17577</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:08:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design, synthesis and biological evaluation of di-substituted noscapine analogs as potent and microtubule-targeted anticancer agents</dc:title><dc:creator>MISHRA, RC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUNDALA, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARNA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>LOPUS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, KK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGARAJU, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAMELBERG, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>TANDON, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>REID, MD</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANEJA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>CANCER THERAPEUTICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUBULIN ISOTYPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERTURB MITOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>APOPTOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURVIVIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LYMPHOMA</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUMORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Noscapine</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anticancer activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tubulin polymerization</dc:subject><dc:description>Noscapine is an opium-derived kinder-gentler microtubule-modulating drug, currently in Phase I/II clinical trials for cancer chemotherapy. Here, we report the synthesis of four more potent di-substituted brominated derivatives of noscapine, 9-Br-7-OH-NOS (2), 9-Br-7-OCONHEt-NOS (3), 9-Br-7-OCONHBn-NOS (4), and 9-Br-7-OAc-NOS (5) and their chemotherapeutic efficacy on PC-3 and MDA-MB-231 cells. The four derivatives were observed to have higher tubulin binding activity than noscapine and significantly affect tubulin polymerization. The equilibrium dissociation constant (K-D) for the interaction between tubulin and 2, 3, 4, 5 was found to be, 55 +/- 6 mu M, 44 +/- 6 mu M, 26 +/- 3 mu M, and 21 +/- 1 mu M respectively, which is comparable to parent analog. The effects of these di-substituted noscapine analogs on cell cycle parameters indicate that the cells enter a quiescent phase without undergoing further cell division. The varying biological activity of these analogs and bulk of substituent at position-7 of the benzofuranone ring system of the parent molecule was rationalized utilizing predictive in silico molecular modeling. Furthermore, the immunoblot analysis of protein lysates from cells treated with 4 and 5, revealed the induction of apoptosis and down-regulation of survivin levels. This result was further supported by the enhanced activity of caspase-3/7 enzymes in treated samples compared to the controls. Hence, these compounds showed a great potential for studying microtubule-mediated processes and as chemotherapeutic agents for the management of human cancers. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:08:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:08:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOORGANIC &amp; MEDICINAL CHEMISTRY LETTERS, 25(10)2133-2140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-894X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1464-3405</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bmcl.2015.03.076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17577</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>