<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16311</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:04:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurement of spatial and temporal behavior of H-alpha emission from Aditya tokamak using a diagnostic based on a photomultiplier tube array</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOWDHURI, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANCHANDA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAIYA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIRANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>AMARDAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TANNA, RL</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, CN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATT, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTOPADHYAY, PK</dc:creator><dc:description>A photo multiplier tube (PMT) array based spectroscopic diagnostic with fast time response of 10 mu s and spatial resolution similar to 3 cm has been developed and installed on Aditya tokamak to study the spatial and temporal behavior of H-alpha emissions from typical discharges. Collimated light has been collected from the plasma along 16 lines of sight passing through entire plasma poloidal cross section of Aditya and detected by two 8 channels PMT arrays after selecting H-alpha emission using interference filter. The studies are carried out during plasma formation phase of Aditya by changing vertical field and its delay with respect to loop voltage. It is observed that plasma initiated in the high field side in typical discharges of Aditya. The plasma formation position is matched with null field location estimated through simulation. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:04:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:04:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS, 85(11)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0034-6748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4889912</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16311</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>