<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1678</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel K-out-of-N auction mechanism and strategic scaling for dynamic bandwidth allocation in GE-PON</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR NAGARAJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDHE, ASHISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>bandwidth allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical fibre lan</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical fibre networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>protocols</dc:subject><dc:description>Dynamic bandwidth allocation for upstream transmission in EPONs has gathered significant attention. Maximizing utilization is inversely related to dynamic bandwidth allocation. We propose an auctioning mechanism for bandwidth allocation with a view to dissolution of the paradox between efficiency (utilization) and dynamism. While conventional bandwidth auctioning schemes pose efficiency as well as fairness issues, our extensions overcome these. We propose three extensions: to increase efficiency we propose a K-out-of-N auctioning mechanism; to promote dynamism and reduce bandwidth starvation, we enhance the auctioning mechanism by introducing strategic scaling; and to cater to services we propose a bid computation mechanism that is uniquely tailored to reflect different service requirements. Through a simulation model we evaluate the performance of our scheme for latency, dynamism, efficiency and blocking probability.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:26:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:01:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:26:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:01:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE Global Telecommunications Conference, San Francisco, California, USA, 27 November-1 December 2006, 1-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0356-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/GLOCOM.2006.359</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1678</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1678</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>