<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-46</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pseudo-dynamic approach of seismic active earth pressure behind retaining wall</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, DEEPANKAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIMBALKAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>earthquake resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural design</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear waves</dc:subject><dc:description>Knowledge of seismic active earth pressure behind rigid retaining wall is very important in the design of retaining wall in earthquake prone region. Commonly used Mononobe-Okabe method considers pseudo-static approach, which gives the linear distribution of seismic earth pressure in an approximate way. In this paper, the pseudo-dynamic method is used to compute the distribution of seismic active earth pressure on a rigid retaining wall supporting cohesionless backfill in more realistic manner by considering time and phase difference within the backfill. Planar rupture surface is considered in the analysis. Effects of a wide range of parameters like wall friction angle, soil friction angle, shear wave velocity, primary wave velocity and horizontal and vertical seismic accelerations on seismic active earth pressure have been studied. Results are provided in tabular and graphical non-dimensional form with a comparison to pseudo-static method to highlight the realistic non-linearity of seismic active earth pressures distribution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Springer, The Netherlands</dc:publisher><dc:date>2007-01-18T16:39:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T11:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007-01-18T16:39:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T11:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006-08</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Geotechnical and Geological Engineering 24 (5), 1103-1113</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-3182</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/46</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/46</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>