<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1328</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-30T10:32:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>S-OSPF: a traffic engineering solution for OSPF based best effort networks</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, ANIRUDHA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, ADITYA KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:subject>multiprotocol label switching</dc:subject><dc:subject>graph theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>routing protocols</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication traffic</dc:subject><dc:description>Open Shortest Path First (OSPF) is one of the most widely used intra-domain routing protocol. It is well known that OSPF protocol does not provide flexibility in terms of packet forwarding to achieve any network optimization objective. Because of the high cost of network assets and commercial and competitive nature of Internet service provisioning, service providers are interested in performance optimization of their networks. This helps in reducing congestion hotspots and improving resource utilization across the network, which, in turn, results in an increased revenue collection. One way of achieving this is through Traffic Engineering. Currently traffic engineering is mostly done by using MPLS. But legacy networks running OSPF would need to be upgraded to MPLS. To achieve better resource utilization without upgrading OSPF network to MPLS is a challenge. In this paper we present a simple but effective algorithm, called Smart OSPF (S-OSPF) to provide traffic engineering solution in an OSPF based best effort network. We formulate an optimization problem based on the traffic demand to minimize the maximum link utilization in the network. Routing of the traffic demand is achieved using OSPF. We have simulated S-OSPF on real networks of two service providers. Simulation results show that S- OSPF based traffic engineering solution performance very closely follows the optimal solution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-10T08:13:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:55:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-10T08:13:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:55:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE Global Telecommunications Conference, Washington, DC, 26-30 November 2007, 1845-1849</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1043-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/GLOCOM.2007.355</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1328</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1328</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>