<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16425</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:01:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic exchange in {Gd-III-radical} complexes: method assessment, mechanism of coupling and magneto-structural correlations</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJESHKUMAR, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE MAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERALIZED GRADIENT APPROXIMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITRONYL NITROXIDE RADICALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYBRID DENSITY FUNCTIONALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RARE-EARTH COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPIN GROUND-STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORRELATION-ENERGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GADOLINIUM(III) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LANTHANIDE COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:description>Density functional studies have been performed on ten different {Gd-III-radical} complexes exhibiting both ferro and antiferromagnetic exchange interaction with an aim to assess a suitable exchange-correlation functional within DFT formalism. This study has also been extended to probe the mechanism of magnetic coupling and to develop suitable magneto-structural correlations for this pair. Our method assessments reveal the following order of increasing accuracy for the evaluation of J values compared to experimental coupling constants: B(40HF)LYP &lt; BHandHLYP &lt; TPSSH &lt; PW91 &lt; PBE &lt; BP86 &lt; OLYP &lt; BLYP &lt; PBE0 &lt; X3LYP &lt; B3LYP &lt; B2PLYP. Grimme's double-hybrid functional is found to be superior compared to other functionals tested and this is followed very closely by the conventional hybrid B3LYP functional. At the basis set front, our calculations reveal that the incorporation of relativistic effect is important in these calculations and the relativistically corrected effective core potential (ECP) basis set is found to yield better Js compared to other methods. The supposedly empty 5d/6s/6p orbitals of Gd-III are found to play an important role in the mechanism of magnetic coupling and different contributions to the exchange terms are probed using Molecular Orbital (MO) and Natural Bond Orbital (NBO) analysis. Magneto-structural correlations for Gd-O distances, Gd-O-N angles and Gd-O-N-C dihedral angles are developed where the bond angles as well as dihedral angle parameters are found to dictate the sign and strength of the magnetic coupling in this series.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:01:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:01:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 16(28)14568-14577</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4cp00214h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16425</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>