<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1426</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Shape and size control of nano dispersed Mg/Al layered double hydroxide</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>spinel ferrites</dc:subject><dc:subject>ion-exchange</dc:subject><dc:subject>sonochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanomaterials</dc:subject><dc:subject>precursors</dc:subject><dc:subject>mg</dc:subject><dc:subject>layered double hydroxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>co-precipitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeta potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>size distribution</dc:subject><dc:description>Controlling the shape and size of the layered inorganic-organic hybrid particles is a challenge with conventional methods of synthesis. The co-precipitation method has been modified to synthesize Mg/Al Layered double hydroxide by controlling the particle growth using ultrasonic wave at the time of nucleation. In this project, magnesium and aluminum ions were considered as model systems with carbonate anion as intercalating agent. The resulting particles are compared with those of LDHs produced by conventional co-precipitation method at constant pH. Powder X-ray diffraction confirmed formation of the layered double hydroxide phases having crystallite size 19-20 nm in both 'a' and 'c' crystallographic directions. Transmission electron microscope and dynamic light scattering revealed nano disperse hexagonal platelets with narrow size distribution and average size was around 48 nm. The modified method reduces the particle size, increases the surface charge, narrows down the size distribution and also reduces the aspect ratio of the particles. Therefore, it is suggested that low amplitude ultrasonic wave prevents the aggregation of the nuclei, thus restricting the particle growth and results in uniform size particles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T05:51:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T05:51:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY,8(8)4218-4223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1533-4880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jnn.2008.AN22</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14599</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1426</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Advanced Nano-Materials,Bombay, INDIA,JAN 08-10, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>