<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1652</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Coal combustion residues—environmental implications and recycling potentials</dc:title><dc:creator>PAPPU, ASOKAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAXENA, MOHINI</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASOLEKAR, SHYAM R</dc:creator><dc:subject>building materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>conservation</dc:subject><dc:subject>recycling</dc:subject><dc:subject>engineering applications</dc:subject><dc:subject>management</dc:subject><dc:description>To meet the electric power requirement, the world population is greatly dependent on fossil fuel. Presently in India, about 75% of the total electrical energy (i.e.~ 100,000 MW) is generated from fossil fuel and about 105 million tons of coal combustion residues (CCRs) as solid waste/by-product is being released annually during combustion of pulverised bituminous, sub bituminous, and lignite coal. Indian coal typically has ash content of 30–60%, which results in low calorific value however low in sulphur, radioactive elements and heavy metals content.

Mostly, the CCRs is being disposed to the ash pond as thin slurry, and more than 65,000 acres of land is occupied in India for storage of this huge quantity of ash which leads ecological and environmental problems. Presently about 27% of the total CCRs produced in India is being recycled and used in various applications. The major utilisation is in cement, concrete, bricks, wood substitute products, soil stabilisation, road base/embankment, and consolidation of ground, land reclamation and for agriculture. In this paper, an attempt has been made to assess the global generation of CCRs, present utilisation and acceptability in Indian context, implications and future potentials to achieve environmental sound management.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-19T08:32:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:31:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-19T08:32:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:31:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Resources, Conservation and Recycling 43(3), 239-262</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-3449</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.resconrec.2004.06.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1652</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1652</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>