<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9108</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fault tolerant control of flexible smart structures using robust decentralized periodic output feedback technique</dc:title><dc:creator>MANJUNATH, TC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>time-invariant systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration control</dc:subject><dc:subject>simultaneous stabilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoelectric sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>pole assignment</dc:subject><dc:subject>actuators</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:description>Active vibration control is an important problem in structures. One of the ways to tackle this problem is to make the structure smart, adaptive and self-controlling. The main objective of active vibration control is to reduce the vibration of a system by automatic modification of the system's structural response. This work features the modeling and design of a robust decentralized controller for a smart flexible system using a periodic output feedback control technique when there is a failure of a system component to function (say, an actuator). The entire structure is modeled in state space form using the finite element method and Euler-Bernoulli theory principles by dividing the master structure into eight finite elements and placing the piezoelectric sensor/actuators as collocated pairs at finite element positions 2, 4, 6 and 8, thus giving rise to a multi-input multi-output plant. Robust decentralized periodic output feedback controllers are designed for the various models of the plant, retaining the first two vibratory modes and considering one actuator failure at a time. The effect of failure of one of the piezopatches on the system is observed. In this control law, the control input to each actuator of the multimodel flexible system is a function of the output of that corresponding sensor only and the gain matrix has all off-diagonal terms zero. The designed robust decentralized periodic output feedback controller provides satisfactory stabilization of the multimodel smart structure system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T18:05:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T18:05:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS &amp; STRUCTURES, 14(4), 624-636</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0964-1726</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0964-1726/14/4/021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9108</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9108</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>