<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14765</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:38:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Disappearance and recovery of luminescence in GdPO4:Eu3+ nanorods: Propose to water/OH center dot release under near infrared and gamma irradiations</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NINGTHOUJAM, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMBUSTION SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAPO4</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN</dc:subject><dc:description>Luminescence intensity of rare-earth doped materials can be varied depending on shape of particles, capping agent, and heat-treatment. This is related to the non-radiative rate possessed by the material. Here, we observed the high quenching of the luminescence intensity of Eu3+ doped GdPO4 prepared in water (H2O) medium. On the contrary, in ethylene glycol (EG) medium, it shows high luminescence. Luminescence intensity is recovered when Eu3+ doped GdPO4 nanorods prepared in H2O medium is heated above 700 degrees C. This transforms hexagonal to monoclinic structure following the removal of water. Luminescence intensity is enhanced by changing the medium from H2O to D2O and also if core-shell formation occurs. Also, we found significant variation in bending and stretching vibrations of O-H and microstructure in this material prepared in H2O and EG. Two types of O-H stretching frequencies are observed at 3450 and 3520cm(-1) in H2O medium prepared sample which are assigned to the O-H having the hydrogen bonding (surface water) and the confined water, respectively. The formation of nanorods is due to the presence of water on the surface of particles or/and inside the pores of compound. The available water in the nanoparticles pores can be utilized for the efficient killing of mass cells tumor by generating reactive free radicals (H-center dot and OH center dot) through the application of laser near infrared (NIR) source and the subsequent irradiation of gamma ray. This proposed mechanism is quite different from the conventional treatment of mass cell/malignant tumor using gamma ray radiation. Sample is highly paramagnetic and it will be useful for magnetic resonance imaging contrast agent. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4731644]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 112(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4731644</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14765</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>