<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17974</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:49:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Discrete and polymeric cobalt organophosphates: isolation of a 3-D cobalt phosphate framework exhibiting selective CO2 capture</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUPPUSWAMY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>WALSH, JPS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MCINNES, EJL</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE-MAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL-ORGANIC FRAMEWORK</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON-PARAMAGNETIC-RESONANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON-DIOXIDE CAPTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TERT-BUTYL PHOSPHATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-SITU FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZEOLITE 13X</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHONATE CAGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUXILIARY LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SWING ADSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Structurally diverse mononuclear, dinuclear, and tetranuclear cobalt organophosphates and a three-dimensional framework based on a D4R cobalt phosphate are reported. The role of auxiliary ligands in determining the nuclearity of the phosphate clusters has further been established. Reaction of cobalt acetate tetrahydrate with 2,6-di-iso-propylphenylphosphate (dippH(2)) in methanol or DMSO in the presence of ancillary N-donor ligands leads to the formation of mononuclear octahedral cobalt phosphate [Co(dippH)(2)(py)(4)] (1), dinuclear octahedral cobalt phosphates [Co(dipp)(NN)(MeOH)(2)](2)center dot 2MeOH (NN = bpy 2; phen 3), tetrahedral cobalt phosphates [Co(dipp)(L)(2)](2)center dot 2(MeOH) (L = imz 4; dmpz 5) and symmetric and asymmetric tetranuclear tetrahedral cobalt phosphates [Co(dipp)(2-apy)](4) (6) and [Co-4(dipp)(4)(2-apy)(3)(DMSO)]center dot(DMSO)center dot(H2O) (7), in nearly quantitative yields. The use of a linear N-donor ditopic linker, 3,6-di(pyridin-4-yl)-1,2,4,5-tetrazine (dptz), as the ancillary ligand leads to the formation of a robust three dimensional, four-fold interpenetrated network based on the D4R platform, {[Co(dipp) (dptz)(0.5)](4)}(n) (8), under ambient conditions. The new compounds have been characterized by analytical, thermo-analytical and spectroscopic techniques. Further, the molecular structures of compounds 1-8 have been established using single crystal X-ray diffraction studies. Compound 1 is a mononuclear complex in which the dippH ligands occupy trans-positions around the octahedral cobalt ion. The core structure of compounds 2-5, a Co2P2O4 ring, resembles the S4R (single-4-ring) SBU of zeolites, whereas the Co4P4O12 inorganic core found in compounds 6 and 7 resembles the D4R (double-4-ring) SBU. Cobalt organophosphate framework 8 shows significant CO2 adsorption at 273 K (7.73 wt% at 1 bar and 18.21 wt% at 15.5 bar) with high selectivity to CO2 uptake over N-2 and H-2 at 273 K. Magnetic studies of these symmetric complexes indicate the presence of weak antiferromagnetic interactions between the metal ions via the phosphate bridging moiety.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:49:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:49:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 44(12)5587-5601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4dt03379e</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17974</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>