<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7945</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hysteresis and phase transitions in a single partially internally wetted catalyst pellet: Thermogravimetric studies</dc:title><dc:creator>HESSARI, FA</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATIA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>multiple steady-states</dc:subject><dc:subject>trickle-bed reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>porous catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase transitions</dc:subject><dc:subject>hysteresis</dc:subject><dc:subject>partial internal wetting</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogenation</dc:subject><dc:subject>steadystate multiplicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>trickle bed reactors</dc:subject><dc:description>The hydrogenation of cyclohexene over palladium supported in a microporous gamma-alumina pellet is studied thermogravimetrically with a view to measuring the extent of partial internal wetting associated with the different steady state branches. As many as three steady state branches having significantly different degrees of internal wetting and reaction rates, with transitions between them, are confirmed from observations of catalyst weight change. It is seen that with reduction in catalyst activity the middle branch, obtained by condensation from a vapor filled pellet, is much more prominent without showing an evaporative transition for the range of hydrogen partial pressures used here. The catalyst activity is therefore an important parameter affecting the structure of the steady state branches. Hysteresis effects are found to occur, and the thermogravimetric results also confirm the importance of history in determining the catalyst state. The measured degree of wetting is in accordance with that estimated from a mathematical model incorporating capillary condensation effects in addition to reaction-diffusion phenomena. The same model also satisfactorily interprets the reaction rate variations and transitions seen in the present work.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GORDON BREACH SCI PUBL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-30T11:05:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-30T11:05:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING COMMUNICATIONS, 157(), 109-133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-6445</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00986449708936685</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7945</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7945</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>