<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16873</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:28:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>In vitro investigation of biodegradable polymeric coating for corrosion resistance of Mg-6Zn-Ca alloy in simulated body fluid</dc:title><dc:creator>GAUR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, RKS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>Magnesium alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Body implant</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silanes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogen evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOL-GEL COATINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNESIUM ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RARE-EARTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPLANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYTOTOXICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTECTION</dc:subject><dc:description>A silane-based biodegradable coating was developed and investigated to improve corrosion resistance of an Mg-6Zn-Ca magnesium alloy to delay the biodegradation of the alloy in the physiological environment. Conditions were optimized to develop a stable and uniform hydroxide layer on the alloys-surface-known to facilitate silane-substrate adhesion. A composite coating of two silanes, namely, diethylphosphatoethyltriethoxysilane (DEPETES) and bis-[3-(triethoxysilyl) propyl] tetrasulfide (BTESPT), was developed, by the sol-gel route. Corrosion resistance of the coated alloy was characterized in a modified-simulated body fluid (m-SBF), using potentiodynamic polarization and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The silane coating provided significant and durable corrosion resistance. During the course of this, hydrogen evolution and pH variation, if any, were monitored for both bare and coated alloys. The coating morphology was characterized using scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and energy dispersive X-ray analysis (EDAX) and the cross-linking in the coating was studied using Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR). As indicated by X-ray diffraction (XRD) results, an important finding was the presence of hydrated magnesium phosphate on the sample that was subjected to immersion in m-SBF for 216 h. Magnesium phosphate is reported to support osteoblast formation and tissue healing. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:28:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:28:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; ENGINEERING C-MATERIALS FOR BIOLOGICAL APPLICATIONS, 4291-101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0928-4931</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-0191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msec.2014.05.035</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16873</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>