<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15943</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:25:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study on the design and performance of a bi-directional cone flowmeter</dc:title><dc:creator>BORKAR, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENUGOPAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>DP devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bi-directional flowmeter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cone flowmeter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Installation effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>FITTINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METER</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study explores a novel design of cone flowmeter for bi-directional flow metering application. Two identical cone shapes are machined with their base circle surfaces joined together with a small step in between them and differential pressure measurement is done across the apex of the cones. The bidirectional cone flowmeter is tested under fully developed flow conditions and its performance under double 90 degrees bend (out-of-plane) is also evaluated. The bi-directional cone flowmeter is tested in a circular pipe (inside diameter of 101 mm) with water as the working medium for the flow Reynolds number ranging from 1.18 x 10(5) to 5.48 x 10(5). Influence of the half cone angle (alpha) and the location of static pressure taps on the coefficient of discharge (C-d) of a cone flowmeter are studied. Two cones with half cone angles alpha=30 degrees and alpha=45 degrees with a constant constriction ratio (beta) of 0.75 are studied. Static pressure taps are located on both sides of the bi-directional cone. Two sets of locations of static pressure taps are studied. First set includes two static pressure taps on the pipe wall in the planes of apexes of the bi-directional cone-called apex taps. Second set includes pressure taps on the pipe wall in the planes at a distance D/4 away from the apexes of the bi-directional cone-called D/4 taps. Double 90 degrees bend (out-ofplane) is placed at 1.5D, 5.5D, 9.5D and 13.5D upstream to the bi-directional cone flowmeter. It is observed that the apex static pressure taps located in the plane of apexes of the bi-directional cone result in statistically consistent coefficient of discharge for all Reynolds numbers covered in this study. The results suggest that the bi-directional cone flowmeter is insensitive to the swirl created by double 90 degrees bend (out-of-plane) placed at the upstream of cone flowmeter, if placed at a distance of 9.5D or more. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:25:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:25:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FLOW MEASUREMENT AND INSTRUMENTATION, 34151-159</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0955-5986</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-6998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.flowmeasinst.2013.09.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15943</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>