<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-687</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study on polypropylene fiber reinforced fly ash slopes</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARDWAJ, DUSHYANT KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, JN</dc:creator><dc:subject>fiber</dc:subject><dc:subject>fly ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>centrifuges</dc:subject><dc:subject>plaxis</dc:subject><dc:description>Fly ash being a waste material can be utilized in construction of roads and embankments. Randomly distributed fiber reinforced soils have recently attracted increasing attention in geotechnical
engineering. At many sites, availability of the land is a huge problem; in such situations construction of steep slope fly ash embankments is worth considering. The polypropylene staple fiber of 1% by dry weight was used with fly ash for the experimental work. Proctor compaction test, direct shear test, and unconfined compression test have been performed without and with polypropylene staple fiber. Centrifuge tests have been performed at 80 % compaction effort to observe the effect of fiber reinforcement taking two different slope angles (θ = 78.6°).
Experimental results show that due to mixing of fiber in fly ash, maximum dry density decreases and optimum amount of water content increases. Fiber reinforcement increases the shear strength of fly ash and changes its brittle behaviour into ductile behaviour. In case of reinforced slope there is a reduction in the vertical settlement and it fails at higher values of ‘g’, which means that polypropylene staple fiber reinforced slopes can sustain higher loads.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:29:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:31:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:29:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:31:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG: Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 3778-3786</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/687</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>