<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17930</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:27:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Remote para-C-H Functionalization of Arenes by a D-Shaped Biphenyl Template-Based Assembly</dc:title><dc:creator>BAG, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATRA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>MODAK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEB, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANCHERLA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAZRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTRON-DEFICIENT ARENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER-CATALYZED ARYLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRUSTRATED LEWIS PAIRS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON-HYDROGEN BONDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIRECTING GROUP</dc:subject><dc:subject>SELECTIVE ARYLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENOL DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBOXYLIC-ACIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLEFINATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Site-selective C-H functionalization has emerged as an efficient tool in simplifying the synthesis of complex molecules. Most often, directing group (DG)-assisted metallacyde formation serves as an efficient strategy to ensure promising regioselectivity. A wide variety of ortho- and meta-C-H functionalizations stand as examples in this regard. Yet despite this significant progress, DG-assisted selective para-C-H functionalizalion in arenes has remained unexplored, mainly because it involves the formation of a geometrically constrained metallacyclic transition state. Here we report an easily recyclable, novel Si-containing biphenyl-based template that directs efficient functionalization of the distal p-C-H bond of toluene by forming a D-shaped assembly. This DG allows the required flexibility to support the formation of an oversized pre-transition state. By overcoming electronic and steric bias, para-olefination and acetoxylation were successfully performed while undermining oand m-C-H activation. The applicability of this D-shaped biphenyl template-based strategy is demonstrated by synthesizing various complex molecules.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:27:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:27:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN CHEMICAL SOCIETY, 137(37)11888-11891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0002-7863</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jacs.5b06793</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17930</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>