<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12297</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Geographic Information System and groundwater quality mapping in Panvel Basin, Maharashtra, India</dc:title><dc:creator>ANBAZHAGAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIR, AM</dc:creator><dc:subject>gis</dc:subject><dc:subject>groundwater</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:description>Panvel Basin of Raigarh district, Maharashtra, India is the study area for groundwater quality mapping using the Geographic Information System (GIS). The study area is typically covered by Deccan basaltic rock types of Cretaceous to Eocene age. Though the basin receives heavy rainfall, it frequently faces water scarcity problems as well as water quality problems in some specific areas. Hence, a GIS based groundwater quality mapping has been carried out in the region with the help of data generated from chemical analysis of water samples collected from the basin. Groundwater samples show quality exceedence in terms of chloride, hardness, TDS and salinity. These parameters indicate the level of quality of groundwater for drinking and irrigation purposes. Idrisi 32 GIS software was used for generation of various thematic maps and for spatial analysis and integration to produce the final groundwater quality map. The groundwater quality map shows fragments pictorially representing groundwater zones that are desirable and undesirable for drinking and irrigation purposes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:27:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:27:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL GEOLOGY, 45(6), 753-761</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0943-0105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00254-003-0932-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12297</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12297</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>