<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17416</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:57:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of PVP template on the formation of porous TiO2 nanofibers by electrospinning technique for dye-sensitized solar cell</dc:title><dc:creator>ELAYAPPAN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANNEERSELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEMALA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NALLATHAMBI, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANGAIAH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>SOLVOTHERMAL SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TITANIUM-DIOXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLID-STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMBRANE ELECTROLYTE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH-EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIBERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIQUID</dc:subject><dc:description>The porous TiO2 nanofibers were prepared by electrospinning technique using polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP) as template as well as pore-forming agent at the calcination temperature of 475 A degrees C for 5 h. The influence of various concentrations of PVP (5, 8 and 10 wt%) on the surface area and porosity of the prepared TiO2 nanofibers (NFs) were studied by using BET-specific surface area analyzer. The TiO2 NFs obtained by using 5 wt% of PVP had higher surface area and porosity than those obtained by using 8 and 10 wt% of PVP. The prepared electrospun TiO2 NFs were characterized by using TG analysis, X-ray diffraction, FTIR, FE-SEM and TEM studies. Finally, dye-sensitized solar cells were assembled using the prepared TiO2 NFs as the photoanode, Pt as the cathode and 0.5 M 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium iodide, 0.5 M LiI, 0.05 M I-2, 0.5 M 4-tertbutylpyridine in acetonitrile as an electrolyte. Among the three photoanodes, the cell assembled using porous TiO2 NFs obtained by using 5 wt% of PVP showed higher power conversion efficiency (PCE) of 4.81 % than those obtained by using 8 and 10 wt% of PVP, which showed the lower PCE of 4.13 and 3.42 %, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:57:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:57:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS A-MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; PROCESSING, 120(3)1211-1218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-8396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1432-0630</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00339-015-9306-x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17416</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>