<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14851</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:00:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Low temperature dielectric dispersion and relaxor like behavior in multiferroic Ba3NbFe3Si2O14</dc:title><dc:creator>RATHORE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>VITTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>FERROELECTRICITY</dc:subject><dc:description>The structure and physical properties such as magnetization, heat capacity, and dielectric constant of the polycrystalline Ba3NbFe3Si2O14 have been studied in detail. It is found to be structurally similar to the single crystal and also has a similar antiferromagnetic transition at T-N similar to 26 K. The heat capacity measured in the temperature range 5 K-300K also shows a single peak at 26K in agreement with the magnetic behavior. The dielectric constant measured both as a function of temperature and frequency, 10 Hz to 1 MHz however exhibits two clear peaks in the temperature ranges, 20K-35K, and 40K-125 K, which are dispersive in nature. Both the peaks are found to be coupled to the magnetic order with the high temperature peak signaling the onset of magnetic order while the low temperature peak signifies the completion of magnetic order. The dispersion behavior is similar to that observed in relaxor ferroelectrics wherein formation of polar nano-regions affects the relaxation dynamics. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3699198]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:00:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:00:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 111(7)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3699198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14851</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>