<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3891</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydrogen-Bonded Complexes of Phenylacetylene with Water, Methanol, Ammonia, and Methylamine. The Origin of Methyl Group-Induced Hydrogen Bond Switching</dc:title><dc:creator>SEDLAK, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOBZA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:subject>microwave spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>interaction energies</dc:subject><dc:subject>perturbation-theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>matrix-isolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzene</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>dimers</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:description>The infrared spectra in the acetylenic C-H stretching region for the complexes of phenylacetylene with water, methanol, ammonia, and methylamine are indicative of change in the intermolecular structure upon substitution with a methyl group. High-level ab initio calculations at CCSD(T)/aug-cc-pVDZ level indicate that the observed complexes of water and ammonia are energetically the most favored structures, and electrostatics play a dominant role in stabilizing these structures. The ability of the pi electron density of the benzene ring to offer a larger cross-section for the interaction and the increased polarizability of the O-H and N-H groups in methanol and methylamine favor the formation of pi hydrogen-bonded complexes, in which dispersion is the dominant force. Further, the observed phenylacetylene-methylamine complex can be tentatively assigned to a kinetically trapped higher energy structure. The observed methyl group-induced hydrogen bond switching in the phenylacetylene complexes can be attributed to the switching of the dominant interaction from electrostatic to dispersion.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T07:09:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T07:09:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 113(24), 6620-6625</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp900813n</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3891</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>