<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17574</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:07:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimization of high cell density fermentation process for recombinant nitrilase production in E. coli</dc:title><dc:creator>SOHONI, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>NELAPATI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAVADEKAR-SUBHEDAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAIKAIWARI, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANGIKAR, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>HETEROLOGOUS PROTEIN-PRODUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH-LEVEL EXPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLASMID STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH-HORMONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RNA-POLYMERASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRATEGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CULTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrilase</dc:subject><dc:subject>High cell density fermentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>E. coli BL21 (DE3)</dc:subject><dc:description>Nitrilases constitute an important class of biocatalysts for chiral synthesis. This work was undertaken with the aim to optimize nitrilase production in a host that is well-studied for protein production. Process parameters were optimized for high cell density fermentation, in batch and fed-batch modes, of Escherichia coli BL21 (DE3) expressing Pseudomonas fluorescens nitrilase with a T7 promoter based expression system. Effects of different substrates, temperature and isopropyl beta-D-1-thiogalactopyranoside (IPTG) induction on nitrilase production were studied. Super optimal broth containing glycerol but without an inducer gave best results in batch mode with 32 degrees C as the optimal temperature. Use of IPTG led to insoluble protein and lower enzyme activity. Optimized fed-batch strategy resulted in significant improvement in specific activity as well as volumetric productivity of the enzyme. On a volumetric basis, the activity improved 40-fold compared to the unoptimized batch process. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:07:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:07:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIORESOURCE TECHNOLOGY, 188,202-208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-8524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2976</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2015.02.038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17574</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>