<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11581</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Steady-state analysis of glucose repression reveals hierarchical expression of proteins under Mig1p control in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>yeast gal genes</dc:subject><dc:subject>catabolite repression</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding</dc:subject><dc:subject>switch</dc:subject><dc:subject>activator</dc:subject><dc:subject>promoter</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>transcription</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>glucose repression</dc:subject><dc:subject>mig1p</dc:subject><dc:subject>mitogen-activated protein kinase (mapk)</dc:subject><dc:subject>transcriptional activator</dc:subject><dc:subject>transcriptional repressor</dc:subject><dc:subject>yeast</dc:subject><dc:description>Glucose repression is a global transcriptional regulatory mechanism commonly observed in micro-organisms for the repression of enzymes that are not essential for glucose metabolism. In Saccharomyces cerevisiae, Mig1p, a homologue of Wilms' tumour protein, is a global repressor protein dedicated to glucose repression. Mig1p represses genes either by binding directly to the upstream repression sequence of structural genes or by indirectly repressing a transcriptional activator, such as Ga14p. In addition, some genes are repressed by both of the above mechanisms. This raises a fundamental question regarding the physiological relevance of the varied mechanisms of repression that exist involving Mig1p. We address this issue by comparing two well-known glucose-repression systems, that is, SUC2 and GAL gene expression systems, which encompass all the above three mechanisms. We demonstrate using steady-state analysis that these mechanisms lead to a hierarchical glucose repression profile of different family of genes. This switch over from one carbon source to another is well-calibrated as a function of glucose concentration through this hierarchical transcriptional response. The mechanisms prevailing in this repression system can achieve amplification and sensitivity, as observed in the well-characterized MAPK (mitogen-activated protein kinase) cascade system, albeit through a different structure. A critical feature of repression predicted by our steady-state model for the mutant strain of S. cerevisiae lacking Gal80p agrees well with the data reported here as well as that available in the literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PORTLAND PRESS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T07:10:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T07:10:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHEMICAL JOURNAL, 388(), 843-849</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0264-6021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1042/BJ20041883</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11581</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11581</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>