<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13987</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:58:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Strain Mode Dependence of Deformation Texture Developments: Microstructural Origin</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVEENDRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANJARLA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARANJAPE, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DELANNAY, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>VANHOUTTE, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>GRAIN-INTERACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLASTIC-DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL PLASTICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROLLING TEXTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FCC METALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYCRYSTALLINE ALUMINUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBDIVISION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORIENTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Fully recrystallized commercial-purity aluminum sheets were deformed by limiting dome height tests, the following strain modes: uniaxial tension (US), near plane strain tension (PS), and equibiaxial tension (BS) were identified using standard procedure. The deformation texture developments differed significantly depending on the strain mode. Although the full constraints Taylor (FCT) model captured the texture developments in US, it failed to reproduce deformation textures in PS and especially in BS. The Advanced LAMEL (ALAMEL) model and the crystal plasticity finite element method (CPFEM) were, however, successful with respect to all three strain modes. Microtexture data brought out interesting observations of orientation gradients. First, the orientation gradients increased from US to PS to BS. Second, such gradients were mostly around initial (or prior deformation) grain boundary regions. A simple algorithm, and an associated computer program, was developed to demarcate such near boundary gradient zones (NBGZs). The area fraction and severity of NBGZ seemed to affect the texture development; FCT was reasonably successful at low NBGZ, whereas high NBGZ required the ALAMEL and the CPFEM models that are capable of addressing strain heterogeneity and grain interactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:58:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:58:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE,42A(7)2113-2124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-010-0580-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13987</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>