<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15791</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:31:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Possible spin-orbit driven spin-liquid ground state in the double perovskite phase of Ba3YIr2O9</dc:title><dc:creator>DEY, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOTESWARARAO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOU, FC</dc:creator><dc:creator>OMRANI, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>RONNOW, HM</dc:creator><dc:subject>TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SR2IRO4</dc:subject><dc:subject>LA</dc:subject><dc:description>We report the structural transformation of hexagonal Ba3YIr2O9 to a cubic double perovskite form (stable in ambient conditions) under an applied pressure of 8 GPa at 1273 K. While the ambient pressure synthesized sample undergoes long-range magnetic ordering at similar to 4 K, the high-pressure (HP) synthesized sample does not order down to 2 K as evidenced from our susceptibility, heat capacity, and nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) measurements. Further, for the HP sample, our heat capacity data have the form gamma T + beta T-3 in the temperature (T) range of 2-10 K with the Sommerfeld coefficient gamma = 10 mJ/mol-Ir K-2. The Y-89 NMR shift has no T dependence in the range of 4-120 K and its spin-lattice relaxation rate varies linearly with T in the range of 8-45 K (above which it is T independent). Resistance measurements of both the samples confirm that they are semiconducting. Our data provide evidence for the formation of a 5d-based, gapless, quantum spin-liquid in the cubic (HP) phase of Ba3YIr2O9. In this picture, the gamma T term in the heat capacity and the linear variation of Y-89 1/T-1 arises from excitations out of a spinon Fermi surface. Our findings lend credence to the theoretical suggestion [Chen, Pereira, and Balents, Phys. Rev. B 82, 174440 (2010)] that strong spin-orbit coupling can enhance quantum fluctuations and lead to a QSL state in the double perovskite lattice.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:31:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:31:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 88(13)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-235X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.88.134425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15791</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>