<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2747</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydrogen embrittlement studies of API5LX52 pipeline steel</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, RC</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVINASH, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, TR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHERIAN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANTO, PF</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, SK</dc:creator><dc:description>API 5LX steels are widely used in off-shore structures. Despite the fact that these steels possess good notch toughness, several hydrogen induced failures are reported to have occurred in the large diameter crude oil pipelines when they are subjected to static and dynamic toads in the oil field production environment. The presence of H2S, CO2 and brine in crude oil not only enhance the corrosion rate but also lead to environmental fracture assisted by enhanced uptake of H atoms in steel. This has prompted the researchers to evaluate steels for resistance to failure by hydrogen embrittlement in oil field production environment. The use of slow strain rate test method has become more common in the laboratory. Furthermore, this is the most severe and positive test method to screen the materials susceptible to HE in a short duration. En the present investigation, the deleterious effects of hydrogen on the mechanical and fracture properties of API 5LX steel have been evaluated by tensile and slow strain rate testing in air and the NACE solution. The susceptibility to HE was found by comparing the properties in environment to that of air. The tensile and slow strain rate tested samples were examined in SEM to understand the change in the mode of failure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T10:31:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T10:31:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>CORROSION AND ITS CONTROLS, VOLS I AND II,1082-1087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-444-82916-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16266</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2747</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Corrosion (CORCON 97),MUMBAI, INDIA,DEC 03-06, 1997</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>