<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15630</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:10:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic, magnetocaloric and magnetotransport properties of RSn1+xGe1-x compounds (R = Gd, Tb, and Er; x=0.1)</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Antiferromagnet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetotransport</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetic entropy change</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOW-TEMPERATURE RESISTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GERMANIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>METALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>R=TB</dc:subject><dc:subject>DY</dc:subject><dc:description>We have studied the magnetic, magnetocaloric and magnetotransport properties of RSn1+xGe1-x(R = Gd, Tb, Er; x = 0.1) series by means of magnetization, heat capacity and resistivity measurements. It has been found that all the compounds crystallize in the orthorhombic crystal structure described by the centrosymmetric space group Cmcm (No. 63). The magnetic susceptibility and heat capacity data suggest that all the compounds are antiferromagnetic. Large negative values of theta(p) in case of GdSn1.1Ge0.9 and TbSn1.1Ge0.9 indicate that strong antiferromagnetic interactions are involved, which is also reflected in the magnetization isotherms. On the other hand ErSn1.1Ge0.9 shows weak antiferromagnetic interaction. The heat capacity data have been analyzed by fitting the temperature dependence and the values of theta(D) and gamma have been estimated. Among these three compounds, ErSn1.1Ge0.9 shows considerable magnetic entropy change of 9.5 J/kg K and an adiabatic temperature change of 3.2 K for a field of 50 kOe. The resistivity data in different temperature regimes have been analyzed and the dominant contributions have been identified. All the compounds show small but positive magnetoresistance. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:10:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:10:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS, 34261-68</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmmm.2013.04.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15630</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>