<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1489</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fuzzy AHP in prioritizing feeders for maintenance in nuclear power plants</dc:title><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, HN</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>fuzzy systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>nuclear power plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>resource allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>maintenance</dc:subject><dc:description>A fuzzy version of prioritization from among several alternatives under different decision criteria of Saaty's pair wise comparison method is presented in this paper. Each ratio expressing the relative significance of a pair of factors is displayed in a matrix from which suitable weights can be extracted. Since these ratios are essentially fuzzy, they express the opinion of a decision-maker on the importance of a pair of factors. This method is used in such a way that information from experts, who are asked to express their opinions in fuzzy numbers with triangular membership functions, is embedded in it. The method is applied at two levels: beginning with the finding of fuzzy weights for the decision criteria, followed by finding the fuzzy weights for the alternatives under each of the decision criteria. Fuzzy scores for the alternatives are obtained. Using the fuzzy scores, experts will be able to prioritize the alternatives for maintenance activities based on the listed criteria. The method is illustrated for outlet feeders in a nuclear power plant with representative values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:09:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:23:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:09:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:23:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management, Singapore, 2-4 December 2007, 149-153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1424415292</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/IEEM.2007.4419169</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1489</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>