<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9028</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>A capacitive immunosensor measurement system with a lock-in amplifier and potentiostatic control by software</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAL, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>impedance measurements</dc:subject><dc:subject>interface</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>isfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>eis capacitance</dc:subject><dc:subject>admittance with software potentiostatic control</dc:subject><dc:subject>immunosensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>medical diagnostics</dc:subject><dc:description>We report an elegant small-signal capacitance measurement system for capacitive immunosensors, prototyped around a computer-controlled two-phase lock-in amplifier. Capacitive immunosensors require low-ionic-strength electrolytes for effective antibody-antigen interaction and low dielectric thickness for high sensitivity to phenomena occurring at the insulator-electrolyte interface. The problem of measuring a high intrinsic sensor capacitance in the presence of a modest parasitic cell resistance is overcome by using a potential-sensing electrode close to the electrolyte-dielectric interface for measuring and controlling the stimulus to the intrinsic device. The current phasor through the capacitive sensor is measured after effecting potential control via a software feedback loop and the sensor capacitance calculated. Capacitance can be measured in the range 100 pF to 0.1 mu F with an accuracy of +/-0.5% at 1 kHz. The technique obviates the need for expensive high-speed potentiostats or impedance analysers for such measurements and can also be used for small-signal admittance measurements in other electrolyte-insulator-semiconductor or electrolyte-insulator-metal systems. The suitability of the proposed measurement system for immunodetection is shown by capacitance measurements on fibronectin-sensitive capacitive immunosensors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T12:35:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T12:35:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MEASUREMENT SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY, 10(11), 1097-1104</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-0233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-0233/10/11/321</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9028</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>