<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2575</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stacked active loads for low power, high speed GaAs digital circuits (SALFL)</dc:title><dc:creator>MRUNAL, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHIRASGAONKAR, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATRIKAR, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>low power</dc:subject><dc:subject>gaas digital circuits dcfl</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic power</dc:subject><dc:subject>static power</dc:subject><dc:description>The next generation of super-computers or base band circuits of advanced radio-telecommunication systems require very high speed switching circuits. Compound semiconductor materials such as Gallium Arsenide (GaAs) win play an important role in such systems. In GaAs devices the hole velocity is approximately 15-20 times lower compared to the electron velocity. This means that the complimentary structures are not as desirable in GaAs as they are in silicon. This leads to higher power consumption in these circuits. In this paper low power GaAs logic family Stacked Active Load FET logic (SALFL) is proposed for the battery operated, portable wireless applications. In this proposed logic family, the ON and OFF state (leakage) currents are reduced using stacked active loads, there by reducing power consumption. GaAs circuits are preferred in high performance wireless front end circuits but are not used in base-band digital circuits due to their high current consumption and domination of Silicon CMOS circuits in integrated circuit applications. But the CMOS technology already at 45nm node is plagued with the problem of sub-threshold leakage currents particularly severe in sub-100nm CMOS digital logic families. Both these problems can be effectively overcome using the GaAs SALFL logic family. Above low power technique is implemented with a standard enhancement/depletion mode FET processes and provides all the standard logic functions (Invertion, AND, OR, NOR NAND etc) like other (DCFL, SCF)logic families. This technique shows improved results with all GaAs devices like pHEMTs and MESFET. With this technique current consumption can be reduced while taking into account area requirements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T10:08:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T10:08:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2006 IEEE ASIA PACIFIC CONFERENCE ON CIRCUITS AND SYSTEMS,1488-1491</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-0386-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15976</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2575</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE Asia Pacific Conference on Circuits and Systems,Singapore, SINGAPORE,DEC 04-07, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>