<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6566</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electronic structure of highly crystalline polyaniline by study of tunneling conduction in n(+)-Si/self-assembled monolayer/polyaniline heterostructures</dc:title><dc:creator>SUTAR, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>LENFANT, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VUILLAUME, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>YAKHMI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>thin-film transistors</dc:subject><dc:subject>self-assembled monolayers</dc:subject><dc:subject>interface</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>base</dc:subject><dc:subject>pani</dc:subject><dc:subject>self-assembly</dc:subject><dc:subject>mis</dc:subject><dc:subject>c-afm</dc:subject><dc:subject>tunneling</dc:subject><dc:subject>electronic structure</dc:subject><dc:description>Highly crystalline polyaniline (PANI) films were deposited on degenerated silicon (n(+)-Si) substrates covered with its native oxide (SiO(2)), surface modified with amino-silane self-assembled monolayers (SAM). Scanning electron microscopy studies reveal formation of single crystal domains scattered all over the surface of film. Height and current images obtained using current-sensing AFM (C-AFM) exhibit pyramidal topography of crystallites, and inhomogeneous conductivity. As the native oxide and SAM acts as a very thin insulating layer (&lt;2 nm) between the metal-like substrate (degenerated Si) and the PANI film, it forms n(+)-Si/SiO(2)/SAM/PANI metal-insulator-semiconductor (MIS) heterostructure. C-AFM probe was used for I-V measurements on the MIS structures and study the tunneling conduction across it. The conductance spectra derived from I-V characteristics corroborates well with the polaron-lattice band structure of doped PANI with presence of polaron bands between the HOMO-LUMO energy gap. These polaron bands are well-resolved from our C-AFM measurements and they are located about 0.25 eV below the LUMO and above the HOMO. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T23:11:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T23:11:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANIC ELECTRONICS, 9(5), 602-608</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1566-1199</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.orgel.2008.04.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6566</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6566</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>