<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8652</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Importance of structural tuning in manganites</dc:title><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUNLAP, RA</dc:creator><dc:subject>rare-earth manganates</dc:subject><dc:subject>a-site cations</dc:subject><dc:subject>ca-mn-o</dc:subject><dc:subject>giant magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>colossal magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>perovskites</dc:subject><dc:subject>dependence</dc:subject><dc:subject>transitions</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>sm</dc:subject><dc:subject>giant magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>electronic structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>perovskites</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic phase transitions</dc:subject><dc:description>Properties of substituted La-manganites are known to be very sensitive to La site substitution, The critical parameters appear to be (a) the charge and concentration of the substituted ions, which determine the Mn3+/Mn4+ ratio, (b) the average ionic radius at the A site and (c) the tolerance factor, t, The latter two parameters determine the distortion and structural tuning of the perovskite structure, Here we report the influence of minor variations in the above parameters on the magnetotransport of compounds around the basic composition La0.6M0.07Ca0.33MnO3 (M = Er, Yb and Pi), The influence of the method of synthesis on different properties is also discussed. The ionic radii of Er3+, Yb3+ and Bi3+ ions are 1.00, 0.985 and 1.11 Angstrom, respectively, compared to 1.32 Angstrom for La3+ and this provides a systematic variation for the investigation of the effects of A site substitution. The zero field resistivity data are essentially similar above the maxima which corresponds, at least approximately, to the Curie temperature as determined by magnetization measurements. However, there are variations below the transition temperature, where there is magnetic ordering, and large variations are often seen in the magnetic data between samples which are very similar in composition, Substantial similarities between field dependent magnetization and resistivity measurements appear to be related to domain wall displacement and rotation. These results will be discussed in the framework of structural tuning which has a strong influence on exchange parameters such as the Mn-O-Mn bond length and angle.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T04:01:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T04:01:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 21(5), 393-398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-4707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02744924</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8652</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8652</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>