<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10825</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental investigation on critical heat flux in horizontal channel for low pressure low flow (LPLF) condition</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHUL, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BABURAJAN, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>look-up table</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>tubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>chf</dc:subject><dc:subject>horizontal channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>chf</dc:subject><dc:subject>lplf</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:description>Studies reported in the past on critical heat flux (CHF) are mostly limited to vertical flow, large channel diameter, high pressure and high mass flux. Only few investigations are reported in the literature for horizontal flow CHF especially under low pressure and low flow conditions. Hence, predictive methods of CHF for horizontal flow are scarce. There is a need for understanding CHF in horizontal flow under low pressure and low flow conditions because they are commonly encountered in nuclear reactor fuel channels of pressurized heavy water reactor (PHWR) under loss of coolant accidental (LOCA) conditions. The present work investigates CHF of horizontal flow for low flow rates (mass flux of 100-400 kg/m(2) s) at nearly atmospheric pressure conditions. Parameters covered in this study are diameter (5.5 mm, 7.5 mm and 9.5 mm), length (0.45 m and 0.8 m) and a inlet temperature of 32 degrees C. The first occurrence of 'red hot' spot on the test section is considered as the onset of critical heat flux condition in the present work. Experimental results obtained are compared with Groeneveld et al. (2007) look up table data for vertical flow after applying correction factor given by Wong et al. (1990). The deviation of experimental CHF data from those predicted using Groeneveld et al. (2007) look up table and Wong et al. (1990) correction factor is more than 50%.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:47:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:47:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANNALS OF NUCLEAR ENERGY, 37(11), 1467-1475</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-4549</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.anucene.2010.06.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10825</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10825</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>