<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15843</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:57:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhancement of anomalous Hall effect in Si/Fe multilayers</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, MS</dc:creator><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERLATTICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAYER</dc:subject><dc:description>Anomalous Hall effect (AHE) studies were performed at 300 K on Si/Fe multilayers prepared by dc magnetron sputtering. About 60 times enhancement in the saturation Hall resistance and 80 times enhancement in anomalous Hall coefficient were obtained in [Si(50 angstrom)/Fe(t(Fe))](20) multilayers when decreasing the Fe layer thickness from 100 to 20 angstrom. The largest anomalous Hall coefficient (R-s) of 1.4 x 10(-7) Omega m T-1 was found for t(Fe) = 20 angstrom, which is about three orders of magnitude larger than that of pure Fe and Fe/Cr, Al/Fe, Cu/Fe, SiO2/FePt/SiO2 multilayers. The ordinary Hall coefficient R-0 was about two orders of magnitude larger than that of pure Fe. The R-s was found to vary with the longitudinal electronic resistivity, rho as R-s alpha rho(2.2), indicating the role of interfaces for the enhancement of the AHE in the multilayers. An increase of Hall sensitivity from 9 m Omega T-1 to 1.2 Omega T-1 was observed on decreasing t(Fe) from 100 to 10 angstrom. The high Hall sensitivity obtained was about three orders of magnitude larger than that of Al/Fe and Cu/Fe multilayers, showing it as an emerging candidate for Hall element for potential applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS D-APPLIED PHYSICS, 46(37)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0022-3727/46/37/375003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15843</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>