<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2344</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Compensation of the nonlinear effects on a hydrostatic driver for the keel system in a yacht using bilinear system</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHPANDE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALPANA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEDI, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>compensation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinearity</dc:subject><dc:subject>bilinear system</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrostatic driver</dc:subject><dc:subject>keel</dc:subject><dc:subject>yacht</dc:subject><dc:description>Technical systems have almost nonlinear system behaviors. For the descriptions of their dynamical causes and effects on system, the physical information, which is concerned as a nonlinear mathematic model, has been used. But the corresponding equations are generally not easy to solve in complete form or their solutions are so complicated to see through the coherence. A common way to settle such a problem is to linearize system exactly in a state space or on a operating points with Taylor's series approximately. An advanced method to an approximation is a bilinear system that offers global separations principle. In this paper, an extended application of this theory is given in a modeling and control on the hydrostatic driver for the keel system in a yacht that mostly have not only advantage of high performance, small volume of building and weight but also high nonlinear behavior.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T04:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T04:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2007 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON CONTROL, AUTOMATION AND SYSTEMS, VOLS 1-6,409-414</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-89-950038-7-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15911</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2344</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Control, Automation and Systems,Seoul, SOUTH KOREA,OCT 17-20, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>