<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10900</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-13T16:46:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Heat transfer and pressure drop in a spirally grooved tube with twisted tape insert</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARADWAJ, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHONDGE, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>corrugated tubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>compound heat transfer enhancement</dc:subject><dc:subject>spirally grooved tube</dc:subject><dc:subject>twisted tape insert</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, experimentally determined pressure drop and heat transfer characteristics of flow of water in a 75-start spirally grooved tube with twisted tape insert are presented. Laminar to fully turbulent ranges of Reynolds numbers have been considered. The grooves are clockwise with respect to the direction of flow. Compared to smooth tube, the heat transfer enhancement due to spiral grooves is further augmented by inserting twisted tapes having twist ratios Y similar or equal to 10.15, 7.95 and 3.4. It is found that the direction of twist (clockwise and anticlockwise) influences the thermo-hydraulic characteristics. Constant pumping power comparisons with smooth tube characteristics show that in spirally grooved tube with and without twisted tape, heat transfer increases considerably in laminar and moderately in turbulent range of Reynolds numbers. However, for the bare spiral tube and for spiral tube with anticlockwise twisted tape (Y = 10.15), reduction in heat transfer is noticed over a transition range of Reynolds numbers. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T04:52:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T04:52:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 52 (7-8), 1938-1944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2008.08.038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10900</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10900</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>