<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12150</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Remote sensing and GIS for artificial recharge study, runoff estimation and planning in Ayyar basin, Tamil Nadu, India</dc:title><dc:creator>ANBAZHAGAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMASAMY, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS GUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>landsat</dc:subject><dc:subject>artificial recharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>gis</dc:subject><dc:subject>runoff estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>curve number</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper focuses on artificial groundwater recharge study in 'Ayyar basin', Tamil Nadu, India. The basin is covered by hard crystalline rock and overall has poor groundwater conditions. Hence, an artificial recharge study was carried out in this region through a project sponsored by Tamil Nadu State Council for Science and Technology. The Indian Remote Sensing satellite 1A Linear Imaging Self Scanning Sensor II (IRS 1A LISS II) satellite imagery, aerial photographs and geophysical resistivity data were used to prioritize suitable sites for artificial recharge and to estimate the volume of aquifer dimension available to recharge. The runoff water available for artificial recharge in the basin is estimated through Soil Conservation Service curve number method. The land use/land cover, hydrological soil group and storm rainfall data in different watershed areas were used to calculate the runoff in the watersheds. The weighted curve number for each watershed is obtained through spatial intersection of land use/land cover and hydrological soil group through GeoMedia 3.0 Professional GIS software. Artificial recharge planning was derived on the basis of availability of runoff, aquifer dimension, priority areas and water table conditions in different watersheds in the basin.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T17:49:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T17:49:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL GEOLOGY, 48(2), 158-170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0943-0105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00254-005-1284-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12150</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12150</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>