<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12477</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Casting cost estimation in an integrated product and process design environment</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUGULE, RG</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>framework</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>step</dc:subject><dc:subject>casting</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer-aided design</dc:subject><dc:subject>cost estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>collaborative engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>integrated product process design</dc:subject><dc:subject>parametric costing</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid model</dc:subject><dc:subject>web-based engineering</dc:subject><dc:description>A casting cost estimation model, driven by the solid model of the part and its attributes (material, geometric, quality and production requirements) is presented. It is meant for product designers with little knowledge of the process, enabling design modi. cations for cost reduction in early stages, when the cost of such modi. cations is low. Analytical equations have been developed to estimate the cost related to material and conversion (energy and labour). A parametric model has been developed for tooling cost, driven by part complexity, which is computed from the part solid model. Parameters related to process plan and methoding or rigging (essentially feeding and gating design), required for accurate estimation of casting costs, are semi-automatically generated by process planning and casting methoding programs. The programs are in turn linked to a web-based intelligent collaborative engineering system called WebICE. This enables exchange of casting project data (including cost data) among product designers, tool makers and foundry engineers over the internet, enabling design modi. cations to achieve the targeted cost. An industrial example is presented to illustrate the entire system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T22:01:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T22:01:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF COMPUTER INTEGRATED MANUFACTURING, 19(7), 676-688</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0951-192X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09511920500324605</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12477</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12477</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>