<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16691</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T13:13:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mixed valency and site-preference chemistry for cerium and its compounds: A predictive density-functional theory study</dc:title><dc:creator>ALAM, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOHNSON, DD</dc:creator><dc:subject>TOTAL-ENERGY CALCULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE BASIS-SET</dc:subject><dc:subject>CE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:description>Cerium and its technologically relevant compounds are examples of anomalous mixed valency, originating from two competing oxidation states-itinerant Ce4+ and localized Ce3+. Under applied stress, anomalous transitions are observed but not well understood. Here we treat mixed valency as an "alloy" problem involving two valences with competing and numerous site-occupancy configurations. We use density-functional theory with Hubbard U (i.e., DFT+U) to evaluate the effective valence and predict properties, including controlling the valence by pseudoternary alloying. For Ce and its compounds, such as (Ce, La)(2)(Fe,Co)(14)B permanent magnets, we find a stable mixed-valent alpha state near the spectroscopic value of nu(s) = 3.53. Ce valency in compounds depends on its steric volume and local chemistry. For La doping, Ce valency shifts towards gamma-like Ce3+, as expected from steric volume; for Co doping, valency depends on local Ce-site chemistry and steric volume. Our approach captures the key origins of anomalous valency and site-preference chemistry in complex compounds.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:13:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:13:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 89(23)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-235X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.89.235126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16691</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>