<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15496</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:59:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spatial Link Scheduling for SCDMA Multihop Cellular Networks: A Cross Layer Framework</dc:title><dc:creator>KANNAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>Scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multihop cellular networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spatial reuse</dc:subject><dc:subject>AD-HOC NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RADIO NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASSIGNMENT</dc:subject><dc:description>Probability of error based Spatial Code Division Multiple Access scheduling algorithm is presented in this paper to systematically reuse the orthogonal CDMA codes in a given cell for Multihop Cellular Network. We assign and reuse the CDMA codes to peer-to-peer links such that the probability of error in all scheduled links are below certain threshold. The proposed scheduling algorithm PoE-LinkSchedule involves two phases. In the first phase we present a scheduling metric "Probability of Error (PoE)" as a function of first and second order statistics of wireless channel coefficients between nodes. The second phase presents a graph theoretical as well as PoE based centralized scheduling algorithm. For a graph of network with n number of nodes, U number of links and theta thickness, the proposed scheduling algorithm has computational complexity of O(Unlogn + Un theta) as opposed to O(U (U) ) in the case of exhaustive search algorithm. The performance of the proposed algorithm is evaluated in terms of spatial reuse and end-to-end throughput. We show that the proposed algorithm has considerably higher end-to-end throughput and higher spatial reuse compared to existing link scheduling algorithms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:59:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:59:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WIRELESS PERSONAL COMMUNICATIONS, 63(2)279-295</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11277-010-0118-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15496</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>