<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16063</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:26:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurement of subcooled boiling pressure drop and local heat transfer coefficient in horizontal tube under LPLF conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>BABURAJAN, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BISHT, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PIPE</dc:subject><dc:description>Horizontal flow is commonly encountered in boiler tubes, refrigerating equipments and nuclear reactor fuel channels of pressurized heavy water reactors (PHWR). Study of horizontal flow under low pressure and low flow (LPLF) conditions is important in understanding the nuclear core behavior during situations like LOCA (loss of coolant accidents). In the present work, local heat transfer coefficient and pressure drop are measured in a horizontal tube under LPLF conditions of subcooled boiling. Geometrical parameters covered in this study are diameter (5.5 mm, 7.5 mm and 9.5 mm) and length (550 mm, 750 mm and 1000 mm). The operating parameters varied are mass flux (450-935 kg/m(2) s) and inlet subcooling (29 degrees C, 50 degrees C and 70 degrees C). Infra-red thermography is used for the measurement of local wall temperature to estimate the heat transfer coefficient in single phase and two phase flows with water as the working medium at atmospheric pressure. Correlation for single phase diabatic pressure drop ratio (diabatic to adiabatic) as a function of viscosity ratio (wall temperature to fluid temperature) is presented. Correlation for pressure drop under subcooled boiling conditions as a function of Boiling number (Bo) and Jakob number (Ja) is obtained. Correlation for single phase heat transfer coefficient in the thermal developing region is presented as a function of Reynolds number (Re), Prandtl number (Pr) and z/d (ratio of axial length of the test section to diameter). Correlation for two phase heat transfer coefficient under subcooled boiling condition is developed as a function of boiling number (Bo), Jakob number (Ja) and Prandtl number (Pr). (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:26:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:26:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 255169-179</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2012.10.012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16063</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>