<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9670</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Parameter identification of torsionally coupled shear buildings from earthquake response records</dc:title><dc:creator>HEGDE, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>eigensystem realization-algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>system-identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>modes</dc:subject><dc:subject>system identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>eigenvalue</dc:subject><dc:subject>eigenvectors</dc:subject><dc:subject>eccentricity</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic response</dc:subject><dc:subject>natural frequency</dc:subject><dc:subject>health monitoring</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents an efficient procedure to determine the natural frequencies, modal damping ratios and mode shapes for torsionally coupled shear buildings using earthquake response records. It is shown that the responses recorded at the top and first floor levels are sufficient to identify the dominant modal properties of a multistoried torsionally coupled shear building with uniform mass and constant eccentricity even when the input excitation is not known. The procedure applies eigenrealization algorithm to generate the state-space model of the structure using the cross-correlations among the measured responses. The dynamic characteristics of the structure are determined from the state-space realization matrices. Since the mode shapes are obtained only at the instrumented floor (top and first floors) levels, a new mode shape interpolation technique has been proposed to estimate the mode shape coefficients at the remaining floor levels. The application of the procedure has been demonstrated through a numerical experiment on an eight-storied torsionally coupled shear building subjected to earthquake base excitation. The results show that the proposed parameter identification technique is capable of identifying dominant modal parameters and responses even with significant noise contamination of the response records. Copyright (C) 2008 . Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T23:55:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T23:55:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING &amp; STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS, 37(11), 1313-1331</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-8847</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/eqe.816</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9670</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9670</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>