<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17912</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:17:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Polymer Stabilized Fe3O4-Graphene as an Amphiphilic Drug Carrier for Thermo-Chemotherapy of Cancer</dc:title><dc:creator>SWAIN, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRADHAN, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>GRAPHENE OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOMEDICAL APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTICANCER DRUG</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PH</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>cancer</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug carrier</dc:subject><dc:subject>graphene</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermo-chemotherapy</dc:subject><dc:description>In light of the growing interest in the search for cheap and effective solutions for cancer treatment, we report a simple one pot synthesis of polymer stabilized iron oxide-graphene (PIG) that could be realized on a large scale. The structural (Fe3O4 particle size of similar to 11 nm), functional (various oxygen containing moieties), and magnetic (moment of similar to 43 emu/g) properties of PIG are explored using various characterization techniques for possible biomedical applications. PIG shows good colloidal stability and is biocompatible even at higher concentrations (2.5 mg/mL) by virtue of cross-linking polymers. The biocompatibility of the composite has been tested using HeLa cell lines by computing the percentage of the reactive oxygen species through the 2,7-dichlorofluorescein (DCF) intensity level. PIG has the ability to load and release both hydrophobic and hydrophilic drugs with a good loading efficiency and capacity. The dug loading efficiency of PIG is measured to be similar to 87% and similar to 91% for doxorubicin (DOX) and paclitaxel (PTXL), respectively. Under an AC magnetic field, superparamagnetic PIG (2.5 mg/mL) takes less than 16 min to reach the stable hyperthermia temperature, suggesting it as a good anticancer material. A time-dependent cellular uptake of doxorubicin-conjugated PIG has been studied to optimize the parameters for thermo-chemotherapy of cancer. The synergetic effect of both the drug and hyperthermia is observed in the killing of the cancerous cells, verified by computing the cell apoptotic population using a flow cytometer. However, it has been noticed that, even in the absence of chemotherapy, PIG shows good antiproliferative activity with thermotherapy alone.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:17:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:17:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACS APPLIED MATERIALS &amp; INTERFACES, 7(15)8013-8022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1944-8244</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acsami.5b02536</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17912</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>