<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14591</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:40:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Health benefit modelling and optimization of vehicular pollution control strategies</dc:title><dc:creator>SONAWANE, NV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SETHI, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>Pollution control strategies</dc:subject><dc:subject>AERMOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>BenMAP</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR-QUALITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSIONS</dc:subject><dc:description>This study asserts that the evaluation of pollution reduction strategies should be approached on the basis of health benefits. The framework presented could be used for decision making on the basis of cost effectiveness when the strategies are applied concurrently. Several vehicular pollution control strategies have been proposed in literature for effective management of urban air pollution. The effectiveness of these strategies has been mostly studied as a one at a time approach on the basis of change in pollution concentration. The adequacy and practicality of such an approach is studied in the present work. Also, the assessment of respective benefits of these strategies has been carried out when they are implemented simultaneously. An integrated model has been developed which can be used as a tool for optimal prioritization of various pollution management strategies. The model estimates health benefits associated with specific control strategies. ISC-AERMOD View has been used to provide the cause-effect relation between control options and change in ambient air quality. BenMAP, developed by U.S. EPA, has been applied for estimation of health and economic benefits associated with various management strategies. Valuation of health benefits has been done for impact indicators of premature mortality, hospital admissions and respiratory syndrome. An optimization model has been developed to maximize overall social benefits with determination of optimized percentage implementations for multiple strategies. The model has been applied for sub-urban region of Mumbai city for vehicular sector. Several control scenarios have been considered like revised emission standards, electric, CNG, LPG and hybrid vehicles. Reduction in concentration and resultant health benefits for the pollutants CO, NOx and particulate matter are estimated for different control scenarios. Finally, an optimization model has been applied to determine optimized percentage implementation of specific control strategies with maximization of social benefits, when these strategies are applied simultaneously. (c) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT, 60193-201</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2012.06.060</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14591</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>