<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9759</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fast on-line/off-line algorithms for optimal reinforcement of a network and its connections with principal partition</dc:title><dc:creator>PATKAR, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAN, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>lattice</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymatroids</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>graphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>on-line algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>graph</dc:subject><dc:subject>network</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymatroid</dc:subject><dc:subject>principal partition</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>reinforcement</dc:subject><dc:description>The problem of computing the strength and performing optimal reinforcement for an edge-weighted graph G(V, E, w) is well-studied. In this paper, we present fast (sequential linear time and parallel logarithmic time) on-line algorithms for optimally reinforcing the graph when the reinforcement material is available continuously on-line. These are the first on-line algorithms for this problem. We invest O(\V\(3)\E\log\V\) time (equivalent to Omega(\V\) invocations of the fastest known algorithms for optimal reinforcement) in preprocessing the graph before the start of our algorithms. It is shown that the output of our on-line algorithms is as good as that of the off-line algorithms. Thus our algorithms are better than the fastest off-line algorithms in situations when a sequence of more than Omega(\V\) reinforcement problems need to be solved. The key idea is to make use of ideas underlying the theory of Principal Partition of a Graph. Our ideas are easily generalized to the general setting of polymatroid functions. We also present a new efficient algorithm for computation of the Principal Sequence of a graph.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:23:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:23:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COMBINATORIAL OPTIMIZATION, 7(1), 45-68</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1382-6905</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1021994406231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9759</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9759</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>