<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14778</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:44:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thickness dependent anomalous magnetic behavior in pulsed-laser deposited cobalt ferrite thin film</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOHRA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>CATION DISTRIBUTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPINEL COFE2O4</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANISOTROPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COERCIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBSTRATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:description>Cobalt ferrite thin films of different thicknesses were pulsed-laser deposited onto a fused quartz substrate held at ambient temperature (RT) by varying deposition time. The samples were ex-situ annealed at 750 degrees C in air for 2 hours. All the films were characterized by X-ray diffraction, Raman spectroscopy and energy dispersive X-ray analysis. The spontaneous magnetization, 4 pi M-S, was found to be 6130 G for the 50 nm thick sample, and this is higher than that for the bulk cobalt ferrite of 5300 G, by 16%. The 4 pi M-S was found to decrease with the increase in film thickness and an overall decrease of 32% was observed, when the film thickness increased from 50 nm to 600 nm. In contrast the films of the same thicknesses, when deposited at substrate temperature of 750 degrees C showed an increase of 4pMS with the increase in film thickness. The thickness dependence of 4 pi M-S in these nanocrystalline thin films has been explained in terms of the cation distribution and the grain size, which are sensitive to the substrate temperature during deposition.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:44:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:44:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS A-MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; PROCESSING, 106(4)931-935</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00339-011-6709-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14778</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>