<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17671</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:59:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Contributions of multiple phenomena towards hydrogenation: A case of Mg</dc:title><dc:creator>SHRINIWASAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOSWAMI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIEN, HY</dc:creator><dc:creator>TANNIRU, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>EBRAHIMI, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>TATIPARTI, SSV</dc:creator><dc:subject>NANOSTRUCTURED MAGNESIUM HYDRIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TI-BASED CATALYSTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESORPTION-KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL HYDRIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ABSORPTION KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHENE NANOSHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SORPTION PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEW-MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEHYDROGENATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mg</dc:subject><dc:subject>MgH2</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogenation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemisorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nucleation and growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Diffusion</dc:subject><dc:description>Heterogeneous hydrogenation involves chemisorption (Chem), nucleation and growth by interfacial movement (NG) and diffusion (Diff). The slowest one of these phenomena is generally considered to control hydrogenation. However, the considered phenomenon cannot explain the hydrogenation in its entirety. Multiple phenomena can contribute to different extents towards hydrogenation. Contributions of multiple phenomena are explained by developing functions of the form xi(t) = Pi(i = Chem, NG, Diff) (j = Chem,) (i not equal j) f(j) (t)center dot(xi(ai(t))(i). xi(t) is the converted fraction of hydride. The indices a(i)(t) represent the extents to which the explicitly considered phenomena act (represented by xi(i)(t) from literature). Constraints Sigma(i)a(i)(t)6 = 1 and the condition f(j)(t)-&gt; 1 ascertain the exhaustiveness of the phenomena considered. Mg-MgH2 is considered as a proof-of-concept system to apply the present approach. The (t) functions are applied to describe the hydrogenation behaviour of Mg (similar to 44 mu m) at 210 degrees C and P-H2 = 1 MPa. Present analysis shows that multiple phenomena can act simultaneously and the dominant one (highest value of index) controls the hydrogenation. This dominant phenomenon can change with time such that chemisorption followed by NG and finally diffusion contribute in controlling hydrogenation. The estimated activation energies for NG (42 kJ/mol H) and diffusion (97 kJ/mol H) compare well with literature. Copyright (C) 2015, Hydrogen Energy Publications, LLC. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:59:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:59:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYDROGEN ENERGY, 40(39)13518-13529</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-3199</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-3487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2015.08.018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17671</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>