<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17130</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:55:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural Comparisons of the Binding Cores Formed by 1,3-di-Amide Derivatives of p-tert-Butylcalix[4] arene: Arms Stabilization through Intra-molecular Interactions Including N-H center dot center dot center dot O, O-H center dot center dot center dot Cl and pi center dot center dot center dot Cl Types</dc:title><dc:creator>DEY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUIONNEAU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>p-tert-Butyl calix[4] arene</dc:subject><dc:subject>1,3-di-Amide derivative</dc:subject><dc:subject>Single crystal X-ray diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Molecular recognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intramolecular hydrogen bond</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SELECTIVE RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HG2+</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper deals with the development of a receptor with selectively functionalized at the lower rim of p-tert-butyl calix[4] arene linked through amide bond, resulting in the diamide derivatives (L-1, L-2 and L-3) suitable for sensing ions and molecules. All the derivatives were thoroughly characterized by analytical and spectral methods. These derivatives were structurally characterized by single crystal X-ray diffraction and the conformational features of the calix[4] arene as well as the pendants are discussed. The L-1 and L-2 exhibited intramolecular hydrogen bond interaction between the N-H and the lower rim phenolic oxygen in addition to the circular hydrogen bonding between the phenolic O-H and the ether oxygen of the adjacent strand. The corresponding H-bond is absent when no 'H' is present on amide-N as in case of L-3. Such intramolecular N-H center dot center dot center dot O interactions observed with the pendant results in a conformational bend responsible for the orientation of the arms and there by the nature of the binding core formed. Thus the binding cores formed differ largely between L-3 and the other two.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ACAD SCIENCES INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:55:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:55:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES INDIA SECTION A-PHYSICAL SCIENCES, 84(2)297-303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0369-8203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2250-1762</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40010-014-0145-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17130</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>