<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-368</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-28T06:48:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>MPOE prefiltering with statistical channel model for DS-CDMA systems</dc:title><dc:creator>KANNAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, MOHIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>fir filters</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>probability</dc:subject><dc:description>In order to reduce the complexity of the mobile receiver, we develop a linear preceding filter based only on the statistical knowledge of the channel. Moreover, the proposed prefilter (precoder) is based on minimizing the probability of error in downlink multiuser transmission. We investigate two approaches for the proposed algorithm. In the first approach we consider a common FIR preceding filter for all users, and jointly minimize the probability of error of all users. In the second approach, we assume separate precoders for each user which are obtained by minimizing the probability of error for the respective user. In order to fully utilize the knowledge available at the transmitter, in both the approaches, the filter weights are computed conditioned on the transmitted bit vector sequence. This also makes the computation of the optimal prefilter coefficients linear in the number of users. We compare the results of the proposed approach, with results based on assuming complete knowledge of the channel. Simulation results clearly show that precoders based only on the statistical knowledge of channel, do provide acceptable BERs. Moreover, individual precoders provide better BER as compared to joint precoders.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-17T08:02:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T15:29:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-17T08:02:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T15:29:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Communications, Glasgow, U.K., 24-28 June 2007, 2822-2828.</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0353-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICC.2007.469</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/368</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/368</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>