<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18108</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:58:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance Analysis of Heat Sinks With Phase-Change Materials Subjected to Transient and Cyclic Heating</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>THERMAL-CONDUCTIVITY ENHANCEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>LATENT-HEAT</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MANAGEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Phase-change cooling technique is a suitable method for thermal management of electronic equipment subjected to transient or cyclic heat loads. The thermal performance of a phase-change based heat sink under cyclic heat load depends on several design parameters, namely, applied heat flux, cooling heat transfer coefficient, thermophysical properties of phase-change materials (PCMs), and physical dimensions of phase-change storage system during melting and freezing processes. A one-dimensional conduction heat transfer model is formulated to evaluate the effectiveness of preliminary design of practical PCM-based energy storage units. In this model, the phase-change process of the PCM is divided into melting and solidification subprocesses, for which separate equations are written. The equations are solved sequentially and an explicit closed-form solution is obtained. The efficacy of analytical model is estimated by comparing with a finite-volume-based numerical solution for both transient and cyclic heat loads.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:58:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:58:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HEAT TRANSFER ENGINEERING, 36(16)1349-1359</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0145-7632</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1521-0537</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01457632.2015.1003714</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18108</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>