<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17692</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T14:10:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of a snow wetness inversion algorithm using polarimetric scattering power decomposition model</dc:title><dc:creator>SURENDAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>YAMAGUCHI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>SAR DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLACIATED TERRAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>COHERENCY MATRIX</dc:subject><dc:subject>WET SNOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>RADAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLASSIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPENSATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BACKSCATTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RETRIEVAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polarimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decomposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dielectric</dc:subject><dc:subject>Snow wetness</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a new snow wetness estimation model is proposed for full-polarimetric Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) data. Surface and volume are the dominant scattering components in wet-snow conditions. The generalized four component polarimetric decomposition with unitary transformation (G4U) based generalized surface and volume parameters are utilized to invert snow surface and volume dielectric constants using the Bragg coefficients and Fresnel transmission coefficients respectively. The snow surface and volume wetness are then estimated using an empirical relationship. The effective snow wetness is derived from the weighted averaged surface and volume snow wetness. The weights are derived from the normalized surface and volume scattering powers obtained from the generalized full-polarimetric SAR decomposition method. Six Radarsat-2 fine resolution full-polarimetric datasets acquired over Himachal Pradesh, India along with the near-real time in situ measurements were used to validate the proposed model. The snow wetness derived from the SAR data by the proposed model with in situ measurements indicated that the absolute error at 95% confidence interval is 1.3% by volume. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF APPLIED EARTH OBSERVATION AND GEOINFORMATION, 42,65-75</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0303-2434</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jag.2015.05.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17692</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>