<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17878</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:00:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Transmission and reflection of internal solitary waves incident upon a triangular barrier</dc:title><dc:creator>SUTHERLAND, BR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEATING, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHRIVASTAVA, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>NUMERICAL EXPERIMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRATIFIED FLUID</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNIFORM SLOPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNDULAR BORES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRAPPED CORES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREAKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOWS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEA</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOPOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>stratified flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>solitary waves</dc:subject><dc:subject>topographic effects</dc:subject><dc:description>We report upon laboratory experiments and numerical simulations examining the evolution of an interfacial internal solitary wave incident upon a triangular ridge whose peak lies below the interface. If the ridge is moderately large, the wave is observed to shoal and break similar to solitary waves shoaling upon a constant slope, but interfacial waves are also observed to transmit over and reflect from the ridge. In laboratory experiments, by measuring the interface displacement as it evolves in time, we measure the relative transmission and reflection of available potential energy after the incident wave has interacted with the ridge. The numerical simulations of laboratory- and ocean-scale waves measure both the available potential and kinetic energy to determine the partition of incident energy into that which is transmitted and reflected. From shallow-water theory, we define a critical amplitude, A(c), above which interfacial waves are unstable. The transmission is found to decrease from one to zero as the ratio of the incident wave amplitude to A(c) increases from less than to greater than one. Empirical fits are made to analytic curves through measurements of the transmission and reflection coefficients.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CAMBRIDGE UNIV PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:00:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:00:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF FLUID MECHANICS, 775,304-327</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-1120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1469-7645</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/jfm.2015.306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17878</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>