<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9581</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel 3D mixed finite-element model for statics of angle-ply laminates</dc:title><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMTEKKAR, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, AH</dc:creator><dc:subject>bidirectional composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>multilayered plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>stresses</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed finite-element</dc:subject><dc:subject>minimum potential energy principle</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminated composite</dc:subject><dc:subject>angle-ply</dc:subject><dc:description>Analysis of angle-ply laminates becomes critical and computationally involved because of the presence of extension-shear coupling. A refined three-dimensional, mixed, 18-node finite-element (FE) model has been developed to analyse angle-ply laminates under static loading. The minimum potential energy principle has been used for the development of the mixed FE model, where the transverse stress components (tau(xz), tau(yz) and sigma(z), where z is the thickness direction) have been incorporated as the nodal degrees of freedom, in addition to the three displacement fields. Further, continuity of transverse stress fields through the thickness of the plate and layerwise continuity of displacement fields have been enforced in the formulation. Because all the constitutive and the compatibility conditions have been ensured within the continuum, the present formulation is unique amongst the family of mixed FE models. Results have been obtained for various angle-ply laminates and compared with analytical and finite-element solutions, which have been found to be in good agreement with them. Some new results on angle-ply with clamped-clamped support condition have also been presented to serve as benchmark results. Copyright (C) 2003 John Wiley Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T18:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T18:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL FOR NUMERICAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING, 57(12), 1695-1716</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5981</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/nme.737</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9581</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9581</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>