<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10109</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>KINETICS OF GROWTH OF THE TI-CO INTERMETALLIC COMPOUNDS DURING RAPID SOLIDIFICATION</dc:title><dc:creator>VITTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>phase-diagrams</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>metals</dc:subject><dc:description>The growth behavior of the disordered and ordered intermetallic compounds in the Ti-Co system from undercooled melts during rapid solidification has been studied in detail. It was found that cooling rates of the order of 10(10) to 10(12) K s-1 were insufficient to suppress the nucleation and growth of the intermetallic compounds. The compound isomorphous to Ti2Co does not exhibit faceting, indicating a nonsingular crystal/liquid interface morphology at high growth velocities. While a TiCo-like compound was found to have a ordered bcc structure, the formation of even the disordered TiCo3 was completely suppressed by the high isothermal velocities, leading to glass formation. The growth velocity of compounds formed in the composition range 23.3 to 59.7 at. pct Co was found to be diffusion limited with nucleation times smaller than the total melt lifetime in the process. The overall glass formation range was found to be very small, although the equilibrium phase diagram shows the presence of a variety of intermetallic compounds.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MINERALS METALS MATERIALS SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T19:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T19:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 24(8), 1869-1875</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-2133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02657861</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10109</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>