<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6117</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>GramyaVikas: A distributed collaboration model for rural development planning</dc:title><dc:creator>ADINARAYANA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>AMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUDHARSAN, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>distributed collaboration</dc:subject><dc:subject>geo-information &amp; communication technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>geographical information systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>needs assessment</dc:subject><dc:subject>open source software/content management system</dc:subject><dc:subject>rural development planning</dc:subject><dc:subject>rural extension community</dc:subject><dc:description>In the context of rural India, planning is mainly prescriptive (through mandated schemes) and top-down (by extension community from the line departments). Realizing the above mode of planning and the increasing demand for Geographical-Information &amp; Communication Technology (Geo-ICT) applications in the rural systems in India, a prototype distributed collaboration tool, called GromyoVikas (rural development), has been developed to assist the rural extension community in their own decision-making processes in a more interactive, integrated and coordinated manner. GramyaVikas, evolved out of the needs assessment of the user community, is a secure and cost-effective system developed for defined users with open source (a) content management system and (b) Geographical information Systems. This web-based tool will help the users to share and retrieve data/information; communicate for taking mutual decisions; make useful queries on spatial and nonspatial database to identify candidate villages/entities; and generate various views or scenarios for different rural development schemes. Presently, this Geo-ICT tool is being developed in an Intranet environment. The resulting system is intended to assist the remote users in analyzing rural-informatics for rural development planning decisions online, with customized GIS tools to suit the requirements of a few line departments for decision-making. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T05:01:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T05:01:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTERS AND ELECTRONICS IN AGRICULTURE, 62(2), 128-140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-1699</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compag.2007.12.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6117</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6117</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>