<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10591</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>C0 FINITE-ELEMENT GEOMETRICALLY NONLINEAR-ANALYSIS OF FIBER REINFORCED COMPOSITE AND SANDWICH LAMINATES BASED ON A HIGHER-ORDER THEORY</dc:title><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOMMINENI, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>plate-bending element</dc:subject><dc:subject>anisotropic rectangular-plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear deformation-theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>bidirectional composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear-analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>refined theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>closed-form</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>frames</dc:subject><dc:subject>shells</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a refined higher-order shear deformation theory for the linear and geometrically non-linear finite element analysis of fibre reinforced composite and sandwich laminates Laminae material is assumed to be linearly elastic, homogeneous and isotropic/orthotropic. This theory accounts for parabolic distribution of the transverse shear strains through the thickness of the laminate and higher-order terms in Green's strain vector in the sense of von Karman. A simple C0 finite element formulation is presented with a total Lagrangian approach and a nine-node Lagrangian quadrilateral element is chosen with nine degrees of freedom per node. Numerical results are presented for linear and geometric non-linear analysis of multi-layer cross-ply laminates and sandwich plates. The present theory predicts displacements and stresses more accurately than the first-order shear deformation theory. The results are compared with available closed-form and numerical solutions of both three-dimensional elasticity and plate theories.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T17:29:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T17:29:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTERS &amp; STRUCTURES, 45(3), 511-520</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0045-7949</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0045-7949(92)90436-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10591</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10591</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>