<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15760</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:15:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Preserved lignin structures in early eocene Surat lignites, Cambay Basin, Western India</dc:title><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALLICK, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKLA, AC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANN, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>Lignite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lignin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Early Eocene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cambay Basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>TETRAMETHYLAMMONIUM HYDROXIDE TMAH</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHROMATOGRAPHY-MASS-SPECTROMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>VASTAN LIGNITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COALIFICATION PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FATTY-ACIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>WOOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMOCHEMOLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEATIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Lignite samples from Vastan and Tadkeshwar lignite mines, Cambay Basin have been analysed to elucidate lignin precursor using thermochemolysis-gas chromatography-mass spectrometry. The thermochemolysis products of lignites are characterized by monomethoxy-, dimethoxy-, and trimethoxybenzene derivatives originated from -hydroxyphenyl, guaiacyl, and syringyl units of lignin polymer, respectively. The other compounds obtained in thermochemolysates of studied lignites are some resin derived C-15 sesquiterpenoids, with a series of fatty acid methyl esters and -alkanes/alkenes. The methylated guaiacyl and syringyl derivatives originate from the cleavage of beta-O-4 linkages and subsequent methylation of acidic hydroxyl groups of preserved lignin. Gymnosperm lignin is characterized mainly by guaiacyl derivatives whereas angiosperm lignin yields some syringyl-type compounds in addition to guaiacyl-type compounds. By analogy with the lignin structure of modern trees, the abundant occurrences of syringyl derivatives in the thermochemolysis products of Surat lignites clearly demonstrate that the palaeofloral community was dominated by angiosperms during the deposition of these lignites.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:15:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:15:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 79(4)345-352</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12594-012-0055-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15760</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>