<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15241</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:44:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrochemical photovoltaic studies of Cd1-xCoxS thin film electrodes deposited by a liquid phase chemical deposition route</dc:title><dc:creator>MANE, ST</dc:creator><dc:creator>PINGALE, PC</dc:creator><dc:creator>LENDAVE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARANDE, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, LP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photovoltaic cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-Cd1-xCox S photo sensing electrode</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flat band potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>BATH DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLAR-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTOR-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPRAY-PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:description>Cd1-xCoxS (0 &lt;= x &lt;= 0.5) thin films were made feasible on the chemomechanically and ultrasonically cleaned stainless steel substrates. The previously optimized conditions were used for the deposition. The electrode/electrolyte interfaces were then formed between the n-type Cd1-xCoxS photo sensing electrodes and a sulphide/polysulphide (0.25 M) redox electrolyte and investigated through the I-V and C-V characteristics in dark, power output characteristics and various other photo responsive characteristics. The dependance of the dark current through the junction and the junction capacitance on the voltage applied across the junction were examined and analyzed. Upon illumination of the interfaces with a light of 10 mW/cm(2), the maximum open-circuit photo voltage of 414 mV and short circuit photocurrent of 0.196 mA/cm(2) were developed in a cell devised with an electrode composition of x = 0.1. This resulted in energy conversion efficiency of 3.84% and a fill factor of 47.1%. The spectral and photo responsiveness of these cells were also studied. The studies at room temperature showed a shift in cut off wavelength from 515 nm to 635 nm for the change of x from 0 to 0.5. The other cell performance parameters were also determined for the series of the cells and the impact of the composition parameter x, on them is discussed at length. Overall, the photovoltaic output performance of the Cd1-xCoxS based electrochemical cell is much improved after Co-implantation (x = 0.1) in CdS. The observed results have been predicted and supported by the microscopic studies of the photoelectrode material. (c) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:44:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:44:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ELECTROCHIMICA ACTA, 102113-119</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2013.03.172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15241</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>