<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12407</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>INFLUENCE OF STREAMWISE PITCH ON LOCAL HEAT TRANSFER DISTRIBUTION FOR IN-LINE ARRAYS OF CIRCULAR JETS WITH SPENT AIR FLOW IN TWO OPPOSITE DIRECTIONS</dc:title><dc:creator>KATTI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>staggered arrays</dc:subject><dc:subject>impinging jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>cross-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>reynolds-number</dc:subject><dc:subject>flat surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>mach number</dc:subject><dc:subject>impingement</dc:subject><dc:subject>visualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>spacings</dc:subject><dc:subject>nozzle</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple circular jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>jet impingement cooling</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat transfer enhancement</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal imaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin metal foil technique</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of streamwise jet-to-jet spacing on local heat transfer distribution due to an in-line rectangular array of confined multiple circular air jets impinging on a surface parallel to the jet plate are experimentally studied. The length-to-diameter ratio of nozzles of the jet plate is 1.0. The flow, after impingement, is constrained to exit in two opposite directions from the confined passage formed between the jet plate and target plate. Mean jet Reynolds numbers based on the nozzle exit diameter (d) covered are 3,000, 5,000, 7,500, and 10,000; jet-to-plate distances studied are d, 2d, and 3d. Streamwise jet-to-jet distances of 3d, 4d, and 5d, and a constant spanwise pitch of 4d, are considered. The jet plates have ten spanwise rows in the streamwise direction and six jets in each spanwise row. The flat heat transfer surface is made of thin stainless-steel metal foil. Local temperature distribution on a target plate is measured using a thermal infrared camera. Wall static pressures in the streamwise direction are measured midway between the spanwise jets to estimate crossflow velocities and individual jet velocities. The streamwise distribution of the jet flow and the cross flow is found to be least influenced by the streamwise pitch variation for the range of parameters considered during the present study. Heat transfer characteristics are explained partially on the basis of flow distribution. The cooling performance, based on the strip-averaged Nusselt number per unit mass flow rate of coolant per unit area of cooled surface, indicates deterioration for lower streamwise pitch and higher jet-to-plate distance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T17:31:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T17:31:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTAL HEAT TRANSFER, 22(4), 228-256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0891-6152</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/08916150903098886</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12407</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12407</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>