<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2086</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Can ac conductivity data in mixed alkali glasses be explained using scaling functions?</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>TANDON, RP</dc:creator><dc:subject>oxide glasses</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionic-conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>mobile ions</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>relaxation</dc:subject><dc:subject>conductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>crossover</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:description>In single ion conducting glasses, the dc conductivity an 1 the onset frequency of the dispersion changes in characteristic fashion and leads to scaling laws. Scaling was not applied to mixed alkali glasses previously. The major objective of this paper is to study whether scaling functions applied to single alkali glasses can explain ion dynamics of mixed alkali glasses. With this purpose experimental results on the mixed alkali glasses in the system xLiF-(80-x) KF-20Al(PO3) (3) are reported. The frequency dependent conductivity data has been recorded at 323 K &lt;= T &lt;= 523 K and over a frequency range 20 Hz &lt;= v &lt;= 1 MHz. While the individual compositions exhibit temperature independent scaling of the ac conductivity, the composition dependent ac conductivity can be explained only using two scaling functions, one each for the dominant K and Li cation regions on either side of the minimum in the ac/dc conductivity of the mixed alkali glasses.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T05:49:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T05:49:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLID STATE IONICS: THE SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF IONS IN MOTION,799-809</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>981-238-932-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/9789812702586_0089</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15620</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2086</dc:identifier><dc:source>9th Asian Conference on Solid State Ionics,Cheju Isl, SOUTH KOREA,JUN 06-11, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>