<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3851</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Feasibility of Reactive Distillation for Fischer-Tropsch Synthesis. 2</dc:title><dc:creator>SRINIVAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALIK, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>bubble-column reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>product distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquid-phase</dc:subject><dc:subject>bed reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>slurry</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>solubility</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:description>The search for alternative sources of transportation fuels and energy security have revived an interest in the Fischer-Tropsch Synthesis (FTS) technology. Over the years, the main driver in FT reactor development has moved from the exothermic heat removal to the product distribution and selectivity. Reactive distillation (RD), a proven reactive separation method that can enhance yields and improve product selectivity in multiple reactant/product systems, was shown to be feasible for FTS in our earlier paper using a simplified kinetics [Srinivas, et al. Feasibility of Reactive distillation for Fischer-Tropsch Synthesis. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2008, 48, 889-899]. This paper looks at the feasibility using a detailed kinetics incorporating olefin readsorption. In-built thermodynamic procedures of Aspen Plus, along with a detailed kinetic model that predicts product distribution, were used in performing the simulations. Some insight is given on the thermodynamics and kinetics used in performing the simulations. Conversion, yield, olefin-to-paraffin ratio, and product distribution are the parameters used for comparison among the different reactor types. Simulation results of the conventional reactors are compared with RD and it is seen that the performance of RD is at par or better than the conventional reactors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T03:45:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T03:45:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 48(10), 4710-4718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie801887m</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3851</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3851</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>