<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17123</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:52:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Application of the windowed-Fourier-transform-based fringe analysis technique for investigating temperature and concentration fields in fluids</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHANAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>BUOYANCY-DRIVEN CONVECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-SHIFT INTERFEROMETER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATTERN-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>3-DIMENSIONAL RECONSTRUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-SOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFERENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOMOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>LYSOZYME</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work is concerned with the development and application of a novel fringe analysis technique based on the principles of the windowed-Fourier-transform (WFT) for the determination of temperature and concentration fields from interferometric images for a range of heat and mass transfer applications. Based on the extent of the noise level associated with the experimental data, the technique has been coupled with two different phase unwrapping methods: the Itoh algorithm and the quality guided phase unwrapping technique for phase extraction. In order to generate the experimental data, a range of experiments have been carried out which include cooling of a vertical flat plate in free convection conditions, combustion of mono-propellant flames, and growth of organic as well as inorganic crystals from their aqueous solutions. The flat plate and combustion experiments are modeled as heat transfer applications wherein the interest is to determine the whole-field temperature distribution. Aqueous-solution-based crystal growth experiments are performed to simulate the mass transfer phenomena and the interest is to determine the two-dimensional solute concentration field around the growing crystal. A Mach-Zehnder interferometer has been employed to record the path-integrated quantity of interest (temperature and/or concentration) in the form of interferometric images in the experiments. The potential of the WFT method has also been demonstrated on numerically simulated phase data for varying noise levels, and the accuracy in phase extraction have been quantified in terms of the root mean square errors. Three levels of noise, i.e., 0%, 10%, and 20% have been considered. Results of the present study show that the WFT technique allows an accurate extraction of phase values that can subsequently be converted into two-dimensional temperature and/or concentration distribution fields. Moreover, since WFT is a local processing technique, speckle patterns and the inherent noise in the interferometric data do not affect the resultant phase values. Brief comparisons of the accuracy of the WFT with other standard techniques such as conventional Fourier-filtering methods are also presented. (C) 2014 Optical Society of America</dc:description><dc:publisher>OPTICAL SOC AMER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:52:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:52:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED OPTICS, 53(11)2331-2344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1559-128X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2155-3165</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1364/AO.53.002331</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17123</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>