<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17120</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:50:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Categorization of the Glaciated Terrain of Indian Himalaya Using CP and FP Mode SAR</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>YAMAGUCHI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARK, SE</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOERNER, WM</dc:creator><dc:creator>CUI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>Compact polarimetry (CP)</dc:subject><dc:subject>dual polarimetry (DP)</dc:subject><dc:subject>full polarimetry (FP)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gangotri</dc:subject><dc:subject>glacier</dc:subject><dc:subject>Himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>mono polarimetry (MP)</dc:subject><dc:subject>remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>snow</dc:subject><dc:subject>DECOMPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the comparison between the potential of synthetic aperture radar (SAR) data in compact polarimetry (CP) versus the fully polarimetric POLSAR mode (FP) for glacier areas. The eigenvalue-based constructed parameters, decompositions and supervised classification schemes were used for this inter-comparison. The comparison is focused on compact polarimetric techniques versus full polarimetric techniques based on both of qualitative and quantitative analysis of the glaciated parameters extraction. Overall performance of CP mode is lower than FP mode for glaciated terrain parameter extraction. Furthermore, it was found over the part of rugged Gangotri glaciated terrain, Indian Himalaya that the reconstruction pseudo polarimetry data is erroneous and highly biased because of data sets do not satisfy the pseudo polarimetric reconstruction conditions in the glaciated terrain.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:50:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:50:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE JOURNAL OF SELECTED TOPICS IN APPLIED EARTH OBSERVATIONS AND REMOTE SENSING, 7(3)872-880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1939-1404</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2151-1535</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2013.2266354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17120</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>