<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4725</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-12T06:21:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Compositional disorder and its influence on the structural, electronic, and magnetic properties of MgC(Ni1-xCox)(3) alloys from first principles</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSEPH, PJT</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>nonoxide perovskite mgcni3</dc:subject><dc:subject>spin fluctuations</dc:subject><dc:subject>interstitial fe</dc:subject><dc:subject>dilute alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>superconductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>1st-principles</dc:subject><dc:subject>al</dc:subject><dc:subject>cu</dc:subject><dc:subject>approximation</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoemission</dc:subject><dc:description>First-principles, density-functional based electronic structure calculations are carried out for MgC(Ni1-xCox)(3) alloys over the concentration range 0 &lt;= x &lt;= 1, using Korringa-Kohn-Rostoker coherent-potential approximation method in the atomic sphere approximation. The self-consistent calculations are used to study the changes as a function of x in the equation of state parameters, total and partial densities of states, magnetic moment and the on-site exchange interaction parameter. To study the magnetic properties as well as its volume dependence, fixed-spin moment calculations in conjunction with the phenomenological Landau theory are employed. The salient features that emerge from these calculations are (i) a concentration independent variation in the lattice parameter and bulk modulus at x similar to 0.75 with an anomaly in the variation of the pressure derivative of bulk modulus, (ii) the fixed-spin moment based corrections to the overestimated magnetic ground state for 0.0 &lt;= x &lt;= 0.3 alloys, making the results consistent with the experiments, and (iii) the possibility of multiple magnetic states at x similar to 0.75, which, however, requires further improvements in the calculations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T12:18:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T12:18:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 72(21), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.72.214206</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4725</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4725</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>