<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1189</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of AJM for deburring</dc:title><dc:creator>BALASUBRAMANIAM, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAN, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>statistical methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>stainless steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>machining</dc:subject><dc:description>Deburring is a major bottleneck in manufacturing organisations. In recent years abrasive jet machining has been gaining increasing acceptability for deburring applications. The influence of abrasive jet deburring process parameters is not known clearly. An experimental investigation has been conducted to identify the abrasive jet deburring process parameters and the edge quality of abrasive jet deburred components. For these experiments, an experimental design based on a Taguchi orthogonal array was used to systematically measure the influence of the major cutting parameters on abrasive jet deburred specimens made of stainless steel. An additional parameter viz. ‘jet height' was identified, which latter significantly affects the deburring process. A profile projector was used to measure the edge quality and also visual inspection was conducted to ascertain the surface damage of the specimens. Results of the edge quality measurements supplemented with visual inspection were analyzed by the ANOVA method, as a result of which it was found that the burr removal was affected by the parameters jet height and angle of impingement. Also a statistical model was developed for the magnitude of the edge radius generated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-21T14:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:07:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-21T14:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:07:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Materials Processing Technology 79(1-3), 52-58</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0924-0136</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0924-0136(97)00305-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1189</dc:identifier><dc:language>en_US</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>