<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16065</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:27:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Identification of the inverse melting line in the vortex phase diagram of a low T-c superconductor, Ca3Rh4Sn13</dc:title><dc:creator>BABU, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAMIZHAVEL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOMY, CV</dc:creator><dc:creator>GROVER, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAL, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLUX LATTICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>II SUPERCONDUCTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELASTIC THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEAK</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>BI2SR2CACU2O8</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VORTICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:description>We present the vortex phase diagram in a weakly pinned single crystal of a low T-c superconductor, Ca3Rh4Sn13 (T-c similar to 8.37 K). We believe that a well ordered Bragg glass phase is sandwiched between the multi-domain vortex glass and an amorphous vortex state in a portion of the field-temperature phase space. From an exploration of the thermal variation of the onset of the non-monotonic variation of the critical current density as fingerprinted by the second magnetization peak (SMP) in the magnetization hysteresis loops, we have sketched a phase boundary akin to the inverse melting phenomenon reported earlier only in samples of high T-c superconductors. We reveal here a step change in the equilibrium magnetization across the SMP and peak effect regions, which is a suggestive feature of the first order phase transition. We have determined a lower field limit (like a spinodal line) of the transition to the vortex glass phase via the identification of the SMP anomaly in the ac susceptibility measurements, where shaking of the vortex matter can facilitate the accession of the underlying equilibrium phase.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:27:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:27:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SUPERCONDUCTOR SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY, 26(12)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-2048</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-6668</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-2048/26/12/125016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16065</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>