<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17066</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T18:07:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of Buckling Strength of Inner Windings in Transformers Under Radial Short-Circuit Forces</dc:title><dc:creator>BAKSHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Buckling</dc:subject><dc:subject>short-circuit force</dc:subject><dc:subject>strain</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>transformers</dc:subject><dc:description>The buckling of conductors of inner windings in transformers is one of the major causes of their failures. It can occur when a large magnitude of radial short-circuit electromagnetic force acts on them. In this paper, initially, mechanical strains developed during winding processes and due to radial short-circuit forces have been determined. The two mechanical strains viz. the short-circuit induced strain and the winding process-induced strain are algebraically added to obtain their resulting strain. The stress corresponding to the resulting strain has been determined by using the Ramberg-Osgood stress-strain relation. The critical buckling stress has been calculated and compared with the resulting stress. The analytically obtained result of the strain induced in the winding conductor during its winding process has been verified using the finite-element method. A case study has been described in which the factor of safety against the buckling strength is determined.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:07:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:07:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER DELIVERY, 29(1)241-245</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8977</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1937-4208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPWRD.2013.2272102</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17066</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>