<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16891</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:31:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling of dynamic hysteresis for grain-oriented laminations using a viscosity-based modified dynamic Jiles-Atherton model</dc:title><dc:creator>BAGHEL, APS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHEKHAWAT, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>Dynamic losses</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetic viscosity approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grain-oriented laminations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Jiles-Atherton model</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOOPS</dc:subject><dc:description>Grain-oriented (GO) materials exhibit arbitrary frequency loss behaviors and anomalies in dynamic hysteresis loop shapes. Significant attempts have been made in the literature to approximate dynamic hysteresis loops using the dynamic Jiles-Atherton (JA) model based Bertotti's approach. Such a model is inefficient in accurate loss computation over a wide range of frequencies and in predictions of correct loop shapes. Moreover, the original static JA model also needs to be improved for accurate prediction of highly steep, gooseneck, and narrow-waist static loops of GO materials. An alternative approach based on magnetic viscosity provides flexibilities to handle indefinite frequency dependence of the losses and to control the anomalous loop shapes. This paper proposes a viscosity-based dynamic JA model which gives accurate prediction of dynamic loops of GO materials. A modified static JA model which considers crystalline and textured structures of GO materials is used to predict static hysteresis loops. The dynamic losses are included in the modified model using the field separation approach. The proposed model is validated using experimental measurements. The computed and measured dynamic loops are in close agreement in the frequency range of 1-200 Hz. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:31:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:31:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICA B-CONDENSED MATTER, 448349-353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-4526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2014.04.012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16891</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>