<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5834</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dechlorination of chlorobenzoates by an isolated bacterial culture</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUMATHI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>4-chlorobenzoate</dc:subject><dc:subject>metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>mineralization</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacterial culture</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>chlorobenzoates</dc:subject><dc:subject>dechlorination</dc:subject><dc:description>A range of chlorobenzoates is produced as dead-end metabolites during the microbial degradation of chlorinated aromatic compounds, including polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) and some herbicides. Hence studies on the microbial degradation of composites of chlorobenzoates are important for developing an effective bioremediation technology. An isolated bacterial culture had the ability to tolerate and grow in the presence of 2-chlorobenzoate (2-cba), 3-chlorobenzoate (3-cba), 4-chlorobenzoate (4-cba), a mixture of these chlorobenzoate isomers, 4-chloro,2-nitrobenzoate (4cnb) and chlorobenzene (cbz) using benzoate as the growth substrate. The microbial culture was able to dechlorinate all the above-mentioned chloroaromatics as well as their mixture to the extent of 50-75% under aerobic conditions. The rate of dechlorination followed the order mixture &gt; 3-cba &gt; 4-cba &gt; 2-cba, with maximal release of 60, 75, 60 and 50 ppm of free chloride respectively, in the presence of 0.6% benzoate. Dechlorination appeared to begin at the end of the exponential growth phase and followed a linear course until the end of the lytic phase. The dechlorinating property of the isolated bacterial culture enabling it to act on mixtures of chlorinated benzoates in the presence of growth substrates such as benzoate may be useful for remediation of sites contaminated with PCB. To our knowledge the isolated bacterial culture is one of the few versatile strains to biotransform a variety of chlorinated aromatic compounds and their mixture through initial dechlorination.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CURRENT SCIENCE ASSOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T07:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T07:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 93(8), 1126-1129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5834</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5834</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>