<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15491</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:57:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kinetic stabilization of microtubule dynamics by indanocine perturbs EB1 localization, induces defects in cell polarity and inhibits migration of MDA-MB-231 cells</dc:title><dc:creator>KAPOOR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Cell migration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indanocine</dc:subject><dc:subject>Metastasis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microtubule dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOCAL ADHESION DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERIZATION DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORGANIZING CENTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOTILE CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUBULIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIBROBLASTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLASP2</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUGS</dc:subject><dc:description>Cell motility is an essential aspect of metastatic spread of cancer. Microtubule-targeted agents exhibit anti-metastatic properties, the underlying mechanism of which remains understudied. In this study, we have investigated the role of microtubule dynamics in migration of cancer cells using indanocine, a synthetic small molecule inhibitor of tubulin. We found that indanocine, at concentrations that did not visibly affect microtubule organization, suppressed dynamic instability of microtubules and reduced the rate of migration of highly metastatic MDA-MB-231 cells. Indanocine-treated cells were defective in lamellipodium formation and could not develop polarized morphology. The kinetic stabilization of microtubules was associated with a marked increase in their acetylation level and a perturbation in the localization of EB1, a microtubule plus end binding protein. Using standard scratch wound healing assay and immunofluorescence analysis; we found that microtubule acetylation occurred in the direction of migration in vehicle-treated cells, whereas indanocine treatment led to a global acetylation of microtubules. The results together suggested that selective stabilization of microtubules was perturbed in the presence of indanocine that possibly resulted in lack of cell polarization and a concurrent reduction in migration of cells. Moreover, microtubule stabilization by indanocine affected adhesion turnover and impaired the polarized pattern of adhesion sites in cells. Together the results indicated that the regulation of microtubule dynamics is required to coordinate cell polarization as well as adhesion asymmetry and support the hypothesis that the perturbation of microtubule dynamics by tubulin-targeted agents can be exploited to restrict the migration of tumor cells. (C) 2012 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:57:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:57:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHEMICAL PHARMACOLOGY, 83(11)1495-1506</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bcp.2012.02.012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15491</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>