<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2113</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Geotechnical investigation of amiyan landslide hazard zone in Himalayan region, Uttaranchal, India</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, K</dc:creator><dc:description>Himalayas witness each year a series of landslides both small and large, specially in the post monsoon period. These natural disasters have occurred in all the sections of the Himalayas from outer to Higher Himalayas. The southern hills of Kumaun in the proximity of the Main Boundary Thrust (MBT) are very prone to recurrent landslides. The slope failures are related to steeper angle of hill slope, extent and type of vegetation, structural condition of bedrock, high rainfall intensity and neotectonism of the MBT. The Amiya landslide on 11 July 1999, which has claimed 22 lives, including 2 persons in a place 20 km northeast of Kathgodam in Kumaun, Uttaranchal state, India. The flow of debris mainly contains different types of sandstone. These sandstone rocks belongs to the Lower Siwalik Formation, dominantly constituting the Amiyan Landslide area have been investigated to determine the different Physico-mechanical properties, dynamic properties and its chemical analysis. In this paper, an attempt has been made to determine the all physico-mechanical properties of sandstone and establish correlation among this parameter. The study reveals that the p-wave velocity and uniaxial compressive strength (UCS) decreased with increasing moisture content. Regression analysis demonstrated that wave velocity, UCS decreased with increased quartz content in the area, which is mainly due to the presence of mica and clay. The different geo-mechanical parameters show good correlation with P-wave velocity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:18:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:18:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Geotechnical Engineering for Disaster Mitigation and Rehabilitation,355-360</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>981-256-469-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/98127016050039_0039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15628</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2113</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Geotechnical Engineering for Disaster Mitigation and Rehabilitation,Singapore, SINGAPORE,DEC 12-13, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>