<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17354</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:19:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Impacts of urbanization on Indian summer monsoon rainfall extremes</dc:title><dc:creator>SHASTRI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAUL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARMAKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>URBAN HEAT-ISLAND</dc:subject><dc:subject>CENSORED QUANTILE REGRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLIMATE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRECIPITATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TREND</dc:subject><dc:subject>VARIABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROJECTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SATELLITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indian summer monsoon</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantile regression</dc:subject><dc:subject>rainfall extremes</dc:subject><dc:subject>urbanization</dc:subject><dc:description>Urban areas have different climatology with respect to their rural surroundings. Though urbanization is a worldwide phenomenon, it is especially prevalent in India, where urban areas have experienced an unprecedented rate of growth over the last 30years. Here we take up an observational study to understand the influence of urbanization on the characteristics of precipitation (specifically extremes) in India. We identify 42 urban regions and compare their extreme rainfall characteristics with those of surrounding rural areas. We observe that, on an overall scale, the urban signatures on extreme rainfall are not prominently and consistently visible, but they are spatially nonuniform. Zonal analysis reveals significant impacts of urbanization on extreme rainfall in central and western regions of India. An additional examination, to understand the influences of urbanization on heavy rainfall climatology, is carried with station level data using a statistical method, quantile regression. This is performed for the most populated city of India, Mumbai, in pair with a nearby nonurban area, Alibaug; both having similar geographic location. The derived extreme rainfall regression quantiles reveal the sensitivity of extreme rainfall events to the increased urbanization. Overall the study identifies the climatological zones in India, where increased urbanization affects regional rainfall pattern and extremes, with a detailed case study of Mumbai. This also calls attention to the need of further experimental investigation, for the identification of the key climatological processes, in different regions of India, affected by increased urbanization.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER GEOPHYSICAL UNION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:19:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:19:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES, 120(2)495-516</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2169-897X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2169-8996</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/2014JD022061</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17354</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>