<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8569</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spatial-temporal variability of seismic hazard in peninsular India</dc:title><dc:creator>JAISWAL, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>incomplete data files</dc:subject><dc:subject>historical seismicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnitude</dc:subject><dc:subject>regions</dc:subject><dc:subject>shield</dc:subject><dc:subject>map</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic hazard</dc:subject><dc:subject>maximum likelihood procedure</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismotectonics</dc:subject><dc:subject>stable continental regions</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper examines the variability of seismic activity observed in the case of different geological zones of peninsular India (10 degrees N-26 degrees N; 68 degrees E-90 degrees E) based on earthquake catalog between the period 1842 and 2002 and estimates earthquake hazard for the region. With compilation of earthquake catalog in terms is of moment magnitude and establishing broad completeness criteria, we derive the seismicity parameters for each geologic zone of peninsular India using maximum likelihood procedure. The estimated parameters provide the basis for understanding the historical seismicity associated With different geological zones of peninsular India and also provide important inputs for future seismic hazard estimation studies in the re-ion. Based on present investigation, it is clear that: earthquake recurrence activity in various geologic zones of peninsular India is distinct and varies considerably between its cratonic and rifting zones. The study identifies the likely hazards due to the possibility of moderate to large earthquakes in peninsular India and also presents the influence of spatial rate variation in the seismic activity of this region. This paper presents the influence of source zone characterization and recurrence rate variation pattern on the maximum earthquake magnitude estimation. The results presented in the paper provide a useful basis for probabilistic seismic hazard studies and microzonation studies in peninsular India.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T23:01:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T23:01:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 117(), 707-718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8569</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8569</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>