<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7047</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis, characterization and catalytic properties of mesoporous TiHMA molecular sieves: selective oxidation of cycloalkanes</dc:title><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>cyclohexane oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium silicate</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen-peroxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>highly efficient</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminophosphates</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolite</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>epoxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkanes</dc:subject><dc:subject>h2o2</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesoporous</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular sieves</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminophosphates</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>cycloalkanes</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclohexane</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclooctane</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclododecane</dc:subject><dc:description>Titanium substituted hexagonal mesoporous aluminophosphate (TiHMA) molecular sieves were synthesized and characterized. Various physicochemical studies, viz., X-ray diffraction, transmission electron microscopy, electron diffraction, environmental scanning electron microscopy, thermal analyses, inductively coupled plasma-atomic emission spectroscopy, diffuse reflectance ultraviolet-visible spectroscopy, Fourier transform Raman spectroscopy, temperature programmed desorption of ammonia and nitrogen absorption-desorption isotherms, confirm the substitution of Ti4+ ions in the tetrahedral framework of HMA. The catalytic activity of TiHMA was evaluated for the oxidation reactions of cyclic saturated hydrocarbons such as cyclohexane, cyclooctane and cyclododecane. The catalyst exhibits excellent substrate conversion and product selectivity, and that it was found to be truly as a heterogeneous catalyst as the activity was practically unaffected upon recycling. In particular, the oxidation was highly successful for the bulkier cycloalkane molecules. Furthermore, the activity of TiHMA is also compared with mesoporous TiMCM-41 as well as microporous TiAPO-5 and TS-1 catalysts. (C) 2004</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T23:26:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T23:26:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROPOROUS AND MESOPOROUS MATERIALS, 73(3), 137-149</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1387-1811</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.micromeso.2004.05.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7047</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>