<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14558</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:23:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Can India's future needs of electricity be met by renewable energy sources? A revised assessment</dc:title><dc:creator>SUKHATME, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Diurnal variation</dc:subject><dc:subject>future electricity needs</dc:subject><dc:subject>renewable energy sources</dc:subject><dc:description>In earlier papers, an attempt was made to assess if renewable energy sources alone could meet India's future needs of electricity. With the information available then, it was concluded that this was not possible. However, over the last year, many papers/comments have been published on the subject matter and new research findings have also become available regarding the high potential of wind energy. It has therefore become necessary to make a revised assessment. India will need 3,128 TWh/yr of electrical energy in the future if it adopts a frugal policy for energy use. The present study shows that this annual need may be met through renewable energy sources alone in the form of solar power (photovoltaic and thermal), wind power and hydroelectric power. The study also points out that because of the intermittent nature of solar and wind power, there is a serious mismatch between the diurnal variation of the electricity generated by renewable sources and the diurnal variation of the demand for electricity. Many difficult technical challenges concerning transmission, distribution, control and storage of energy will have to be overcome in order to remove the mismatch. Only then will it be possible to supply power generated by renewable energy sources to match the electricity demand on a round-the-clock basis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:23:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:23:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 103(10)1153-1161</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14558</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>