<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2142</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of reverse micro-EDM process for generating high aspect ratio micro-electrode arrays</dc:title><dc:creator>MASTUD, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>arrayed micro-electrodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>reverse micro-edm</dc:subject><dc:description>Deep arrayed micro-hole arrays find applications in air-bearings, inkjet nozzles, micro filters, and single cell manipulation devices. Typically, high aspect ratio micro-electrodes are required for creation of deep blind/through holes. Reverse micro-EDM has the potential for generating high aspect ratio arrayed micro-electrodes. It involves reverse replication of arrayed micro-holes in a plate on to a larger diameter bulk electrode thereby creating high aspect ratio micro-rod arrays. While the process is well-known for its application in the macro-domain, there have been extremely limited studies in its application in the micro-domain. In this work, micro-electrode arrays having different cross-sections and dimensions have been fabricated. A micro-electrode 60 mu m in diameter and an aspect ratio of 33 has been successfully fabricated. Machined micro-electrodes are assessed for geometrical accuracy, surface finish, and surface morphology. The chemical composition of machined rods has been investigated via Energy Dispersive Spectroscopy (EDS).</dc:description><dc:publisher>PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERING PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:32:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:32:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>4M/ICOMM 2009 - THE GLOBAL CONFERENCE ON MICRO MANUFACTURE,153-156</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1243/17547164C0012009026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15632</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2142</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Mult-Material Micro Manufacture/ International Conference on Micro Manufacting,Karlsruhe, GERMANY,SEP , 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>