<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-676</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Removal of arsenic from water by electrocoagulation</dc:title><dc:creator>RATNA KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, SANJEEV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHILAR, KC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>coagulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexation</dc:subject><dc:subject>current density</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study electrocoagulation (EC) has been evaluated as a treatment technology for arsenite [As(III)] and arsenate [As(V)] removal from water. Laboratory scale experiments were conducted with three electrode materials namely, iron, aluminum and titanium to assess their efficiency. Arsenic removal obtained was highest with iron electrodes. EC was able to bring down aqueous phase arsenic concentration to less than 10 μgl-1 with iron electrodes. Current density was varied from 0.65 to 1.53 mAcm -2 and it was observed that higher current density achieved rapid arsenic removal. Experimental results at different current densities indicated that arsenic removal was normalized with respect to total charge passed and therefore charge density has been used to compare the results. Effect of pH on arsenic removal was not significant in the pH range 6-8. Comparative evaluation of As(III) and As(V) removal by chemical coagulation (with ferric chloride) and electrocoagulation has been done. The comparison revealed that EC has better removal efficiency for As(III), whereas As(V) removal by both processes was nearly same. The removal mechanism of As(III) by EC seems to be oxidation of As(III) to As(V) and subsequent removal by adsorption/complexation with metal hydroxides generated in the process.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:08:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:07:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:08:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:07:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Chemosphere 55(9), 1245-1252</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0045-6535</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2003.12.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/676</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/676</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>