<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15054</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:03:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Energy Management in Microgrids Using Demand Response and Distributed Storage-A Multiagent Approach</dc:title><dc:creator>NUNNA, HSVSK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOOLLA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Demand response</dc:subject><dc:subject>demand-side management</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy markets simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>microgrids and multiagent systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>PART I</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESOURCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOOLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, an agent-based energy-management system is proposed to facilitate power trading among microgrids with demand response and distributed storage (DRaDS). The key focus of this approach is to utilize diversity in load consumption patterns of the customers and energy availability from the distributed energy resources, distributed storage, and demand response (DR) in reducing the peak demand and minimizing the cost of electricity. An index-based incentive mechanism is also proposed to encourage customers participating in DR based on frequency and size of the participation. The proposed strategies are validated using two case studies with interconnected microgrids. Based on extensive simulation results of the system being developed using the Java Agent DEvelopment framework (JADE), it has been found that multiagent-based energy management with DRaDS is successful in reducing the system peak and cost benefit for customers with a high priority index.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:03:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:03:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER DELIVERY, 28(2)939-947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPWRD.2013.2239665</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15054</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>