<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-678</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Computation of point of application of seismic passive resistance by pseudo-dynamic method</dc:title><dc:creator>NIMBALKAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, DEEPANKAR</dc:creator><dc:subject>soil structure interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic passive resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>retaining walls</dc:subject><dc:description>Computation of seismic passive resistance and its point of application is an important aspect of seismic design of retaining wall. Several researchers in the past had obtained seismic passive earth pressures by using the conventional pseudo-static method. In this pseudo-static method, peak ground acceleration is assumed as constant and seismic passive pressure thus obtained shows the linear variation along the height of the retaining wall. There is hardly any scope to find out the point of application of seismic passive resistance by pseudo-static approach but to assume it to act at one-third height from the base of the wall. Rectifying these errors, in recently developed pseudo-dynamic method of analysis, all these factors are considered to compute seismic passive earth pressures. In this paper, an attempt has been made to compute the point of application of seismic passive resistance using limit equilibrium method of analysis with pseudo-dynamic approach. Effects of variation of parameters like wall friction angle, time period of earthquake ground motion, seismic shear and primary wave velocities of backfill soil, soil amplification and seismic peak horizontal and vertical ground accelerations on the seismic passive earth pressure are studied.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:08:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:27:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:08:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:27:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG: Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 2636-2643</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/678</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/678</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>