<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16559</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:37:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of post deposition annealing on thermal evaporated ZnSe:Te towards a scintillator application</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, MN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, SG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Scintillator</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZnSe:Te</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thermal evaporator</dc:subject><dc:subject>LASER</dc:subject><dc:description>ZnSe having a wide but direct bandgap (bulk band gap 2.7 eV) is very efficient for detecting nuclear radiations by using its scintillation property. With a high absolute light output and radiation spectra which match well with Si-photodiode spectral sensitivity, ZnSe scintillators have adequately minimized the gap between "scintillator-photodiode" series for modern radiation detectors. Promising features like long decay time and high values of intrinsic radiation absorption make ZnSe based scintillators a very interesting research filed. Here in this report, we investigate an inexpensive and easy method to realize ZnSe:Te film on a quartz substrate. ZnSe:Te film is deposited using a thermal evaporator using ZnSe and ZnTe powders as raw materials to start with. After the deposition, the samples are exposed to a thermal annealing step for 1 h. The temperatures are kept at 624,674 and 724 K. We have confirmed presence of a preferred [1 1 1] oriented polycrystalline ZnSe:Te thin films by XRD experiments. Photoluminescence experiment using a He:Cd laser at 324 nm at low temperature (8 K) reports an emission at 2.54 eV due to non-equilibrium carrier plasma. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:37:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:37:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROELECTRONIC ENGINEERING, 12684-87</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-9317</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1521-3757</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mee.2014.06.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16559</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>