<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11058</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T03:18:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Morphology and resistivity of Al thin films grown on Si(111) by molecular beam epitaxy</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEBNATH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASWAL, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUTHE, KP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>YAKHMI, JV</dc:creator><dc:subject>aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>metallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>si</dc:subject><dc:subject>al thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular beam epitaxy</dc:subject><dc:subject>xps</dc:subject><dc:subject>afm</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-to-insulator transition</dc:subject><dc:description>Thin films of aluminium metal with varying thickness between 10 and 200nm were grown on (I 1 1) Si substrates at 250 degrees C under UHV conditions using molecular beam epitaxy (MBE). Grown thin films were characterized by in situ Xray photoelectron spectroscopy, and ex situ X-ray diffraction, atomic force microscopy and temperature-dependent electrical resisitivity measurements. The results showed that (i) films grow via 3D-island Volmer-Weber growth mechanism, (ii) with increasing film thickness the average grain size increases and the coalescence takes place for thickness &gt; 60 nm, and (iii) independent of the thickness, films grow with (111) orientation. The room-temperature value of resistivity contrary to the predictions of existing theoretical models is found to increase monotonically up to a thickness of 40 nm. This anomalous feature was understood in terms of the film morphology, whereby charge transport takes place via variable range hopping (VRH). For film thickness &lt;= 50 nm, the resistivity vs. temperature curves exhibited a metal-to-insulator (M-I) transition at low temperature, and analysis of insulating region supported the 2D-VRH mechanism of charge transport. However, for thickness &gt;= 60 mn the resistivity decreased sharply and the M-I transition disappeared. The bulk value of resistivity (2.59 mu Omega cm) was obtained for thickness &gt; 200 urn. (c) 2005</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T15:16:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T15:16:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>VACUUM, 79(3-4), 178-185</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0042-207X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2005.03.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11058</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>