<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-425</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-19T10:59:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Base station selection strategy in multihop cellular networks: a new approach</dc:title><dc:creator>MARATHE, NV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>cellular radio</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication traffic</dc:subject><dc:description>Multihop cellular networks (MCN) have been proposed for quite a long time as of now. The major improvements these networks offer over the conventional cellular networks are increase in capacity and coverage area. However the congestion near the base station (BS) happens to be the bottleneck even in the approach of MCN. Therefore approach to reduce this congestion is a potential area of further research in this field. Our proposed architecture is one such attempt in this direction. In the proposed scheme instead of a single cell covered by a particular base station the entire coverage area of the cellular network consisting of many cells is considered as a whole and an attempt has been made to find out the direct links between the source and the destination of a connection without approaching any of the base stations. Since in MCN any mobile terminal (MT) can communicate with another MT directly; much importance should not be attached to the parent or associated base station. Rather the any suitable base station should be the last hop in this network only when an attempt to find out the direct links between the source and the destination of a connection fails. This failure may either because the path is too long or either of source and destination is outside the network. Out of the cluster of parent BS and six neighbouring BSs one base station is to be selected depending upon the distance and the channel occupancy. This approach distributes the traffic load almost uniformly over the entire region and overcomes the problem of localized congestion in an effective manner.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-20T05:48:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T00:35:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-20T05:48:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T00:35:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on Signal Processing, Communications and Networking, Chennai, India, 4-6 January 2008, 401-404</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1924-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICSCN.2008.4447227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/425</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>