<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14665</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:19:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic hazard and site-specific ground motion for typical ports of Gujarat</dc:title><dc:creator>SHUKLA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Probabilistic seismic hazard</dc:subject><dc:subject>Uniform hazard spectra</dc:subject><dc:subject>Site-specific ground motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ground response analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amplification factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Port sites</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPT blow count</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATERFRONT RETAINING WALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBABILISTIC ASSESSMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>EARTHQUAKE</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOILS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISPLACEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Economic importance of major ports is well known, and if ports are located in seismically active regions, then site-specific seismic hazard studies are essential to mitigate the seismic risk of the ports. Seismic design of port sites and related structures can be accomplished in three steps that include assessment of regional seismicity, geotechnical hazards, and soil structure interaction analysis. In the present study, site-specific probabilistic seismic hazard analysis is performed to identify the seismic hazard associated with four typical port sites of Gujarat state (bounded by 20 degrees-25.5 degrees N and 68 degrees-75 degrees E) of India viz. Kandla, Mundra, Hazira, and Dahej ports. The primary aim of the study is to develop consistent seismic ground motion for the structures within the four port sites for different three levels of ground shaking, i.e., operating level earthquake (72 years return period), contingency level earthquake (CLE) (475 year return period), and maximum considered earthquake (2,475 year return period). The geotechnical characterization for each port site is carried out using available geotechnical data. Shear wave velocities of the soil profile are estimated from SPT blow counts using various empirical formulae. Seismicity of the Gujarat region is modeled through delineating the 40 fault sources based on the seismotectonic setting. The Gujarat state is divided into three regions, i.e., Kachchh, Saurashtra, and Mainland Gujarat, and regional recurrence relations are assigned in the form of Gutenberg-Richter parameters in order to calculate seismic hazard associated with each port site. The horizontal component of ground acceleration for three levels of ground shaking is estimated by using different ground motion attenuation relations (GMAR) including one country-specific GMAR for Peninsular India. Uncertainty in seismic hazard computations is handled by using logic tree approach to develop uniform hazard spectra for 5% damping which are consistent with the specified three levels of ground shaking. Using recorded acceleration time history of Bhuj 2001 earthquake as the input time motion, synthetic time histories are generated to match the developed designed response spectra to study site-specific responses of port sites during different levels of ground shaking. It is observed that the Mundra and Kandla port sites are most vulnerable sites for seismic hazard as estimated CLE ground motion is in order of 0.79 and 0.48 g for Mundra and Kandla port sites, respectively. Hazira and Dahej port sites have comparatively less hazard with estimated CLE ground motion of 0.17 and 0.11 g, respectively. The ground amplification factor is observed at all sites which ranges from 1.3 to 2.0 for the frequency range of 1.0-2.7 Hz. The obtained spectral accelerations for the three levels of ground motions and obtained transfer functions for each port sites are compared with provisions made in Indian seismic code IS: 1893-Part 1 (2002). The outcome of present study is recommended for further performance-based design to evaluate the seismic response of the port structures with respect to various performance levels.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:19:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:19:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURAL HAZARDS, 60(2)541-565</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-011-0042-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14665</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>