<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1295</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Heuristic and optimal techniques for light-trail assignment in optical ring WDM networks</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALACHARLA, PAPARAO</dc:creator><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>network protocols</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical switches</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication traffic</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper we address the problem of constrained optimization (ILP formulation) and propose a set of heuristic algorithms for assigning light-trails [1−4,7,10] to WDM ring networks to facilitate IP centric dynamic communication at the optical layer. A light-trail is a generalization of a lightpath such that multiple nodes can take part in communication along the path without the need for optical switching. A light-trail represents an opportunistic medium in which multiple spatially distributed sub-lambda flows can be groomed despite without the need for optical switching. A light-trail is analogous to an optical bus such that multiple connections between source–destination pairs can be provisioned under the constraint that no two connections have overlapping time-intervals. This enables traffic grooming at the optical layer. In this paper we first describe a constrained optimization procedure for assigning light-trails in WDM ring networks. We then show five heuristic algorithms that solve the light-trail assignment problem in polynomial time. The heuristic algorithms are based on dynamic (unknown traffic) and static (known traffic) approaches. A simulation study compares the performance of ILP and heuristic algorithms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:33:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:53:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:33:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:53:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computer Communications 30(5), 990-998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0140-3664</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.comcom.2006.08.030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1295</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1295</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>