<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15203</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:53:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulation-optimization model for groundwater contamination remediation using meshfree point collocation method and particle swarm optimization</dc:title><dc:creator>MEENAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:subject>Groundwater contamination</dc:subject><dc:subject>remediation</dc:subject><dc:subject>pump and treat</dc:subject><dc:subject>meshfree method</dc:subject><dc:subject>point collocation method</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle swarm optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation-optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENETIC ALGORITHM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PUMPING RATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:description>Remediation of the groundwater contamination problem is a tedious, time consuming and expensive process. Pump and treat (PAT) is one of the commonly used techniques for groundwater remediation in which the contaminated groundwater is pumped, treated and put back to the aquifer system or other sources. Developing simulation-optimization (S/O) model proved to be very useful in the design process of an effective PAT system. Simulation models help in predicting the spatial and temporal variation of the contamination plume while optimization models help in minimizing the cost of pumping. Generally, grid or mesh based models such as Finite Difference Method (FDM) or Finite Element Methods (FEM) is used for the groundwater flow and transport simulation. But it is found that grid/mesh generation is a time consuming process. Therefore, recently Meshfree (MFree) based numerical models are developed to avoid this difficulty of meshing and remeshing. MFree Point Collocation Method (PCM) is a simple meshfree method used for the simulation of coupled groundwater flow and contaminant transport. For groundwater optimization problems, even though number of methods such as linear programming, nonlinear programming, etc. are available, evolutionary algorithm based techniques such as genetic algorithm (GA) and particle swarm optimization (PSO) are found to be very effective. In this paper, a simulation model using MFree PCM for confined groundwater flow and transport and a PSO based single objective optimization model are developed and coupled to get an effective S/O model for groundwater remediation using PAT. The S/O model based on PCM and PSO is applied for a polluted hypothetical confined aquifer and its performance is compared with Finite Element Method Binary Coded Genetic Algorithm (FEM GA) model. It is found that both the models are in good agreement with each other showing the applicability of the present approach. The PCM PSO based S/O model is simple and more effective in groundwater contamination remediation design using PAT.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:53:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:53:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SADHANA-ACADEMY PROCEEDINGS IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES, 37(3)351-369</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15203</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>