<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15088</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:20:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling and predicting the effects of submerged arc weldment process parameters on weldment characteristics and shape profiles</dc:title><dc:creator>NARANG, HK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAPATRA, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>JHA, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>Submerged arc welding</dc:subject><dc:subject>macrostructures</dc:subject><dc:subject>bead height</dc:subject><dc:subject>penetration depth</dc:subject><dc:subject>shape profile</dc:subject><dc:subject>factorial design</dc:subject><dc:subject>WELDING PROCESS PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FINITE-ELEMENT-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-AFFECTED ZONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEAD GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DILUTION</dc:subject><dc:description>The submerged arc weldment cross section shape profiles indicate the macrostructure zones' boundaries of both the base metal and weld that are affected by the weld thermal cycle. These macrostructure zones are broadly designated as the weld reinforcement, penetration and heat affected zones. The present investigation is aimed at predicting the shape profiles and characteristics of the submerged arc weldment zones based on statistical analysis. A full factorial design matrix was used for the submerged arc weldment butt-bead-on plate welds to study the effects of welding input variables. The outputs from the welding, such as the weld macrostructure characteristics, were mathematically modelled with respect to the input process variables. The interaction effects of the welding input process variables on the responses were also investigated. Based on the weldment characteristics, including that of the bead contact angle, a mapping technique was developed for the graphical representation of the macrostructure zones' shape profiles. The modelling approach adopted in the present investigation can be used to predict the fusion and heat affected zone shape profiles of submerged arc-based repair welds and claddings.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:20:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:20:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART B-JOURNAL OF ENGINEERING MANUFACTURE, 226(B7)1230-1240</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0954405412441561</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15088</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>