<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14854</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:02:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Bandwidth enhancement using gap-coupled hexagonal microstrip antennas in L band</dc:title><dc:creator>RASHMI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>hexagonal microstrip antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>gap coupling</dc:subject><dc:subject>bandwidth</dc:subject><dc:subject>off-axis coupling</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESONANCE FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EDGES</dc:subject><dc:description>New configurations, involving parasitic gap coupling of identical hexagonal microstrip antennas, are investigated to enhance the bandwidth. A better coupling between the driven and the parasitic patches is realized owing to the straight sides of the hexagonal microstrip antennas. The overall configuration exhibits an enhanced gain due to the increased aperture size. Different gap-coupled configurations, including a novel configuration of the off-axis gap coupling of three hexagonal microstrip antennas, are presented. For this novel configuration, measured bandwidth as large as 101.2 MHz at the center frequency of 1.884 GHz has been obtained, this is almost four times as compared to that of a single hexagonal patch. Both on-axis and off-axis gap coupling of three hexagonal microstrip antennas are explored and the off-axis configuration demonstrates a bandwidth enhancement of approximate to 1.35 times over that of the on-axis configuration. For all the configurations, measured and simulated bandwidths are in close agreement. (c) 2013 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:02:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:02:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROWAVE AND OPTICAL TECHNOLOGY LETTERS, 55(11)2703-2709</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/mop.27892</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14854</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>