<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16871</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:27:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Test and characterization of a prototype silicon-tungsten electromagnetic calorimeter</dc:title><dc:creator>MUHURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRATRE, VB</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUKHWANI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>JENA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAN, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAYAK, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAINI, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGARAJU, RN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Calorimeter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electromagnetic shower</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silicon pad detectors</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHOWER DEVELOPMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENIX EXPERIMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLE PHYSICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DETECTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIRECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLLIDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SI/W</dc:subject><dc:description>New generation high-energy physics experiments demand high precision tracking and accurate measurements of a large number of particles produced in the collisions of elementary particles and heavy-ions. Silicon-tungsten (Si-W) calorimeters provide the most viable technological option to meet the requirements of particle detection in high multiplicity environments. We report a novel Si-W calorimeter design, which is optimized for gamma/pi(0) discrimination up to high momenta. In order to test the Feasibility of the calorimeter, a prototype mini-tower was constructed using silicon pad detector arrays and tungsten layers. The performance of the mini-tower was tested using pion and electron beams at the CERN Proton Synchrotron (PS). The experimental results are compared with the results from a detailed GEANT-4 simulation. A linear relationship between the observed energy deposition and simulated response of the mini-Lower has been obtained, in line with our expectations. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:27:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:27:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION A-ACCELERATORS SPECTROMETERS DETECTORS AND ASSOCIATED EQUIPMENT, 76424-29</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-9002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-9576</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nima.2014.07.019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16871</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>