<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2197</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-20T07:25:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>PULRP: Path Unaware Layered Routing Protocol for underwater sensor networks</dc:title><dc:creator>GOPI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANNAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDER, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:description>We propose a Path Unaware Layered Routing Protocol (PULRP) for dense underwater 3D sensor networks. An up link transmission is considered, where a set of underwater sensor nodes report events to the sink node. PURLP algorithm consists of two phases. In the first phase (layering phase), a layering structure is presented which is a set of concentric spheres, around a sink node. The radius of the concentric spheres is chosen based on probability of successful packet forwarding as well as packet delivery latency. In the second phase (communication phase), we propose a method to choose the intermediate relay nodes and an on the fly routing algorithm for packet delivery from source node to sink node across the chosen relay nodes. The proposed algorithm, PULRP finds the routing path on the fly and hence it does not require any fixed routing table, localization or time synchronization processes. Our findings show that the proposed algorithm has a considerably better successful packet delivery rate compared to the Under Water Diffusion (UWD) algorithm proposed in [1] and Dijkstra's shortest path algorithm. In addition the delay involved in PULRP is comparable with that of UWD.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T13:48:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T13:48:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2008 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMMUNICATIONS, PROCEEDINGS, VOLS 1-13,3141-3145</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2074-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-3607</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICC.2008.591</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2197</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC 2008),Beijing, PEOPLES R CHINA,MAY 19-23, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>