<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14650</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:11:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Finite Element Modeling of Laser-Assisted Machining of AISI D2 Tool Steel</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>TELI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMANTA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Finite element analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laser</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laser-assisted machining</dc:subject><dc:subject>Machinability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Machining</dc:subject><dc:subject>INCONEL 718</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:description>Finite element analysis (FEA) is widely used in predicting machining-induced temperature profiles, forces, stresses, strains; however, its only drawback is high computational cost. This paper presents a finite element (FE) approach for predicting above mentioned machining induced state variables in laser-assisted machining (LAM) via a computationally efficient FE model of orthogonal and oblique LAM of AISI D2 tool steel. The commercial FE software DEFORM 3D (R) has been used in this study. The simulations of the laser-assisted orthogonal and longitudinal cutting have been performed and validated with the results reported in the literature. The model predicts the temperature distribution, flow stress reduction due to laser heating, and cutting forces. The prediction errors in cutting and thrust forces are less than 8%. In addition, parametric simulations have been carried out for cutting speed, cutting edge radius, and rake angle at different laser powers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS AND MANUFACTURING PROCESSES, 28(4)443-448</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10426914.2012.700160</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14650</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>