<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2700</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Adaptive coherency maintenance techniques for time-varying data</dc:title><dc:creator>MAJUMDAR, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOUDGALYA, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>dynamic data</dc:subject><dc:subject>temporal coherency</dc:subject><dc:subject>data dissemination</dc:subject><dc:subject>push</dc:subject><dc:subject>pull</dc:subject><dc:subject>control-theory</dc:subject><dc:description>Often, data used in on-line decision making (for example, in determining how to react to changes in process behavior traffic flow control, etc.) is dynamic in nature and hence the timeliness of the data delivered to the decision making process becomes very important. The delivered data must conform to certain time or value based application specific inconsistency, bounds. A system designed to disseminate dynamic data can exploit user-specified coherency requirements by fetching and disseminating only those changes that are of interest to users and ignoring intermediate changes. But, the design of mechanisms for such data delivery is challenging given that dynamic data changes rapidly and unpredictably, the latter making it very hard to use simple prediction techniques. In this paper we address these challenges. Specifically, we develop mechanisms to obtain timely and consistency-preserving updates for dynamic data by pulling data from the source at strategically chosen points in time. Motivated by the need for practical system design, but using formal analytical techniques, we offer a systematic approach based on control-theoretic principles. Our solution, is also unique from a control-theoretic perspective due to the presence of inherent non-linear system components and the dependence between the sampled time and sampled value. A proportional controller with dynamically changing tuning criteria is used in this work as a means of deciding when to next refresh data from the source. Using real-world traces of real-time data we show the superior performance of our feedback-driven control-theoretic approach by comparing with (i) a previously proposed adaptive refresh technique and (ii) a new pattern matching technique.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T20:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T20:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>RTSS 2003: 24TH IEEE INTERNATIONAL REAL-TIME SYSTEMS SYMPOSIUM, PROCEEDINGS,98-107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-2044-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16119</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2700</dc:identifier><dc:source>24th IEEE International Real-Time Systems Symposium (RTSS 2003),CANCUN, MEXICO,DEC 03-05, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>