<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4333</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-05T08:26:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Emission studies on photonic crystals fabricated using dyed polystyrene colloids</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIR, RV</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KURODA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAKODA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>inhibited spontaneous emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>opal</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:description>Three dimensionally ordered photonic crystals are fabricated with rhodamine B dyed polystyrene colloidal spheres using the inward growing self-assembling method in less than 3 h. This avoids the difficulties due to infiltration of active materials into passive photonic crystals. The superior optical quality of the photonic crystals fabricated using this method results in high reflectance values even at large angles of incidence. The study of emission characteristics on these functionalized photonic crystals shows a clear trend dependent on the angle of emission, wavelength, and the angle-resolved transmittance. The dip observed in the emission spectrum clearly matches the photonic stop band position at different angles of observation. The emission spectrum measured at different angles was found to follow a simple functional form related to the intrinsic emission of the dye and the stop band effect due to the photonic crystal environment. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T17:05:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T17:05:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 102(12), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.2825636</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4333</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>