<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12362</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Multi-level scheduling decisions in a class of FMS using simulation based metamodels</dc:title><dc:creator>SRIDHARAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BABU, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>flexible manufacturing system</dc:subject><dc:subject>meta-modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper pertains to a detailed simulation study conducted on a typical Flexible Manufacturing System (FMS). Initially, the configurations of the FMS under study have been established. Two types of FMSs have been evolved: one is failure free and the other is failure prone. For each of these cases, simulation models have been developed using SLAMSYSTEM. Orders arriving randomly at the FMS are subjected to three levels of scheduling decisions namely, launching of parts into the system, routing of parts through machines and sequencing of parts on AGVs at a central buffer. The simulation results have been used to develop metamodels for the two types of FMSs. These metamodels have been subjected to statistical analysis to ascertain their adequacy to represent the simulation models. These metamodels have been found to be useful for simulating the FMSs under study so as to evaluate various multi-level scheduling decisions in the FMS.</dc:description><dc:publisher>STOCKTON PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T15:05:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T15:05:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE OPERATIONAL RESEARCH SOCIETY, 49(6), 591-602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0160-5682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/sj.jors.2600534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12362</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12362</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>