<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10645</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Corrosion of 2205 duplex stainless steel in chloride medium containing sulfate-reducing bacteria</dc:title><dc:creator>ANTONY, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHONGDAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>microbiologically influenced corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>passivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>duplex stainless steels</dc:subject><dc:subject>sulfate-reducing bacteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>polarization</dc:subject><dc:subject>crevice corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>passive film</dc:subject><dc:description>Sulfate-reducing bacteria (SRB) play significant role in the corrosion of stainless steels exposed to marine and soil environment. Sulfate reduction by bacterial species results in the production of H2S, which can significantly influence the anodic and cathodic processes and ultimately enhances the corrosion of materials. In the present study, 2205 type duplex stainless steel (DSS) coupons in solution-annealed condition were exposed to chloride medium containing SRB species, Desulfovibrio desulfuricans, for 40 days and examined by microscopy. Etching of the duplex structure, pitting as well as crevice attack were noticed. Similar results were obtained by microscopic studies with coupons exposed for 14 days in medium containing SRB followed by anodic polarization. SEM studies, of crevices observed after anodic polarization, indicated that the attack was initiated at the grain boundaries and slowly encroached into austenite grains. The initiation of attack was also evident from AFM studies of coupon exposed under freely corroding conditions for 7 days. ESCA studies reveal that under anaerobic conditions of SRB growth sulfidation of passive film occurs. The modified passive film found to depolarize the cathodic reactions. The nature and mechanism of SRB attack on DSS and possibility of detection at early stages were discussed. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T21:16:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T21:16:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ELECTROCHIMICA ACTA, 52(12), 3985-3994</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-4686</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2006.11.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10645</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10645</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>