<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17468</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:13:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stability analysis of thick piezoelectric metal based FGM plate using first order and higher order shear deformation theory</dc:title><dc:creator>JADHAV, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJORIA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>VIBRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Functionally graded material</dc:subject><dc:subject>First order shear deformation theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Higher order shear deformation theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electro-mechanical loading</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the stability analysis of functionally graded plate integrated with piezoelectric actuator and sensor at the top and bottom face, subjected to electrical and mechanical loading. The finite element formulation is based on first order and higher order shear deformation theory, degenerated shell element, von-Karman hypothesis and piezoelectric effect. The equation for static analysis is derived by using the minimum energy principle and solutions for critical buckling load is obtained by solving eigenvalue problem. The material properties of the functionally graded plate are assumed to be graded along the thickness direction according to simple power law function. Two types of boundary conditions are used, such as SSSS (simply supported) and CSCS (simply supported along two opposite side perpendicular to the direction of compression and clamped along the other two sides). Sensor voltage is calculated using present analysis for various power law indices and FG (functionally graded) material gradations. The stability analysis of piezoelectric FG plate is carried out to present the effects of power law index, material variations, applied mechanical pressure and piezo effect on buckling and stability characteristics of FG plate.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:13:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:13:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MECHANICS AND MATERIALS IN DESIGN, 11(4)387-403</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1569-1713</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-8841</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10999-014-9283-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17468</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>