<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18250</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:27:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of Precipitation Retrievals From Orbital Data Products of TRMM Over a Subtropical Basin in India</dc:title><dc:creator>INDU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>RAINFALL MEASURING MISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MULTICHANNEL MICROWAVE IMAGERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SATELLITE-BASED RAINFALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROFILING ALGORITHM</dc:subject><dc:subject>BRIGHTNESS TEMPERATURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHYSICAL RETRIEVALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MONSOON REGION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANALYSIS TMPA</dc:subject><dc:subject>RADAR DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAUGE DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Asian Precipitation Highly Resolved Observational Data Integration Toward Evaluation of the Water Resources (APHRODITE)</dc:subject><dc:subject>basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>orbital</dc:subject><dc:subject>precipitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tropical Rainfall Measuring Mission (TRMM)</dc:subject><dc:subject>uncertainty</dc:subject><dc:description>The spatial error structure of daily precipitation derived from the latest version 7 (v7) tropical rainfall measuring mission (TRMM) level 2 data products are studied through comparison with the Asian precipitation highly resolved observational data integration toward evaluation of the water resources (APHRODITE) data over a subtropical region of the Indian subcontinent for the seasonal rainfall over 6 years from June 2002 to September 2007. The data products examined include v7 data from the TRMM radiometer Microwave Imager (TMI) and radar precipitation radar (PR), namely, 2A12, 2A25, and 2B31 (combined data from PR and TMI). The spatial distribution of uncertainty from these data products were quantified based on performance metrics derived from the contingency table. For the seasonal daily precipitation over a subtropical basin in India, the data product of 2A12 showed greater skill in detecting and quantifying the volume of rainfall when compared with the 2A25 and 2B31 data products. Error characterization using various error models revealed that random errors from multiplicative error models were homoscedastic and that they better represented rainfall estimates from 2A12 algorithm. Error decomposition techniques performed to disentangle systematic and random errors verify that the multiplicative error model representing rainfall from 2A12 algorithm successfully estimated a greater percentage of systematic error than 2A25 or 2B31 algorithms. Results verify that although the radiometer derived 2A12 rainfall data is known to suffer from many sources of uncertainties, spatial analysis over the case study region of India testifies that the 2A12 rainfall estimates are in a very good agreement with the reference estimates for the data period considered.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:27:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:27:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING, 53(12)6429-6442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-2892</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-0644</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TGRS.2015.2440338</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18250</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>