<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18397</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:53:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Origin of the Mile Tilek Tuff, South Andaman: evidence from Ar-40-Ar-39 chronology and geochemistry</dc:title><dc:creator>AWASTHI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, JS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDE, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>BARREN ISLAND VOLCANO</dc:subject><dc:subject>JAVA SUBDUCTION COMPLEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDIAN-OCEAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRACE-ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIO-PLIOCENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISOTOPE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEA</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARC</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ar-40-Ar-39 dating</dc:subject><dc:subject>geochemical fingerprinting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mile Tilek Tuff</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sumatra</dc:subject><dc:description>The Mile Tilek Tuff is one of several consolidated volcanic ash deposits in the Andaman and Nicobar Islands that has preserved evidence of a large-scale volcanic eruption in Southeast Asia. Assumed to be of Mio-Pliocene age (similar to 25-2 Ma), the tuff was thought to have been generated by the Andaman-Indonesia volcanic arc. Little was known about its source volcano because of absence of critical isotope data. To provide accurate age information and determine its source, we dated the tuff by Ar-40-Ar-39 method and measured its trace element contents and Sr-Nd isotopic ratios. The Ar-40-Ar-39 plateau age for the whole rock is 0.73 +/- 0.16 (2 sigma) Ma, which suggests that the tuff got deposited much later than previously believed. Chemically, the tuff possesses typical characteristics of subduction zone magmatism. Its Sr-Nd isotopic compositions (Sr-87/Sr-86 = 0.7073 and epsilon(Nd) &lt;= 0.9) suggest substantial continental crustal contamination of its source magma, which points to a source volcano in Sumatra. Based on available age information on large-scale volcanic eruptions in Indonesia, we speculate that the Ranau volcano in south Sumatra could have been the source of the Mile Tilek Tuff.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:53:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:53:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 108(2)205-210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18397</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>