<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18404</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:57:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Physico-chemical characteristics of Jharkhand and West Bengal thermal springs along SONATA mega lineament, India</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, HK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHARAM, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASELLI, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRUPTI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>LASHIN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>AL ARIFI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>EASTERN-INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMICAL-COMPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUILIBRIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAKRESWAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISCHARGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DILUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hazaribagh thermal spring</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bakreswar and Tantloi thermal spring</dc:subject><dc:subject>geochemistry of thermal water</dc:subject><dc:description>The chemical and isotopic compositions of thermal springs located along the Son-Narmada-Tapti (SONATA) mega lineament in central India have been investigated. The issuing temperatures of the thermal waters vary from 31 degrees to 89 degrees C for the thermal springs and 24 degrees to 25 degrees C for the cold springs. These thermal springs are located on the Archean Chotanagpur Gneissic Complex (CGC) in the eastern part of peninsular India. The thermal springs are mostly alkaline in nature with pH varying from 7.5 to 9.5. Piper diagram suggests that the chemistry of the thermal waters is compatible with the granitic host rocks through which the waters circulate. Mineral saturation index suggests that the thermal waters are saturated with cristobalite and quartz at lower temperatures (less than similar to 130 degrees to 150 degrees C), and calcite and forsterite at higher temperatures (similar to 160 degrees to 250 degrees C). The estimated reservoir temperature based on chemical geothermometers is in the range of 132 degrees-265 degrees C, which favours a medium enthalpy geothermal system. Oxygen isotope fractionation of Bakreswar and Tantloi thermal springs highlights a higher reservoir temperature than estimated by chemical geothermometer. Positive gravity anomalies over Bakreswar and Tantloi areas strongly suggest a basement/mantle upliftment or mafic intrusion which could account for the heat source close to the surface. However, the large negative gravity anomaly depression around the Surajkund and Katkamsandi thermal springs indicates presence of deep seated faults.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:57:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:57:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 124(2)419-430</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-774X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18404</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>