<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8235</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-13T06:41:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analytical Description of the Load-Loss Asymmetry Phenomenon in Three-Phase Three-Limb Transformers</dc:title><dc:creator>ESCARELA-PEREZ, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALVAREZ-RAMIREZ, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAUSHIK, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>cuts</dc:subject><dc:subject>asymmetry phenomenon</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite-element models (fems)</dc:subject><dc:subject>network models</dc:subject><dc:subject>short-circuit impedances</dc:subject><dc:description>The asymmetry phenomenon observed during the load-loss test of three-phase transformers is rigorously analyzed. The transformer is represented as a three-port impedance network despite its six-port network nature, making any formal study more tractable. The analytical restrictions required for such a representation are derived. As a result, it is possible to mathematically prove (and understand) the asymmetrical behavior of a three-phase transformer subjected to the load-loss test. Only two circuit-field simulations or tests (single-phase load-loss tests) are required to obtain the impedance system of the six-winding transformer. A 3-D finite-element (FE) model of a transformer is used here to obtain its short-circuit impedances, exemplifying the use and extent of the analytical results. The eddy currents generated at the transformer tank and frame are properly taken into consideration. The short-circuit impedance model is validated with the 3-D FE model and with a six-port network approach that has been previously verified.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T20:57:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T20:57:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER DELIVERY, 24(2), 695-702</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8977</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPWRD.2008.923988</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8235</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8235</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>