<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14590</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:39:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Convective Heat Transfer Characterization of Aviation Turbine Fuel-Metal Oxide Nanofluids</dc:title><dc:creator>SONAWANE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANDARKAR, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANIK, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>EFFECTIVE THERMAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS SUSPENSIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BROWNIAN-MOTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENHANCEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPENDENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COOLANT</dc:subject><dc:description>A thorough experimental investigation of the thermophysical properties (thermal conductivity, viscosity, and specific heat), heat transfer performance, and pressure drop characteristics of aviation turbine fuel (ATF)-based Al2O3, TiO2, and CuO nanofluids was carried out for potential regenerative cooling application in semicryogenic rocket engines. The effects of volume concentration, size, and material of suspended particles, as well as the effect of the temperature of the nanofluid, were investigated. Although an enhanced thermal conductivity led to an increased heat transfer coefficient, the Prandtl number was seen to ha l e a bigger influence on the heat transfer characteristics. In particular, the correlation developed for the Nusselt number showed a much higher influence of the Prandfl number than for single-phase fluids. As a result, the ATF-CuO nanofluid performed the best amongst the three metal oxide nanofluids at a given particle size, concentration, and temperature. The enhancement is seen to improve with temperature, demonstrating the suitability of such a nanofluid at the conditions encountered during the regenerative cooling of the rocket engines (similar to 150 degrees C).</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUTICS  ASTRONAUTICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:39:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:39:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THERMOPHYSICS AND HEAT TRANSFER, 26(4)619-628</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/1.T3893</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14590</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>