<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10100</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>3-DIMENSIONAL FINITE-ELEMENT MODELING OF GAS METAL-ARC WELDING</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, SC</dc:creator><dc:subject>heat-transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluid-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>gma</dc:subject><dc:subject>pools</dc:subject><dc:description>The modeling of the gas metal-arc (GMA) welding process in three dimensions for moving heat sources has been attempted using the finite element method. The occurrence of finger penetration in the weldment resulting from a streaming type of metal transfer at high contents is explained by assuming that the heat content of transferring droplets is distributed in a certain volume of the workpiece below the arc. Volumetric distribution of the heat content of transferring droplets has been considered as an internal heat-generation term, and the differences between penetration characteristics in two cases of globular and streaming conditions of metal transfer have been analyzed. It is shown that weld penetration depends on the depth at which the droplets distribute their energy inside the workpieces. Temperature dependence of thermo-physical properties, i.e.. thermal conductivity and specific heat, has been included. Latent heat is incorporated by a direct iteration method. Heat losses from the plate caused by convection and radiation are also considered. The model is validated by predicting the weld-bead dimensions and comparing them with experimental data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MINERALS METALS MATERIALS SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T18:23:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T18:23:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS B-PROCESS METALLURGY AND MATERIALS PROCESSING SCIENCE, 25(3), 435-441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02663394</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10100</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>