<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5190</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Contrasting responses of Rb-Sr systematics to regional and contact metamorphism, Laramie Mountains, Wyoming, USA</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>FROST, CD</dc:creator><dc:creator>FROST, BR</dc:creator><dc:subject>anorthosite complex</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear zones</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxygen-isotope</dc:subject><dc:subject>sphene growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>morton pass</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>strontium</dc:subject><dc:subject>geochronology</dc:subject><dc:subject>province</dc:subject><dc:subject>range</dc:subject><dc:subject>contact metamorphism</dc:subject><dc:subject>laramie mountains</dc:subject><dc:subject>rb-sr and sm-nd isotopes</dc:subject><dc:subject>regional metamorphism</dc:subject><dc:description>Archean supracrustal sequences of pelitic, quartzitic, calcareous and mafic compositions in the central Laramie Mountains, Wyoming, have been affected by two metamorphic events: a 1.78 Ga amphibolite-grade regional metamorphism, and a 1.43 Ga contact metamorphism resulting from the intrusion of the Laramie Anorthosite Complex (LAC). Rb-Sr whole-rock isotopic data from both outside and within the LAC contact aureole define a linear array that lies along a 1.78 Ga isochron. This date has been independently established as the time of amphibolite facies regional metamorphism associated with collision of the Archean Wyoming province and the Proterozoic Colorado province along the Cheyenne belt. The Rb-Sr isotopic data require that Sr was redistributed during regional metamorphism on a scale of at least tens of metres. Although within the 2 km-wide aureole of LAC the pelitic rocks were thermally metamorphosed at temperatures greater than 800 degrees C, none of the whole-rock Rb-Sr data from samples within the LAC aureole show evidence of resetting at 1.43 Ga. It is interpreted that the regional metamorphism involved fluid transport which facilitated Sr isotopic resetting, whereas the contact metamorphism occurred in a relatively dry environment in which isotopic mobility was restricted to centimetre-scale or less. Rb-Sr data for biotite, feldspar and whole rock from a regional metamorphosed pelitic schist give an isochron age of 1450 +/- 40 Ma, which is interpreted as a cooling age resulting from crustal uplift. Rb-Sr data for biotite, quartz + feldspar and whole rock from a pelitic schist affected by contact metamorphism give an isochron age of 1420 +/- 43 Ma, the time of isotopic re-equilibration in response either to crustal uplift or to both contact metamorphism and crustal uplift. This study demonstrates that although the response of isotopic systems to metamorphism is complex, isotopic data provide insight into metamorphic processes that is difficult to obtain by other means.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BLACKWELL SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T05:48:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T05:48:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF METAMORPHIC GEOLOGY, 17(3), 259-269</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-4929</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5190</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>