<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12413</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>MODEL TESTING OF SINGLE- AND THREE-STAGE MODIFIED SAVONIUS ROTORS AND VIABILITY STUDY OF MODIFIED SAVONIUS PUMP ROTOR SYSTEMS</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAMOJI, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEDARE, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>modified savonius rotors</dc:subject><dc:subject>model testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>coefficient of power</dc:subject><dc:subject>reynolds number</dc:subject><dc:subject>rayleigh number</dc:subject><dc:subject>roto-dynamic pumps</dc:subject><dc:subject>piston pumps</dc:subject><dc:subject>discharge</dc:subject><dc:description>The suitability of modified Savonius wind rotors for water-pumping application is studied with a mathematical model developed for estimating the discharge over a period of time. Single- and three-stage modified Savonius rotors, which are extensively tested in an open jet wind tunnel, are chosen. The best geometrical configuration for a single-stage rotor has shown a maximum coefficient of power of 19% at a Reynolds number of 120000, which increases with the increase in the Reynolds number. The coefficient of power at a higher Reynolds number experienced in the field trials is estimated by extrapolating the results at a lower Reynolds number. The discharge for these modified Savonius rotors is estimated from the mathematical models developed for roto-dynamic and piston pumps at design wind velocities of 6 and 8.5 m/sec. The estimated discharges for a single-stage rotor of 3 m diameter at design wind velocities of 6 and 8.5 m/sec are 5000 and 6000 m(3)/month for roto-dynamic pumps. The estimated discharge is substantially higher for roto-dynamic pumps than for piston pumps.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T17:55:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T17:55:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF GREEN ENERGY, 6(1), 22-41</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1543-5075</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15435070802701744</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12413</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12413</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>