<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7082</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>THE NEW CLASS OF SUPERCONDUCTING QUATERNARY R-T-B-C SYSTEMS (R=RARE EARTH, T=NI, PD)</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGARAJAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GODART, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAZUMDAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSAIN, Z</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEVYCLEMENT, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PADALIA, BD</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYARAGHAVAN, R</dc:creator><dc:description>Our discovery of superconductivity (SC) at an elevated temperature (similar to 12K) in the system Y-Ni-B-C [1-4] has opened up an entirely new area of research in superconductivity in intermetallics. Our specific heat measurements show that YNi2B2C is strongly-coupled superconductor. SC and magnetism coexist, below 7K, in ErNi2B2C. From mu-SR studies, carried out on LuNi2B2C and TmNi2B2C, Ni-atoms are inferred to carry local moment. Substituents such as Th and Gd (at the Y-sites) and Fe and Co (at the Ni-sites) depress Te of YNi2B2C. Superconductivity is quenched in Y0.9U0.1Ni2B2C. In multiphase Y-Pd-B-C system (obtained by replacing Ni by Pd), we observe two SC-transitions, T-c similar to 22K and 10K. LuPd4BC0.2 has a minority SC-phase with T-c similar to 10 K. Microwave absorption has been used to study the temperature dependence of the lower critical field, H-c1, in YPd5B3C0.35. ThNi2B2C, a multiphase material, exhibits SC at similar to 5K whereas two SC transitions are observed in ThPd2B2C (T-c similar to 20K and 14K) and in ThPd4BC. No SC is observed in U-based Ni- and Pd-borocarbides and in YT2B2C (T = Co, Rh, Ir and Os) down to 4.2K.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T02:19:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T02:19:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICA C, 235(), 150-153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-4534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0921-4534(94)91335-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7082</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7082</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>