<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17578</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:09:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Control of MarRAB Operon in Escherichia coil via Autoactivation and Autorepression</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAJAPAT, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAINI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>MULTIPLE-ANTIBIOTIC-RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSCRIPTIONAL REGULATORY NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COUPLED CHEMICAL-REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POSITIVE-FEEDBACK</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLULAR HETEROGENEITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MARA/SOXS/ROB REGULON</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENE-EXPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESS GENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFLUX PUMP</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLI K-12</dc:subject><dc:description>Choice of network topology for gene regulation has been a question of interest for a long time. How do simple and more complex topologies arise? In this work, we analyze the topology of the marRAB operon in Escherichia coil, which is associated with control of expression of genes associated with conferring resistance to low-level antibiotics to the bacterium. Among the 2102 promoters in E. co/i, the marRAB promoter is the only one that encodes for an autoactivator and an autorepressor. What advantages does this topology confer to the bacterium? In this work, we demonstrate that, compared to control by a single regulator, the marRAB regulatory arrangement has the least control cost associated with modulating gene expression in response to environmental stimuli. In addition, the presence of dual regulators allows the regulon to exhibit a diverse range of dynamics, a feature that is not observed in genes controlled by a single regulator.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CELL PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:09:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:09:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOPHYSICAL JOURNAL, 109(7)1497-1508</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-3495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1542-0086</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bpj.2015.08.017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17578</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>