<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17855</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T05:48:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Computation of feedback control for time optimal state transfer using Groebner basis</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>MULLA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>PILLAI, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>CONSTRAINED LINEAR-SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Time optimal control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Feedback</dc:subject><dc:subject>Groebner basis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Limit cycle</dc:subject><dc:description>Computation of time optimal feedback control law for a controllable linear time invariant system with bounded inputs is considered. Unlike a recent paper by the authors, the target final state is not limited to the origin of state-space, but is allowed to be in the set of constrained controllable states. Switching surfaces are formulated as semi-algebraic sets using Groebner basis based elimination theory. Using these semi-algebraic sets, a nested switching logic is synthesized to generate the time optimal feedback control. However, the optimal control law enforces an unavoidable limit cycle in the time-optimal trajectory for most non-origin target points. The time-period of this limit-cycle is dependent on the target position. This dependence is algebraically characterized and a method to compute the time-period of the limit-cycle is provided. As a natural extension, the set of constrained controllable states is also computed. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:48:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:48:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SYSTEMS &amp; CONTROL LETTERS, 79,1-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-6911</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-7956</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sysconle.2015.02.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17855</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>