<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1375</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optoelectronic and nonlinear optical processes in low dimensional semiconductors</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>nanocomposite thin-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>cds-zno</dc:subject><dc:subject>optoelectronic process</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear optical process</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor</dc:subject><dc:description>Spatial confinement of quantum excitations on their characteristic wavelength scale in low dimensional materials offers unique possibilities to engineer the electronic structure and thereby control their physical properties by way of simple manipulation of geometrical parameters. This has led to an overwhelming interest in quasi-zero dimensional semiconductors or quantum dots as tunable materials for multitude of exciting applications in optoelectronic and nonlinear optical devices and quantum information processing. Large nonlinear optical response and high luminescence quantum yield expected in these systems is a consequence of huge enhancement of transition probabilities ensuing from quantum confinement. High quantum efficiency of photoluminescence, however, is not usually realized in the case of bare semiconductor nanoparticles owing to the presence of surface states. In this talk, I will focus on the role of quantum confinement and surface states in ascertaining nonlinear optical and optoelectronic properties of II-VI semiconductor quantum dots and their nanocomposites. I will also discuss the influence of nonlinear optical processes on their optoelectronic characteristics.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T01:28:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T01:28:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF MATERIALS SCIENCE,29(6)559-565</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-4707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12034-006-0004-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1375</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st Indo-Singapore Symposium on Advanced Functional Materials,Bombay, INDIA,FEB 24-26, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>