<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15378</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:49:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structure, magneto-structural transitions and magnetocaloric properties in Ni50-xMn37+xIn13 melt spun ribbons</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, DMR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, NVR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, DVS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVAS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUTHU, SE</dc:creator><dc:creator>ARUMUGAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Martensite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inverse magnetocaloric effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC ENTROPY CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MARTENSITIC TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEUSLER ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Melt spun Ni50-xMn37+xIn13 (2 &lt;= x &lt;= 5) ribbons were investigated for the structure, microstructure, magneto-structural transitions and inverse magnetocaloric effect (IMCE) associated with the first-order martensitic phase transition. The influence of excess Mn in Ni site (or Ni/Mn content) on the martensite transition and the associated magnetic and magnetocaloric properties are discussed. It was found that with the increase in Mn content, the martensitic transition shifted from 325 to 240 K as x is varied from 2 to 4, and the austenite phase was stabilized at room temperature. The x=5 ribbon did not show the martensitic transition. For the x=3 ribbon, the structural and magnetic transitions are close together unlike in the x=4 ribbon in which they are far (similar to 60 K) apart. The zero field cooled and field cooled curves support the presence of exchange bias blocking temperature due to antiferromagnetic interactions in the ribbons. A large change in the magnetization between the martensite and austenite phases was observed for a small variation in the Ni/Mn content, which resulted in large IMCE. A large positive magnetic entropy change (Delta S-M) of 32 J/kg K at room temperature (similar to 300 K) for a field change of 5 T with a net refrigeration capacity of 64 J/kg was obtained in the Ni47Mn40In13 ribbon. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS, 324(1)26-32</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmmm.2011.07.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15378</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>