<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1303</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Behavior of CFRPC strengthened reinforced concrete beams with varying degrees of strengthening</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMANA, VPV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, TARUN</dc:creator><dc:creator>MORTON, SE</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, ABHIJIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>bending (deformation)</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>concrete reinforcements</dc:subject><dc:subject>failure analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper summarizes the results of experimental and analytical studies on the flexural strengthening of reinforced concrete beams by the external bonding of high-strength, light-weight carbon fiber reinforced polymer composite (CFRPC) laminates to the tension face of the beam. Four sets of beams, three with different amounts of CFRPC reinforcement by changing the width of CFRPC laminate, and one without CFRPC were tested in four-point bending over a span of 900 mm. The tests were carried out under displacement control. At least one beam in a set was extensively instrumented to monitor strains and deflections over the entire range of loading till the failure of the beam. The increase in strength and stiffness provided by the bonded laminate was assessed by varying the width of laminate. The results indicate that the flexural strength of beams was significantly increased as the width of laminate increased. Theoretical analysis using a computer program based on strain compatibility is presented to predict the ultimate strength and moment–deflection behavior of the beams. The comparison of the experimental results with theoretical values is also presented, along with an investigation of the beam failure modes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:36:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:57:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:36:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:57:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Composites Part B: Engineering 31(6-7), 461-470</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1359-8368</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S1359-8368(00)00022-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1303</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>