<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1543</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>A practical fast parallel routing architecture for Clos networks</dc:title><dc:creator>ZHENG, SQ</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>LU, ENYUE</dc:creator><dc:subject>multistage interconnection networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>parallel algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>pipeline processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication network routing</dc:subject><dc:description>Clos networks are an important class of switching networks due to their modular structure and much lower cost compared with crossbars. For routing I/O permutations of Clos networks, sequential routing algorithms are too slow, and all known parallel algorithms are not practical. We present the algorithm-hardware codesign of a unified fast parallel routing architecture called distributed pipeline routing (DPR) architecture for rearrangeable nonblocking and strictly non-blocking Clos networks. The DPR architecture uses a linear interconnection structure and processing elements that performs only shift and logic AND operations. We show that a DPR architecture can route any permutation in rearrangeable nonblocking and strictly nonblocking Clos networks in O(√N) time. The same architecture can be used to carry out control of any group of connection/disconnection requests for strictly nonblocking Clos networks in O(√N) time. Several speeding-up techniques are also presented. This architecture is applicable to packet and circuit switches of practical sizes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-20T06:37:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:25:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-20T06:37:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:25:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the ACM / IEEE symposium on Architecture for networking and communications systems, San Jose, California, USA, 3-5 December 2006, 21-30</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-59593-580-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1543</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1543</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>