<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17291</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:18:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Boundary induced phase transition with stochastic entrance and exit</dc:title><dc:creator>MITRA, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>phase diagrams (theory)</dc:subject><dc:subject>driven diffusive systems (theory)</dc:subject><dc:subject>stochastic particle dynamics (theory)</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASYMMETRIC EXCLUSION MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR MOTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPARTMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUILIBRIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHYSICS</dc:subject><dc:description>We study an open-chain totally asymmetric exclusion process (TASEP) with stochastic gates present at the two boundaries. The gating dynamics has been modeled with the physical system of ion-channel gating in mind. These gates can randomly switch between an open state and a closed state. In the open state, the gates are highly permeable such that any particle arriving at the gate immediately passes through. In the closed state, a particle becomes trapped at the gate and cannot pass through until the gate switches open again. We calculate the phase-diagram of the system and find important and non-trivial differences with the phase-diagram of a regular open-chain TASEP. In particular, depending on the switching rates of the two gates, the system may or may not admit a maximal current phase. Our analytic calculations within mean-field theory capture the main qualitative features of our Monte Carlo simulation results. We also perform a refined mean-field calculation where the correlations at the boundaries are taken into account. This theory shows significantly better quantitative agreement with our simulation results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:18:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:18:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF STATISTICAL MECHANICS-THEORY AND EXPERIMENT,</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-5468</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1742-5468/2014/10/P10019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17291</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>