<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7500</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of the structure and corrosion behavior of PEO coatings on AM50 maginesium. alloy by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy</dc:title><dc:creator>GHASEMI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BLAWERT, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>DIETZEL, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAINER, KU</dc:creator><dc:subject>am60 magnesium alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>anodic films</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical breakdown</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnesium</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrolyte</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasma electrolytic oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>coating</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrosion</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work coatings were developed on the surface of AM50 magnesium alloy using four different electrolytes containing 10 wt.% each of K3PO4 and Na3PO4 in combination with either potassium or sodium hydroxides. Electrolyte conductivity and breakdown voltage were measured in order to correlate the property of the coating to the nature of electrolyte. Further, the coatings were examined using scanning electron microscopy for surface morphology and cross sectional investigation, X-ray diffraction for phase determination, and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy for corrosion resistance evaluation. The effect of employing different ions in the electrolytes results in different surface morphologies, chemical phases and, consequently, the corrosion resistance of the coatings. The EIS results indicate the presence of porous and compact layers in the structure of the PEO coatings, whilst the overall coating resistance mainly results from the compact layer, the role of the porous layer as a barrier against corrosion is negligible. Finally, a correlation between the passive current density of the bare alloy and the corrosion resistance of the PEO coating is proposed. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-28T21:23:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-28T21:23:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SURFACE &amp; COATINGS TECHNOLOGY, 202(15), 3513-3518</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0257-8972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2007.12.033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7500</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7500</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>