<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3745</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization of covalent linkages in organically functionalized MCM-41 mesoporous materials by solid-state NMR and theoretical calculations</dc:title><dc:creator>WIENCH, JW</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVADHUT, YS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRUSKI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANAPATHY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>silica nanosphere</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular-sieves</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-shifts</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>catalysts</dc:subject><dc:subject>si-29</dc:subject><dc:subject>condensation</dc:subject><dc:subject>recognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:description>The covalent linkages formed during functionalization of MCM-41 mesoporous molecular sieves with five chloroalkylsilanes ((EtO)(3)Si(CH2Cl), (MeO)(3)Si(CH2CH2CH2Cl), Cl3Si(CH2CH2CH3), Cl2Si(CH3)(CH2Cl) and Cl2Si(CH3)(2)) have been investigated using high-resolution solid-state NMR spectroscopy and DFT calculations. Structural information was obtained from H-1-C-13 and H-1-Si-29 heteronuclear (HETCOR) NMR spectra, in which high resolution in the H-1 dimension was obtained by using fast MAS. The H-1-C-13 HETCOR results provided the assignments of H-1 and C-13 resonances associated with the surface functional groups. Sensitivity-enhanced H-1-Si-29 HETCOR spectra, acquired using Carr-Purcell-Meiboom-Gill refocusing during data acquisition, revealed the identity of Si-29 sites (Q(n), T-n, and D-n) and the location of functional groups relative to these sites. Optimal geometries of local environments representing the Q(n), T-n and D-n resonances were calculated using molecular mechanics and ab initio methods. Subsequently, DFT calculations of Si-29, C-13, and H-1 chemical shifts were performed using Gaussian 03 at the B3LYP/6-311++G(2d,2p) level. The theoretical calculations are in excellent accord with the experimental chemical shifts. This work illustrates that state-of-the-art spectroscopic and theoretical tools can be used jointly to refine the complex structures of inorganic-organic hybrid materials.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T18:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T18:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY B, 111(15), 3877-3885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-6106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp067417x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3745</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3745</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>