<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1515</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>A comparative dielectric relaxation study of PMN-PT and PMN-PZ ceramics using impedance spectroscopy</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDIT, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATRO, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>WADHAWAN, VK</dc:creator><dc:subject>morphotropic phase-boundary</dc:subject><dc:subject>pb(mg1/3nb2/3)o-3-pbtio3 ceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>relaxor</dc:subject><dc:subject>ferroelectricity</dc:subject><dc:subject>polarization</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>ferroelectrics</dc:subject><dc:subject>relaxors</dc:subject><dc:subject>polarisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>impedance</dc:subject><dc:subject>permittivity</dc:subject><dc:description>AC-impedance spectroscopic studies in the temperature range of 30-400 degrees C are carried out on solid solutions of lead magnesium niobate (PMN) with lead titanate (PT) and lead zirconate (PZ), both of them in the 65/35 atomic ratio. For PMN-PT this corresponds to the morphotropic phase boundary composition (with normal ferroelectric behaviour), and for PMN-PZ it is near the phase boundary between normal ferroelectric and relaxor ferroelectric compositions. The variation of dielectric permittivity with temperature at different frequencies shows normal ferroelectric and relaxor-like dependence for PMN-PT and PMN-PZ, respectively. Temperature-dependent spectroscopic modulus plots reveal a much broader peak for PMN-PZ compared to that for PMN-PT, which is consistent with the dielectric behaviour. PMN-PT shows nearly ideal Debye behaviour below T-m (the temperature of the permittivity maximum) and the behaviour departs from ideality above T-m, whereas non-ideal Debye behaviour is seen both below and above T-m for PMN-PZ. Complex modulus plots fit well with two depressed semicircles and three depressed semicircles, respectively, for PMN-PT and PMN-PZ. The relaxation observed in the spectroscopic plots around 1 MHz for PMN-PT has been assigned to polarisation relaxation expected for normal-sized domains. No such relaxation could be observed for PMN-PZ around I MHz because of the mesoscopic domain sizes. (c) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T15:25:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T15:25:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING B-SOLID STATE MATERIALS FOR ADVANCED TECHNOLOGY,120,194-198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2005.02.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14929</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1515</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th International Symposium on Ferroic Domains (ISFD-8),Tsukuba, JAPAN,AUG 24-27, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>