<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14085</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:02:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Attention, polychronicity, and expertise in prospective memory performance: Programmers' vulnerability to habit intrusion error in multitasking</dc:title><dc:creator>SANJRAM, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAN, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>EXECUTIVE CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>RETRIEVAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTENTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPERIENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SITUATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>KNOWLEDGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRATEGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>NOVICE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Atypical action</dc:subject><dc:subject>HCI</dc:subject><dc:subject>Habit intrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>ProM error</dc:subject><dc:subject>Programmer multitasking</dc:subject><dc:description>The paper examines prospective memory (ProM) in programmer multitasking and reports administration of a naturalistic atypical action. The study emphasizes on how attention, time orientation, and expertise affect ProM performance in multitasking among a group of computer science and engineering students (N = 108). The results suggest that attention play a crucial role in multitasking and ProM performance with respect to whether or not a word display requires more attention to be devoted in monitoring and identifying it for an appropriate action. Polychrons exhibit lesser degree of ProM performance failure than monochrons whereas expertise does not have an effect. Finally, results show that out of overall ProM performance failure, habit intrusion errors comprise of 16.22% occurring 1.75 times in every 10 valid click responses of ProM task. Moreover, experts demonstrate a superior performance over novices in programming. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:02:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:02:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HUMAN-COMPUTER STUDIES,69(6)428-439</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1071-5819</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2011.01.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14085</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>