<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16362</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:29:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Indication of transverse radial flow in high-multiplicity proton-proton collisions at the Large Hadron Collider</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUHURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAYAK, JK</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARMA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>transverse radial flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>proton-proton collisions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Large Hadron Collider</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUARK-GLUON-PLASMA</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAVY-ION COLLISIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERDENSE MATTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLLABORATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERSPECTIVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEARCH</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE</dc:subject><dc:description>We analyze the measured spectra of pi(+/-), K-+/-, p((p) over bar) in proton-proton (pp) collisions at root s = 0.9, 2.76 and 7 TeV in the light of blast-wave model to extract the transverse radial flow velocity and kinetic temperature at freeze-out for the system formed in pp collisions. The dependence of the blast-wave parameters on average charged particle multiplicity of event sample or the 'centrality' of collisions has been studied and compared with results of similar analysis in nucleus-nucleus (AA) and proton-nucleus (pA) collisions. We analyze the spectra of K-s(0), Lambda((Lambda) over bar) and Xi(-) also to see the dependence of blast-wave description on the species of produced particles. Within the framework of the blast-wave model, the study reveals indication of collective behavior for high-multiplicity events in pp collisions at LHC. Strong transverse radial flow in high-multiplicity pp collisions and its comparison with that in pA and AA collisions match with predictions from a very recent theoretical work (Shuryak and Zahed 2013 arXiv:hep-ph/1301.4470) that addresses the conditions for applicability of hydrodynamics in pp and pA collisions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:29:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:29:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS G-NUCLEAR AND PARTICLE PHYSICS, 41(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0954-3899</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-6471</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0954-3899/41/3/035106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16362</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>