<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14710</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:42:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of electro-osmotic flow on energy conversion on superhydrophobic surfaces</dc:title><dc:creator>SESHADRI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAIER, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>NANOFLUIDIC CHANNELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SLIP</dc:subject><dc:description>It has been suggested that superhydrophobic surfaces, due to the presence of a no-shear zone, can greatly enhance transport of surface charges, leading to a considerable increase in the streaming potential. This could find potential use in micro-energy harvesting devices. In this paper, we show using analytical and numerical methods, that when a streaming potential is generated in such superhydrophobic geometries, the reverse electro-osmotic flow and hence current generated by this, is significant. A decrease in streaming potential compared to what was earlier predicted is expected. We also show that, due to the electro-osmotic streaming-current, a saturation in both the power extracted and efficiency of energy conversion is achieved in such systems for large values of the free surface charge densities. Nevertheless, under realistic conditions, such microstructured devices with superhydrophobic surfaces have the potential to even reach energy conversion efficiencies only achieved in nanostructured devices so far. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4802044]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:42:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:42:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICS OF FLUIDS, 25(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4802044</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14710</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>