<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18315</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:00:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mechanism of Anti-Cancer Activity of Benomyl Loaded Nanoparticles in Multidrug Resistant Cancer Cells</dc:title><dc:creator>KINI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>DRUG-DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREAST-CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYALKYLCYANOACRYLATE NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERIC NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHITOSAN NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTROLLED-RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>P-GLYCOPROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYCLOSPORINE-A</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENE DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benomyl</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chitosan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) Nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anticancer Therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microtubules</dc:subject><dc:subject>Apoptosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug Resistance</dc:subject><dc:description>Polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles loaded with benomyl as anticancer drug formulation against multidrug-resistant EMT6/AR1 cells were synthesized by amine-carboxylate reaction. Using transmission electron microscopy, the average size of chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles and benomyl-encapsulated polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles was estimated to be 155 +/- 20 nm and 160 +/- 25 nm, respectively. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy revealed that poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) and chitosan are linked by covalent bonds. Zeta potentials of benomyl-encapsulated polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles at pH 4, 7.2, and 10 were 30 +/- 1.8, 19 +/- 0.65, and -22 +/- 0.15 mV, respectively, indicating the formation of stable, hydrophilic nanoparticles. The release of benomyl from benomyl-encapsulated polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles followed pH-dependent kinetics. The uptake of fluorescein isothiocyanate-labeled chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles was concentration-dependent in both MCF-7 and multidrug-resistant EMT6/AR1 cells. EMT6/AR1 cells showed 10-fold higher resistance to benomyl compared to MCF-7 cells; in contrast, benomyl-encapsulated polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles effectively inhibited proliferation of MCF-7 and EMT6/AR1 cells with a half-maximal inhibitory concentration of 4 +/- 0.5 and 9 +/- 0.5 mu M, respectively. In the presence of a P-glycoprotein inhibitor, the activity of benomyl was increased, suggesting that benomyl is a substrate for P-glycoprotein. Further, benomyl-encapsulated polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles depolymerized microtubules both in interphase and mitosis. It blocked cell cycle progression at G2/M and induced apoptosis in EMT6/AR1 cells, suggesting that benomyl-encapsulated polymeric chitosan-poly(D, L-lactide-co-glycolide) nanoparticles have chemotherapeutic activity against multidrug-resistant cancer cells.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:00:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:00:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOMEDICAL NANOTECHNOLOGY, 11(5)877-889</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-7033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-7041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jbn.2015.1998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18315</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>