<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10299</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling deformation behaviour of clay liners in a small centrifuge</dc:title><dc:creator>VISWANADHAM, BVS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>landfills</dc:subject><dc:subject>municipal solid waste</dc:subject><dc:subject>clay liners</dc:subject><dc:subject>centrifuge modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonuniform settlements</dc:subject><dc:subject>model tests</dc:subject><dc:description>In modern solid waste landfills, liner systems are essential structural elements that ensure that waste materials are safely separated from the environment. Many liner systems have been developed and used over the past decade. Among impermeable layers, clay liners are regarded as one of the very significant components of liner system and are being used worldwide as a waste containment system in landfills. One of the failures associated with clay liners is the occurrence of nonuniform settlements, resulting from the sudden collapse of waste, or the decomposition of waste materials, and (or) the subgrade over which the liner is laid. This paper deals with the use of a small centrifuge to model the deformation behaviour of clay liners. Model tests were performed in a small geotechnical centrifuge to investigate the behaviour of clay liners in landfills subjected to nonuniform settlements at sharp curvatures. A parametric study was conducted to analyze the influence of parameters like thickness, consistency, and overburden on the behaviour of clay liners. The clay liner without any overburden is observed to experience severe cracking in the form of deep and wide cracks at the maximum curvature zone. The depth and width of the cracks are found to decrease with an increase in clay liner thickness. The cracking failure pattern is suppressed by shearing for a clay liner with an increase in overburden pressure. Based on model test results, the clay liner with an adequate overburden is found to be free from cracking failure even when subjected to sharp curvatures. The effective usage of a small geotechnical centrifuge to model the deformation behaviour of clay liners is demonstrated adequately.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL RESEARCH COUNCIL CANADA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:05:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:05:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CANADIAN GEOTECHNICAL JOURNAL, 39(6), 1406-1418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-3674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1139/t02-075</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10299</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>