<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-236</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thin film single halo (SH) SOI nMOSFETs - hot carrier reliability for mixed mode applications</dc:title><dc:creator>NAJEEB-UD-DIN HAKIM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMGOPAL RAO, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>mosfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>amplification</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>hot carriers</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor device models</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor device reliability</dc:subject><dc:description>For the first time, we report a study on the hot carrier reliability performance of single halo (SH) thin film silicon-on-insulator (SOI) nMOSFETs for mixed signal applications. The single halo structure has a high pocket impurity concentration near the source end of the channel and a low impurity concentration in the rest of the channel. Besides having excellent DC output characteristics, better Vth-L roll-off control, lower DIBL, higher breakdown voltages and kink free operation, these devices show higher AC transconductance, higher output resistance and better dynamic intrinsic gain (gmR0). Experimental results show that SH SOI MOSFETs exhibit a lower hot carrier degradation in small-signal transconductance and dynamic output resistance, in comparison with the conventional (CON) homogeneously doped SOI MOSFETs. From 2D device simulations, the lower hot carrier degradation mechanism in SH-SOI MOSFETs is analyzed and compared with the conventional SOI MOSFETs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-09T06:25:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T19:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-09T06:25:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T19:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TENCON 2003: Proceeding of the Conference on Convergent Technologies for Asia-Pacific Region (V 2), Banglore, India, 15-17 October 2003, 613-617</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8162-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/TENCON.2003.1273241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/236</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/236</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>