<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15676</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:33:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Quantification of the uncertainty in stress index B-2 for pipe bends subjected to out-of-plane bending</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Pipe bends</dc:subject><dc:subject>Primary stress index</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monte Carlo simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fabrication uncertainty</dc:subject><dc:subject>Out-of-plane bending</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERNAL-PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NONLINEAR-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELBOWS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOAD</dc:subject><dc:description>Over the last decade, the requirement for moving from a deterministic design to a more rational reliability-based load and resistance factor design (LRFD) guideline has been emphasised in the area of pressure vessel and piping. For reliability-based code calibration of pipe bends, a quantification of the uncertainty in the primary stress indices (for pressure B-1 and for bending B-2) is the first significant task. This paper presents a Monte Carlo simulation-based probabilistic characterisation of B-2 for Class 2 and 3 Type 304 stainless steel thin pipes with a 90 degrees long radius bend, subjected to out-of-plane flexure. The ASME B&amp;PV Code, Section III equations (NC 3673.2 and ND 3673.2) to calculate B-2 are proposed to be revised using a random variable (K), for which detailed statistics (including the cumulative distribution function) are provided. An alternative equation, based on linear regression analysis, is also suggested which provides a better fit for the B-2 statistics. These information can be used suitably to formulate an LRFD equation for pipe bends. (c) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:33:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:33:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRESSURE VESSELS AND PIPING, 9524-30</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpvp.2012.05.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15676</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>