<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2809</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of the hydrogen content on the mechanical properties of chemical vapour deposited diamond</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARDA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIKDER, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVASTHI, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHTA, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIST, HD</dc:creator><dc:description>Thin films of diamond were deposited on Si (100), WC-Co and stainless steel (SS) substrates at various deposition conditions by microwave plasma CVD and hot filament CVD techniques. The films were characterised using micro-Raman spectroscopy, X-Ray diffraction and scanning electron microscopy. The elastic recoil detection analysis was used to measure the hydorgen concentration in the films. Stress in the films was investigated by measuring shift in the Raman diamond Line. A converse trend in the stress state of the films grown on Si by MPCVD and HFCVD as a function of pressure and a correlation with H content is observed. Stress state changes from tensile to compressive with H concentration. A preliminary study of the diamond coatings on WC-Cobalt and SS with and without a buffer layer which consists of electroplated Ni with dispersed diamond particles was also performed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>EUROPEAN POWDER METALLURGY ASSOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T13:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T13:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN HARD MATERIALS PRODUCTION,423-427</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-899072-03-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16307</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2809</dc:identifier><dc:source>European Conference on Advances in Hard Materials Production,STOCKHOLM, SWEDEN,MAY 27-29, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>