<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15033</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:52:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improper L-infinity Optimal/Suboptimal Controllers</dc:title><dc:creator>PAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELUR, MN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Dissipative systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>improper transfer function</dc:subject><dc:subject>L-infinity-control</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal control</dc:subject><dc:subject>polynomial matrix representations</dc:subject><dc:subject>system invariant zeros</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUADRATIC DIFFERENTIAL FORMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider L-infinity-control of MIMO systems and address solvability of the problem over all finite dimensional LTI controllers: i.e., controllers whose transfer functions can be proper or improper. We show that improper controllers are easily dealt with using the behavioral approach, unlike the standard state-space/transfer-matrix methods, and argue that there are cases where an improper controller can outperform a proper controller. In this setting, we next formulate and prove necessary and sufficient conditions for suboptimal L-infinity-control problem solvability and relate this to existing results about system invariant zeros. Further, we infer that in our formulation, assuming suboptimal solvability conditions on the system, an optimal controller always exists, possibly with an improper transfer function. In other words, the infimum L-infinity-norm of the closed loop system is achievable when dealing with both proper and improper controller transfer functions. We illustrate these results through an example for which the optimal L-infinity-controller has an improper transfer function.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:52:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:52:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON AUTOMATIC CONTROL, 57(5)1280-1285</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAC.2012.2191869</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15033</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>