<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9713</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Case-control study of non-Hodgkin's lymphoma among women and heterosexual men in the San Francisco Bay Area, California</dc:title><dc:creator>HOLLY, EA</dc:creator><dc:creator>LELE, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRACCI, PM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MCGRATH, MS</dc:creator><dc:subject>acquired-immunodeficiency-syndrome</dc:subject><dc:subject>former college-students</dc:subject><dc:subject>homosexual men</dc:subject><dc:subject>malignant-lymphomas</dc:subject><dc:subject>helicobacter-pylori</dc:subject><dc:subject>medical conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple-myeloma</dc:subject><dc:subject>gastric lymphoma</dc:subject><dc:subject>immune-system</dc:subject><dc:subject>syndrome aids</dc:subject><dc:subject>allergy and immunology</dc:subject><dc:subject>case-control studies</dc:subject><dc:subject>hypersensitivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>immunization</dc:subject><dc:subject>immunosuppression</dc:subject><dc:subject>life style</dc:subject><dc:subject>lymphoma</dc:subject><dc:subject>non-hodgkin's</dc:subject><dc:subject>risk factors</dc:subject><dc:description>A population-based case-control study was conducted between 1988 and 1995 in the San Francisco Bay Area of California to determine risk factors for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma. Participants completed in-person interviews, and blood was drawn to test for viruses and lymphocyte subsets. This report includes data for 1,281 cases and 2,095 controls. In multivariate analyses, the factors associated with a decreased risk for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma were allergy to plants, bee and wasp stings, five or more vaccinations, drugs to lower blood cholesterol, nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, total number of sexual partners, and lifetime marijuana use, whereas an increased risk was associated with cimetidine and other histamine H-2-receptor antagonists, splenectomy, gonorrhea, and body mass index. Unique to sex-specific models was an increased risk for endocrine gland disorders among women and for polio among men. Median CD3, CD4, CD8, CD20, and lymphocyte counts for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma patients were significantly lower than those for controls. These results implicate environmental factors that may influence the early stages of lymphomagenesis by stimulating the immune system. Antigen-driven B cells that accumulate to form lymphoma may be suppressed by immunologic stresses such as exposure to an increased number of sexual partners and to certain medications. A history of allergies provides evidence for a persistent capacity for B-cell differentiation and therefore a decreased accumulation of B cells. The decreased risk for non-Hodgkin's lymphoma with use of nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs and cholesterol-lowering drugs is consistent with a macrophage inflammatory role in B-cell proliferation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHNS HOPKINS UNIV SCHOOL HYGIENE PUB HEALTH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T02:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T02:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AMERICAN JOURNAL OF EPIDEMIOLOGY, 150(4), 375-389</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0002-9262</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9713</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9713</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>