<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10241</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Luminescence studies in KMgF(3):Eu,Ag</dc:title><dc:creator>MADHUSOODANAN, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSE, MT</dc:creator><dc:creator>INDIRA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:subject>alkali halides</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron spin resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>luminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>radiation dosimetry</dc:subject><dc:description>A new sensitive material KM(g)F(3):Eu,Ag has been developed with double dopants europium (Eu) and silver (Ag) by melting equal molecular proportions or KF and MgF(2) along with dopants (0.2 mol % each) in argon atmosphere. Luminescence studies have been carried out in this material to check its possible use in radiation dosmetry applications. Thermoluminescence (TL) studies in this material show that its TL sensitivity is three times that of the existing tissue equivalent material LiF:Mg,Ti (TLD- 100), while KMgF(3) doped with Eu alone and Ag alone shows sensitivities equal to that of TLD-100. KMgF(3):Eu,Ag shows a major TL peak around NOT unlike TLD-100 which has a complicated glow curve shape. The TL emission spectra of gamma irradiated material show characteristic emission of Eu(2+). Compared to KMgF(3):Eu, the emission intensity of Eu has been found more in KMgF(3):Eu,Ag. Photoluminescence studies show that there is no conversion of Eu(2+) to Eu(3+) on gamma irradiation. Electron spin resonance (ESR) studies have been carried out in this material to check if there is any valance conversion of Eu and Ag. Both the irradiated as well as unirradiated materials show signal for Eu(2+) ion did not show my signal to for Ag(2+) ion. Hence, in the presence of Ag(+) more Eu(2+) is entering into the crystal lattice which enhances the luminescence efficiency.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T05:29:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T05:29:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF PURE &amp; APPLIED PHYSICS, 47(6), 459-460</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-5596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10241</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>