<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1577</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Geochemical stratigraphy of Deccan flood basalts of the Bijasan Ghat section, Satpura Range, India</dc:title><dc:creator>SHETH, HC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHONEY, JJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHARA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>geochemical</dc:subject><dc:subject>geochronology</dc:subject><dc:subject>geology</dc:subject><dc:subject>rocks</dc:subject><dc:description>The ~240-m-thick Bijasan Ghat section exposes Deccan basalt flows and dykes that have major and trace element compositions suggestive of variable amounts of contamination by continental material. Most flows and a dyke are chemically similar to lavas of the Poladpur Formation in the southwestern Deccan. One flow and one dyke are similar to lavas of the Bushe Formation in the southwest, and one dyke is similar to lavas of the Mahabaleshwar Formation in the southwest. The type-sections of these formations are located ~350 km to the south of Bijasan Ghat, but many Poladpur-type lavas, a few Mahabaleshwar-like lavas and dykes, and a few broadly Bushe-like lavas and dykes have recently been identified in the Satpura region. Lavas resembling the thick Ambenali Fm. of the southwest are absent from Bijasan Ghat and nearby areas. Our data further extend the known outcrop area of Poladpur-like flows (estimated at ≥3×105 km2), one of the most widespread Deccan magma types. Seven ‘giant plagioclase basalt’ flows encountered in seven different sections in this region cannot unambiguously be correlated at present, either physically or chemically, and therefore are of little use in deciphering the complicated stratigraphic and structural make-up of the regional lava pile.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-30T02:59:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-30T02:59:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:02:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Asian Earth Sciences 23(1), 127-139</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1367-9120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1367-9120(03)00116-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1577</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1577</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>