<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16303</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:00:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>On the evolution of cured voxel in bulk photopolymerization upon focused Gaussian laser exposure</dc:title><dc:creator>BHOLE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>MICROSCALE TRUSS STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INCOHERENT WHITE-LIGHT</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER WAVE-GUIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW LITHOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEREOLITHOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MASK</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLIDIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFERENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>INHIBITION</dc:subject><dc:description>Unconstrained depth photopolymerization is emerging as a promising technique for fabrication of several polymer microstructures such as self propagating waveguides, 3D freeform structures by bulk lithography, and polymer nanoparticles by flash exposure. Experimental observations reveal governing physics beyond Beer Lambert's law and scattering effects. This paper seeks to model unconstrained depth photopolymerization using classical nonlinear Schrodinger equation coupled with transient diffusion phenomenon. The beam propagation part of the proposed model considers scattering effects induced due to spatial variation of the refractive index as a function of the beam intensity. The critical curing energy model is used to further predict profile of polymerized voxel. Profiles of photopolymerized voxel simulated using proposed model are compared with the corresponding experimental results for several cases of exposure dose and duration. The comparison shows close match leading to conclusion that the experimentally observed deviation from Beer Lambert's law is indeed due to combined effect of diffusion of photoinitiator and scattering of light because of change in the refractive index. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:00:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:00:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 116(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4891109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16303</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>