<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15219</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:01:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Size dependent optical properties of the CdSe-CdS core-shell quantum dots in the strong confinement regime</dc:title><dc:creator>MATHEW, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAN, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARDWAJ, BS</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSEPH, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>RADHAKRISHNAN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAMPOORI, VPN</dc:creator><dc:creator>VALLABHAN, CPG</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NONLINEARITIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROEMULSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ABSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPE</dc:subject><dc:description>We have investigated the third-order optical nonlinearity in CdSe and CdSe-CdS core-shell quantum dots with particle sizes in the range 4.4-5.2 nm by the z-scan technique. Optical absorption and fluorescence properties show quantum confinement effect and the fluorescence peak is shifted when the diameter of the core-shell quantum dots becomes large. Their nonlinear absorption and nonlinear refraction were observed with nanosecond laser radiation of 532-nm wavelength. At an excitation irradiance of 392MW/cm(2), the CdSe-CdS core-shell quantum dots exhibit a reverse saturation and a negative nonlinear refractive index indicating a clear nonlinear behavior. The introduction of CdS shell around CdSe core gives large third-order nonlinearity and third-order optical susceptibility decreases with increasing particle core size in the case of core-shell quantum dots within the range of our investigations. The third-order susceptibility of these quantum dots vary from 3.39 x 10(-11) to 5.77 x 10(-11) esu. The optical limiting threshold of the quantum dots varies in the range from 0.298 to 0.345GW/cm(2) and this therefore makes CdSe-CdS core-shell quantum dots a promising candidate for reverse-saturable absorption based devices at high laser intensities such as optical limiters. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3702430]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:01:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:01:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 111(7)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3702430</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15219</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>