<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-204</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-19T05:49:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Universal single-stage grid-connected inverter</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, BS</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, SACHIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, VIVEK</dc:creator><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric network topology</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric power generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:description>A new single-stage grid-connected inverter, suitable for distributed generation applications, is proposed. The inverter is universal in the sense that it can be switched between buck, boost, and buck--boost configurations by appropriately altering the pulse width modular (PWM) control. Discontinuous current mode (DCM) operation is implemented to facilitate shuffling between configurations during the converter operation. Such flexibility ensures maximum benefit of the buck, boost, and the buck--boost operations (e.g., low device stresses, higher efficiency, higher boosting capability, etc.). The PWM is achieved by comparing a high frequency carrier (triangular) waveform with a suitable reference waveform, which is not necessarily sinusoidal, but has a shape specific to the individual configuration and is derived by equating the power fed into the grid with that extracted from the source during each switching cycle. The values of the components (inductors and capacitors) need to be optimized so that DCM is maintained and the required amount of energy is transferred to the grid in all the three configurations during their respective operation. All the design expressions have been derived. A salient feature of this inverter is its compatibility with various types of sources (PV array, fuel cell, etc.) with varying voltage levels and control requirements. Being single-stage, the proposed topology offers additional advantages like modularity, compactness, and low cost. All the details of simulation and experimental work are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-01T04:55:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-01T04:55:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE Transactions on Energy Conversion 23(1), 128-37</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8969</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TEC.2007.905066</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/204</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/204</dc:identifier><dc:language>en_US</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>