<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11344</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stability of waterfront retaining wall subjected to pseudo-static earthquake forces</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHMAD, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>breaking wave impact</dc:subject><dc:subject>pseudodynamic method</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>vertical wall</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressures</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrodynamic pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic active earth pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>wall inertia</dc:subject><dc:subject>sliding</dc:subject><dc:subject>overturning</dc:subject><dc:subject>factor of safety</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil and wall friction angle</dc:subject><dc:description>Waterfront retaining walls supporting dry backfill are subjected to hydrostatic pressure on upstream face and earth pressure on the downstream face. Under seismic conditions, if such a wall retains a submerged backfill, additional hydrodynamic pressures are generated. This paper pertains to a study in which the effect of earthquakes along with the hydrodynamic pressure including inertial forces on such a retaining wall is observed. The hydrodynamic pressure is calculated using Westergaard's approach, while the earth pressure is calculated using Mononobe-Okabe's pseudo-static analysis. It is observed that when the horizontal seismic acceleration coefficient is increased from 0 to 0.2, there is a 57% decrease in the factor of safety of the retaining wall in sliding mode. For investigating the effect of different parameters, a parametric study is also done. It is observed that if phi is increased from 30 degrees to 35 degrees, there is an increase in the factor of safety in the sliding mode by 20.4%. Similar observations were made for other parameters as well. Comparison of results obtained from the present approach with [Ebeling, R.M., Morrison Jr, E.E., 1992. The seismic design of waterfront retaining structures. US Army Technical Report ITL-92-11. Washington DC] reveal that the factor of safety for static condition (k(h) = 0), calculated by both the approaches, is 1.60 while for an earthquake with kh = 0.2, they differ by 22.5% due to the consideration of wall inertia in the present study. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T14:44:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T14:44:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>OCEAN ENGINEERING, 34(14-15), 1947-1954</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-8018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.oceaneng.2007.03.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11344</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>