<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15355</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:37:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of hydrodynamic behaviour of a pilot-scale trickle bed reactor packed with hydrophobic and hydrophilic packings using radiotracer technique</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANT, HJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>Radiotracer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trickle bed reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Residence time distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrophobic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrophilic</dc:subject><dc:description>A radiotracer study was carried out in a trickle bed reactor (TBR) independently filled with two different types of packing i.e., hydrophobic and hydrophilic. The study was aimed at to estimate liquid holdup and investigate the dispersion characteristics of liquid phase with both types of packing at different operating conditions. Water and H-2 gas were used as aqueous and gas phase, respectively. The liquid and gas flow rates used ranged from 0.83 x 10(-7)-16.67 x 10(-7) m(3)/s and 0-3.33 x 10(-4) m(3) (std)/s, respectively. Residence time distribution (RTD) of liquid phase was measured using Br-82 as radiotracer and about 10 MBq activity was used in each run. Mean residence time (MRT) and holdup of liquid phase were estimated from the measured RTD data. An axial dispersion with exchange model was used to simulate the measured RTD curves and model parameters (Peclet number and MRT) were obtained. At higher liquid flow rates, the TBR behaves as a plug flow reactor, whereas at lower liquid flow rates, the flow was found to be highly dispersed. The results of investigation indicated that the dispersion of liquid phase is higher in case of hydrophobic packing, whereas holdup is higher in case of hydrophilic packing.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:37:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:37:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF RADIOANALYTICAL AND NUCLEAR CHEMISTRY, 294(1)71-75</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10967-011-1512-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15355</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>