<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5172</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Post- and prejunctional consequences of ecto-ATPase inhibition: electrical and contractile studies in guinea-pig vas deferens</dc:title><dc:creator>GHILDYAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALANI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANCHANDA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>excitatory junction potentials</dc:subject><dc:subject>sympathetic purinergic neurotransmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>receptor-mediated enhancement</dc:subject><dc:subject>central-nervous-system</dc:subject><dc:subject>smooth-muscle cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>dorsal-horn neurons</dc:subject><dc:subject>adenosine-triphosphate</dc:subject><dc:subject>synaptic potentials</dc:subject><dc:subject>neuromuscular-transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>transmitter release</dc:subject><dc:description>At sites of purinergic neurotransmission, synaptic ecto-ATPase is believed to limit the actions of ATP following its neural release. However, details of the modulation by this enzyme of the ATP-mediated conductance change and the possible mechanisms mediating this modulation remain unelucidated. We have addressed these issues by studying the effect of ARL 67156, a selective ecto-ATPase inhibitor, on ATP-mediated electrical and contractile activity in the sympathetically innervated guinea-pig vas deferens. ARL 67156 at 100 mu m significantly potentiated the amplitude of spontaneous excitatory junction potentials (SEJPs) by 81.1% (P &lt; 0.01) and prolonged their time courses (rise time by 49.7%, decay time constant by 38.2%; P &lt; 0.01). Moreover, the frequency of occurrence of SEJPs was strikingly increased (from 0.28 +/- 0.13 to 0.90 +/- 0.26 Hz; P &lt; 0.01), indicating an additional, primarily presynaptic, effect of ecto-ATPase inhibition. The frequency of occurrence of discrete events (DEs), which represent nerve stimulation-evoked quantal release of neurotransmitter, was also increased (similar to 6-fold; P &lt; 0.01), along with the appearance of DEs at previously 'silent' latencies. Purinergic contractions of the vas deferens were potentiated significantly (P &lt; 0.01) by ARL 67156; these potentiated contractions were suppressed by the A1 agonist adenosine (P &lt; 0.01) but left unaffected by the A1 antagonist 8-phenyltheophylline (8-PT). Our results indicate (i) that ecto-ATPase activity, in addition to modulating the ATP-mediated postjunctional conductance change, may regulate transmitter release prejunctionally under physiological conditions, and (ii) that the prejunctional regulation may be mediated primarily via presynaptic P2X, rather than A1, receptors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BLACKWELL PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T04:27:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T04:27:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSIOLOGY-LONDON, 575(2), 469-480</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3751</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1113/jphysiol.2006.109678</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5172</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>