<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-689</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Open graded asphalt concrete for mitigation of reflection cracking on asphalt concrete overlays</dc:title><dc:creator>BHOSALE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, JN</dc:creator><dc:subject>reflection cracking</dc:subject><dc:subject>open graded asphalt concrete</dc:subject><dc:subject>crack propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>differential deflection</dc:subject><dc:subject>base isolation</dc:subject><dc:description>Conventional pavement rehabilitation technique of laying asphalt concrete (AC) overlay over it has a major problem of reflection cracking. The existing cracking pattern on the old distressed rehabilitated pavement gets reflected on the newly laid AC overlay soon within first few months and starts its deterioration which results in drastic reduction in overlay life and the purpose with which it laid does not get fulfilled to the desired/designed extent. This paper presents the laboratory studies carried out on open graded asphalt concrete (OGAC) as a crack relief layer on indigenously developed Asphalt Concrete Slab Fatigue Testing Equipment under opening and mixed modes of displacement. The conventional dense bituminous macadam (DBM) and the OGAC overlays are investigated under cyclic simulated thermal and traffic loads with 5 mm differential deflection of zero load efficiency factor. Variation of tensile strength and strain in AC overlay with number of simulated thermal load cycles are observed and cumulative decay of parameters viz. tensile force, stiffness and shear modulus are computed. Overlay life, decay parameters and base isolation effectiveness factor (BIEF) are also evaluated. It is found that, the OGAC overlay works as a crack relief layer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:30:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:31:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:30:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:31:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG: Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 4409-4416</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/689</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/689</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>