<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3019</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Deformation and fracture behaviour of plate specimens subjected to underwater explosion - a review</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJENDRAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>plate deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>shock factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>impulse</dc:subject><dc:subject>deflection-time history</dc:subject><dc:subject>terminal strain to fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>impulsive loads</dc:subject><dc:subject>shock response</dc:subject><dc:subject>square plates</dc:subject><dc:description>Behaviour of plate specimens subjected to underwater explosion is of interest to metal forming community and ship designers. The break down of the original molecule of an explosive into product molecules associated with the evolution of large amount of heat generates a shock front in the water medium, followed by a gas bubble pulsation. The interaction of the shock wave with a plate imparts energy to it. which is dissipated in the form of deformation. The intensity of explosion determines whether a plate undergoes elastic deformation, yielding, plastic deformation or fracture. When the deformation is in the elastic range, the stress developed in the plate is given as a function of the material and shock wave parameters. As the intensity of explosion progressively increases, the elastic to plastic transition occurs over a specific shock factor. Plastic deformation is predicted as a function of geometric and material properties of the plate and shock pulse impulse. Deflection-time history reveals the reloading effects of the shock wave. As the deforming plate absorbs maximum energy, depending on its strength and ductility, it underizoes fracture. Terminal strain to fracture is considered as the criterion for explosive shock performance of ship materials. (C) 2005 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T19:31:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T19:31:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF IMPACT ENGINEERING,32(12)1945-1963</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0734-743X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijimpeng.2005.05.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13830</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3019</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>