<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14502</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:19:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tuning the Observability of Surface Plasmon in Silica-Gold Raspberry Shaped Nanoparticles Using Cuprous Oxide Shell</dc:title><dc:creator>TYAGI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASLAM, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>gold nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>cuprous oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>core-shell</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasmon</dc:subject><dc:subject>cloaking</dc:subject><dc:subject>dielectric constant</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESONANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASSEMBLIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPHERES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:description>A raspberry shaped silica-gold nanoparticle system has been coated with a cuprous oxide shell using a simple wet chemical approach. The optical properties of such particles depend on thin dielectric shell material, and we calculate far-field scattering and extinction of cuprous oxide coated silica-gold composite. In accordance with our theoretical findings, for ultrasmall gold nanoparticles (AuNPs &lt; nm) attached over silica, the localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR) peak is completely suppressed after Cu2O coating. The cloaking (nonobservability) of the LSPR peak in extinction spectra has been explained via calculation of contribution from absorbance (&lt;10%) and scattering (&gt;90%) in the composite nanostructure. For larger particles (&gt;5 nm), the traditional red-shift of the plasmon peak (from 532 to 588 nm) is still significant due to the large dielectric constant (approx. 8.0 @ 600 nm) of cuprous oxide (Cu2O) coating. A complete and controlled suppression of LSPR in small sized gold nanoparticles due to high dielectric refractory oxide shell could play a significant role in plasmon derived applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:19:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:19:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACS APPLIED MATERIALS &amp; INTERFACES, 5(23)12268-12274</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/am4039079</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14502</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>