<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18326</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:05:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ballistic impact behavior of 2D plain weave fabric targets with multiple layers: Analytical formulation</dc:title><dc:creator>SHAKTIVESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIR, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:subject>YARN PULL-OUT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY-ABSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANALYTICAL-MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>THICK COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>WOVEN FABRICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROJECTILE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARMOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PENETRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fabric target</dc:subject><dc:subject>ballistic impact</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress wave propagation in porous medium</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy balance</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy absorbing mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>conical deformation</dc:subject><dc:description>An analytical formulation is presented for the prediction of ballistic impact behavior of fabric targets. The formulation is based on stress wave propagation in porous medium and energy balance between the rigid projectile and the fabric target. During the ballistic impact event, energy lost by the projectile is absorbed by the fabric target through various damage and energy absorbing mechanisms such as compression of the fabric target directly below the projectile, compression in the region surrounding the impacted zone, shear plugging, stretching and tensile failure of yarns/layers in the region consisting of primary yarns, tensile deformation of yarns/layers in the region consisting of secondary yarns, conical deformation on the back face of the fabric target, in-plane friction between the warp and fill yarns and through the thickness friction between the moving projectile and the fabric target. The formulation presented considers both shear plugging and tensile failure of yarns during conical deformation and is valid for a wide range of fabric target thicknesses. Solution procedure for the evaluation of ballistic impact performance is presented. Further, experimental results are presented for the validation of analytical predictions. A good match is observed between the analytical predictions and the experimental results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:05:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:05:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF DAMAGE MECHANICS, 24(1)116-150</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1056-7895</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1530-7921</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1056789514524074</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18326</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>