<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5283</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>APPLICATION OF SINGULAR-VALUE DECOMPOSITION TO DETERMINE STREAMLINE DISTRIBUTION FOR UNIT MOBILITY RATIO DISPLACEMENT</dc:title><dc:creator>MARATHE, RV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHENOY, UV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHILAR, KC</dc:creator><dc:description>A new method is proposed to obtain streamline distribution in a horrizontal plane of a homogeneous reservoir. The method is a generalization df the classical method of images used to obtain the potential and velocity distribution in a symmetric pattern flood. However, it is extremely difficult to use the classical method of images, as shapes of reservoirs and locations of wells are generally arbitrary in nature. Further, methods based on finite difference techniques are difficult to implement, because they require substantial post-processing for front tracking and cannot handle singularities near the well. In the the proposed method, a large number of image wells (N) are arbitrarily located outside the reservoir boundary, which can be either sealing type or uniform pressure (flow potential type). A large number of points M, (M&gt;N) are selected along the reservoir boundary and the appropriate boundary conditions are written (no flow isopotential). This leads to M linear equations in N unknowns, which can be conveniently solved using the Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) technique for the unknown rates df the image wells. The iso-potentials, streamlines and single-fluid fronts can then be obtained using the principle of suprposition.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CANADIAN INST MINING METALL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T11:31:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T11:31:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CANADIAN PETROLEUM TECHNOLOGY, 34(5), 55-62</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5283</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5283</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>