<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18321</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:03:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>High-strain rate compressive behavior of multi-walled carbon nanotube dispersed thermoset epoxy resin</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDYA, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAVALA, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHANG, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>KORATKAR, NA</dc:creator><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOUGHENING MECHANISMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOAD-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILLED EPOXY</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-SITU</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TENSILE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanocomposites</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermosets</dc:subject><dc:subject>split Hopkinson pressure bar</dc:subject><dc:description>Compressive high-strain rate behavior of thermoset epoxy resin dispersed with multi-walled carbon nanotubes is presented. The present study investigates the effect of strain rate as well as effect of multi-walled carbon nanotube dispersion on the compressive stress-compressive strain behavior of thermoset epoxy resin. The amount of multi-walled carbon nanotubes dispersion was varied up to 3% by weight. The studies were carried out on compressive split Hopkinson pressure bar apparatus in the strain rate range of 800-3700/s. Processing of multi-walled carbon nanotubes-dispersed thermoset epoxy resin, testing, damage, and energy absorbing mechanisms and key findings are reported. It is observed that the compressive strength of thermoset epoxy resin increases up to 147% at high-strain rate compared with that at quasi-static loading. The corresponding increase for multi-walled carbon nanotubes-dispersed thermoset epoxy resin is up to 140%. It is also observed that the compressive strength and energy-absorption capability of thermoset epoxy resin increase with the addition of multi-walled carbon nanotubes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:03:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:03:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COMPOSITE MATERIALS, 49(8)903-910</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9983</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1530-793X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0021998314527329</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18321</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>