<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17195</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:29:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ultra-thin SiNx in superlattice via nitridation of a-Si in-situ hot wire chemical vapor deposition</dc:title><dc:creator>RAI, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALASUBRAMANIAM, KR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Photovoltaics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:subject>Superlattices</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amorphous semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silicon nitride</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hot-wire chemical vapor deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILICON-NITRIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISIBLE PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLAR-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:description>The fabrication of ultra-thin SiNx (&lt;2 nm) is a necessary step in third generation photovoltaics, memory, or light-emitting diode applications. Using the low temperature, cheap, scaleable synthesis technique of hot-wire chemical vapor deposition (HWCVD) for this purpose poses many challenges. Here, an approach of fabricating ultra thin SiNx of thickness similar to 1.9 nm in a superlattice (SL) structure via nitridation of a-Si layers in-situ HWCVD at 250 degrees C is reported. Quantum well SL and quantum dot (QD) SL films are realized, wherein SiNx layers are formed by nitriding a-Si. Both these films investigated by Raman spectroscopy and high resolution transmission electron microscopy, reveal the formation of ultra-thin SiNx in a SL structure with a-Si, accompanied by sharp interfaces. In addition, annealing of the SL structures, results in QDs of crystalline Si in the a-Si layers, maintaining the SiNx layer as well as the sharp interface between the SiNx and a-Si layers of the as-deposited SL structure. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:29:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:29:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS, 565101-104</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2014.07.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17195</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>