<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17498</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:28:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Foundations for Value Education in Engineering: The Indian Experience</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Skepticism about value education</dc:subject><dc:subject>The concept of 'Profession'</dc:subject><dc:subject>Paradigm shift in 'professional ethics'</dc:subject><dc:subject>Institutionalization of responsibility: Committed behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>Student engagement through 'action-oriented' programmes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Convergence of plurality of motivation</dc:subject><dc:description>The objective of this paper is to discuss some of the foundational issues centering around the question of integrating education in human values with professional engineering education: its necessity and justification. The paper looks at the efforts in 'tuning' the technical education system in India to the national goals in the various phases of curriculum development. The contribution of the engineering profession in national development and India's self-sufficiency is crucially linked with the institutionalization of expertise and the role of morality and responsibility. This linkage can be created through a proper understanding of the social role of the profession-what motivates the professionals and what makes professional life meaningful. Value education facilitates the process of moral maturity and the development of a 'holistic' mindset. This paper deals with the need to create such a mindset, the human values associated with it and gives examples of efforts to impart such education through 'action-oriented' programmes introduced in some institutes of engineering in India.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:28:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:28:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING ETHICS, 21(2)479-504</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1353-3452</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1471-5546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11948-014-9537-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17498</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>