<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12951</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Yagyopathy versus oral and IV drug administration: Evaluation for pulmonary tuberculosis using compartment modeling</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAGHUVANSHI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDYA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>inhalation</dc:subject><dc:subject>bioavailability</dc:subject><dc:subject>deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>absorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>yagya (homa)</dc:subject><dc:subject>pulmonary drug administration</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical modeling for pharmacokinetic simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>pulmonary tuberculosis</dc:subject><dc:description>With pulmonary drug administration gaining more and more importance, there is an obvious need for improvement in the existing methods and search for the newer ones. We have carried out the first ever study on the potentials of yagyopathy in this regard. While introducing this new mode of pulmonary drug administration, we also highlight some preliminary clinical and empirical results on drug inhalation characterization of yagyopathy that indicate its effectiveness in the treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis and thus motivate the present study. We construct mathematical models to evaluate the efficacy of this method of herbal cure vis-a-vis the common modes of oral and intravenous medication. The models are analyzed mathematically for the availability of the drug and other important pharmacokinetic features for the case when the site of infection and hence of desired activation is located in the lungs. Computer simulation experiments and validation are also carried out using available data from relevant empirical studies. The results further support significant potential of yagyopathy especially in terms of higher lung deposits, (bio) availability and residence time. The scope of yagyopathy and related research directions are discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-09-02T03:19:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-09-02T03:19:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL SYSTEMS, 14(3), 463-489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0218-3390</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0218339006001891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12951</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>