<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2008</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Underlay aware resiliency in P2P overlays</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, SDM</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLUR, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOVINDAN, VK</dc:creator><dc:subject>p2p overlays</dc:subject><dc:subject>event broker networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>availability</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed algorithm</dc:subject><dc:description>Modern distributed applications that run on P2P overlays need the overlay to be resilient to failures in the underlying communications network. An example application is that of event dissemination where the P2P overlay (the event broker network) delivers events published by a client to subscribers based on subscription filters. Achieving high availability requires that the overlay be aware of, and utilize the path redundancies in the underlying physical network. In addition, the overlay should be self organizing, as broker nodes may dynamically join or leave the network and centralized control is not an option in large scale networks. In this paper, we present Trimarg, an efficient distributed algorithm for achieving a self organizing overlay with an availability degree of three. Our algorithm is based on a graph theoretic foundation for highly available overlay networks and is designed to handle the concurrency issues of a large scale distributed system. The resulting unstructured P2P overlay ensures 3-degree of availability in the presence of node and link failures in the underlying physical network. We have proved the correctness of the algorithm and analyzed its complexity to show that the time complexity is O(diameter * degree)(2) of the network and the message complexity is O(diameter * degree). Our algorithm is the first of its kind to deal with concurrency issues and self organizing capabilities of the resultant overlay.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T00:49:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T00:49:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DISTRIBUTED COMPUTING AND NETWORKING,5408,99-113</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-540-92294-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2008</dc:identifier><dc:source>10th International Conference on Distributed Computing and Networking,Hyderabad, INDIA,JAN 03-06, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>