<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17931</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:27:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Quinine-Derived Thiourea and Squaramide Catalyzed Conjugate Addition of alpha-Nitrophosphonates to Enones: Asymmetric Synthesis of Quaternary alpha-Aminophosphonates</dc:title><dc:creator>BERA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAMBOOTHIRI, INN</dc:creator><dc:subject>ENANTIOSELECTIVE MICHAEL-ADDITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHONIC ACID-DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHIRAL SULFINYL AUXILIARY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEREOSELECTIVE-SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMINO PHOSPHONATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIASTEREOSELECTIVE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISOTHIOCYANATO PHOSPHONATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTITUMOR-ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALDOL REACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROPHOSPHONYLATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Conjugate addition of a-nitrophosphonates to enones was carried out in the presence of two sets of organocatalysts, viz. a quinine-thiourea and a quinine-squaramide. The quinine-thiourea provided the products possessing an a-quaternary chiral center in high enantioselectivities only in the case of electron rich enones. On the other hand, the quinine-squaramide was more efficient in that a wide variety of electron rich and electron poor enones underwent Michael addition of nitrophosphonates to afford the quaternary a-nitrophosphonates in excellent yields and enantioselectivities. The hydrogen bonding donor ability of the bifunctional catalyst, as shown in the proposed transition states, appears primarily responsible for the observed selectivity. However, a favorable p-stacking between the aryl groups of thiourea/squaramide and aryl vinyl ketone also appeared favorable. The reaction was amenable to scale up, and the enantioenriched quaternary a-nitrophosphonates could be easily transformed to synthetically and biologically useful quaternary a-aminophosphonates and other multifunctional molecules.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:27:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:27:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 80(3)1402-1413</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo502332r</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17931</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>