<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2793</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Water quality modelling in distribution networks</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJPARA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>chlorine concentration</dc:subject><dc:subject>decay</dc:subject><dc:subject>pipe</dc:subject><dc:description>A technique for the solution of unsteady flows in a multi quality water distribution system is introduced. The proposed method is compared with Preissman's scheme and dynamic analysis for water quality simulations. Each method is coupled with distribution system flow simulation model and has been used on several pipe networks of varying sizes. The front tracking method produces most accurate simulations where as Preissmen's scheme may produce oscillation. The dynamic analysis does not simulate for travel time as may be expected. However, in network simulations, with time step, larger than the longest travel time, extended period simulation may be adequate. In networks, where simulations are required at shorter time steps, front tracking method should be used.</dc:description><dc:publisher>US COMMITTEE LARGE DAMS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T01:19:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T01:19:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHALLENGES FACING IRRIGATION AND DRAINAGE IN THE NEW MILLENNIUM, VOLS I AND II: MEETING HUMAN AND ENVIRONMENTAL NEEDS THROUGH SUSTAINABILITY, REHABILITION AND MODERNIZATION,A369-A382</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-887903-09-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16193</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2793</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on the Challenges Facing Irrigation and Drainage in the New Millennium,FT COLLINS, CO,JUN 20-24, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>