<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17107</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:43:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Observation of Lorentzian lineshapes in the room temperature optical spectra of strongly coupled Jaggregate/metal hybrid nanostructures by linear two-dimensional optical spectroscopy</dc:title><dc:creator>WANG, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOMMER, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE SIO, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GROSS, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VOGELGESANG, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIENAU, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>nano-optics</dc:subject><dc:subject>coherent optical spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-dimensional optical spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>exciton-plasmon-coupling</dc:subject><dc:subject>line broadening</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTOR QUANTUM DOTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYNTHETIC HETERODIMER SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE-PLASMON POLARITONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEAR-FIELD SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENGINEERING COHERENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITED-STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENCE INTERMITTENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARA-TERPHENYL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:description>We analyze the linear optical reflectivity spectra of a prototypical, strongly coupled metal/molecular hybrid nanostructure by means of a new experimental approach, linear two-dimensional optical spectroscopy. White-light, broadband spectral interferometry is used to measure amplitude and spectral phase of the sample reflectivity or transmission with high precision and to reconstruct the time structure of the electric field emitted by the sample upon impulsive excitation. A numerical analysis of this time-domain signal provides a two-dimensional representation of the coherent optical response of the sample as a function of excitation and detection frequency. The approach is used to study a nanostructure formed by depositing a thin J-aggregated dye layer on a gold grating. In this structure, strong coupling between excitons and surface plasmon polaritons results in the formation of hybrid polariton modes. In the strong coupling regime, Lorentzian lineshape profiles of different polariton modes are observed at room temperature. This is taken as an indication that the investigated strongly coupled polariton excitations are predominantly homogeneously broadened at room temperature. This new approach presents a versatile, simple and highly precise addition to nonlinear optical spectroscopic techniques for the analysis of line broadening phenomena.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF OPTICS, 16(11)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2040-8978</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2040-8986</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/2040-8978/16/11/114021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17107</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>