<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1693</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>A better sheet-formability test</dc:title><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MILES, MP</dc:creator><dc:creator>WAGONER, RH</dc:creator><dc:description>Instability predictions are important in sheet-metal forming processes, one such instability being splitting failures due to localized necking. The majority of such sheet-metal industrial splitting failures occur near to the plane-strain state. Therefore, sheet-metal industries have always been looking for an ''ideal'' formability test which allows them to evaluate sheets for their ability to resist splitting failures under near plane-strain conditions. Several formability tests have been developed in the past but none have been very successful. Presently, a new test has been designed, constructed and used to evaluate the formability of different sheet materials. The results from this new test are compared with standard limiting-dome-height (LDH) tests and finite-element simulations. The results show that the new test is more reproducible, more closely follows the desirable plane strain path and takes roughly 1/6 of the time to perform relative to the LDH test. Strain measurements and finite-element simulations have revealed that the improvements are a result of the new test geometry, which produces a more stable and repeatable plane-strain state near to the splitting failure locations. The failure heights in the new tests were predicted using a section analysis finite-element program, SHEET-S.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T09:11:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T09:11:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS PROCESSING TECHNOLOGY,50,385-394</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0924-0136</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0924-0136(94)01400-U</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14861</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1693</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Conference on Numerical Simulation of 3-D Sheet Metal Forming Processes (NUMISHEET 93),ISEHARA, JAPAN,AUG 31-SEP 02, 1993</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>