<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7850</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Deformational history of Eastern Ghat Mobile Belt around Lathore, Balangir district, Orissa</dc:title><dc:creator>BISWAL, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANJEEVAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAYAK, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>charnockites</dc:subject><dc:subject>tectonics</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural geology</dc:subject><dc:subject>eastern ghat mobile belt</dc:subject><dc:subject>orissa</dc:subject><dc:description>The calc-gneiss and garnet-sillimanite-gneiss of Eastern Ghat Mobile Belt around Lathore bear the imprint of multiple phases of deformtion. The folds of the first generation, F-1, are isoclinal, intrafolial and vary in style from reclined to upright. This has developed a pervasive axial planar gneissosity. The second generation folds, F-2, which are coaxial with the F-1 are open to tight with a planar axial surface dipping moderately to SE and varied plunging axis. At places mesoscopic plane non-cylindrical F-2 sheath folds are noticed. Gentle upright folds, F-3, with NW-SE striking axial plane represent structure of third generation. Superimposition of F-2 on F-1 has resulted in Type 3 interference pattern and dome and basin structures are due to the interference of F-2 and F-3 folds. F-1 and F-2 folds are attributed to WNW-ESE buckling and F-3 is reported to be due to shortening across it, The 'sheath folds' are due to heterogeneous simple shear along the axial plane of the F-2 fold. The map shows a large scale southwesterly plunging overturned F-2 fold. Post-exhumation deformation has resulted in brittle shearing parallel to the axial plane of F-2 fold. The structure of the area points to a collisional tectonic setting like other granulite belts of Gondwanaland.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GEOLOGICAL SOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T22:23:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T22:23:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 51(2), 219-225</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7850</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7850</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>