<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18273</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:39:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Determination of the Concentration of Carbonic Species in Natural Waters: Results from a World-Wide Proficiency Test</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, MP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PORTUGAL, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGLOFF, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ARMIENTA, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHARAM, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANCHEZ, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RENDEROS, RE</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUANCO, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAN GELDERN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>IAEA INTERLABORATORY COMPARISONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOCHEMICAL REFERENCE MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IAVCEI FIELD WORKSHOPS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INORGANIC CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOLCANIC GASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOTAL ALKALINITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>VULCANO</dc:subject><dc:subject>IAGC</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISLAND</dc:subject><dc:subject>acid-base titration</dc:subject><dc:subject>analytical method</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO2 chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>interlaboratory comparison</dc:subject><dc:subject>natural waters</dc:subject><dc:subject>titrage acide-base</dc:subject><dc:subject>methode analytique</dc:subject><dc:subject>chimie du CO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>comparaison inter-laboratoires</dc:subject><dc:subject>eaux naturelles</dc:subject><dc:description>The results of an international interlaboratory proficiency test for the determination of carbonic species are presented. Eight laboratories analysed twelve water samples (four synthetic waters, one lake water, four geothermal waters, one seawater and two petroleum waters) by two methods: (a) individual laboratory analytical procedure and (b) acid-base titration curves in tabular form following a standardised protocol. In case (b), the concentrations of carbonic species were calculated by the organiser using the (1) Hydrologists' method, (2) Geochemists' method and/or (3) initial pH and total alkalinity method. For synthetic waters, the averaged % trueness and precision of measurement of the two methods were (trueness=7.6, precision=9.4) and (9.0, 3.4) for total alkalinity, and (6.6, 31.0) and (7.8, 6.1) for carbonic alkalinity, respectively. This indicates that the total alkalinity calculation procedure is in general correct in the individual laboratory method, but the carbonic alkalinity calculation procedure has serious problems. The measurements of total alkalinity for lake and seawaters were in agreement in both the methods; however, the individual laboratory measurement method for geothermal and petroleum waters was conceptually incorrect. Thus, the analytical procedures for the determination of carbonic species were reviewed. To apply the Hydrologists' and/or Geochemists' methods, the location of NaHCO3EP and H2CO3EP is necessary, even for samples with pH lower than that of NaHCO3EP, and a backward titration curve after complete removal of CO2 must be performed. The initial pH and total alkalinity method is appropriate where a complete analysis of species that contribute to the alkalinity is known. Les resultats d'un test international inter-laboratoires d'aptitude pour la determination des especes carboniques sont presentes. Huit laboratoires ont analyse douze echantillons d'eau (quatre eaux synthetiques, une eau lacustre, quatre eaux geothermales, une eau de mer, et deux eaux de petrole) par deux methodes: (a) la procedure d'analyse de chaque laboratoire et (b) les courbes de titrage acide-base sous forme de tableau suivant un protocole standardise. Dans le cas (b) les concentrations des especes carboniques ont ete calculees par l'organisateur en utilisant (1) la methode des hydrologues, (2) la methode des geochimistes et/ou (3) la methode du pH initial et de l'alcalinite totale. Pour les eaux de synthese la justesse et la precision moyennees en pourcentage de la mesure par les deux methodes etaient respectivement de (justesse = 7,6, precision = 9,4) et (9,0, 3,4) pour l'alcalinite totale et de (6,6, 31,0) et (7,8, 6,1) pour l'alcalinite carbonique. Ceci indique que la procedure de calcul pour l'alcalinite totale est en general correcte pour la methode d'analyse de chaque laboratoire, mais que la procedure de calcul pour l'alcalinite carbonique a de serieux problemes. Les mesures par les deux methodes de l'alcalinite totale des eaux de mer et de lac sont en bon accord; Toutefois, la methode de mesure de chaque laboratoire pour les eaux geothermales et de petrole est conceptuellement incorrecte. Ainsi, les procedures d'analyse pour la determination des especes carboniques ont ete examinees. Pour appliquer les methodes des hydrologues et/ou des geochimistes la localisation de NaHCO3EP et H2CO3EP est necessaire, meme pour les echantillons dont le pH est inferieur a celui de NaHCO3EP, et une courbe de titrage retrograde apres l'elimination complete du CO2 doit etre realisee. La methode du pH initial et de l'alcalinite totale est appropriee lorsque l'analyse complete des especes qui contribuent a l'alcalinite a ete realisee.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:39:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:39:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOSTANDARDS AND GEOANALYTICAL RESEARCH, 39(2)233-255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1639-4488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1751-908X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-908X.2014.00306.x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18273</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>