<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18387</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:48:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Gradation effect on sediment trapping efficiency in structures of vortex tube</dc:title><dc:creator>BYRRAJU, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>Vortex tube</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orifice percentage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sediment</dc:subject><dc:subject>The Froude number</dc:subject><dc:description>Unfamiliarity with sediment problems in the watershed has outdated a number of projects during their work, brought up heavy costs. Usually it is tried to prevent entering the sediment that moves as bed load in the rivers to the basin that methods such as increasing the basin bed level, mounting floor wall or submerged plates for removing sediment from the inlet, and desalting basin, using vortex tube include such methods. Since lots of variables are effective in sediment trapping and loss of vortex tube water, the aim of this study was to evaluate the performance of vortex tube in vitro and controlled discharge with four ratio of tube slit width to diameter (t/d), 0.15, 0.20, 0.25 and 3.0 and using three gradation include: D-1 (particles passing the sieve 8 and remaining on the sieve 10), D-2 (particles passing the sieve 16 and remaining on the sieve 20) and D-3 (particles passing the sieve 20 and remaining on the sieve 30) at an angle of 45 degrees with different discharges. The results showed that if the amount of water loss is not limiting criterion and a region is not facing with water shortage and water supply problems and prevention of the entry of sediment to the system is preferred to water supply, the more favorable option is t/d = 0.3, but if the water supply in a region is very important and there is essentially water shortage, a better option is t/d = 0.25. (C) 2015 IASE Publisher All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ADVANCED SCIENCE EXTENSION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:48:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:48:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ADVANCED AND APPLIED SCIENCES, 2(3)24-29</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2313-626X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2313-3724</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18387</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>