<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17570</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:05:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Self healing hydrogels composed of amyloid nano fibrils for cell culture and stem cell differentiation</dc:title><dc:creator>JACOB, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASU, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JHA, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUKUL, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHAYE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALIK, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>ASSEMBLED PEPTIDE NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALZHEIMERS-DISEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FMOC-DIPHENYLALANINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-SYNUCLEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOSENSOR APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOFIBER SCAFFOLD</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>TISSUE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGGREGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amyloid hydrogel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanofibrils</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-assembly</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stem cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tissue engineering</dc:subject><dc:description>Amyloids are highly ordered protein/peptide aggregates associated with human diseases as well as various native biological functions. Given the diverse range of physiochemical properties of amyloids, we hypothesized that higher order amyloid self-assembly could be used for fabricating novel hydrogels for biomaterial applications. For proof of concept, we designed a series of peptides based on the high aggregation prone C-terminus of A beta 42, which is associated with Alzheimer's disease. These Fmoc protected peptides self assemble to beta sheet rich nanofibrils, forming hydrogels that are thermoreversible, non-toxic and thixotropic. Mechanistic studies indicate that while hydrophobic, pi-pi interactions and hydrogen bonding drive amyloid network formation to form supramolecular gel structure, the exposed hydrophobic surface of amyloid fibrils may render thixotropicity to these gels. We have demonstrated the utility of these hydrogels in supporting cell attachment and spreading across a diverse range of cell types. Finally, by tuning the stiffness of these gels through modulation of peptide concentration and salt concentration these hydrogels could be used as scaffolds that can drive differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells. Taken together, our results indicate that small size, ease of custom synthesis, thixotropic nature makes these amyloid-based hydrogels ideally suited for biomaterial/nanotechnology applications. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:05:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:05:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOMATERIALS, 54,97-105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0142-9612</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1878-5905</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biomaterials.2015.03.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17570</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>