<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10248</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Photocontrol of alpha-chymotrypsin activity by covalently linked 2-carboxyazobenzene units</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADHUSUDNAN, KS</dc:creator><dc:subject>photoregulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacteriorhodopsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>rhodopsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>light</dc:subject><dc:description>alpha-Chymotrypsin exhibits photoswitchable catalytic activities in aqueous solution after eight of its thirteen backbone amino groups are covalently attached via amide linkage to trans-2-carboxyazobenzene [Ph-N=N-Ph-(o-CO2H), 1]. Irradiation of trans-azo-analogue of the enzyme in phosphate buffer (pH=7.6) at 314 nm gives the cis-azo-analogue of the enzyme with a quantum efficiency of 0.14 at ambient temperature. The trans--&gt;cis photoreaction is reversed by irradiating the cis-au, enzyme at 430 nm. Both trans- and cis-forms of the ate-enzyme catalyze the hydrolysis of p-nitrophenyl acetate and the rates of this right-induced hydrolysis are found to be 7.77 and 6.98 (x 10(4)) mol/min respectively. Under similar conditions the hydrolysis rate of unmodified enzyme is found to be 8.97 x 10(4) moles/min. The photoisomerizable azobenzene units of 1 effect perturbation in the structure of alpha-chymotrypsin, thereby offering a convenient method to control its substrate binding affinity and hence its catalytic activity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T05:58:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T05:58:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF CHEMISTRY SECTION B-ORGANIC CHEMISTRY INCLUDING MEDICINAL CHEMISTRY, 38(8), 885-888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0376-4699</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10248</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>