<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2602</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of mode switched controllers for a Pseudo continuous current mode boost converter</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEKUMAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>dc-dc power conversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>state space averaging</dc:subject><dc:subject>switched hybrid systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid automaton</dc:subject><dc:subject>pccm</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage regulation</dc:subject><dc:description>The Pseudo Continuous Current Mode (PCCM) operation of a boost converter can be treated as an intermediate between the Continuous Current Mode (CCM) and Discontinuous Current Mode (DCM) operation. The advantages in DCM operation and CCM operation can be effectively compromised to get this intermediate operation. In addition, the control flexibility and stability in DCM operation of a boost converter can be attributed to, the PCCM operation as far as the control design is concerned. In this paper, three types of mode switched control designs based on the hybrid automaton model, namely, system theoretical design, circuit theoretical design and energy based design for a PCCM boost converter are analyzed and compared. Analysis, control design and simulation results are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T12:14:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T12:14:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2006 IEEE International Conference on Power Electronic, Drives and Energy Systems, Vols 1 and 2,443-448</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7803-9771-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2602</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Conference on Power Electronic, Drives and Energy Systems,New Delhi, INDIA,DEC 12-15, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>