<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15526</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:18:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>INVESTIGATIONS TO ESTABLISH THE INFLUENCE OF THE THERMAL ENERGY FIELD ON SOIL PROPERTIES</dc:title><dc:creator>KADALI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEKSHMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>elevated temperatures</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil</dc:subject><dc:subject>characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>physical characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>mineralogical characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATION-EXCHANGE CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TREATMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>LASER DIFFRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOREST SOIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIRE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MINERALOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRENGTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>WILDFIRE</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes details of a study to investigate and demonstrate the changes undergone by soil when it is exposed to elevated temperatures. Such situations are commonly encountered while designing the foundations for the furnaces, boiler units, forging units, brick kilns, rocket launching pads, buried power-supply cables, air-conditioning ducts, underground explosions, disposal of high-level radioactive and industrial toxic wastes, ground modifications or soil-stabilization techniques, etc. As such, investigations to establish changes undergone by the soil when it is exposed to elevated temperatures assume some importance. With this in view, individual samples of six soils, with entirely different characteristics, were subjected to temperatures up to 300 degrees C (sequentially in steps of 50 degrees C) and after each step of thermal treatment, these samples were characterized for their physical, chemical and mineralogical properties. Based on a critical synthesis of the results, it has been demonstrated that elevated temperatures cause (i) a change in the color, (ii) an increase in the specific gravity, particle size and weight loss, (iii) a reduction in the specific surface area, cation-exchange capacity and zeta-potential, and (iv) a structural transformation of the soil. Though these changes would affect the engineering properties of the soil to a large extent, the scope of this paper is limited to demonstrating the alterations in physical, chemical and mineralogical changes, only, occurring in the soil when it is exposed to elevated temperatures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>UNIV MARIBOR</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:18:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:18:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA GEOTECHNICA SLOVENICA, 10(2)58-76</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15526</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>