<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16590</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:46:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic Anisotropy of Mononuclear Ni-II Complexes: On the Importance of Structural Diversity and the Structural Distortions</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>BADKUR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>CASSCF calculations</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic anisotropy</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel</dc:subject><dc:subject>magneto-structural correlations</dc:subject><dc:subject>zero-field splitting</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE MAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZERO-FIELD SPLITTINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HETEROLEPTIC NICKEL(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPIN-HAMILTONIAN PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STATE PERTURBATION-THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NI(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COORDINATION-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LANTHANIDE COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:description>Mononuclear Ni-II complexes are particularly attractive in the area of single-molecule magnets as the axial zero-field splitting (D) for the Ni-II complexes is in the range of -200 to +200cm(-1). Despite this advantage, very little is known on the origin of anisotropy across various coordination ligands, coordination numbers, and particularly what factors influence the D parameter in these complexes. To answer some of these questions, herein we have undertaken a detailed study of a series of mononuclear Ni-II complexes with ab initio calculations. Our results demonstrate that three prominent spin-conserved low-lying d-d transitions contribute significantly to the D value. Variation in the sign and the magnitude of D values are found to correlate to the specific structural distortions. Apart from the metal-ligand bond lengths, two different parameters, namely, and , which are correlated to the cis angles present in the coordination environment, are found to significantly influence the axial D values. Developed magneto-structural D correlations suggest that the D values can be enhanced significantly by fine tuning the structural distortion in the coordination environment. Calculations performed on a series of Ni-II models with coordination numbers two to six unfold an interesting observationthe D parameter increases significantly upon a reduction in coordination number compared with a reference octahedral coordination. Besides, if high symmetry is maintained, even larger coordination numbers yield large D values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:46:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:46:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL, 20(33)10305-10313</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-6539</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1521-3765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/chem.201402694</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16590</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>