<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9197</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis protocol and superconducting properties of (Hg, Cr)Sr2CuO4+delta</dc:title><dc:creator>BALAMURUGAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>hg0.7cr0.3sr2cuo4+delta</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>hg1-xcrxsr2cuo4+delta</dc:subject><dc:subject>(hg,cr)sr2cuo4+delta</dc:subject><dc:subject>hgba2cuo4+delta</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>mo</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we report the study of our results on the synthesis protocol and the superconducting properties of (Hg, Cr)Sr2CuO4+delta. We have used several distinct approaches for the synthesis of good quality (Hg, Cr)/Sr-1201 samples by varying the processing parameters such as starting materials, precursor and annealing treatments as well as the sample container. The (Hg, Cr)/Sr-1201 samples were synthesized in partial vacuum, and systematically characterized by powder XRD, X-T, dc-electrical-resistance and dc-magnetization measurements. XRD data confirm that they are of tetragonal Hg/Ba-1201 type structure. Good quality (Hg, Cr)/Sr-1201 samples were obtained from the sample prepared using a strontium nitrate source with a maximum T-C(onset) similar to 60 K, which is higher than the samples prepared using a carbonate source (T-C(onset) similar to 56 K). It is found that T-C is not affected by the subsequent Ar or O-2 annealing treatment. Remarkably, the annealed samples show significant improvement in the diamagnetic transition.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T01:18:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T01:18:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SUPERCONDUCTOR SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY, 18(3), 264-270</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-2048</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-2048/18/3/010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9197</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>