<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18394</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:52:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Slag Prediction in Submerged Rocket Nozzle Through Two-Phase CFD Simulations</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATURVEDI, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHALCRABORTY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>COMPOSITE PROPELLANT</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERNAL FLOWS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Slag prediction</dc:subject><dc:subject>submerged rocket nozzle</dc:subject><dc:subject>CFD simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid rocket motor</dc:subject><dc:subject>rocket motor performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>nozzle erosion</dc:subject><dc:description>A computational procedure has been established to predict the slag in a practical solid rocket motor with submerged nozzle. Both single-phase and two-phase flow analyses have been performed in the rocket motor port. Three-dimensional Navier-Stokes equations along with SST turbulence model have been solved for gas-phase calculations. The effect of ejected alumina particles from the propellant geometry on the flow field has been simulated through Lagrangian tracking method. The computational methodology is firstly validated by comparing against other numerical results of rocket motors available in the literature before applying the same to predict the slag accumulation of a submerged rocket motor for strategic applications. Burn-back geometries at different instants have been simulated and parametric studies were performed to find out the effect of Al2O3 particle size. It was observed that the slag capture rate increases uniformly with Al2O3 particle size. The predicted slag accumulation data match closely with the ground test data for the range of conditions simulated in the present work.</dc:description><dc:publisher>DEFENCE SCIENTIFIC INFORMATION DOCUMENTATION CENTRE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:52:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:52:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DEFENCE SCIENCE JOURNAL, 65(2)99-106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-748X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0976-464X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18394</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>