<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4177</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>New methodology for estimating biofuel consumption for cooking: Atmospheric emissions of black carbon and sulfur dioxide from India</dc:title><dc:creator>HABIB, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHRIVASTAVA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>STEHR, JW</dc:creator><dc:creator>DICKERSON, RR</dc:creator><dc:subject>ocean experiment</dc:subject><dc:subject>air-pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>agricultural waste</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomass fuels</dc:subject><dc:subject>indoex 1999</dc:subject><dc:subject>level so2</dc:subject><dc:subject>combustion</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerosol</dc:subject><dc:subject>cookstoves</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>emission inventory</dc:subject><dc:subject>regional pollution</dc:subject><dc:description>The dominance of biofuel combustion emissions in the Indian region, and the inherently large uncertainty in biofuel use estimates based on cooking energy surveys, prompted the current work, which develops a new methodology for estimating biofuel consumption for cooking. This is based on food consumption statistics, and the specific energy for food cooking. Estimated biofuel consumption in India was 379 (247-584) Tg yr(-1). New information on the user population of different biofuels was compiled at a state level, to derive the biofuel mix, which varied regionally and was 74:16:10%, respectively, of fuelwood, dung cake and crop waste, at a national level. Importantly, the uncertainty in biofuel use from quantitative error assessment using the new methodology is around 50%, giving a narrower bound than in previous works. From this new activity data and currently used black carbon emission factors, the black carbon ( BC) emissions from biofuel combustion were estimated as 220 (65-760) Gg yr(-1). The largest BC emissions were from fuelwood (75%), with lower contributions from dung cake (16%) and crop waste (9%). The uncertainty of 245% in the BC emissions estimate is now governed by the large spread in BC emission factors from biofuel combustion (122%), implying the need for reducing this uncertainty through measurements. Emission factors of SO2 from combustion of biofuels widely used in India were measured, and ranged 0.03-0.08 g kg(-1) from combustion of two wood species, 0.05-0.20 g kg(-1) from 10 crop waste types, and 0.88 g kg(-1) from dung cake, significantly lower than currently used emission factors for wood and crop waste. Estimated SO2 emissions from biofuels of 75 (36-160) Gg yr(-1) were about a factor of 3 lower than that in recent studies, with a large contribution from dung cake (73%), followed by fuelwood (21%) and crop waste ( 6%).</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER GEOPHYSICAL UNION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T06:35:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T06:35:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GLOBAL BIOGEOCHEMICAL CYCLES, 18(3), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0886-6236</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1029/2003GB002157</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4177</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>