<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1858</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Formability studies on transverse tailor welded blanks</dc:title><dc:creator>BHASKAR, VV</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:description>Tailor Welded Blanks (TWB) technology is one of the several approaches that have been used to reduce the weight of the automobile body. TWBs are made up of two or more blanks having different/same properties (geometry, material etc.) prior to forming. The formability of these blanks depends on material and geometric parameters like strength ratio and thickness ratio. The study of these blanks can be classified on the basis of the weld orientation chosen viz. transverse weld or longitudinal weld with respect to the major straining direction. This paper studies the formability issues related to transverse TWB by FE simulation. The formability is assessed by analyzing tensile and Limit Dome Height (LDH) tests. The weld region is assumed to be a line in all the simulations. While modeling the tensile test, ultimate tensile strength (UTS) and elongation are monitored, and in LDH testing, pole height and maximum load (in near plane strain condition) are monitored. LDH testing shows that as thickness ratio increases, the load bearing capacity and the pole height decreases. There is a contribution from both the thicker and the thinner blank to the overall deforming volume. Failure location analysis shows that there is an abrupt change in the location of the failure from punch nose region to weld line region as the thickness ratio reaches a critical magnitude (1.08). The study of material properties shows that as the yield strength ratio (S ratio) and strain hardening exponent ratio (N ratio) between the blanks increases, the maximum load which the blank can sustain without failure (UTS) increases. This becomes constant and comparable to that of single sheet at higher N and S ratios.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T10:49:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T10:49:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Numisheet 2005: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference and Workshop on Numerical Simulation of 3D Sheet Metal Forming Processes, Pts A and B,778,699-704</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7354-0265-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0094-243X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1858</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th International Conference and Workshop on Numerical Simulation of 3D Sheet Metal Forming Processes,Detroit, MI,AUG 15-19, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>