<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3965</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>MULTICOMPONENT BATCH DISTILLATION COLUMN DESIGN</dc:title><dc:creator>DIWEKAR, UM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADHAVAN, KP</dc:creator><dc:description>Batch distillation is characterized as a system that is difficult to design because compositions are changing continuously with time. The models reported in the literature and used in the simulators like PROCESS and BATCHFRAC, etc., are too complex to use for obtaining optimal design because of high computational time and large memory requirement. In this work we are presenting a short-cut method for design of multicomponent batch distillation columns, operating under variable reflux and constant reflux conditions. The method is essentially a modification of the short-cut method widely used in the design of continuous multicomponent columns. The technque has been tested for both binary and multicomponent systems, and the results compare favorably with the rigorous methods of design. The method is very efficient and can be used for preliminary design and analysis of batch columns. The model used in this method has a number of tuning parameters that can be used for model adaptation. The main features of the short-cut method include lower computational time (which is independent of the number of plates in the column), lower memory requirements, and its adaptability to design.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T13:23:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T13:23:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 30(4), 713-721</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie00052a014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3965</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3965</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>