<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17541</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:50:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>The Self in Exile: Heidegger's Destruction of Subjectivity</dc:title><dc:creator>GEORGE, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Subject</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dasein</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interiority</dc:subject><dc:subject>Humanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Other</dc:subject><dc:description>The modern notion of the subject as constant self-presence that conditions the truthful appearance of phenomena is brought under sustained critical scrutiny by Heidegger. More than critical scrutiny, Heidegger offered a positive sketch of what is other than the subject, Dasein. Understanding the human being as openness for the circulation and preservation of the meaning of what-is as such is posed as the negation of the self-contained closure and interiority that subjectivity is. Levinas sees materialism and the loss of interiority and freedom in Heidegger's project, inclining more towards an ethics of things rather than persons. However, Levinas's criticisms themselves are not free of the modern predilection for the human, albeit in a fresh and rich way. Conversely, it can be argued that that being which is open to the world of things and people still has a profound interior dimension because it is in each case mine. The Heideggerian notion of human agency and freedom may be appropriated as a possible response to technological nihilism and modern subjectivism.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:50:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:50:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF INDIAN COUNCIL OF PHILOSOPHICAL RESEARCH, 32(2)183-197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0970-7794</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2363-9962</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40961-015-0022-x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17541</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>