<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2588</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Three dimensional hybrid model for analysis of wave scattering in infinite plates</dc:title><dc:creator>NAYAK, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>composite plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>cracks</dc:subject><dc:description>Guided wave scattering in an infinite plate containing a circular cylindrical hole is analyzed by using a numerical method, based on sound theoretical concepts. The analysis is accomplished using a hybrid method, called the global local finite element method, which uses a combination of a finite element approach with a Lamb wave mode expansion approach for analyzing scattering of guided waves by flaws in an infinite layered anisotropic plate. In this method, a bounded region containing the flaws is discretized into finite elements, while the wave field in the unbounded exterior region is calculated by using a Rayleigh-Ritz approach coupled with the modal summation technique. The scattered field is calculated through the application of the nodal force-displacement relation and by satisfying the continuity condition at the interface between the discretized and exterior regions. This approach can be used for analyzing the scattering of three-dimensional guided waves by flaws in an infinite layered anisotropic plate, which has not yet been studied by other researchers in this area.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:04:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:04:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Structural Health Monitoring and Intelligent Infrastructure, Vols 1 and 2,1113-1120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-415-39650-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15990</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2588</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Conference on Structural Health Monitoring of Intelligent Infrastructure,Shenzhen, PEOPLES R CHINA,NOV 16-18, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>