<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17676</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T14:01:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Coordination in a multiple producers-distributor supply chain and the value of information</dc:title><dc:creator>THOMAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAMOORTHY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESWARAN, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSIGHTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decentralised decision-making</dc:subject><dc:subject>Value of information</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coordinated scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decentralised supply chain</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lagrangian relaxation</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper analyses coordination and the value of information in a decentralised multiple-producers-distributor supply chain. The impact of sharing two vital pieces of information of this supply chain(i) production capacity and (ii) resource constraints - is examined with an example from a coal supply chain. The different components of decentralised supply chain coordination are identified. The 'value of information' is computed using a decentralised approach which is developed based on an iterative Lagrangian relaxation algorithm. Results and analysis based on extensive computational experiments with different models which have different levels of information-sharing are presented. As the results show, information-sharing significantly contributes to the strengthening of coordination in a decentralised supply chain. The resource constraint information is found to have higher impact than the production capacity information. The paper concludes with a few ideas to extend and generalise this work. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:01:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:01:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION ECONOMICS, 167,63-73</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-5273</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-7579</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpe.2015.05.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17676</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>