<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16054</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:21:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Visible light-driven novel nanocomposite (BiVO4/CuCr2O4) for efficient degradation of organic dye</dc:title><dc:creator>BAJAJ, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>PHOTOCATALYTIC ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRRADIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CUCR2O4</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYBRID</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, BiVO4/CuCr2O4 nanocomposites synthesized via a chemical route are applied as a photocatalyst for the degradation of methylene blue (MB) dye. The photocatalytic activity results indicated a substantial degradation of MB dye by similar to 90% over the surface of nanocomposite catalyst under visible light illumination. The nanocomposite showed a photocatalytic activity for MB dye degradation which is three times higher compared to that of BiVO4. This has been attributed to photogenerated electron-hole pair charge separation. The prepared photocatalysts were characterized using X-ray diffraction (XRD), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), UV-Vis absorption and photoluminescence spectroscopy. Furthermore, an oxidizing reagent such as H2O2 was added to the photocatalytic system, which may act as an alternative electron scavenger and resulting in a notably enhanced rate of pollutant destruction. In addition, the effect of polyaniline has also been studied by synthesizing an organic/inorganic hybrid material (BiVO4/CuCr2O4/PANI). It has been observed that 95% photodegradation of organic dye takes place on the nanocomposite surface with visible light. A possible mechanism explaining the origin of enhanced performance of nanocomposite and nanohybrid is proposed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:21:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:21:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 42(19)6736-6744</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2dt32753h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16054</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>