<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5836</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Isotopic paleobiology of some tertiary larger foraminifera from Kutch, India</dc:title><dc:creator>SARASWATI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATRA, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJI, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>stable isotopes</dc:subject><dc:subject>benthic foraminifera</dc:subject><dc:subject>algal symbiosis</dc:subject><dc:description>The paleobiology of some Tertiary larger foraminifera from Kutch is inferred using oxygen and carbon isotopic data, Spiroclypeus and Heterostegina (having chamber-lets) show lower delta(13)C values than Nummulites and Assilina (having undivided chambers). This difference is attributed to algal endosymbionts for whom division of chambers is functionally advantageous, The isotopic data also support the view that pustules on the surface of some larger foraminifera developed to concentrate light for the benefit of endosymbionts. Isotopic variability is greater in megalospheric than in microspheric farms, indicating that the megalospheric forms are more tolerant of ecological variation than the microspheric ones, and this could be one of the reasons why they are more common in the geologic record, Similarly, variability in delta(18)O and delta(13)C isotopic values indicate that the family Nummulitidae is more stenotopic, whereas Lepidocyclinidae and Miogypsinidae appear to be more eurytopic. The order of extinction of the genera Assilina, Nummulites and Spiroclypeus also parallels the progressive decline in delta(13)C in their skeletal carbonates, This parallelism possibly indicates a greater role for endosymbionts in the evolution of larger foraminifera.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CUSHMAN FOUNDATION FORAMINIFERAL RES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T07:57:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T07:57:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF FORAMINIFERAL RESEARCH, 27(1), 69-74</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0096-1191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5836</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5836</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>