<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17154</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:08:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design-in-reliability: From library modeling and optimization to gate-level verification</dc:title><dc:creator>JAIN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUDI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SREENIVASAN, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>NBTI</dc:subject><dc:subject>EM</dc:subject><dc:subject>Signal probability</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel and comprehensive framework for aging analysis is presented in this work, comprehending degradation from BTI, hot-carriers and electro-migration. For the first time, all the primary variables affecting the aging of an interconnect and the transistor - namely, the equivalent duty-cycles, slews and frequencies are incorporated into the calculation. Additionally, from electro-migration stand-point, the framework allows calculation of the exact RMS and 'recovered' average current for every metal segment internal to the circuit, thus making it practically a universal model for aging analysis. Through detailed waveform-processor developed for validation, the aging model is ensured to be within 5% of exact SPICE calculations. The immediate application of such an extensive and accurate modeling is drawn in terms of influencing changes to the library design/architecture itself, showcased through circuit and layout optimization from EM, hot-carriers and NBTI constraints. Finally, we demonstrate the ultimate benefit from such a library model for doing exact gate-level aging analysis, as well as against asymmetric aging. Results from 28 nm production library models and complex SoC are shared. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:08:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:08:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROELECTRONICS RELIABILITY, 54(6/7)1421-1432</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0026-2714</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.microrel.2014.03.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17154</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>