<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12649</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nonlinear analysis of reinforced concrete beams strengthened with polymer composites</dc:title><dc:creator>PENDHARI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>bonded frp reinforcement</dc:subject><dc:subject>rc beams</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>rc beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>frpc</dc:subject><dc:subject>fe analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>strengthening</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear</dc:subject><dc:subject>ultimate load</dc:subject><dc:description>Strengthening of existing old structures has traditionally been accomplished by using conventional materials and techniques, viz., externally bonded steel plates, steel or concrete jackets, etc. Alternatively, fibre reinforced polymer composite (FRPC) products started being used to overcome problems associated with conventional materials in the mid 1950s because of their favourable engineering properties. Effectiveness of FRPC materials has been demonstrated through extensive experimental research throughout the world in the last two decades. However there is a need to use refined analytical tools to simulate response of strengthened system. In this paper, an attempt has been made to develop a numerical model of strengthened reinforced concrete (RC) beams with FRPC laminates. Material models for RC beams strengthened with FRPC laminates are described and verified through a nonlinear finite element (FE) commercial code, with the help of available experimental data. Three dimensional (3D) FE analysis has been performed by assuming perfect bonding between concrete and FRPC laminate. A parametric study has also been performed to examine effects of various parameters like fibre type, stirrup's spacing, etc. on the strengthening system. Through numerical simulation, it has been shown that it is possible to predict accurately the flexural response of RC beams strengthened with FRPC laminates by selecting an appropriate material constitutive model. Comparisons are made between the available experimental results in literature and FE analysis results obtained by the present investigators using load-deflection and load-strain plots as well as ultimate load of the strengthened beams. Furthermore, evaluation of crack patterns from FE analysis and experimental failure modes are discussed at the end.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TECHNO-PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T08:28:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T08:28:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STRUCTURAL ENGINEERING AND MECHANICS, 24(1), 1-18</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1225-4568</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12649</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12649</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>