<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3728</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Aromatics to triquinanes. Synthesis and photoreaction of tricyclo[5.2.2.0(2,6)]undecanes having an alpha-methoxy beta,gamma-unsaturated carbonyl chromophore: A novel, efficient, and general route to linearly fused cis:anti:cis tricyclopentanoids</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>THOMAS, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>pi-methane photorearrangement</dc:subject><dc:subject>radical cyclization</dc:subject><dc:subject>natural-products</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclo-additions</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic-synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>squarate esters</dc:subject><dc:subject>(+/-)-coriolin</dc:subject><dc:subject>photochemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>rearrangement</dc:subject><dc:subject>construction</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel, general, and stereoselective route for rapid creation of functionalized, linearly fused cis:anti:cis triquinanes from aromatic precursors has been presented. Cycloaddition of 2-methoxy-spiro[cyclohexa-2,4-diene-6-2'oxacyclopropan]one with various dienophiles and the photochemical reaction of appropriately designed tricyclic systems, having an alpha-methoxy beta,gamma-enone chromophore upon triplet (T-3) sensitization, are the key elements of our approach. A new and efficient methodology for the synthesis of endo-annulated bicyclo[2.2.2]octenones having an alpha-methoxy beta,gamma-enone chromophore (23-36) from o-vanillyl alcohol has been reported. The 2-methoxyspiro[cyclo-hexa-2,4-diene-6-2'-oxacyclopropan]one was generated by oxidation of o-vanillyl alcohol and trapped with cyclopentadiene (17), spiroheptadiene (18), and dimethylfulvene (19) to give the adducts 20-22 which were elaborated to a variety of chromophoric systems 23-36. The structure and stereochemistry of the tricyclic chromophoric systems (20-36) has been established through their high-field (300 MHz) H-1 NMR, C-13 NMR, and COSY spectra. Triplet-sensitized photochemical reaction of the chromophoric systems (23, 28-35) has been investigated. The triplet excitation of 28-34 led directly to the formation of functionalized triquinanes (43-48) in a single, stereoselective step. Interestingly, the irradiation of 23 furnished a novel tetracyclic product 40, whereas the irradiation of the substrate 35, having an additional alpha,beta-enone chromophore, gave a highly unusual pentacyclic product 55 as a result of participation of the OCH3 group in the photoreaction.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T17:25:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T17:25:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 62(16), 5310-5320</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo9702296</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3728</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3728</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>