<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1448</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stress field estimation around a semi-constrained inclusion and its validation by interpreting hydride platelet orientation around a blister in a Zr–2.5Nb alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>crystal microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermoanalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>niobium</dc:subject><dc:subject>zirconium alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>A methodology for estimating the stress field in the matrix surrounding a semi-constrained inclusion is proposed. The stress free misfit volume associated with the inclusion was partitioned into semi-constrained and constrained components. The objective was achieved by carrying out a series of sectioning, cutting and imposition of constrained misfit displacement on an imaginary notch of geometry identical to that of the inclusion–matrix contour. The stress field was computed using elastic finite element analysis for plane stress condition. The misfit displacement model thus developed was applied to compute the stress field around a hydride blister grown under controlled thermal boundary condition in Zr–2.5Nb pressure tube (PT) alloy and was validated by interpreting the hydride platelet orientation in the matrix surrounding the blister. Finally, an assessment of the structural integrity of the Zr–2.5Nb PT material containing hydride blister was made in view of this analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-06T05:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:51:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-06T05:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:51:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Materials Science and Engineering: A 339(1-2), 17-28</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0921-5093(02)00115-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1448</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1448</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>