<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10972</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Inventory of aerosol and sulphur dioxide emissions from India: I - Fossil fuel combustion</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>use motor vehicles</dc:subject><dc:subject>coal fly-ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>anthropogenic emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>particulate-emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>co2 emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>asia</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>climate</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>so2</dc:subject><dc:subject>pm2.5</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbonaceous aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>fly ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>power plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>brick-kilns</dc:subject><dc:subject>indoex</dc:subject><dc:description>A comprehensive, spatially resolved (0.25degrees x 0.25degrees) fossil fuel consumption database and emissions inventory was constructed, for India, for the first time. Emissions of sulphur dioxide and aerosol chemical constituents were estimated for 1996-1997 and extrapolated to the Indian Ocean Experiment (INDOEX) study period (1998-1999). District level consumption of coal/lignite, petroleum and natural gas in power plants. industrial, transportation and domestic sectors was 9411 PJ, with major contributions from coal (54%) followed by diesel (18%). Emission factors for various pollutants were derived using India specific fuel characteristics and information on combustion/air pollution control technologies for the power and industrial sectors. Domestic and transportation emission factors, appropriate for Indian source characteristics, were compiled from literature. SO2 emissions from fossil fuel combustion for 1996-1997 were 4.0 Tg SO2 yr(-1), with 756 large point sources (e.g. utilities, iron and steel, fertilisers, cement, refineries and petrochemicals and non-ferrous metals), accounting for 62%. PM2.5 emitted was 0.5 and 2.0 Tg yr(-1) for the 100% and the 50% control scenario, respectively, applied to coal burning in the power and industrial sectors. Coal combustion was the major source of PM2.5 (92%) primarily consisting of fly ash, accounting for 98% of the "inorganic fraction" emissions (difference between PM2.5 and black carbon + organic matter) of 1.6 Tg yr(-1). Black carbon emissions were estimated at 0.1 Tg yr(-1), with 58% from diesel transport. and organic matter emissions at 0.3 Tg yr(-1), with 48% from brick-kilns. Fossil fuel consumption and emissions peaked at the large point industrial sources and 22 cities, with elevated area fluxes in northern and western India. The spatial resolution of this inventory makes it suitable for regional-scale aerosol-climate studies. These results are compared to previous studies and differences discussed. Measurements of emission factors for Indian sources are needed to further refine these estimates. (C) 2002 . .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T09:30:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T09:30:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT, 36(4), 677-697</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1352-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1352-2310(01)00463-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10972</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>