<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10926</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Highly aromatic character of biogeomacromolecules in Chitinozoa: A spectroscopic and pyrolytic study</dc:title><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BROCKE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARTKOPF-FRODER, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>LITTKE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>WILKES, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANN, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>chromatography mass-spectrometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic-matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>gas chromatography</dc:subject><dc:subject>crude oils</dc:subject><dc:subject>invertebrate cuticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-composition</dc:subject><dc:subject>aliphatic polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>kerogen formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>cell-wall</dc:subject><dc:subject>gc-ms</dc:subject><dc:description>Extraordinarily well-preserved chitinozoans from an Upper Silurian sedimentary sequence in south-east Turkey were recovered from different depth levels, hand-picked from the palynological residue, cleaned and analysed by micro-FTIR and Curie point pyrolysis-gas chromatography-mass spectrometry. Hand-picked chitinozoans were predominantly represented by the genera Bursachitina, Calpichitina, Cingulochitina, Ancyrochitina, Angochitina and Pterochitina. Both spectroscopic and pyrolytic investigations suggest that biogeomacromolecules of these Chitinozoa consist of both aliphatic and aromatic moieties. The micro-FTIR spectra of Chitinozoa are characterized by aliphatic CH, (3000-2800 and 1460-1450 cm(-1)) and CH3 (1375 cm(-1)) absorptions and aromatic C = C (1560-1610 cm(-1)) and CH (3050 cm(-1) and 700-900 cm(-1)) absorptions. Major pyrolysis products from the Chitinozoa include both aromatic compounds such as alkylbenzenes, alkylnaphthalenes, alkylphenols and alkylphenanthrenes and aliphatic hydrocarbons including a homologous series of n-alkene/n-alkane doublets. Aromatic compounds predominate over aliphatic compounds. 1,2,3,4-Tetramethylbenzene is the most abundant pyrolysis product of the studied Chitinozoa. No pyrolysis products diagnostic of chitin were detected in the present study and it is unlikely that the original biomacromolecules of Chitinozoa prior to fossilization were made of chitin. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T06:47:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T06:47:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANIC GEOCHEMISTRY, 38(10), 1625-1642</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0146-6380</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.orggeochem.2007.06.014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10926</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10926</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>