<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15223</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:35:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Recent developments in the reverse micro-electrical discharge machining in the fabrication of arrayed micro-features</dc:title><dc:creator>MASTUD, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>micromachining</dc:subject><dc:subject>reverse micro-electrical discharge machining</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-electrical discharge machining</dc:subject><dc:subject>high aspect ratio structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>process mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROELECTRODE ARRAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASSISTED EDM</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIBRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HOLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WEAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>RODS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOOL</dc:subject><dc:description>High aspect ratio arrayed micro-structures and textured surfaces are required in diversified applications such as electrical contacts, printing heads, electrodes for micro-batteries, injection nozzles, nano-material delivery systems, biomedical implants, and hydrophobic surfaces. Reverse micro-electrical discharge machining (R-MEDM) process has a capability to fabricate such arrayed features on a variety of workpiece materials irrespective of their mechanical properties. R-MEDM is a variant of micro-electrical discharge machining (MEDM) process, key difference being, extruded arrayed features are fabricated in the R-MEDM process against the micro-cavities that are machined in MEDM. This article highlights the recent advances in process characterization and modelling of mechanics of the R-MEDM process. The focus of discussion is on comparing the process with the other micromachining processes presently available for the fabrication of arrayed micro-features. In addition, R-MEDM process characteristics in the fabrication of arrayed features on 'easy' and 'difficult' to erode materials are presented. It is understood that R-MEDM has comparable or in some cases better performance in the fabrication of arrayed features than the processes like micro-milling, micro-wire EDM, micro-wire electrical discharge grinding (EDG) and block EDG.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:35:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:35:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART C-JOURNAL OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERING SCIENCE, 226(C2)367-384</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0954406211424672</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15223</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>