<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16951</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:01:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Concentration-independent rate constant for biodiesel synthesis from homogeneous-catalytic esterification of free fatty acid</dc:title><dc:creator>HASSAN, SZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>VINJAMUR, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Concentration-independent rate constant</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taguchi method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biodiesel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Esterification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Free fatty acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION-EXCHANGE-RESINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WASTE COOKING OIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLEIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUNFLOWER OIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACETIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METHANOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUILIBRIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALCOHOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSESTERIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Dependence of the second-order rate constant (SRC) on the reactants' concentration, for esterification or Fatty acids, is found empirically in the published reports. Taguchi method is used to study dependency of the rate constant on temperature, reactants' concentration, and catalyst loading for the synthesis of biodiesel from sulfuric acid-catalyzed esterification of free fatty acid (ETA) with methanol. On the basis of general literature on dependency of rate constant on reactants' concentration and the esterification-rate determining step, concentration term embedded in the units of SRC has been identified as catalyst concentration. Accordingly SRC has been modified to include the catalyst concentration in the rate law, which is consistent with the general mass-action rate law reported by Blum and bus (1964) and Pikar (2011). Analysis of the modified rate constant showed it to be independent of the reactants' concentration, It is thus named as 'concentration independent rate constant (ClRC)'. The predictions of kinetics of the esterification of FFA are better using CIRC than other commonly used rate forms. The modified rate constant is shown to be equivalent to Bronsted-Bjerrum relation. Moreover, the modified rate constant is more general than the reported ones for esterification of fatty acids and it predicts kinetics well over a wide range of reaction parameters. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved,</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:01:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:01:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING SCIENCE, 107290-301</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4405</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2013.12.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16951</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>