<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2884</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Impact behavior of woven fabric composites : experimental studies</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BORADE, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>resistance</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental studies have been presented on the impact behavior of plain weave E-glass/epoxy laminates with different combinations of impactor mass and incident impact velocity with the same incident impact energy of 24.43 J. Four combinations of impactor mass-incident impact velocity have been considered. Impact tests have been carried out on an instrumented drop weight impact test apparatus. The unsupported area of the specimens during the impact loading was 127 mm x 127 mm with clamped boundary condition. Post impact compression testing of impacted specimens has been carried out using Compression After Impact test fixture as per NASA 1142 standard. Impact and post impact compression behavior has been presented. In general, it is observed that, for the material tested, impact resistance and damage tolerance characteristics are higher for low mass and high velocity combination compared with high mass and low velocity combination.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC EXPERIMENTAL MECHANICS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T18:41:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T18:41:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE SEM IX INTERNATIONAL CONGRESS ON EXPERIMENTAL MECHANICS,750-753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-91205-369-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1046-672X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2884</dc:identifier><dc:source>SEM 9th International Congress on Experimental Mechanics,ORLANDO, FL,JUN 05-08, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>