<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17837</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T05:09:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>A low-power, low-cost soil-moisture sensor using dual-probe heat-pulse technique</dc:title><dc:creator>JORAPUR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALAPARTHY, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARIK, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOHN, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHASURESH, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>WATER-CONTENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITY SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSTRUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>Low-power DPHP sensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Soil density</dc:subject><dc:subject>System design</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wireless communication</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the development and testing of an integrated low-power and low-cost dual-probe heat-pulse (DPHP) soil-moisture sensor in view of the electrical power consumed and affordability in developing countries. A DPHP sensor has two probes: a heater and a temperature sensor probe spaced 3 mm apart from the heater probe. Supply voltage of 3.3V is given to the heater-coil having resistance of 33 Omega power consumption of 330 mW, which is among the lowest in this category of sensors. The heater probe is 40 mm long with 2 mm diameter and hence is stiff enough to be inserted into the soil. The parametric finite element simulation study was performed to ensure that the maximum temperature rise is between 1 degrees C and 5 degrees C for wet and dry soils, respectively. The discrepancy between the simulation and experiment is less than 3.2%. The sensor was validated with white clay and tested with red soil samples to detect volumetric water-content ranging from 0% to 30%. The sensor element is integrated with low-power electronics for amplifying the output from thermocouple sensor and TelosB mote for wireless communication. A 3.7V lithium ion battery with capacity of 1150 mAh is used to power the system. The battery is charged by a 6V and 300 mA solar cell array. Readings were taken in 30 min intervals. The life-time of DPHP sensor node is around 3.6 days. The sensor, encased in 30 mm x 20 mm x 10 mm sized box, and integrated with electronics was tested independently in two separate laboratories for validating as well as investigating the dependence of the measurement of soil-moisture on the density of the soil. The difference in the readings while repeating the experiments was found out to be less than 0.01%. Furthermore, the effect of ambient temperature on the measurement of soil-moisture is studied experimentally and computationally. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:09:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:09:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSORS AND ACTUATORS A-PHYSICAL, 233,108-117</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0924-4247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sna.2015.06.026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17837</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>