<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1959</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Semantic characterization of real world events</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGARGADDE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARADARAJAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>databases</dc:subject><dc:description>Reducing the latency of information delivery in an event driven world has always been a challenge. It is often necessary to completely capture the attributes of events and relationships between them, so that the process of retrieval of event related information is efficient. In this paper, we discuss a formal system for representing and analyzing real world events to address these issues. The event representation discussed in this paper accounts for the important event attributes, namely, time, space, and label. We introduce the notion of sequence templates that not only provides event related semantics but also helps in semantically analyzing user queries. Finally, we discuss the design for our Query-Event Analysis System, which is an integrated system to (a) identify a best sequence template given a user query; (b) select events based on the best sequence template; and (c) determine content related to the selected events for delivering to users.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T17:50:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T17:50:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DATABASE SYSTEMS FOR ADVANCED APPLICATIONS, PROCEEDINGS,3453,675-687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>3-540-25334-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15193</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1959</dc:identifier><dc:source>10th International Conference on Database Systems for Advanced Applications (DASFAA 2005),Beijing, PEOPLES R CHINA,APR 17-20, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>