<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10567</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>AXIALLY SYMMETRICAL STRESS-DISTRIBUTION IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD OF A PENNY SHAPED CRACK UNDER GENERAL SURFACE LOADINGS</dc:title><dc:creator>PARIHAR, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, JVSK</dc:creator><dc:description>An infinite isotropic elastic solid weakened by a penny shaped crack is considered. The penny shaped crack (a plane crack bounded by a circle) is subjected to surface tractions which are symmetrical about the centre of the circle but not necessarily self-equilibrating. The stress in the solid is due to tractions on the crack surfaces and the distribution of stress is axially symmetric. The stress and displacement components at a general point in the solid are derived in terms of stress and displacement discontinuities at the plane of the crack. Using the boundary conditions and the continuity conditions on the plane of the crack, the problem is reduced to that of solving Abel type integral equations which admit closed form solutions. Some particular cases of loading on the crack surfaces are discussed in detail. The results are compared with those available in the literature. Variations of stress components with points in the solid are shown graphically for the case when one face of the penny shaped crack is subjected to a uniform pressure while the other face is free from tractions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T16:01:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T16:01:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 39(6), 1067-1095</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0013-7944(91)90114-G</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10567</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10567</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>