<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2626</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Strategies for efficient streaming in delay-tolerant multimedia applications</dc:title><dc:creator>KRITHIVASAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>IYER, S</dc:creator><dc:description>We consider Multimedia applications where clients specify a minimum desired stream rate (quality) and a time till when they are willing to wait, termed delay tolerance. The Content Service Provider's (CSP) objective is to service as many clients' requests for the same multimedia content with a single stream while satisfying their requirements. We propose an optimization approach to determine the rates delivered at clients and study three transcoder deployment strategies: (i) Source Transcoding (ST): when content encoded at different rates are available only at the source (ii)Anywhere Transcoding (AT): when transcoding capability is available at all intermediate nodes, and (iii)Selected Node Transcoding when transcoding capability is available at selected intermediate nodes. Considering the complexity of the optimal solution, we propose a set of heuristic based algorithms for delivering enhanced rates to clients using the three strategies. A practical content dissemination network is used to demonstrate the effectiveness of our strategies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T13:51:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T13:51:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ISM 2006: EIGHTH IEEE INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON MULTIMEDIA, PROCEEDINGS,419-426</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7695-2746-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16029</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2626</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th IEEE International Symposium on Multimedia,San Diego, CA,DEC 11-13, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>