<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3729</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assembling Discrete D4R Zeolite SBUs through Noncovalent Interactions. 3. Mediation by Butanols and 1,2-Bis(dimethylamino)ethane</dc:title><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUPPUSWAMY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOGOI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>STEINER, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>tert-butyl phosphate</dc:subject><dc:subject>ray crystal-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular-sieves</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>coordinated water</dc:subject><dc:subject>auxiliary ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>ancillary ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrazole ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>zinc enzymes</dc:subject><dc:description>The use of tetrameric zinc phosphate [Zn(dipp)(CH(3)OH)](4) (1; dipp = diisopropylphenylphosphate dianion) as a suitable building block for realizing new noncovalently linked extended structures, via facile replacement of coordinated methanol molecules by other alcohols, is reported herein. Compounds [Zn(dipp)(sec-butanol)](4)center dot 4H(2)O (2) and [Zn(dipp)(tert-butanol)](4)center dot 4H(2)O (3) have been synthesized by the addition of sec- or tert-butanol to 1 at room temperature. The reaction of zinc acetate or zinc sulfate with dippH(2) in the presence of N,N,N',N ''-tetramethylethylenediamine (tmeda) under similar reaction conditions results in the formation of [H(2)tmeda][Zn(4)-(dipp)(4)(MeOH)(2)(OAc)(2)]center dot(CH(3)OH) (4) or [H(2)tmeda][Zn(3)(diPP)(3)(dippH)(2)(CH(3)OH)]center dot(CH(3)OH)(3) (5), respectively. Analytically pure compounds 2-5 have been isolated in the form of single crystals directly from the respective reaction mixtures in very good yields and characterized with the aid of analytical and spectroscopic studies. Single-crystal X-ray diffraction studies reveal that compounds 2 and 3 are neutral tetranuclear zinc phosphates. Compound 4 is also a tetrameric phosphate but is anionic. The core structures of compounds 2-4 resemble the double-4-ring secondary building unit (D4R SBU) in zeolites. Compound 5 is a trinuclear ionic zinc phosphate built from three fused S4R SBUs. Compounds 4 and 5 represent the first examples of discrete anionic zinc organ ophosphates. The presence of coordinated sec- or tert-butanol molecules and a planar water tetramer cluster in 2 and 3, and the H(2)tmeda cations and methanol solvents in 4 and 5, leads to the formation of zigzag chainlike supramolecular assemblies in the solid state.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T17:31:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T17:31:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 49(5), 2153-2162</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic901932r</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3729</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3729</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>