<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15847</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:59:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Radiative opacity of low-Z plasma using screened hydrogenic model including l-splitting</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENON, SVG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Rosseland and planck opacity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Average atom model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Screened hydrogenic model</dc:subject><dc:subject>LASER-PRODUCED PLASMAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSE-PLASMAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATOMIC-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Z-ELEMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HOT</dc:subject><dc:subject>COEFFICIENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STATE</dc:subject><dc:description>Radiative opacities of low-Z plasma are computed using average atom model. Screened Hydrogenic Model including l-splitting (SHML) is used as the atomic model to obtain the internal structure of ions embedded in plasma. The phenomenon of pressure ionization of levels is described by a Gaussian density dependent degeneracy function. Use of the most recent compilation of the screening constants makes it possible to include l-splitting in a direct manner. The average ionization in the plasma is obtained by self-consistently solving the non-linear set of coupled SHML equations along with the charge neutrality condition of Wigner-Seitz cell. The frequency dependent opacity of Aluminum plasma is compared with the data obtained from Los Alamos (LANL) opacity library and a reasonable agreement is seen. The computed values of Rosseland and Planck opacity of C, Al and Fe plasma are also in good agreement with the LANL opacity database value for different plasma density and temperature. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:59:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:59:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF QUANTITATIVE SPECTROSCOPY &amp; RADIATIVE TRANSFER, 113(4)286-293</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jqsrt.2011.11.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15847</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>