<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17487</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:23:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Estimation of Sintering Kinetics of Oxidized Magnetite Pellet Using Optical Dilatometer</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, TKS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHMED, HM</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANDERSSON, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>BJORKMAN, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>IRON-ORE PELLETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATION-ENERGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATHEMATICAL-MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDURATION PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CURVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINA</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>UO2</dc:subject><dc:description>The quality of magnetite pellet is primarily determined by the physico-chemical changes the pellet undergoes as it makes excursion through the gaseous and thermal environment in the induration furnace. Among these physico-chemical processes, the oxidation of magnetite phase and the sintering of oxidized magnetite (hematite) and magnetite (non-oxidized) phases are vital. Rates of these processes not only depend on the thermal and gaseous environment the pellet gets exposed in the induration reactor but also interdependent on each other. Therefore, a systematic study should involve understanding these processes in isolation to the extent possible and quantify them seeking the physics. With this motivation, the present paper focusses on investigating the sintering kinetics of oxidized magnetite pellet. For the current investigation, sintering experiments were carried out on pellets containing more than 95 pct magnetite concentrate from LKAB's mine, dried and oxidized to completion at sufficiently low temperature to avoid sintering. The sintering behavior of this oxidized pellet is quantified through shrinkage captured by Optical Dilatometer. The extent of sintering characterized by sintering ratio found to follow a power law with time i.e., Kt(n). The rate constant K for sintering was determined for different temperatures from isothermal experiments. The rate constant, K, varies with temperature as ln(TK(1/n)) = ln K' - Q/RT; and the activation energy (Q) and reaction rate constant (K') are estimated. Further, the sintering kinetic equation was also extended to a non-isothermal environment and validated using laboratory experiments. (C) The Minerals, Metals &amp; Materials Society and ASM International 2014</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:23:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:23:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS B-PROCESS METALLURGY AND MATERIALS PROCESSING SCIENCE, 46(2)635-643</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5615</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1543-1916</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11663-014-0273-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17487</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>