<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1204</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:09:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assessment of turbidity of seawater using remote sensing data</dc:title><dc:creator>BEHERA, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIPATHY, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>INAMDAR, AB</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASOLEKAR, SR</dc:creator><dc:subject>landsat</dc:subject><dc:description>The study aims at the application of Landsat Thematic Mapper (TM) data for detection and measurement of physical aspects of marine pollution in the Thane creek region adjoining Bombay city and its suburbs. Collection of marine water samples in the Thane creek region has been synchronised with the satellite passes of Landsat. The water samples were analysed for turbidity, an important physical pollution parameter. An attempt has been made to establish the relationship between the real time values of the marine pollution parameter (turbidity in this case) analysed in the laboratory and the digital counts (function of surface radiance) from the remotely sensed data using statistical technique. A two step approach has been followed to relate the TM data with the marine pollution parameter. The advantage df this methodology in detection and measurement of turbidity is discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>COUNCIL SCIENTIFIC INDUSTRIAL RESEARCH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T11:18:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T11:18:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF MARINE SCIENCES,25(2)103-108</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0379-5136</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1204</dc:identifier><dc:source>National Seminar on Conservation and Sustainable Development of Coastal Resources,BURHAMPUR, INDIA,DEC 14-17, 1994</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>