<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18038</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:22:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>An amorphous barium titanate thin film improves light trapping in Si solar cells</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRIYADARSHINI, BG</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHTA, BR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>ANTIREFLECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:description>A new anti-reflection coating based on amorphous barium titanate (a-BTO) was developed using RF magnetron sputtering technique. Systematic studies on the structural and optical properties were carried on a-BTO thin films deposited on polished Si and textured Si substrates. In the visible range of the solar spectrum, the refractive index was found to be 2.02-1.91 with high transmittance of greater than 85%. Maximum reduction in the reflectance for a-BTO on polished Si and textured Si substrates was found to be 100% (at 550 nm) and 85% (at 400 nm), respectively. Further, improvement in cell efficiency of a Si solar cell with a-BTO anti-reflection coating was found with an increase from 9.3% to 10% accompanied by improvements in overall performance parameters such as short circuit density (J(sc)), open circuit voltage (V-oc) and fill factor (FF). These results indicate that an a-BTO thin film deposited using RF magnetron sputtering can be used as an alternative anti-reflection coating for Si based photovoltaic cells.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:22:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:22:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 5(74)59881-59886</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5ra07923c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18038</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>