<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11664</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>A mechanistic study on the thermal unfolding of cytochrome c in presence of 4-chlorobutan-1-ol: Differential scanning calorimetric and spectroscopic approach</dc:title><dc:creator>MEHTA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>partially folded state</dc:subject><dc:subject>molten-globule state</dc:subject><dc:subject>proton-resonance assignments</dc:subject><dc:subject>horse ferricytochrome-c</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-alkyl sulfates</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural-characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>denatured state</dc:subject><dc:subject>beta-sheet</dc:subject><dc:subject>trifluoroethanol</dc:subject><dc:description>Extensive studies have been carried out on thermal unfolding and conformational characterization of cytochrome c in the presence of 4-chlorobutan-1-ol at pH 4.0, 6.0 and 7.0 using micro differential scanning calorimetry, fluorescence, and circular dichroism measurements. Cytochrome c follows a simple two-state reversible thermal unfolding in the presence of low concentration (&lt;25 x 10(-3) mol dm(-3)) of the alcohol at pH 4.0 as reflected by equal calorimetric and van't Hoff enthalpies. However, at concentrations higher than 50 x 10(-3) mol dm(-3), the calorimetric transitions are irreversible and scan rate dependent, thus restricting the application of equilibrium thermodynamics. It has been observed that between 25 x 10(-3) mol dm(-3) and 50 x 10(-3) mol dm(-3) alcohol concentration, cytochrome c exists in two conformational states at pH 4.0 following N &amp;REVARR; E &amp;RARR; U unfolding mechanism, where N &amp;REVARR; E transition occurs at 67.6&amp;DEG;C and E &amp;RARR; U at 83.0&amp;DEG;C. The spectroscopic results indicate that the protein at 83.0&amp;DEG;C (where the second transition ends) in the presence of the alcohol is in the molten globule state. Quantitative thermodynamic parameters accompanying the thermal denaturation process have been evaluated. 4-Chlorobutan-1-ol has also been observed to induce cooperative thermal transitions in cytochrome c at pH 6.0 and 7.0 whereas in the absence of the alcohol, no thermal transition is observed. From the scan rate dependent irreversible thermal transitions, an average activation energy of 136 &amp;PLUSMN; 2 U mol(-1) has been calculated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T12:37:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T12:37:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 5(24), 5514-5522</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b311845b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11664</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11664</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>