<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16581</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:43:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis of meso-Pyrrole-Substituted 22-Oxacorroles by a '' 3+2 '' Approach</dc:title><dc:creator>KALITA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALITA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEE, WZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ABC-type corroles</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocompatible</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescent probes</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrrolyl-22-oxacorroles</dc:subject><dc:subject>UV</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vis spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORE-MODIFIED CORROLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>1ST EXAMPLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIPYRROMETHANES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SMARAGDYRINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONDENSATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Unsymmetrical 22-oxacorrole containing two aryl groups and one pyrrole group at the meso position was synthesized by condensing one equivalent of 16-oxatripyrrane with one equivalent of meso aryl dipyromethane under mild acid-catalyzed conditions followed by oxidation with 2,3-dichloro-5,6-dicyano-1,4-benzoquinone (DDQ). This [3+2] condensation approach was expected to yield meso-free 25-oxasmaragdyrin but unexpectedly afforded unsymmetrical meso-pyrrole-substituted 22-oxacorrole. We demonstrated the versatility of the reaction by synthesizing four new meso-pyrrole-substituted 22-oxacorroles. The reactivity of -position of meso-pyrrole was tested by carrying out various functionalization reactions such as bromination, formylation, and nitration and obtained the functionalized meso-pyrrole-substituted 22-oxacorroles in decent yields. The X-ray structure obtained for one of the functionalized meso-pyrrole substituted 22-oxacorrole revealed that the macrocycle was nearly planar and the meso-pyrrole was in the perpendicular orientation with respect to the macrocyclic plane. The meso-pyrrole-substituted 22-oxacorroles absorb strongly in 400-700nm region with one strong Soret band and four weak Q bands. The 22-oxacorroles are strongly fluorescent and showed emission maxima at approximate to 650nm with decent quantum yields and singlet-state lifetimes. The 22-oxacorroles are redox-active and exhibited three irreversible oxidations and one or two reversible reduction(s). A preliminary biological study indicated that meso-pyrrole corroles are biocompatible.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:43:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:43:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL, 20(33)10404-10413</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-6539</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1521-3765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/chem.201402710</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16581</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>