<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12134</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Patterns of recrystallization in warm- and hot-deformed AA6022</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVEENDRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNA, KVM</dc:creator><dc:creator>WEILAND, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>commercial purity aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>plane-strain compression</dc:subject><dc:subject>cold-rolled aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>texture development</dc:subject><dc:subject>cube texture</dc:subject><dc:subject>single-crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>fcc metals</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nucleation</dc:subject><dc:subject>orientation</dc:subject><dc:description>AA6022 samples were deformed at different temperatures and strain rates. Although deformation was immediately followed by quenching, as-deformed samples, especially samples subjected to higher deformation temperatures, contained a finite percentage of statically recrystallized grains. Crystallographic texture and microtexture measurements were employed to bring out developments in deformed and recrystallized microstructures and to outline the overall patterns of recrystallization. The latter was best represented through the so-called nucleation factor, an estimate of an orientation-sensitive nucleation. For a given orientation, nucleation factors were measured as the number of recrystallized grains divided by the number of deformed bands. With an increase in deformation temperatures, the dominance in nucleation appeared to have changed from cube {001}&lt; 100 &gt; to particle-stimulated nucleation (PSN) to cube again and, finally, to no preference. Relative stored-energy differences, with respect to working temperatures, explain the observed patterns in the orientation-sensitive nucleation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T16:33:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T16:33:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 39A(11), 2760-2771</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-008-9620-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12134</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12134</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>