<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7567</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>An adaptive approach in distance protection using an artificial neural network</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>WARKE, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, SH</dc:creator><dc:subject>transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>transmission line protection</dc:subject><dc:subject>adaptive protection schemes</dc:subject><dc:subject>neural networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>relay protection</dc:subject><dc:subject>distance protection schemes</dc:subject><dc:description>All relay settings are a compromise. Adaptive relaying accepts that relays that protect a power system may need to change their characteristics to suit the prevailing power system conditions. This philosophy has a wide range of applications covering many protective schemes. Here we consider a two-terminal transmission line, confirm that fault resistance and the location of faults can produce erroneous relay function and finally suggest ways to ensure the generation of the correct signal for relay operation. Retaining the microprocessor based framework, we show how artificial neural networks (ANNs) can be used effectively to achieve adaptive relaying for the above-mentioned problem. Adaptive relaying covers a large number of applications and the characteristics of relays vary widely, so the philosophy of adaptive relaying must vary accordingly. A modified multilayered perceptron model employs an additional node in the input layer. This additional input facilitates changes in the relay characteristic. The desired change in the quadrilateral relay characteristic is achieved by making appropriate changes in the thresholds and weights of the hidden layer neurons. A multiparameter adaptive scheme assumes that the additional input of the phase angle is available. Simulation results using ANNs for the different applications of adaptive relaying mentioned above are presented and discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T03:26:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T03:26:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ELECTRIC POWER SYSTEMS RESEARCH, 37(1), 39-44</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0378-7796</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0378-7796(96)01040-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7567</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7567</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>