<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4203</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic Stability Analysis of a Tethered Aerostat</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJANI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANT, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUDHAKAR, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes a model that has been developed to study the stability characteristics of aerostats. This model incorporates the concepts of apparent mass, dynamic tether and allows 6 degrees of freedom for the motion of the aerostat. Estimation of aerodynamic coefficients is based on empirical relations and curves available in literature. Weight and buoyancy are calculated based on geometry of the aerostat. Appropriate values for operational altitude and desired angle of attack of the aerostat are assumed. Moment balance about confluence point gives the optimal location of the confluence point. Equations of motion for the aerostat and dynamic tether are simulated and appropriate boundary conditions are applied. Force balance gives the tether tension force and its orientation at the confluence point. Based on the tether tension and its orientation at the confluence point, the tether profile is estimated by breaking up the tether into several elastic segments, each in equilibrium. Once equilibrium is established, the wind is perturbed and the response of the aerostat is simulated. The paper reports the results of simulation carried out for the TCOM 365Y aerostat and the aerostat response to various ambient velocity profiles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUT ASTRONAUT</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T08:35:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T08:35:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF AIRCRAFT, 47(5), 1531-1538</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/1.47010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4203</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>