<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16315</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:06:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of strongly coupled plasma on photoionization cross section</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>DENSE-PLASMAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEBYE PLASMA</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATOMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POTENTIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LI</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of strongly coupled plasma on the ground state photoionization cross section is studied. In the non relativistic dipole approximation, cross section is evaluated from bound-free transition matrix element. The bound and free state wave functions are obtained by solving the radial Schrodinger equation with appropriate plasma potential. We have used ion sphere potential (ISP) to incorporate the plasma effects in atomic structure calculation. This potential includes the effect of static plasma screening on nuclear charge as well as the effect of confinement due to the neighbouring ions. With ISP, the radial equation is solved using Shooting method approach for hydrogen like ions (Li+2, C+5, Al+12) and lithium like ions (C+3, O+5). The effect of strong screening and confinement is manifested as confinement resonances near the ionization threshold for both kinds of ions. The confinement resonances are very much dependent on the edge of the confining potential and die out as the plasma density is increased. Plasma effect also results in appearance of Cooper minimum in lithium like ions, which was not present in case of free lithium like ions. With increasing density the position of Cooper minimum shifts towards higher photoelectron energy. The same behaviour is also true for weakly coupled plasma where plasma effect is modelled by Debye-Huckel potential. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:06:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:06:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICS OF PLASMAS, 21(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1070-664X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4862550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16315</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>