<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9606</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design and experimental evaluation of simultaneous periodic output feedback control for piezoelectric actuated beam structure</dc:title><dc:creator>EZHILARASI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>UMAPATHY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>simultaneous stabilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration control</dc:subject><dc:subject>smart structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>smart structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoelectric</dc:subject><dc:subject>simultaneous control</dc:subject><dc:subject>periodic output feedback</dc:subject><dc:subject>system identification</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the design and experimental implementation of a simultaneous periodic output feedback controller to minimize structural vibration using collocated piezoelectric actuator and sensor. The linear dynamic model of piezoelectric-bonded cantilever beams is obtained using online recursive least-square parameter estimation. A digital control system that consists of simulink modelling software and dSPACE 1104 controller board is used for identification and control. The performance of simultaneous controller is evaluated by considering a cantilever beam structure of three different lengths and mass. The effectiveness of the controller is demonstrated experimentally by exciting the structures at resonance. The advantage of the simultaneous periodic output feedback controller implemented in this paper is unique in the sense that the common controller gain reduces the first two vibration modes of three plants, which is not commonly shown in the literature with other feedback controllers. From the experimental results it is observed that with the simultaneous output feedback controller the vibration reduction is approximately 75% for the first mode and 60% for the second mode for all the three plants. Copyright (C) 2008 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T19:56:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T19:56:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STRUCTURAL CONTROL &amp; HEALTH MONITORING, 16(3), 335-349</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1545-2255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/stc.258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9606</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>