<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15431</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:27:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nanocrystal-based Ohmic contacts on n and p-type germanium</dc:title><dc:creator>KISHORE, VP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARAMAHANS, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SADANA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>LODHA, S</dc:creator><dc:description>We report a simple method of forming Ohmic contacts to n and p-type germanium (Ge) simultaneously using Au nanocrystals embedded in Ti contact metal. The electric field due to the work-function difference of Ti and Au reduces the tunneling resistance at the Ti-Au/Ge interface for n and p-type contacts. The nanocrystal-based contacts on n-Ge exhibit quasi-Ohmic current-voltage characteristics with &gt;1000x increase in current density and an apparent reduction of 0.18 eV in the barrier height over Ti/n-Ge and Au/n-Ge contacts that show rectifying characteristics due to Fermi level pinning. On n(+)Ge, the nanocrystal-based contacts exhibit Ohmic characteristics with &gt;35x reduction in zero-bias resistance over Ti/n(+)Ge contacts. Similar to Ti and Au contacts on p-Ge, Au nanocrystals embedded in Ti continue to exhibit Ohmic characteristics. This is in contrast to methods that convert p-type contacts from Ohmic to rectifying in the process of forming an Ohmic contact on n-Ge by inserting a thin dielectric layer between the metal and Ge. Device simulations reinforce the observed decrease in tunneling resistance due to the enhanced electric field at the Ti-Au/Ge interface. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3700965]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:27:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:27:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 100(14)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1077-3118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3700965</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15431</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>