<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9013</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>FT-IR spectroscopic investigation of hydrous components in sillimanite from Eastern Ghat Granulite Belt, India</dc:title><dc:creator>KARANTH, RV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:subject>high-temperature behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>boron</dc:subject><dc:subject>ft-ir</dc:subject><dc:subject>sillimanite</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrous</dc:subject><dc:subject>boron</dc:subject><dc:subject>granulite</dc:subject><dc:subject>metamorphism</dc:subject><dc:description>FT-IR spectra of sillimanite samples from high grade regionally metamorphosed rocks belonging to the granulite terrain (amphibolite to pyroxene granulite facies) deciphers prominent OH features. Heating experiments indicate growth of prominent band at 3161cm(-1). Heating above 1000 degrees C all OH features disappear in intensity into broad features with slight shift of bands towards lower energies. Complete dehydration requires temperatures above 1000 degrees C. Coexistence of boron and OH features are also observed in all sillimanite samples. The high temperature behaviour of sillimanite from the granulite terrain discerns that the hydrous species in sillimanite were incorporated much below 700 degrees C, however, secondary hydration due to pegmatite activity retrograde metamorphism and migmatisation is not ruled out. Thus a near anhydrous condition were probably not achieved during the granulite facies metamorphism in Eastern ghat granulite terrain.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INT ASSOC GONDWANA RESEARCH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T11:43:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T11:43:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GONDWANA RESEARCH, 2(1), 89-94</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1342-937X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1342-937X(05)70129-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9013</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>