<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17059</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T18:03:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>A dual grid level set method based study of interface-dynamics for a liquid jet injected upwards into another liquid</dc:title><dc:creator>LAKDAWALA, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>GADA, VH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Level set method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Periodic uniform drop formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quasi-periodic non-uniform drop formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chaotic non-uniform drop formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Co-flowing jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>INCOMPRESSIBLE 2-PHASE FLOWS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINEAR CAPILLARY INSTABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DROP FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PINCH-OFF</dc:subject><dc:subject>SATELLITE FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMMISCIBLE LIQUIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISCOUS FLOWS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAMINAR-FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUID METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREAKUP</dc:subject><dc:description>Dynamics and breakup of an axi-symmetric liquid jet injected upwards into another stationary or co-flowing immiscible liquid is investigated numerically. Simulations are done using an in-house code based on a novel DGLSM (dual grid level set method). Furthermore, a novel procedure - based upon physical interpretation of the various functions in Level Set Method - is demonstrated here as a powerful numerical tool to calculate certain parameters (diameter as well as frequency of drop formation and temporal variation of jet length at the axis), which characterize the unsteady interface-dynamics. Six different combination of the dispersed and continuous fluid are subjected to various injection velocity, resulting in a large variation in the non-dimensional governing parameters such as viscosity-ratio and Weber number. From the temporal variation of jet length and instantaneous interface, three drop formation regimes are proposed: Periodic Uniform Drop formation (P-UD), Quasi-Periodic Non-Uniform Drop formation (QP-NUD) and Chaotic Non-Uniform Drop formation (C-NUD); demarcated in a drop formation regime map for various Weber number and viscosity ratio. Their effect on the mean value of jet breakup length (L-d (m)), detached drop diameter (D-d m) and drop formation frequency (St(m)) is also studied. After a more detailed study on stationary continuous fluid, the effect of co-flowing continuous fluid is studied; and is found to stabilize the drop formation regime and increase the frequency of drop formation. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:03:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:03:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MULTIPHASE FLOW, 59206-220</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-9322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-3533</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijmultiphaseflow.2013.11.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17059</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>