<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14355</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T10:02:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>SAR interferometric coherence analysis for snow cover mapping in the western Himalayan region</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>DIFFERENTIAL RADAR INTERFEROMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>AREAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>InSAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>coherence</dc:subject><dc:subject>snow cover</dc:subject><dc:subject>digital earth</dc:subject><dc:subject>microwave remote sensing</dc:subject><dc:description>Information of snow cover (SC) over Himalayan regions is very important for regional climatological and hydrological studies. Precise monitoring of SC in the Himalayan region is essential for water supply to hydropower stations, irrigation requirements, and flood forecasting. Microwave remote sensing has all weather, day and night earth observation capability unlike optical remote sensing. In this study, spaceborne synthetic aperture radar interferometric (InSAR) coherence analysis is used to monitor SC over Himalayan rugged terrain. The feasibility of monitoring SC using synthetic aperture radar (SAR) interferometry depends on the ability to maintain coherence over InSAR pair acquisition time interval. ERS-1/2 InSAR coherence and ENVISAT ASAR InSAR coherence images are analyzed for SC mapping. Data sets of winter and of snow free months of the Himalayan region are taken for interferogram generation. Coherence images of the available data sets show maximum decorrelation in most of the area which indicates massive snowfall in the region in the winter season and melting in the summer. Area showing coherence loss due to decorrelation is mapped as a snow-covered area. The result is validated with field observations of snow depth and it is found that standing snow is inversely related to coherence in the Himalayan region.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T10:02:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T10:02:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF DIGITAL EARTH,4(1)78-90</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1753-8947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17538940903521591</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14355</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>