<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2686</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Programmable hybrid mechanisms</dc:title><dc:creator>SETH, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>cam-follower systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>function generators</dc:subject><dc:subject>coupler curves</dc:subject><dc:subject>actuator</dc:subject><dc:subject>motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>speed</dc:subject><dc:subject>programmable mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid machines</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>servo actuator</dc:subject><dc:subject>function generator</dc:subject><dc:description>A programmable hybrid mechanism (PHM) is a combination of a servomechanism with a conventionally driven mechanism and has the potential to combine the advantages of both. A PHM can generate the output movement that is possible in a conventional mechanism and also permit these movements to be modulated using the servo-actuator. PHMs can offer batch-to-batch or even cycle-to-cycle programmability and thus allow development of machines that are capable of handling wider variations in products without incurring delays due to setups. A PHM can provide better tuning of motion characteristics than those obtainable from servomechanisms alone. It has also been claimed that due to the sharing of power between the main drive and the servo drive, the power rating necessary for the servo actuator can be lowered, thus offering a cost advantage compared to the system using only the servo-drive. Research work reported in this emerging area of research has been reviewed here.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CHINA MACHINE PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T19:15:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T19:15:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ELEVENTH WORLD CONGRESS IN MECHANISM AND MACHINE SCIENCE, VOLS 1-5, PROCEEDINGS,1146-1150</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>7-111-14073-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2686</dc:identifier><dc:source>11th World Congress in Mechanism and Machine Science,Tianjin, PEOPLES R CHINA,APR 01-04, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>