<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8696</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Relationship between power law coefficients and major blood constituents affecting the whole blood viscosity</dc:title><dc:creator>HUSSAIN, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:subject>cerebrovascular accidents</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantification</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformability</dc:subject><dc:subject>abnormalities</dc:subject><dc:subject>membrane</dc:subject><dc:subject>cerebrovascular accidents (cva)</dc:subject><dc:subject>blood viscosity</dc:subject><dc:subject>power law</dc:subject><dc:subject>haematocrit</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibrinogen</dc:subject><dc:subject>cholesterol</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work concerns a quantitative analysis of parameters that affect apparent blood viscosity at different low shear rates, i.e, between 1 s(-1) and, 100 s(-1). Viscosity profile of a large number of blood samples from thromboembolic stroke cases and age and sex matched healthy controls were studied which confirmed non-Newtonian power law behaviour of blood. The power law coefficients, n and k, which are unique to each blood sample, were related with blood viscosity parameters in the form of a mathematical equation by performing nonlinear regression analysis. It was possible to calculate n and k of power law model by supplying the values of major blood constituents in the equation obtained for stroke and controls. The calculation of n and k of a blood sample using the equation obtained, provided a quick information on its apparent viscosity values at any given shear rate without viscometry. The calculated and the experimental viscosity were found in good agreement within a permissible error range. The relation obtained between power law coefficients and major blood constituents in the present investigation would give a quantification of different blood viscosity parameters contributing to the resistance to flow of blood. Such an analysis may be considered as a scientific basis for the study of blood fluidity in different disease conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T06:48:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T06:48:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES, 24(3), 329-337</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0250-5991</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02941247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8696</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8696</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>