<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18227</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:02:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>An Adaptive General Four-Component Scattering Power Decomposition With Unitary Transformation of Coherency Matrix (AG4U)</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANICKAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>YAMAGUCHI, Y</dc:creator><dc:subject>MODEL-BASED DECOMPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAR DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decomposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>polarimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthetic aperture radar (SAR)</dc:subject><dc:subject>unitary transformation</dc:subject><dc:description>An adaptive general four-component scattering power decomposition method (AG4U) is proposed in this letter. The degree of polarization m is used as a criterion for the adaptive nature of the proposed decomposition. In this method, one among the two complex special unitary transformation matrices is chosen to transform a real unitary rotated coherency matrix based on the largest value of m. This transformed matrix is then utilized for the existing Yamaguchi et al. four-component decomposition scheme with an extended volume scattering model. The proposed decomposition is applied to Radarsat-2 full-polarimetic C-band data over San Francisco and Uninhabited Aerial Vehicle Synthetic Aperture Radar (UAVSAR) full-polarimetric L-band data over the Hayward Fault in California. The scattering powers estimated from the decomposition techniques of Yamaguchi et al. (Y4O), Singh et al. (G4U), and AG4U are compared. AG4U shows appreciable improvements in the scattering powers, particularly in urban areas oriented about the radar line of sight compared with the Y4O and G4U decompositions. It also shows reduced percentage of pixels with negative powers considerably compared with the Y4O decomposition.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:02:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:02:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING LETTERS, 12(10)2110-2114</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1545-598X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-0571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/LGRS.2015.2451369</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18227</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>