<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14213</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:44:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of coal/solid recovered fuel (SRF) with coal/refuse derived fuel (RDF) in a fluidised bed reactor</dc:title><dc:creator>WAGLAND, ST</dc:creator><dc:creator>KILGALLON, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>COVENEY, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SMITH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>LONGHURST, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>POLLARD, SJT</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIMMS, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>FIRED POWER-PLANT</dc:subject><dc:subject>BITUMINOUS COAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEWAGE-SLUDGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUE-GAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMBUSTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COCOMBUSTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MERCURY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental study was undertaken to compare the differences between municipal solid waste (MSW) derived solid recovered fuel (SRF) (complying with CEN standards) and refuse derived fuel (RDF). Both fuels were co-combusted with coal in a 50 kW fluidised bed combustor and the metal emissions were compared. Synthetic SRF was prepared in the laboratory by grinding major constituents of MSW such as paper, plastic, textile and wood. RDF was obtained from a local mechanical treatment plant. Heavy metal emissions in flue gas and ash samples from the (coal + 10% SRF) fuel mixture were found to be within the acceptable range and were generally lower than that obtained for coal + 10% RDF fuel mixture. The relative distribution of heavy metals in ash components and the flue gas stream shows the presence of a large fraction (up to 98%) of most of the metals in the ash (except Hg and As). Thermo-gravimetric (TG) analysis of SRF constituents was performed to understand the behaviour of fuel mixtures in the absence and presence of air. The results obtained from the experimental study will enhance the confidence of fuel users towards using MSW-derived SRF as an alternative fuel. Crown Copyright (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:44:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:44:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WASTE MANAGEMENT,31(6)1176-1183</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0956-053X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.wasman.2011.01.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14213</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>