<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15517</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T07:10:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>The influence of expert opinions on the selection of wastewater treatment alternatives: A group decision-making approach</dc:title><dc:creator>KALBAR, PP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARMAKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASOLEKAR, SR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wastewater treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Group decision-making</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiple-attribute decision-making</dc:subject><dc:subject>Analytical hierarchy process</dc:subject><dc:subject>Life cycle assessment</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANALYTIC HIERARCHY PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRIORITIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>JUDGMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATRICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOPSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AHP</dc:subject><dc:description>The application of multiple-attribute decision-making (MADM) to real life decision problems suggests that avoiding the loss of information through scenario-based approaches and including expert opinions in the decision-making process are two major challenges that require more research efforts. Recently, a wastewater treatment technology selection effort has been made with a 'scenario-based' method of MADM. This paper focuses on a novel approach to incorporate expert opinions into the scenario-based decision-making process, as expert opinions play a major role in the selection of treatment technologies. The sets of criteria and the indicators that are used consist of both qualitative and quantitative criteria. The group decision-making (GDM) approach that is implemented for aggregating expert opinions is based on an analytical hierarchy process (AHP), which is the most widely used MADM method. The pairwise comparison matrices (PCMs) for qualitative criteria are formed based on expert opinions, whereas, a novel approach is proposed for generating PCMs for quantitative criteria. It has been determined that the experts largely prefer natural treatment systems because they are more sustainable in any scenario. However, PCMs based on expert opinions suggest that advanced technologies such as the sequencing batch reactor (SBR) can also be appropriate for a given decision scenario. The proposed GDM approach is a rationalized process that will be more appropriate in realistic scenarios where multiple stakeholders with local and regional societal priorities are involved in the selection of treatment technology. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T07:10:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T07:10:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ENVIRONMENTAL MANAGEMENT, 128844-851</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-4797</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1095-8630</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2013.06.034</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15517</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>