<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18168</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:30:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mesoscopic quantum superposition of the generalized cat state: A diffraction limit</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANIGRAHI, PK</dc:creator><dc:subject>PHASE-SPACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTON DISTRIBUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SQUEEZED STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFERENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OSCILLATIONS</dc:subject><dc:description>The orthogonality of cat and displaced cat states, underlying Heisenberg limited measurement in quantum metrology, is studied in the limit of a large number of states. The mesoscopic superposition of the generalized cat state is correlated with the corresponding state overlap function, controlled by the sub-Planck structures arising from phase-space interference. The asymptotic expression of this overlap function is evaluated, and the validity of large phase-space support and distinguishability of the constituent states, in which context the asymptotic limit is achieved, are discussed in detail. For a large number of coherent states, uniformly located on a circle, the overlap function significantly matches the diffraction pattern for a circular ring source with uniform angular strength. This is in accordance with the van Cittert-Zernike theorem, where the overlap function, similar to the mutual coherence function, matches a diffraction pattern. The physical situation under consideration is delineated in phase space by utilizing the Husimi Q function.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:30:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:30:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW A, 92(5)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1050-2947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1094-1622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.92.053819</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18168</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>