<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16233</identifier><datestamp>2014-11-21T12:37:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization and Optimal Designs for Choice Experiments</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAI, FENG-SHUN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, ASHISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANNA, SOUMEN</dc:creator><dc:subject>choice sets</dc:subject><dc:subject>choice design</dc:subject><dc:subject>factorial design</dc:subject><dc:subject>main effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hadamard matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>orthogonal array</dc:subject><dc:description>Street and Burgess (2007) present a comprehensive exposition of designs for choice experiments till then. The choice design involves $n$ attributes (factors) with $i$-th attribute at $l_i$ level, and all choice sets are of size $m$. A choice design comprises $N$ such choice sets. Recently, Demirkale, Donovan and Street (2013) considered the setup of symmetric factorials ($l_i=l$) and obtained $D$-optimal choice designs under main effects model. They provide some sufficient conditions for a designs to be $D$-optimal. In this paper, we first derive a slightly modified Information matrix of a choice design for estimating the factorial effects of a $l_1 \times l_2 \times \cdots \times l_n$ choice experiment. It is seen that such a modification gives the Information matrix the desired additive property and thus, overcomes the existing shortcoming of situations where, with addition of a choice set the information content of the design decreases. While comparing designs with different $N$, we see that one needs to work with the modified information matrix. For a $2^n$ choice experiment, under the main effects model, we give a simple necessary and sufficient condition for the Information matrix to be diagonal. Furthermore, we characterize the structure of the choice sets which gives maximum $trace$ of the Information matrix. Our characterization of such an Information matrix facilitates construction of universally optimal designs with minimal number of choice sets and gives more flexibility for choosing $m$. Finally, we provide universally optimal choice designs for estimating main effects, which are optimal in the class of all designs with given $N$, $n$ and $m$.</dc:description><dc:date>2014-11-21T12:37:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-11-21T12:37:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-11-21</dc:date><dc:type>Technical Report</dc:type><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16233</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>