<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14927</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:48:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Vibtrational energy harvesting using photo-patternable piezoelectric nanocomposite cantilevers</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASHANTHI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MIRIYALA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAIKWAD, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOUSSA, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>THUNDAT, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>Energy harvesting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Micro Electra Mechanical Systems (MEMS)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanocomposites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Piezoelectric</dc:subject><dc:subject>SU-8 polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZnO</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNO NANOWIRE ARRAYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILM</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOGENERATOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER</dc:subject><dc:description>Here we report on fabricating photo-patternable polymer nanocomposite cantilevers for harvesting electrical energy from mechanical vibrations. The optimized piezoelectric polymer nanocomposite enables direct photo patterning and, therefore, easy fabrication of microcantilevers eliminating expensive etching steps. Integrating piezoelectric zinc oxide (ZnO) nanopartides (NPs) with optimum weight fraction into a photosensitive SU-8 polymer matrix not only retains the highly desired piezoelectric and semiconducting properties of the ZnO, but also combines the photo-patternability and the optical transparency of the SU-8. The maximum output power produced by nanocomposite cantilevers was 0.025 mu W across a resistive load of 100 k Omega with peak to peak voltage of similar to 140 mV at a resonance frequency of 4 kHz. This inexpensive platform offers design flexibility and ease of fabrication for harvesting mechanical vibrations. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:48:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:48:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANO ENERGY, 2(5)923-932</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2013.03.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14927</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>