<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10192</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of multistep aging on the stress corrosion cracking behavior of aluminum alloy 7010</dc:title><dc:creator>BOBBY-KANNAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>series aluminum-alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>cleavage fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>7010 aluminum alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>slow strain rate testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress corrosion cracking</dc:subject><dc:description>The role of multistep aging on the stress corrosion cracking (SCC) behavior of aluminum alloy 7010 has been investigated. The material in the form of 5-mm-thick sheets was heat-treated to two different tempers. The heat treatments are peak-aged. obtained by a two-step aging (i.e., solution treated at 465 degreesC. water quenched at room temperature, and aged at 100 degreesC/8 h and 120 degreesC/8 h) and over-aged, obtained by a three-step aging (i.e.. solution treated at 465 degreesC, water quenched at room temperature, and aged at 100 degreesC/8 h followed by 120 degreesC/8 h and 170 degreesC/8 h). SCC behavior was investigated using slow strain rate testing (SSRT) in air and 3.5% sodium chloride (NaCl) solution (environment). U-bend testing was carried out as a qualitative test. SSRT results show a remarkable improvement in the SCC resistance in three-step aged samples. For example, the percent reduction in area dropped from 28.1% (in air) to just 24.4% (in environment), and there was no drop in the percent elongation (similar to10%) when tested at a strain rate of 10(-6)/s. Two-step aged samples were found to be inferior compared with the three-step aged sample-the percent reduction in area of two-step aged samples dropped from 9.9% (in air) to 3.3% (in environment) and percent of elongation dropped from 10% (in air) to 3% (in environment). U-bend test results are also in conformity with the SSRT results, showing high resistance to SCC in the three-step aged alloy, though no direct correlation can be made. Anodic dissolution along the grain boundaries leading to intergranular cracking was evident in the SSRT and U-bend fractured specimens of the two-step aged alloy, whereas, such an attack was less prominent in the three-step aged alloy leading to a relatively more ductile fracture. The breaking of grain boundary precipitate network in the three-step aged condition could be a possible reason for better SCC resistance of the three-step aged alloy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ASSN CORROSION ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T02:09:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T02:09:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CORROSION, 59(10), 881-889</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0010-9312</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10192</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10192</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>