<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15798</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:35:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Upper Bounds on the Capacity of Binary Channels With Causal Adversaries</dc:title><dc:creator>DEY, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAGGI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LANGBERG, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARWATE, AD</dc:creator><dc:subject>Arbitrarily varying channels (AVCs)</dc:subject><dc:subject>channel coding</dc:subject><dc:subject>jamming</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBABILITY FUNCTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMMUNICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we consider the communication of information in the presence of a causal adversarial jammer. In the setting under study, a sender wishes to communicate a message to a receiver by transmitting a codeword x = (x(1),..., x(n)) bit-by-bit over a communication channel. The sender and the receiver do not share common randomness. The adversarial jammer can view the transmitted bits x(i) one at a time and can change up to a p-fraction of them. However, the decisions of the jammer must be made in a causal manner. Namely, for each bit x(i), the jammer's decision on whether to corrupt it or not must depend only on x(j) for j &lt;= i. This is in contrast to the "classical" adversarial jamming situations in which the jammer has no knowledge of x, or knows x completely. In this study, we present upper bounds (that hold under both the average and maximal probability of error criteria) on the capacity which hold for both deterministic and stochastic encoding schemes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:35:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:35:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INFORMATION THEORY, 59(6)3753-3763</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIT.2013.2245721</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15798</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>