<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9754</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrochemical studies of kerosene-pyrolysed carbon films</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KICHAMBARE, PD</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEUMANN-SPALLART, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>polycrystalline diamond film</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>conducting carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemical</dc:subject><dc:subject>kerosene</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin film</dc:subject><dc:description>Polycrystalline thin films of conducting carbon are deposited on alumina substrates by the pyrolysis of kerosene vapour at 1000 degrees C for 2 h in argon atmosphere. Preliminary structural analysis is done by XRD, laser-Raman, FTIR and SEM studies. The electrochemical behaviour of as-grown conducting carbon films was investigated in various electrolytes at different pH and the performance was compared with that of platinum and glassy electrodes. The electrochemical window of the kerosene carbon electrode in 100 mM H2SO4 was found to be 2.91 V which is greater than that of glassy carbon (2.79 V) and platinum (2.02 V). Cyclic voltammetry reveals that Pt electrode has almost an equal tendency towards hydrogen and oxygen evolution, whereas glassy carbon favours hydrogen evolution and kerosene carbon favours oxygen evolution. It is suggested that the kerosene carbon electrode can be used as an oxygen electrode more efficiently. Unlike diamond films or glassy electrodes, kerosene carbon thin films are of low cost and good stability; they are also easy to grow on various ceramic substrates of any size. Moreover, these electrodes are very economical and promising for application in chlor-alkali industry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:06:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:06:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED ELECTROCHEMISTRY, 28(12), 1399-1403</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-891X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1003476125326</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9754</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9754</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>