<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6289</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Understanding interfacial polycondensation: Experiments on polyurea system and comparison with theory</dc:title><dc:creator>DHUMAL, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>composite reverse-osmosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyamide microcapsules</dc:subject><dc:subject>controlled release</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyarylate</dc:subject><dc:subject>microencapsulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanocomposites</dc:subject><dc:subject>interfacial polycondensation</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyurea</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular weight distribution</dc:subject><dc:description>Interfacial polycondensation, with its multiphase character and the involvement of several rate and equilibrium processes, presents unique challenges to our ability to understand and design processes for achieving desired properties. In a recent study [1], we have presented a detailed model for the process and shown that it explains the salient features as reported in the literature for several interfacial systems. In the present paper, we report extensive experimental studies on the polyurea system and their comparison with the model. Two geometries - the spherical geometry of the microcapsule and the flat-film geometry - have been used to study qualitative and quantitative features of the polycondensation and the nature of the film that forms. While some aspects, such as the manner in which the solvent influences the kinetics, confirm earlier findings, inadequacies have been identified in the sample preparation protocols followed in earlier work, because of which property estimations may carry a large error. Improved protocols have accordingly been developed and used to study the development of film properties in time and as a function of the important preparation variables. Detailed molecular weight distributions have been determined using a GPC technique and used to derive important properties of the polyurea (such as Mark-Houwink parameters) as well as to gain insights into mechanisms. The data have been used to determine the rate parameters in the Dhumal and Suresh [1] model. The predictions of the model, as far as trends are concerned, are shown to be satisfactory given the level of uncertainty about parameter values and the complexity of the system being studied. Where discrepancies exist, the reasons have been established and the areas for improvement of the model identified. The findings reported are of interest to applications such as controlled release and membrane separations, in which permeation rate through the membrane is of importance and depends upon various membrane properties like crystallinity, morphology, etc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T16:29:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T16:29:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER, 51(5), 1176-1190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3861</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.polymer.2010.01.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6289</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6289</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>