<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16367</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:32:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Role of dual nuclear baths on spin blockade leakage current bistabilities</dc:title><dc:creator>BUDDHIRAJU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURALIDHARAN, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>spin blockade</dc:subject><dc:subject>double quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:subject>electronic transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUANTUM DOTS</dc:subject><dc:description>Spin-blockaded electronic transport across a double quantum dot (DQD) system represents an important advancement in the area of spin-based quantum information. The basic mechanism underlying the blockade is the formation of a blocking triplet state. The bistability of the leakage current as a function of the applied magnetic field in this regime is believed to arise from the effect of nuclear Overhauser fields on spin-flip transitions between the blocking triplet and the conducting singlet states. The objective of this paper is to present the nuances of considering a two bath model on the experimentally observed current bistability by employing a self consistent simulation of the nuclear spin dynamics coupled with the electronic transport of the DQD set up. In doing so, we first discuss the important subtleties involved in the microscopic derivation of the hyperfine mediated spin flip rates. We then give insights as to how the differences between the two nuclear baths and the resulting difference Overhauser field affect the two-electron states of the DQD and their connection with the experimentally observed current hysteresis curve.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:32:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:32:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 26(48)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-648X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/26/48/485302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16367</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>