<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10959</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Integrating standard transactions in firm real-time database systems</dc:title><dc:creator>THOMAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHADRI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARITSA, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>real-time database</dc:subject><dc:subject>concurrency control</dc:subject><dc:description>Real-time database systems are designed to handle workloads where transactions have completion deadlines and the goal is to meet these deadlines. However, many real-time database environments are characterized by workloads that are a mix of real-time and standard (non-real-time) transactions. Unfortunately, the system policies used to meet the performance goals of real-time transactions often work poorly for standard transactions. In particular, optimistic concurrency control algorithms are recommended for real-time transactions, whereas locking-based protocols are suited for standard transactions. In this paper, we present a new database system architecture in which realtime transactions use optimistic concurrency control and, simultaneously, standard transactions use locking. We prove that our architecture maintains data integrity and show, through a simulation study, that it provides significantly improved performance for the standard transactions without diminishing the real-time transaction performance. We also show, more generally, that the proposed architecture correctly supports the co-existence of any group of concurrency control algorithms that adhere to a standard interface.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T08:47:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T08:47:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INFORMATION SYSTEMS, 21(1), 3-28</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-4379</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0306-4379(96)00002-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10959</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10959</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>