<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12795</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>2-(4 ',4 '-dimethyl-3 ',4 '-dihydrooxazol-2 '-yl)phenol: Some first-row transition metal complexes of this naturally occurring binding group</dc:title><dc:creator>MUGESH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTCHER, RJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>cobalt(ii)-substituted zinc metalloenzymes</dc:subject><dc:subject>monomeric selenolato complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>im = imidazole</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>coordination behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>r= ch3</dc:subject><dc:subject>ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>se</dc:subject><dc:subject>n,n-dimethylbenzylamine</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxazolines</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal assisted hydrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen bonds</dc:subject><dc:subject>chirality</dc:subject><dc:subject>siderophores</dc:subject><dc:description>The synthesis and characterization of monomeric Mn-III, Co-II Ni-II, Cu-II, and Zn-II phenolates derived from a biologically relevant ligand, 2-(4',4'-dimethyl-3',4'-dihydrooxazol-2'-yl)phenol (1), are described. The addition of Mn(OAc)(2). 4H(2)O to an ethanolic solution of 1 affords an unexpected 1:3 complex [Mn(OR){O(Ox)}(2)] (2) [R = C6H4CONHC(Me-2) CH2OH, Ox = 2-(4,4-dimethyl-2-oxazolinyl)phenyl] in which one of the five-membered oxazoline rings is partially hydrolyzed. The complexes [M{O(Ox)}(2)] [M = Co (3), Ni (4), Cu (6), or Zn (7)] were prepared in good yield by the reactions of 1 with the corresponding metal acetates. Novel formation of the six-coordinate NP complex 5 with neutral acetic acid was observed during the crystallization process. The complexes were characterized by elemental analysis, magnetic susceptibility, as well as EPR, H-1 NMR, electronic, and mass spectral techniques. Complexes 2, 3, 5, 6, and 7 were characterized by single crystal X-ray diffraction studies. Complex 2 is six-coordinate whereas complexes 3, 6, and 7 are four-coordinate with two oxazoline bidentate Ligands. The geometry around the metal center is found to be distorted tetrahedral for all of the four-coordinate complexes. Complex 5 is octahedral with four coordination sites occupied by the two bidentate oxazoline Ligands and the other two are occupied by two neutral acetic acid molecules. The hydroxy groups of the coordinated acetic acid are hydrogen-bonded to the phenolate oxygen atoms of the oxazoline ligands. The variable-temperature H-1 NMR spectroscopic studies of complex 7 indicate that the interconversion between the (M) and (P) helix is slow at low temperatures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-09-01T13:50:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-09-01T13:50:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, (3), 669-678</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1434-1948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12795</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12795</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>