<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12837</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic and magnetotransport properties in (LaxSm1-x)(2/3)Sr1/3MnO3 (x=1/3, 1/2 and 2/3) manganites</dc:title><dc:creator>ASTHANA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>cation</dc:subject><dc:subject>size</dc:subject><dc:description>The magnetic and transport properties of (LaxSm1-x)(2/3)Sr1/3MnO3 (x = 1/3, 1/2 and 2/3) manganites, prepared by the citrate-gel route, have been investigated. These compounds are found to crystallize in the orthorhombic structure. The hopping between Mn3+ and Mn4+ sites is controlled by the Mn-O-Mn bond angle. The magnetoresistance in 8.5 kOe fields varies from 15 to 25 percent over the temperature range 300 K to 80 K. The conduction mechanism can be understood by using the correlated small polaron model. The metal-insulator as well as magnetic transition temperatures are close to each other, which indicates the dominance of long-range ferromagnetic ordering in the present system. At low temperatures, a weak ferromagnetic to antiferromagnetic transition is indicated, which could be due to competing super-exchange and double exchange interactions. The charge localization at lower temperatures could be the possible explanation for increasing magnetoresistance. The maximum magnetic moment at 5 K, for all the samples is similar to 3.6 mu(B)/Mn, which is close to the 3.7 mu(B)/Mn, as obtained by considering the Mn spins only. (c) 2006 WILEY-VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KGaA, Weinheim.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-09-01T18:16:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-09-01T18:16:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS, 243(8), 1922-1928</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0370-1972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pssb.200541167</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12837</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12837</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>