<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2660</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>On design and implementation of an Embedded automatic speech recognition system</dc:title><dc:creator>PHADKE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIMAYE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAMANIAN, K</dc:creator><dc:description>We present a new design of an Embedded Speech Recognition System. It combines the aspects of both hardware and software design to implement a speaker dependent, isolated word, small vocabulary speech recognition system. The feature extraction is based on modified Mel-scaled Frequency Cepstral Coefficients (MFCC) and template matching employs Dynamic Time Warping (DTW). A novel algorithm has been used to improve the detection of start of a word. The hardware is built around the industry standard TMS320LF2407A DSP. The board is designed to serve as a general purpose DSP development board for the 24X series of TI DSPs. It contains, apart from the DSR the external SRAM, FLASH, ADC interface, I/O interfacing blocks and JTAG interface. Both the hardware and the software have been designed concurrently, with a view to achieve high-speed recognition with maximum accuracy in minimum power and making the device portable. The proposed solution is a low-cost, high-performance, scalable alternative to other existing products.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T17:13:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T17:13:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>17TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON VLSI DESIGN, PROCEEDINGS: DESIGN METHODOLOGIES FOR THE GIGASCALE ERA,127-132</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-2072-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16070</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2660</dc:identifier><dc:source>17th International Conference on VLSI Design,Mumbai, INDIA,JAN 05-09, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>