<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14866</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:08:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Physically-based distributed soil erosion and sediment yield model (DREAM) for simulating individual storm events</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMSANKARAN, RAAJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOTHYARI, UC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALCHEREK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUGESAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>soil erosion modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>sediment yield modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>GIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>spatially distributed modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>storm event-based watershed modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Himalayan watershed</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGRICULTURAL WATERSHEDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GARHWAL HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SMALL CATCHMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RUNOFF</dc:subject><dc:subject>GIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MANAGEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>EUROSEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROLOGY</dc:subject><dc:description>A relatively simple process-oriented, physically-based distributed (PBD) hydrological model, the distributed runoff and erosion assessment model (DREAM), is described, and a validation study conducted in the semi-forested watershed of Pathri Rao, in the Garhwal Himalayas, India, is reported. DREAM takes account of watershed heterogeneity as reflected by land use, soil type, topography and rainfall, measured in the field or estimated through remote sensing, and generates estimates of runoff and sediment yield in spatial and temporal domains. The model is based on simultaneous solution of flow dynamics, based on kinematic wave theory, followed by solution of soil erosion dynamics. As the storm rainfall proceeds, the process of overland flow generation is dependent on the interception storage and infiltration rates. The components of the soil erosion model have been modified to provide better prediction of sediment flow rates and sediment yields. The validation study conducted to test the performance of the model in simulating soil erosion and sediment yield during different storm events monitored in the study watershed showed that the model outputs are satisfactory. Details of a sensitivity analysis, model calibration and the statistical evaluation of the results obtained are also presented and discussed. It is noteworthy that the distributed nature of the model combined with the use of geographical information system (GIS) techniques permits the computation and representation of the spatial distribution of sediment yield for simulated storm events, and a map of the spatial distribution of sediment yield for a simulated storm event is presented to highlight this capability.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HYDROLOGICAL SCIENCES JOURNAL-JOURNAL DES SCIENCES HYDROLOGIQUES, 58(4)872-891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/02626667.2013.781606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14866</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>