<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1841</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrically induced junction MOSFET for high performance sub-50nm CMOS technology</dc:title><dc:creator>DIXIT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, RO</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>channel</dc:subject><dc:description>Degrading of short-channel effects (SCE) e.g. Drain-Induced-Barrier-Lowering (DIBL), charge-sharing etc., as CMOS devices are scaled into the sub-50nm regime, is a major roadblock for ULSI technologies. This problem can be circumvented to some extent by a proper scaling of MOSFET vertical dimensions (junction depths, oxide thickness etc.). In this work we propose a novel implementation of an electrically induced junction (EJ) MOSFET. An EJ-MOSFET is different from conventional CMOS device in that the gate voltage electrically induces the shallow source-drain extensions (SDEs). In such a device the SDEs are underneath the gate and contain low-doped regions of opposite conductivity as that of deep source-drain (S/D). In order to turn ON the device, a voltage is applied at the gate of EJ-MOSFET device, such that these low doped regions below poly-Si gate get inverted and serve as SDEs. Consequently, the effective channel length in this condition is the distance between these low-doped regions. On the contrary, at any gate voltage less than that required for inverting these regions, no SDEs are induced, and the effective channel length is equal to the physical separation between the deep S/D junctions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MATERIALS RESEARCH SOCIETY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T09:47:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T09:47:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SILICON MATERIALS-PROCESSING, CHARACTERIZATION AND RELIABILITY,716,305-310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-55899-652-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0272-9172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1841</dc:identifier><dc:source>Symposium on Silicon Materials held at the 2002 MRS Spring Meeting,SAN FRANCISCO, CA,APR 01-05, 2002</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>