<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12698</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of geofibers on the flexural behavior of compacted soil beams</dc:title><dc:creator>VISWANADHAM, BVS</dc:creator><dc:creator>JHA, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWAR, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>fiber reinforcement</dc:subject><dc:subject>clay liners</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>waste</dc:subject><dc:subject>landfills</dc:subject><dc:subject>rubber</dc:subject><dc:subject>layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>geosynthetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexure</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexural testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibers</dc:subject><dc:subject>fiber reinforcement</dc:subject><dc:subject>cracking</dc:subject><dc:subject>image analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>Earth structures constructed of fine-grained soils have a tendency to crack. One possible solution to this problem is the inclusion of discrete and randomly distributed geofibers. The purpose of the research presented herein was to assess the feasibility of using commercially available geofibers to improve the tensile strength-strain characteristics of soils. An experimental investigation consisting primarily of flexural tensile tests was conducted to examine the influence of geofibers on the flexural behavior of three different types of soil molded at three different water contents. Polypropylene tape fibers were used in this study as reinforcing elements. The test results showed that the geofibers were effective in improving the tensile strength-strain characteristics of the moist-compacted fine-grained soils used in the present study. The inclusion of geofibers increased tensile strain at crack initiation of a soil moist-compacted at different molding water contents. With an increase in plasticity index of the soil, fiber content and molding water content, a trend of increasing tensile strain at crack initiation was observed. Among several fiber contents and aspect ratios, it appears that 0.5% polypropylene tape fibers and an aspect ratio (length to breadth) in the range 30-45 provided the best combination to increase tensile strain at crack initiation and effectiveness to restrain the cracking of soils. Further, the flexural rigidity at crack initiation was found to increase with an increase in the fiber content for soils having a low plasticity index and moist-compacted at low molding water contents.</dc:description><dc:publisher>THOMAS TELFORD PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-09-01T07:07:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-09-01T07:07:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOSYNTHETICS INTERNATIONAL, 17(2), 86-99</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1072-6349</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1680/gein.2010.17.2.86</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12698</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12698</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>