<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14815</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T11:03:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spatial and spectral distributions of emission from dye-doped photonic crystals in reflection and transmission geometries</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RUKHLENKO, ID</dc:creator><dc:creator>PREMARATNE, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>photonic crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>suppression of spontaneous emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>polar plots</dc:subject><dc:subject>reflection and transmission geometries</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAND-GAP</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:description>Spectral distribution of emission was measured in a large angular range (8 deg to 180 deg) around a self-assembled photonic crystal synthesized from colloids of Rhodamine-B dye-doped polystyrene. Its comparison with the emission from the same dye-doped colloids in a liquid suspension provides a better understanding of the anisotropic propagation of light within the structure due to its pseudo-gap properties. The spontaneous emission is suppressed by 40% in the presence of the stop band over a large bandwidth (similar to 50%) of the first-order bandgap in the Gamma L direction, due to the appropriate choice of the colloidal diameter. Spectral shifts in the spontaneous emission spectrum occur with the variation in the detection angle. The inevitable disorder in the self-assembled crystals and the resultant effect on emission was modeled by comparing the experimentally obtained reflection spectrum with the band structure calculated using the Korringa-Kohn-Rostoker method to exclude finite-size effects. Reflection and transmission are complementary because of the absence of strong absorptive effects. The extent of redistribution in the emission from a photonic crystalline environment with respect to a homogeneous emitter is significant in the spectral and spatial domains. (C) 2012 Society of Photo-Optical Instrumentation Engineers (SPIE). [DOI: 10.1117/1.JNP.6.063526]</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-SOC PHOTO-OPTICAL INSTRUMENTATION ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T11:03:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T11:03:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOPHOTONICS, 6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/1.JNP.6.063526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14815</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>