<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17114</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:47:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>A boron-dipyrrin-mercury(II) complex as a fluorescence turn-on sensor for chloride and applications towards logic gates</dc:title><dc:creator>MADHU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALAIYARASI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASU, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JADHAV, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ANION-BINDING PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BODIPY DYES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BORON-DIPYRROMETHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-SOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIVING CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTRACELLULAR CHLORIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUTURE PERSPECTIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION</dc:subject><dc:description>Chloride (Cl-) plays an important role in many cellular responses, including control of membrane potential, neurotransmission, regulation of cell volume and charge balance. Due to its physiological relevance, there is a growing need for improved optical sensors that can detect Cl- ions in biological and environmental samples. Herein, we have developed new N-acylhydrazone substituted BODIPY-mercury(II) based fluorescent turn-on sensors 1-Hg2+ and 2-Hg2+, which showed remarkable selectivity and specificity towards Cl- ions under physiological conditions. The new BODIPY compounds 1 and 2 were synthesized by treating their corresponding 3,5-diformyl BODIPYs 3 and 4 with isonicotinohydrazide in one step under simple reaction conditions. Compounds 1 and 2 absorb in 615-650 nm and emit in 625-660 nm regions. BODIPYs 1 and 2 showed exclusive sensing towards Hg2+ and formed 1-Hg2+ and 2-Hg2+ complexes, respectively, which resulted in the quenching of fluorescence. Job's plot analyses and HR-MS studies supported the formation of 1-Hg2+ and 2-Hg2+ complexes. Complexes 1-Hg2+ and 2-Hg2+ were found to be exclusive fluorescence turn-on sensors for chloride ions. Upon addition of Cl- ions to 1-Hg2+ and 2-Hg2+ complexes, the mercury(II) ions were extracted from the complexes by releasing the free BODIPYs 1 and 2 which reflected in the significant enhancement of fluorescence intensity (22-fold) with a detection limit of 108 nM. The reversibility and reusability of sensors for the detection of Hg2+ and Cl- ions were tested for six cycles. Interestingly, the sensor can be used to construct an IMPLIES logic gate system as demonstrated in this paper. Furthermore, the probe is cell membrane-permeable and can readily be used to detect the intracellular Cl- ions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY C, 2(14)2534-2544</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c3tc32188f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17114</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>