<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16387</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:42:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Constraining the variation in the fine-structure constant using SDSS DR7 quasi-stellar object spectra</dc:title><dc:creator>RAHMANI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHESHWARI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIANAND, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>atomic data</dc:subject><dc:subject>line: profiles</dc:subject><dc:subject>quasars: absorption lines</dc:subject><dc:subject>quasars: emission lines</dc:subject><dc:subject>TESTING FUNDAMENTAL PHYSICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPACE-TIME VARIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>UVES LARGE PROGRAM</dc:subject><dc:subject>COSMIC TIME</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROGRAPH</dc:subject><dc:subject>VARIABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIMITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATOMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>VARY</dc:subject><dc:description>We report on a robust constraint on the possible variation of the fine-structure constant, alpha equivalent to e(2)/(h) over barc, obtained using O III lambda lambda 4959,5007 nebular emission lines from quasi-stellar objects (QSOs). We find Delta alpha/alpha = -(2.1 +/- 1.6) x 10(-5), based on a well-selected sample of 2347 QSOs from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Data Release 7 with 0.02 &lt; z &lt; 0.74. Our result is consistent with a non-varying a at a level of 2 x 10(-5) over approximately 7 Gyr. This is the largest sample of extragalactic objects yet used to constrain the variation of alpha. While this constraint is not as stringent as those determined using the many-multiplet method, it is free from various systematic effects. A factor of similar to 4 improvement in Delta alpha/alpha achieved here compared to a previous study is consistent with what is expected based on the sample used here, which is a factor of 14 times larger. This suggests that errors are mainly dominated by statistical uncertainty. We also find that the ratio of transition probabilities corresponding to the O III lambda 5007 and lambda 4959 lines is 2.933 +/- 0.002, in good agreement with the measurements of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</dc:description><dc:publisher>OXFORD UNIV PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:42:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:42:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MONTHLY NOTICES OF THE ROYAL ASTRONOMICAL SOCIETY, 439(1)L70-L74</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0035-8711</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1365-2966</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/mnrasl/slt183</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16387</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>