<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4179</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Origin of surface and columnar Indian Ocean Experiment (INDOEX) aerosols using source- and region-tagged emissions transport in a general circulation model</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOUCHER, O</dc:creator><dc:subject>physical particle properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>sulfur-dioxide emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>dust aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>inventory</dc:subject><dc:subject>lidar</dc:subject><dc:subject>variability</dc:subject><dc:subject>combustion</dc:subject><dc:subject>advection</dc:subject><dc:description>We study the relative influence of aerosols emitted from different sectors and geographical regions on aerosol loading in south Asia. Sectors contributing aerosol emissions include biofuel and fossil fuel combustion, open biomass burning, and natural sources. Geographical regions include India (the Indo-Gangetic plain, central India, south India, and northwest India), southeast Asia, east Asia, Africa-west Asia, and the rest of the world. Simulations of the Indian Ocean Experiment (INDOEX), from January to March 1999, are made in the general circulation model of Laboratoire de Meteorologie Dynamique (LMD-ZT GCM) with emissions tagged by sector and geographical region. Anthropogenic emissions dominate (54-88%) the predicted aerosol optical depth (AOD) over all the receptor regions. Among the anthropogenic sectors, fossil fuel combustion has the largest overall influence on aerosol loading, primarily sulfate, with emissions from India (50-80%) and rest of the world significantly influencing surface concentrations and AOD. Biofuel combustion has a significant influence on both the surface and columnar black carbon (BC) in particular over the Indian subcontinent and Bay of Bengal with emissions largely from the Indian region (60-80%). Open biomass burning emissions influence organic matter (OM) significantly, and arise largely from Africa-west Asia. The emissions from Africa-west Asia affect the carbonaceous aerosols AOD in all receptor regions, with their largest influence (AOD-BC: 60%; and AOD-OM: 70%) over the Arabian Sea. Among Indian regions, the Indo-Gangetic Plain is the largest contributor to anthropogenic surface mass concentrations and AOD over the Bay of Bengal and India. Dust aerosols are contributed mainly through the long-range transport from Africa-west Asia over the receptor regions. Overall, the model estimates significant intercontinental incursion of aerosol, for example, BC, OM, and dust from Africa-west Asia and sulfate from distant regions (rest of the world) into the INDOEX domain.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER GEOPHYSICAL UNION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T06:51:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T06:51:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES, 113(), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0148-0227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1029/2007JD009538</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4179</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4179</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>