<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16993</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:30:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>The Deccan tholeiite lavas and dykes of Ghatkopar-Powai area, Mumbai, Panvel flexure zone: Geochemistry, stratigraphic status, and tectonic significance</dc:title><dc:creator>SHETH, HC</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZELLMER, GF</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEMONTEROVA, EI</dc:creator><dc:creator>IVANOV, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATEL, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Volcanism Flood basalt</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deccan Traps</dc:subject><dc:subject>Panvel flexure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mumbai</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tholeiite</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOOD-BASALT ERUPTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTINENTAL-MARGIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOLCANIC PROVINCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN-GHATS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTRACTION CHROMATOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRUSTAL CONTAMINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRACE-ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PB-ISOTOPE</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRAPS</dc:subject><dc:description>Mumbai City, situated on the western Indian coast, is well known for exposures of late-stage Deccan pillow basalts and spilites, pyroclastic rocks, rhyolite lavas, and trachyte intrusions. These rock units, and a little-studied sequence of tholeiitic flows and dykes in the eastern part of Mumbai City, constitute the west-dipping limb of a regional tectonic structure called the Panvel flexure. Here we present field, petrographic, major and trace element and Sr-Nd isotopic data on these tholeiitic flows and dykes, best exposed in the Ghatkopar-Powai area. The flows closely resemble the Mahabaleshwar Formation of the thick Western Ghats sequence to the east, in Sr-Nd isotopic ratios and multielement patterns, but have other geochemical characteristics (e.g., incompatible trace element ratios) unlike the Mahabaleshwar or any other Formation. The flows may have originated from a nearby eruptive center, possibly offshore of Mumbai. Two dykes resemble the Ambenali Formation of the Western Ghats in all geochemical characteristics, though they may not represent feeders of the Ambenali Formation lavas. Most dykes are distinct from any of the Western Ghats stratigraphic units. Some show partial (e.g., Sr-Nd isotopic) similarities to the Mahabaleshwar Formation, and these include several dykes with unusual, concave-downward REE patterns suggesting residual amphibole and thus a lithospheric source. The flows and dykes are inferred to have undergone little or no contamination, by lower continental crust. Most dykes are almost vertical, suggesting emplacement after the formation of the Panvel flexure, and indicate considerable east-west lithospheric extension during this late but magmatically vigorous stage of Deccan volcanism. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:30:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:30:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ASIAN EARTH SCIENCES, 8469-82</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1367-9120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1878-5786</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jseaes.2013.05.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16993</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>