<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15343</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:31:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>High Resolution TerraSAR-X Image Speckle Suppression and its Fusion with Multispectral IRS LISS-III Data for Himalayan Glacier Feature Extraction</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>TerraSAR-X</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glacier features</dc:subject><dc:subject>Speckle noise</dc:subject><dc:subject>PCA</dc:subject><dc:subject>IHS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOCAL STATISTICS</dc:subject><dc:description>In this study an attempt is made for studying the Himalayan glacier features using TerraSAR-X and Indian Remote Sensing Satellite, Linear Imaging Self Scanning System III (IRS LISS - III) images. New generation, synthetic aperture radar (SAR) data from TerraSAR-X (TS-X) sensor provide opportunity for glacier feature studies in Himalayan rugged terrain. Spot Light High resolution mode TS-X data give idea about glacial features which remained untraceable from other existing SAR system. However, presence of speckle noise in SAR images degrades the interpretability of the glacier features. Speckle suppression filters (Lee, Frost, Enhanced Lee, Gamma-Map) are applied on SAR intensity images. On the basis of field sight seeing and insitu observations it is observed that still features are not clear. Hence attempt has been made for fusing multitemporal multispatial speckle reduced TS-X SAR data and multispectral IRS LISS-III data for extracting the glacial features such as crevasses, exposed ice and superaglacier lakes. Principal component analysis (PCA) represents the high spectral resolution data in a linear subspace with minimum information loss. Herein, PCA based image fusion technique is adopted for this study and comparison is made between IHS fusion technique and PCA based technique for glacier studies in the Himalayan region.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:31:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:31:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE INDIAN SOCIETY OF REMOTE SENSING, 40(2)325-334</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12524-011-0137-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15343</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>