<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14501</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:18:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>High velocity impact performance of three-dimensional woven composites</dc:title><dc:creator>UDATHA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, CVS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIR, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Three-dimensional woven composite</dc:subject><dc:subject>high velocity impact</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy absorption mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>ballistic limit velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>FINITE-ELEMENT CALCULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNIT-CELL APPROACH</dc:subject><dc:subject>BALLISTIC IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEXTILE COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BRAIDED COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRIC COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>THICK COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PENETRATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Performance of three-dimensional orthogonal woven E-glass/epoxy composites under high velocity impact is presented. The analytical method used is based on wave propagation and energy balance between the projectile and the target. Different damage and energy absorbing mechanisms for a typical three-dimensional orthogonal woven composite are compression of the target directly below the projectile, compression in the surrounding region of the impacted zone, tension in the region consisting of primary yarns, tensile deformation in the region consisting of secondary yarns, shear plugging, bulge formation on the back face of the target, matrix cracking and friction between the target and the projectile. Experimental studies are also presented on high strain rate characterization, shear plugging behavior and high velocity impact behavior. For comparison, studies are also presented on the performance of two-dimensional plain weave E-glass/epoxy composites. A good match is observed between the analytical predictions and experimentally obtained limit velocities for complete penetration. It is observed that limit velocity for complete penetration for three-dimensional woven composite is higher than that for two-dimensional plain weave composite.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:18:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:18:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF STRAIN ANALYSIS FOR ENGINEERING DESIGN, 47(7)419-431</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0309324712448578</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14501</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>