<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11675</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Air-stable, convenient to handle Pd based PEPPSI (pyridine enhanced precatalyst preparation, stabilization and initiation) themed precatalysts of N/O-functionalized N-heterocyclic carbenes and its utility in Suzuki-Miyaura cross-coupling reaction</dc:title><dc:creator>RAY, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAIKH, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>ring-opening polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>halogenoaluminate(iii) ionic liquids</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon bond formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>palladium(ii) complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-metal</dc:subject><dc:subject>catalytic application</dc:subject><dc:subject>ruthenium catalysts</dc:subject><dc:subject>selective synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>olefin metathesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic halides</dc:subject><dc:description>Several new air-stable, convenient to handle and easily synthesized Pd based PEPPSI ( Pyridine Enhanced Precatalyst Preparation, Stabilization and Initiation) type precatalysts supported over N/O-functionalized N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHC) namely, trans-[1-(benzyl)-3-( N-t-butylacetamido) imidazol-2-ylidene] Pd( pyridine) Cl-2 ( 2), trans-[1-(2-hydroxy-cyclohexyl)-3( benzyl) imidazol-2-ylidene] Pd( pyridine) Cl2 ( 3) and trans-[1-(o-methoxybenzyl)-3-(t-butyl)imidazol-2-ylidene] Pd( pyridine) Br-2 ( 4), have been designed. Specifically, the Pd-NHC complexes, 2, 3 and 4, were conveniently synthesized from their respective imidazolium halide salts by the reaction with PdCl2 in pyridine in presence of K2CO3 as a base. A new imidazolium chloride salt, 1-(benzyl)-3-( N-t-butylacetamido) imidazolium chloride ( 1) was synthesized by the alkylation reaction of benzyl imidazole with N-t-butyl-2-chloroacetamide. The molecular structures of the imidazolium chloride salt, 1, and the Pd-NHC complexes, 2, 3 and 4, have been determined by X-ray diffraction studies. The density functional theory studies of the 2, 3 and 4 complexes were carried out to in order to gain insight about their structure, bonding and the electronic properties. The nature of the NHC-metal bond in these complexes was examined using Charge Decomposition Analysis (CDA), which revealed that the N-heterocyclic carbene ligands are effective r-donors. In addition, the catalysis studies revealed that the Pd-NHC complexes, 2, 3 and 4, are effective catalysts for the Suzuki-Miyaura type C-C cross-coupling reactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T13:31:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T13:31:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, (40), 4546-4555</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b706607d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11675</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11675</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>