<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17949</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:36:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flagellar filament bio-templated inorganic oxide materials - towards an efficient lithium battery anode</dc:title><dc:creator>BEZNOSOV, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>VELURI, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PYATIBRATOV, MG</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MACFARLANE, DR</dc:creator><dc:creator>FEDOROV, OV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>ION BATTERIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODE MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HALOBACTERIUM-SALINARUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-FE2O3</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LI</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONVERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:description>Designing a new generation of energy-intensive and sustainable electrode materials for batteries to power a variety of applications is an imperative task. The use of biomaterials as a nanosized structural template for these materials has the potential to produce hitherto unachievable structures. In this report, we have used genetically modified flagellar filaments of the extremely halophilic archaea species Halobacterium salinarum to synthesize nanostructured iron oxide composites for use as a lithium-ion battery anode. The electrode demonstrated a superior electrochemical performance compared to existing literature results, with good capacity retention of 1032 mAh g(-1) after 50 cycles and with high rate capability, delivering 770 mAh g(-1) at 5 A g(-1) (similar to 5 C) discharge rate. This unique flagellar filament based template has the potential to provide access to other highly structured advanced energy materials in the future.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, 5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2045-2322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep07736</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17949</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>