<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1454</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Conductometric Hg sensor based on polyaniline as transducer</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, PR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CONTRACTOR, AQ</dc:creator><dc:subject>microtubules</dc:subject><dc:subject>environment</dc:subject><dc:subject>conducting polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemical sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>heavy metals</dc:subject><dc:description>Mercury is a common pollutant in natural water. Several chelating agents have been used to treat mercury poisoning. Among these agents British-anti-Lewisite (dimercaprol, 2,3-dimercapto-1-propanol. BAL) is a particularly successful antidote to inorganic mercury poisoning. In the present study a conductometric electrochemical sensor for Hg2+ ions was developed using polyaniline as the transducer as well as the immobilization matrix and BAL as the receptor for the heavy metal ion determination. There is a release of H* ions in solution when Hg BAL complex is formed Causing in increase in the conductance of the polyaniline film. The study was performed using Hg2+ solutions of varying concentrations prepared in 10(-2)M HCl solution as the supporting electrolyte. The polyaniline conductance was measured in the presence of different concentrations or Hg2+ ions. The study showed an increase in the conductance of the polyaniline film in the presence of increasing concentrations of Hg2+ ions at -0.2 V gate potential vs. SCE. This conductometric sensor showed a good sensitivity in concentrations as low as 10 M-12 of Hg2+ ions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T18:15:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T18:15:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYTICAL CHEMISTRY,85(41609)831-835</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-7319</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03067310500154031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14719</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1454</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th Workshop on Biosenors and BioAnalytical Mu-Techniques in Environmental and Clinical Analysis,Rome, ITALY,OCT 08-12, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>