<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3315</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Survey on measurement of tangential momentum accommodation coefficient</dc:title><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>spinning rotor gauge</dc:subject><dc:subject>velocity slip coefficients</dc:subject><dc:subject>rarefied-gas flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>rectangular microchannels</dc:subject><dc:subject>mass-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>viscosity</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>air</dc:subject><dc:subject>compressibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>rarefaction</dc:subject><dc:description>The value of tangential momentum accommodation coefficient (TMAC) is required while prescribing the boundary condition for flow of gases in the slip and transition flow regimes. The precise determination of its value is important for several other applications as well. This article reviews the experimental techniques employed by researchers over the decades to measure this coefficient and the values reported in the literature, with relevance to calculation of the slip velocity. The review shows that the value of TMAC is dependent on a number of parameters including nature of the gas, pressure of the gas, material of the surface, surface cleanliness and roughness, and surface temperature. For monatomic gases, the TMAC at about 0.93 is almost constant with respect to the Knudsen number, and this value can be employed for most commonly available surface materials. However, for nonmonatomic gases, TMAC decreases with an increase in Knudsen number; a correlation of TMAC with Knudsen number for this class of gases, is proposed based on the available data. It is also revealed that TMAC depends strongly on the surface cleanliness and roughness, while temperature has an influence although it may not be very important for values greater than the room temperature. (C) 2008 American Vacuum Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A V S AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T11:51:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T11:51:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VACUUM SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY A, 26(4), 634-645</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0734-2101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1116/1.2943641</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3315</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3315</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>