<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8869</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ranking and choice with qualitative attributes using fuzzy functions</dc:title><dc:creator>DHINGRA, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMANAJES, M</dc:creator><dc:description>Urban transport planning is a complex process involving various modes and factors that influence the ordering preference of the modes. This study discusses the factors that determine the utility of the modes. The importance of relative weights of the transport attributes is recognised and the weights vector of the set of attributes is obtained. The study attempts to arrive at the utility values of three competing modes : viz, bus. train and paratransit. An approach is developed based on a questionnaire in which the rows represent the alternative modes and the columns represent the attributes. The fuzzy membership functions, which attempt to endorse a kind of mathematical precision to heuristic human thought process are developed individually for all attributes. The concepts of Type 1 and Type 2 fuzzy sets are notionally introduced in order to allow the distinction between grades of membership to become blurred. The commuters' responses which are in the linguistic form are defuzzified and converted into quantitative form using fuzzy functions. These fuzzy functions are used to obtain rating matrices, a cell of which represents an element of the fuzzy set and a column of which represents a fuzzy set. With these rating matrices as an input, the possibility of applying fuzzy set concepts to model an individual's mode choice pattern is investigated based on two types of derived dominance relations for the aggregate matrices. An extensive survey is conducted and the methodology is applied for Bombay Metropolitan Region for ranking and prioritising the three modes of transport. The utility value and performance ratio of all the corridors, for ail the modes and for all the interest groups are evaluated and suggestions are made to improve the transport scenario in BMR.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIANA UNIVERSITY NORTHWEST, DIVISION BUSINESS &amp; ECONOMICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T16:37:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T16:37:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FIRST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON OPERATIONS AND QUANTITATIVE MANAGEMENT, VOL 1 AND 2, (), 185-192</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8869</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8869</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>