<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1218</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Automatic segmentation of text into structured records</dc:title><dc:creator>BORKAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAWAGI, S</dc:creator><dc:description>In this paper we present a method for automatically segmenting unformatted text records into structured elements. Several useful data sources today are human-generated as continuous text whereas convenient usage requires the data to be organized as structured records. A prime motivation is the warehouse address cleaning problem of transforming dirty addresses stored in large corporate databases as a single text field into subfields like "City" and "Street". Existing tools rely on hand-tuned, domain-specific rule-based systems. We describe a tool DATAMOLD that learns to automatically extract structure when seeded with a small number of training examples. The tool enhances on Hidden Markov Models (HMM) to build a powerful probabilistic model that corroborates multiple sources of information including, the sequence of elements, their length distribution, distinguishing words from the vocabulary and an optional external data dictionary.; Experiments on real-life datasets yielded accuracy of 90% on Asian addresses and 99% on US addresses. In contrast, existing information extraction methods based on rule-learning techniques yielded considerably lower accuracy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T12:21:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T12:21:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SIGMOD RECORD,30(2)175-186</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0163-5808</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14411</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1218</dc:identifier><dc:source>ACM SIGMOD International Conference on Management of Data,SANTA BARBARA, CALIFORNIA,MAY 21-24, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>