<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16783</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:43:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rapid mold-free manufacturing of microfluidic devices with robust and spatially directed surface modifications</dc:title><dc:creator>PARDON, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHARIL, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARLSSON, JM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUPEKAR, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>CARLBORG, CF</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAN DER WIJNGAART, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARALDSSON, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>Lab on chip</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microfluidics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photolithography</dc:subject><dc:subject>OSTE polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface modification</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER MICROFABRICATION TECHNOLOGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SU-8</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROPHORESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHIP</dc:subject><dc:description>A new and easy-to-use method that allows for mold-free and rapid prototyping of microfluidic devices, comprising channels, access holes, and surface-modified patterns, is presented. The innovative method is based on direct photolithographic patterning of an off-stoichiometry thiol-ene (OSTE) polymer formulation, tailor-made for photolithography, which offers unprecedented spatial resolution and allows for efficient, robust and reliable, room temperature surface modification and glue-free, covalent room temperature bonding. This mold-free process does not require clean room equipment and therefore allows for rapid, i.e., less than one hour, design-fabricate-test cycles, using a material suited for larger-scale production. The excellent photolithographic properties of this new OSTE formulation allow patterning with unprecedented, for thiol-ene polymer systems, resolution in hundreds of micrometers thick layers, 200 mu m thick in this work. Moreover, we demonstrated robust, covalent and spatially controlled modification of the microchannel surfaces with an initial contact angle of 76A degrees by patterning hydrophobic/hydrophilic areas with contact angles of 102A degrees and 43A degrees, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:43:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:43:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROFLUIDICS AND NANOFLUIDICS, 17(4)773-779</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1613-4982</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1613-4990</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10404-014-1351-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16783</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>