<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17269</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:06:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Glyco-conjugate as selective switch-on molecule for Hg2+ in the presence of albumin proteins, blood serum milieu and on silica gel solid support</dc:title><dc:creator>ARETI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>YARRAMALA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMANTA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHEDKAR, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-MEDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>MERCURY IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIVING CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMODOSIMETER</dc:subject><dc:subject>RHODAMINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACETONITRILE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSITIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:description>The glyco-conjugate, L-S, its Hg2+ complex, and the L-O were synthesized and characterized in their solid state by FTIR, diffuse reflectance, and powder XRD. The mercury complex shows dumbbell-like microstructures as a result of the metal ion-induced aggregation of the glyco-conjugate as studied based on scanning electron microscopy. The aggregation was also supported by atomic force microscopy. The Hg2+ was detected on L-S-coated silica gel sheets by switch-on fluorescence, wherein, the enhancement in the fluorescence intensity varies linearly with the added Hg2+ in the concentration range 5-60 mu M. The concentration-dependent variation was also detected on silica gel sheets by viewing their colour under 365 nm light. Hg2+ was detected by the L-S-coated silica gel sheets by switchon fluorescence even in the presence of blood serum. Thus, this method is extendable for the detection and quantification of Hg2+ present in blood and or in biological fluids using disposable silica gel sheets. The sensing of Hg2+ in HEPES buffer solution is well demonstrated in this paper using various techniques, such as fluorescence, absorption, visual color, ESI MS, and H-1 NMR. In the buffer medium, the L-S exhibit selective chromogenic as well as fluorogenic properties towards Hg2+ by showing similar to 75-fold higher fluorescence emission intensity and the studies were further extended to show that none of the 13 ions studied compete for Hg2+. A minimum detection limit of 25 +/- 4 ppb was shown by L-S for Hg2+ in the buffer. All the experimental studies carried out support the formation of 2 : 1 complex between L-S and Hg2+. At higher mole ratios of Hg2+, the same yields the oxo-product, viz., L-O. The structure of the 2 : 1 complex was modeled by DFT using B3LYP/LANL2DZ.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:06:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:06:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 4(31)16290-16297</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4ra00223g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17269</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>