<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1455</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dechlorination of chlorophenols using magnesium–palladium bimetallic system</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, UPENDRA D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, SUMATHI</dc:creator><dc:subject>dechlorination</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnesium</dc:subject><dc:subject>palladium</dc:subject><dc:subject>acetic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnesium printing plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenols</dc:subject><dc:subject>silver</dc:subject><dc:description>Ninety-four percent removal of 10 mg L−1 of pentachlorophenol (PCP) was achieved by treatment with 154.5 mM Mg0 and 0.063 mM K2PdCl6 in the presence of 175 mM acetic acid in 1 h reaction time. Dechlorination of PCP was found to be sequential and phenol was identified as the end product along with accumulation of trace concentrations of tetra- and trichlorophenols. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX) revealed that palladium in its metallic form (Pd0) produced by reduction of Pd4+, was spatially separated from magnesium granules when acid was included in the reaction. These colloidal palladium particles generated active reductive species of hydrogen and dechlorinated chlorophenols. In the absence of acid, the efficiency of dechlorination of PCP by Pd/Mg0 system was very low and chief mechanism of removal of the compound was through sorption onto solid surfaces. Thus, it was important to include acid in the system to: (a) facilitate corrosion of Mg0 and reduction of Pd4+ to Pd0, (b) provision of protons to produce H2, (c) retard formation of insoluble oxides and hydroxides that may deposit on the magnesium granules and sorb PCP and its partially dechlorinated products and. Application of 154.5 mM Mg0/0.063 mM K2PdCl6 on PCP, 2,4,5-trichlorophenol (TCP) and 2-chlorophenol (MCP) with organic chloride equivalence showed that the rate and extent of removal increased with decrease in number of chlorine atoms on phenol.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-09T04:29:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:54:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-09T04:29:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:54:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Hazardous Materials 147(1-2), 431-438</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.jhazmat.2007.01.029</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1455</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1455</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>