<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1214</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Efficient and extensible algorithms for multi query optimization</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHADRI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUDARSHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHOBE, S</dc:creator><dc:description>Complex queries are becoming commonplace, with the growing use of decision support systems. These complex queries often have a lot of common sub-expressions, either within a single query, or across multiple such queries run as a batch. Multiquery optimization aims at exploiting common sub-expressions to reduce evaluation cost. Multi-query optimization has hither-to been viewed as impractical, since earlier algorithms were exhaustive, and explore a doubly exponential search space. In this paper we demonstrate that multi-query optimization using heuristics is practical, and provides significant benefits. We propose three cost-based heuristic algorithms: Volcano-SH and Volcano-RU, which are based on simple modifications to the Volcano search strategy and a greedy heuristic. Our greedy heuristic incorporates novel optimizations that improve efficiency greatly Our algorithms are designed to be easily added to existing optimizers. We present a performance study comparing the algorithms, using workloads consisting of queries from the TPC-D benchmark. The study shows that our algorithms provide significant benefits over traditional optimization, at a very acceptable overhead in optimization time.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T12:00:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T12:00:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SIGMOD RECORD,29(2)249-260</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0163-5808</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14407</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1214</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Management of Data,DALLAS, TX,MAY 16-18, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>