<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16051</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:20:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Graphene supported nickel nanoparticle as a viable replacement for platinum in dye sensitized solar cells</dc:title><dc:creator>BAJPAI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULSHRESTHA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAFIEE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>KORATKAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>PULSED-LASER DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COUNTER-ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPARENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:description>A platinum free counter electrode for dye sensitized solar cells was developed using graphene platelets (GP) supported nickel nanoparticles (NPs) as the active catalyst. Few layered GP were prepared by chemical oxidation of graphite powders followed by thermal exfoliation and reduction. The nanoparticles of nickel were deposited directly onto the platelets by pulsed laser ablation. The composite electrodes of GP and Ni nanoparticles (GP-Ni) thus obtained showed better performance compared to conventional Pt thin film electrodes (Std Pt) and unsupported Ni NPs. The efficiencies of the cells fabricated using GP-Ni, Std Pt and Ni NP CEs were 2.19%, 2% and 1.62%, respectively. The GP-Ni composite solar cell operated with an open circuit voltage of 0.7 V and a fill factor of 0.6. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy using the I-3(-)/I- redox couple confirms lower values of charge transfer resistance for the composite electrodes, 4.67 Omega cm(2) as opposed to 7.73 Omega cm(2) of Std Pt. The better catalytic capability of these composite materials is also reflected in the stronger I-3(-) reduction peaks in cyclic voltammetry scans.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:20:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:20:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOSCALE, 4(3)926-930</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2nr11127f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16051</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>