<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12506</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Extremum seeking loops with quadratic functions: estimation and control</dc:title><dc:creator>BANAVAR, RN</dc:creator><dc:description>Extremum-seeking (also peak-seeking) controllers are designed to operate at an a priori unknown set-point that extremizes the value of a performance function. Traditional approaches to the problem assume a time-scale separation between the gradient computation and function minimization and the system dynamics. The work here, in contrast, assumes that the performance function can be approximated by a quadratic function with affinite number of parameters. These parameters are estimated on-line and the extremum seeking controller operates based on these estimated values. A significant advantage of a quadratic function is that it allows the peak-seeking control loop to be reduced to a linear system. For such a loop, the wealth of linear system analysis and synthesis tools can be employed. First, the control loop is analysed assuming that the parameters in the function are known ( full information case) and then when the parameters are estimated on line (the partial information case).</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T23:45:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T23:45:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF CONTROL, 76(14), 1475-1482</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7179</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00207170310001599131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12506</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12506</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>