<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15816</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:44:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>On numerical analysis of composite and laminated cylinders of finite length subjected to partially distributed band load</dc:title><dc:creator>DESAI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>Semi analytical method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Circular cylinder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Band load</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laminates</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHELL THEORY SOLUTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELASTICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESSES</dc:subject><dc:description>A simplified and accurate semi analytical numerical model is presented here to investigate the behavior of cylinders of finite length subjected to partially distributed band load. A diaphragm supported laminated cylinder under symmetric load which is considered as a two dimensional (2D) plane strain problem of elasticity in (r, z) direction. The boundary conditions are satisfied exactly in axial direction (z) by taking an analytical expression in terms of Fourier series expansion. Fundamental (basic) dependent variables are chosen in the radial coordinate of the cylinder. First order simultaneous ordinary differential equations are obtained as mathematical model which are integrated through an effective numerical integration technique by first transforming the boundary value problem (BVP) into a set of initial value problems (IVPs). The proposed method is successful in handling the 2D and three dimensional (3D) elasticity problems involving wide range of loadings, material properties and mixed variables. For cylinders subjected to band load, the convergence study is carried out and presented for different harmonics. The numerical results obtained are also first validated with existing literature for their accuracy. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:44:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:44:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRESSURE VESSELS AND PIPING, 111321-330</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0308-0161</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-3541</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpvp.2013.10.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15816</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>