<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17115</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:48:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Boron-dipyrromethene based multi-anionic sensor and a specific cationic sensor for Fe3+</dc:title><dc:creator>LAKSHMI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>BODIPY DYES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROSCOPIC PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CU2+</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONS</dc:subject><dc:description>Symmetrical and unsymmetrical phenylhydrazone substituted boron-dipyrromethenes were synthesized by treating 3,5-diformyl boron-dipyrromethene with phenylhydrazine/2,4-dinitrophenylhydrazine in ethanol at reflux temperature. The X-ray structure of the unsymmetrical boron-dipyrromethene (BODIPY) was shown to have an almost extended planar orientation of BODIPY with 2,4-dinitrophenylhydrozone unit at the 3-position and ethyl acetal at the 5-position with small torsional angles. A strong absorption band at similar to 600 to 700 nm and a weak emission band at similar to 620 to 710 nm were observed for the phenylhydrazone substituted BODIPYs. The compounds showed interesting absorption properties in DMSO and DMF solvents compared to other solvents by shifting similar to 150 nm towards the red region. Anion binding studies indicated that the unsymmetrical phenylhydrazone substituted BODIPY could be applied as a sensor for F-, CH3COO- and H2PO4- ions as confirmed by various spectroscopic studies. Furthermore, the unsymmetrical phenylhydrazone substituted BODIPY had the unique ability of acting as a two step fluorescence enhanced chemodosimetric sensor for Fe3+ ion.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:48:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:48:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY C, 2(28)5576-5586</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4tc00317a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17115</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>