<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8581</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>A GIS based hydrogeomorphic approach for identification of site-specific artificial-recharge techniques in the Deccan Volcanic Province</dc:title><dc:creator>SHANKAR, MNR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>artificial-recharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>dvp</dc:subject><dc:subject>cis</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogeology</dc:subject><dc:description>The Deccan Volcanic Province (DVP) of India, as a whole, faces a severe shortage of water despite receiving a high annual rainfall, this is primarily due to excess runoff and lack of water conservation practices. In this study, an attempt is made to identify zones favourable for the application and adaptation of site-specific artificial-recharge techniques for augmentation of groundwater through a Geographical Information System (GIS) based hydrogeomorphic approach in the Bhatsa and Kalu river basins of Thane district, in western DVP. The criteria adopted for the GIS analysis were based on the hydrogeomorphological characteristics of both basins extracted from the IRS-1C LISS-III data supported by information on drainage pattern, DEM derived slope, lineament density, drainage density, and groundwater condition. The integrated study helps design a suitable groundwater management plan for a basaltic terrain.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T23:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T23:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 114(5), 505-514</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8581</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8581</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>