<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8312</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-22T07:18:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Eigenfilter Approach to the Design of One-Dimensional and Multidimensional Two-Channel Linear-Phase FIR Perfect Reconstruction Filter Banks</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, BD</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, PG</dc:creator><dc:creator>GADRE, VM</dc:creator><dc:subject>wavelet bases</dc:subject><dc:subject>transformations</dc:subject><dc:subject>symmetries</dc:subject><dc:subject>variables</dc:subject><dc:subject>eigen-filter design</dc:subject><dc:subject>least-square filter design</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-channel filter bank</dc:subject><dc:description>We present an eigenfilter-based approach for the design of two-channel linear-phase FIR perfect-reconstruction (PR) filter banks. This approach can be used to design I-D two-channel filter banks, as well as multidimensional nonseparable two-channel filter banks. Our method consists of first designing the low-pass analysis filter. Given the low-pass analysis filter, the PR conditions can be expressed as a set of linear constraints on the complementary-synthesis low-pass filter. We design the complementary-synthesis filter by using the eigenfilter design method with linear constraints. We show that, by an appropriate choice of the length of the filters, we can ensure the existence of a solution to the constrained eigenfilter design problem for the complementary-synthesis filter. Thus, our approach gives an eigenfilter-based method of designing the complementary filter, given a "predesigned" analysis filter, with the filter lengths satisfying certain conditions. We present several design examples to demonstrate the effectiveness of the method.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T02:09:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T02:09:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON CIRCUITS AND SYSTEMS I-REGULAR PAPERS, 55(11), 3542-3551</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1549-8328</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TCSI.2008.925818</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8312</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8312</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>