<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2991</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis of diverse polycyclic compounds via catalytic metathesis</dc:title><dc:creator>KOTHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>amino acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>polycycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>metathesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>heterocycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>spiro compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>ring-closing metathesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>amino-acid derivatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>diels-alder reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>cross-enyne metathesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclic 1-amino-1-carboxylic acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>allylic acetate isomerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>imido alkylidene complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>olefin-metathesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>claisen rearrangement</dc:subject><dc:subject>key steps</dc:subject><dc:description>A variety of olefin-metathesis protocols have been used to prepare spirocyclic compounds, cyclic sulfones, and constrained a-amino acid derivatives. Conceptually, a new approach to a novel cyclophane ring system has been realized via ring-closing metathesis (RCM). Also, tetracyclic compounds related to anthracycline antibiotics have been assembled using Claisen rearrangement and RCM as key steps. Further, a sequential use of the Diels-Alder reaction and ring-opening cross-metathesis delivered highly fuctionalized spiroindane derivatives, and trisubstituted benzene derivatives have been assembled using Grubbs' catalyst. Finally, the enyne and cross-enyne metathesis sequences have been used to prepare several constrained cc-amino acid derivatives. 1 Introduction 2 Application of Ring-Closing Metathesis To Give Spiro-cyclic Compounds 3 Application of Ring-Closing Metathesis To Give Cyclophane Derivatives 4 Application of Ring-Closing Metathesis To Give Cyclic Sulfone Derivatives 5 Application of Ring-Closing Metathesis To Give Cyclic alpha-Amino Acid Derivatives and Modified Peptides 6 Application of Ring-Closing Metathesis to Benzannulation 7 Application of Enyne Metathesis to the Synthesis of Constrained a-Amino Acid and Naphthoxepin Derivatives 8 Application of Cross-Enyne Metathesis to the Synthesis of Highly Functionalized Phenylatanine Derivatives 9 Application of Ring-Opening Cross-Metathesis to Spiro-indanes 10 Synthesis of Trisubstituted Benzene Derivatives Using Grubbs' Catalyst 11 Metathesis of a Novel Enyne System 12 Macroheterocycles via Cross-Enyne and Ring-Closing Metathesis Cascade Reactions 13 Conclusions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GEORG THIEME VERLAG KG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-12T11:26:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-12T11:26:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>SYNLETT,(18)2767-2784</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0936-5214</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1055/s-2007-990954</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13757</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2991</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>