<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2681</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Speech processing for hearing aids for moderate bilateral sensorineural hearing loss</dc:title><dc:creator>CHEERAN, AN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, PC</dc:creator><dc:description>Binaural dichotic presentation can be used for reducing the effects of increased temporal and spectral masking associated with sensorineural loss and for improving speech perception by persons with moderate bilateral loss. Speech processing schemes based on adjustable gain filtering, spectral splitting with perceptually balanced comb filters, temporal splitting with trapezoidal fading and inter-aural switching period of 20 and 40 ms, and combined splitting with cyclically swept comb filters with cycle time of 20, 40, and 80 ms were implemented. Experimental evaluation was carried out through listening tests involving recognition of randomly presented words by hearing impaired subjects, for establishing the effect of processing schemes and parameters. Binaural filtering always resulted in improvement. Maximum number of subjects showed large improvement with spectral splitting. Temporal splitting was better with 20 ms switching, while the combined splitting gave best improvements for cycle time of 40 ms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T18:55:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T18:55:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2004 IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ACOUSTICS, SPEECH, AND SIGNAL PROCESSING, VOL IV, PROCEEDINGS: AUDIO AND ELECTROACOUSTICS SIGNAL PROCESSING FOR COMMUNICATIONS,17-20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16095</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2681</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing,Montreal, CANADA,MAY 17-21, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>