<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12304</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Three-manifold invariants from Chern-Simons field theory with arbitrary semi-simple gauge groups</dc:title><dc:creator>KAUL, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMADEVI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>3-manifolds</dc:subject><dc:subject>links</dc:subject><dc:subject>representations</dc:subject><dc:subject>algebras</dc:subject><dc:subject>witten</dc:subject><dc:subject>knots</dc:subject><dc:description>Invariants for framed links in S-3 obtained from Chern-Simons gauge field theory based on an arbitrary gauge group (semi-simple) have been used to construct a three-manifold invariant. This is a generalization of a similar construction developed earlier for SU(2) Chern-Simons theory. The procedure exploits a theorem of Lickorish and Wallace and also those of Kirby, Fenn and Rourke which relate three-manifolds to surgeries on framed unoriented links. The invariant is: an appropriate linear combination of framed link invariants which does not change under Kirby calculus. This combination does not see the relative orientation of the component knots. The invariant Is related to the partition function of Chern-Simons theory. This thus provides an efficient method of evaluating the partition function for these field theories. As some examples, explicit computations of these manifold invariants: for a few three-manifolds have been done.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:59:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:59:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMMUNICATIONS IN MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS, 217(2), 295-314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0010-3616</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s002200000347</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12304</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>