<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-373</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>New paradigm of tracing algorithms: application to fair loss allocation in Indian system</dc:title><dc:creator>ABHYANKAR, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOMAN, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:subject>load flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>power grids</dc:subject><dc:subject>transmission network calculations</dc:subject><dc:description>MW power flow tracing was invented to assess the extent of network usage by the participants so as to allocate the transmission charges and losses. MW power tracing, a post-facto analysis of power flow solution, is amenable to multiple solutions. This implies multiplicity of solution space of cost and loss allocation problem. Existing tracing methods enforce a 'proportionate sharing rule' to arrive at a solution. Case studies indicate that with such a sharing rule, extent of network usage predicted for large and distant loads can be much higher than the postage stamp or pro-rata allocation. To alleviate this problem, we suggest a new paradigm of MW power tracing algorithms wherein, we exploit the multiplicity of solution space so as to achieve a fair and equitable distribution of losses among the participants. We show that real power tracing represents a generic class of multi-commodity network flow problems and can be formulated as a linear constrained optimization problem. We propose a tracing compliant modified postage stamp allocation method which computes a traceable solution that minimizes deviation from the postage stamp allocation of losses. Results on practical data of central transmission utility of Western Regional Grid of India demonstrate the claims.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-17T08:04:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T17:00:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-17T08:04:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T17:00:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on Future Power Systems, Amsterdam, The Netherlands, 16-18 November 2005, 1-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-78205-02-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/373</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/373</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>