<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6803</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Neutron induced degradation in nitrided pyrogenic field oxide MOS capacitors</dc:title><dc:creator>VAIDYA, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAIKH, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, AN</dc:creator><dc:subject>radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>neutron induced damage</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrided oxides</dc:subject><dc:description>Neutron induced oxide charge trapping and generation of interface states in MOS capacitors with pyrogenic and nitrided pyrogenic field oxides have been studied. In order to assess the damage due to neutrons alone, it is necessary to account for the damage produced by the accompanying gamma rays from neutron radiation. This is done by measuring the intensity of gamma radiation accompanying neutrons at different neutron fluences at the irradiation position. MOS capacitor structures were subjected to neutron radiation in a swimming pool type of reactor. Other samples from the same batch were then subjected to an equivalent dose of gamma radiation from a Co(60) source. The difference in the damage observed was used to characterize the damage caused by neutrons. It is observed that neutrons, though uncharged, are capable of causing ionization damage. This damage is found to be significant when the radiation is performed under biased conditions. Nitridation in different ambients is found to improve the radiation performance of pyrogenic field oxides with respect to positive charge build up as well as interface state generation. Pyrogenic oxide nitrided in N(2)O is found to be the best oxynitride as damage due to neutrons is the least. (C) 2002  .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T22:41:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T22:41:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION B-BEAM INTERACTIONS WITH MATERIALS AND ATOMS, 194(3), 311-318</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-583X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0168-583X(02)00781-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6803</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>