<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2948</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-22T06:09:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel high force density linear segmented switched reluctance machine</dc:title><dc:creator>VATTIKUTI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>VANDANA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:description>Linear switched reluctance machine (LSRM) has low force density, high acoustic noise and low energy conversion ratio. In this paper a novel linear segmented switched reluctance machine (LSSRM) having high force density and energy conversion ratio is proposed. This machine has segmented rotor and full pitch winding on the stator. This machine is the linear counterpart of segmented switched reluctance machine (SSRM). It is proved through finite element based simulation study (FEM) that LSSRM gives approximately double the force, for the same frame size as LSRM. This is achieved by decreasing the reluctance in the aligned position without affecting saliency ratio. The reluctance of LSSRM is decreased by reducing the flux path length and increasing the air gap area. This is achieved by modifying the winding arrangement from concentrated to full-pitched, changing translator pole width (TPW) and stator pole shoe width (SPW). The FEM results are validated analytically. The geometric parameters affecting the output force are optimized to get the maximum ratio of propulsive force to normal force. Also, converter volt-ampere rating is determined.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-28T01:27:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-28T01:27:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IECON 2008: 34TH ANNUAL CONFERENCE OF THE IEEE INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS SOCIETY, VOLS 1-5, PROCEEDINGS,1030-1035</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1767-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1553-572X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16473</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2948</dc:identifier><dc:source>34th Annual Conference of the IEEE-Industrial-Electronics-Society,Orlando, FL,NOV 10-13, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>