<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9104</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental study on flame pattern formation and combustion completeness in a radial microchannel</dc:title><dc:creator>FAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MINAEV, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIU, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARUTA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>gas-turbine engine</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-combustor</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixtures</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>microreactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>cfd</dc:subject><dc:description>Combustion behavior in a radial microchannel with a gap of 2.0 mm and a diameter of 50 mm was experimentally investigated. In order to simulate the heat recirculation, which is an essential strategy in microscale combustion devices, positive temperature gradients along the radial flow direction were given to the microchannel by an external heat source. A methane-air mixture was supplied from the center of the top plate through a 4.0 mm diameter delivery tube. A variety of flame patterns, including a stable circular flame and several unstable flame patterns termed unstable circular flame, single and double pelton-like flames, traveling flame and triple flame, were observed in the experiments. The regime diagram of all these flame patterns is presented in this paper. Some characteristics of the various flame patterns, such as the radii of stable and unstable circular flames, major combustion products and combustion efficiencies of all these flame patterns, were also investigated. Furthermore, the effect of the heat recirculation on combustion stability was studied by changing the wall temperature levels.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MICROMECHANICS AND MICROENGINEERING, 17(12), 2398-2406</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-1317</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0960-1317/17/12/002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9104</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9104</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>