<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-980</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:55:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>CdS/ZnS core–shell nanoparticles in arachidic acid LB films</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALWAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJOR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>absorption spectra</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>blodgett films</dc:subject><dc:description>Core–shell CdS/ZnS nanoparticles in arachidic acid film were prepared through a novel Langmuir–Blodgett (LB) approach. Post-deposition treatment of the precursor LB multilayers of cadmium arachidate with H2S gas followed by intercalation of Zn2+ ions and further sulfidation result in the formation of CdS/ZnS nanoparticles in the LB film. The formation of these nanoparticles and resulting changes in layered structures were studied by FTIR and X-ray reflection measurements. The optical properties were studied using UV–vis absorption and photoluminescence spectroscopy. A red-shift in the absorption spectrum and enhancement of CdS excitonic emission together with reduction of surface states emission suggest that after the intercalation step, a thin layer of ZnS surrounds the CdS nanoparticles, thus forming a core–shell structure. Subsequent to the second sulfidation, a further red-shift in absorption suggests the formation of a thicker ZnS coating on CdS. Electron diffraction of CdS nanoparticles coated with thicker ZnS showed the diffraction patterns of only ZnS, as expected for core–shell structures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-19T05:10:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:26:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-19T05:10:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:26:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Applied Surface Science 254(16), 5028-5033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0169-4332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2008.01.152</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/980</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/980</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>