<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9587</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>An advanced soil moisture accounting, procedure for SCS curve number method</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>rainfall-runoff models</dc:subject><dc:subject>calibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>catchment</dc:subject><dc:subject>initial soil moisture store</dc:subject><dc:subject>rainfall-runoff modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>direct surface runoff</dc:subject><dc:subject>scs-cn method</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil moisture accounting</dc:subject><dc:description>The Soil Conservation Service Curve Number (SCS-CN) method has been a topic of much discussion, especially in the last three decades. Recently, Michel et al. (2005) pointed out several inconsistencies in the soil moisture accounting (SMA) procedure used in the SCS-CN method and developed a procedure that is more consistent from the SMA viewpoint. However, the model proposed by them does not have any expression for initial soil moisture store level (VO) and hence there is a scope for further improvement. Like the original method, there is sudden jump in Vo and therefore a quantum jump in computed runoff is possible. In the present study, an attempt is made to develop an expression for Vo to make the model a continuous watershed model. Then, the performance of the new model is compared with the model proposed by Michel et al. and the original SCS-CN model by applying them in a large number of small watersheds in the United States. The present model was found to perform significantly better than both the original SCS-CN model and the model proposed by Michel et al. Copyright (c) 2007 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T18:35:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T18:35:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HYDROLOGICAL PROCESSES, 21(21), 2872-2881</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-6087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/hyp.6503</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9587</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9587</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>