<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15016</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:34:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Changes in the glaciers of ChandraBhaga basin, Himachal Himalaya, India, between 1980 and 2010 measured using remote sensing</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDEY, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHHOTA SHIGRI GLACIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORDILLERA BLANCA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GARHWAL-HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLIMATE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MASS-BALANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LANDSAT TM</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INVENTORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SATELLITE</dc:subject><dc:description>This study reports the glacier changes of ChandraBhaga basin, northwest Himalaya, India, from 1980 to 2010. Satellite remote-sensing data from the Landsat Multispectral Scanner (MSS) and Thematic Mapper (TM), the Linear Imaging Self Scanning Sensor (LISS) and Advanced Wide Field Sensor (AWiFS) of the Indian Remote Sensing (IRS) series, and the Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM) digital elevation model (DEM) were used to study the changes in glacier parameters such as glacier area, length, snout elevation, and the impact of glacier topographical parameters (glacier slope, aspect, and altitude range) on the glacier changes. It was found that the total glaciated area had shrunk to 368.2 km(2) in 2010 from 377.6 km(2) in 1980, a loss of 2.5%. The average position of glacier terminuses retreated by 465.5 +/- 169.1 m from 1980 to 2010 with an average rate of 15.5 +/- 5.6 m year(1). The decadal scale analysis showed that the average rate of retreat had increased the most in the recent decade. A moraine-dammed lake located in the study region was found to have expanded in area from (0.65 +/- 0.01) km(2) in 1980 to (1.26 +/- 0.03) km(2) in 2010. Glaciers with steep slope and less altitude range have lost more area than the glaciers having gentle slope and greater altitude range.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:34:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:34:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF REMOTE SENSING, 34(15)5584-5597</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2013.793464</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15016</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>