<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10524</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of first order kinetics for tertiary creep in aisi 304 stainless steel</dc:title><dc:creator>PHANIRAJ, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>NANDAGOPAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANNAN, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>RODRIGUEZ, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>fracture-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>rupture</dc:subject><dc:description>The results of constant load creep tests on AISI 304 stainless steel at 873 and 973 K for different test conditions were found to obey the first order kinetics for tertiary creep. Distinct master creep curves were obtained at 873 and 973 K with a separate set of constant values of K', epsilon(t), beta' and C-MG. A relationship between steady-state creep rate epsilon over dot(s) , time spent in tertiary creep t(t) and limiting tertiary creep strain epsilon(t) is formulated as epsilon over dot(s) . t(t)/epsilon(t) = constant and is found to be valid for all test conditions. Further, this relation is identical to the modified Monkman-Grant relation (MMGR) for the conditions satisfying f = 1/lambda; it is postulated that the validity of MMGR is a consequence of first order kinetics. Another important outcome of this study is a generalised relation of the form epsilon over dot(s) . t(r) = (epsilon(23).epsilon(f))(1/2); and this relation is compared with the relation proposed by Radhakrishnan, i.e. epsilon over dot(s) . t(r) = (epsilon(23)(2) .epsilon(f))(1/3). It is suggested that cavities act as vacancy sinks and accelerate dislocation climb controlled recovery process leading to tertiary creep. Copyright (C) 1996 Acta Metallurgica Inc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T12:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T12:58:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA MATERIALIA, 44(10), 4059-4069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1359-6454</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1359-6454(96)00023-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10524</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>