<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10258</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rate intensification of mass transfer process using ferrofluids</dc:title><dc:creator>SURESH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHALERAO, S</dc:creator><dc:description>The rate of inter-phase mass transfer process is of central importance in several processes in the chemical industry. This rate depends on the mass transfer coefficient, which in turn is determined by molecular process taking place in a region close to the phase interface. The mass transfer coefficient is, therefore, not substantially influenced by the mixing processes taking place for away from the interface. In this study the authors present a novel stratagem for enhancement of mass transfer rates by employing ferrofluids in the 'interfacial region' and causing them to oscillate using a magnetic field external to the equipment. Taking a gas-liquid system as an example to illustrate the strategy, it is shown that 40-50% increase in mass transfer rates are easily achieved, and that the increase depends on the ferrofluid loading and the strength of the magnetic field employed. Some limitations of the methods employed in the present work are also discussed, and it is possible that much higher enhancements are potentially possible.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T06:33:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T06:33:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF PURE &amp; APPLIED PHYSICS, 40(3), 172-184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-5596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10258</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>