<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1319</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of a specialised finite element for the analysis of composite structures with ply drop-off</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, ABHIJIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARUGHESE, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>stress analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminated composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>ply drop-off element</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:description>A global–local approach for the analysis of tapered laminated composites is presented. The method is considerably more economical than existing techniques. A new drop-off element that is degenerated from a 2-dimensional (2-D) drop-off element is introduced to carry out the global analysis. The drop-off element accommodates the termination of plies within the element and therefore, the size of the stiffness matrix reduces. At the vicinity of the drop-off where the stress concentration is high a local analysis with a refined mesh is performed with the results of the global analysis. Since a fine mesh is to be adopted only near the drop-off there is substantial economy in the computational effort and time as compared to the conventional analysis models. The present method has been validated extensively against published results. A discussion of the stress/strain distribution at different locations has been presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-09T09:27:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:03:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-09T09:27:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:03:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Composite Structures 46(1), 1-16</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0263-8223(99)00013-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1319</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1319</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>