<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2959</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-08T07:14:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cloud computing over metropolitan area WDM networks : the Light-trails approach</dc:title><dc:creator>GOKHALE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUMASTE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>light-trails</dc:subject><dc:subject>it-virtualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>cloud computing</dc:subject><dc:description>Cloud computing and IT-service provisioning is critical for the growth of enterprises in being able to provision computationally intensive applications. A high-speed networks infrastructure is necessary for the proliferation of cloud computing to meet disparate IT application demands. Light-trails - a generalization of lightpath with ability to provision sub-wavelength demands, meet dynamic bandwidth needs and cater to optical multicasting in a low-cost platform are investigated as a candidate technology for cloud computing. A time-slotted light-trail system is assumed and an algorithm is proposed based on utility concepts. Scheduling connections over light-trails in a timely manner to meet the tasks of an IT-service are considered. Memory resource management as a constraint is further incorporated in the algorithm thereby making the IT application pragmatically reside over the light-trails infrastructure. An exhaustive simulations study showcases the benefits of light-trails for cloud computing - the results obtained are over a wide range of services with serial, parallel and mixed set of constituent tasks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-28T02:26:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-28T02:26:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2010 IEEE GLOBAL TELECOMMUNICATIONS CONFERENCE GLOBECOM 2010,-</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-5638-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1930-529X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2959</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE Global Telecommunications Conference (GLOBECOM 2010),Miami, FL,DEC 06-10, 2010</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>