<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1340</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Soap : the polymorphic genie of hierarchically structured soft condensed-matter products</dc:title><dc:creator>RAUT, JS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIK, VM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGHAL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>stearate</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibers</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluid</dc:subject><dc:subject>acid</dc:subject><dc:description>More than 5 million tonnes of metal salts of fatty acids are manufactured and used worldwide every year, to create a range of soft condensed-matter products such as bar soaps, stick deodorants, personal care creams, toothpastes, and lubricant greases. These molecules, popularly known as soaps, are capable of forming a plethora of states and self-assembled aggregates such as micelles, liquid crystals, solid crystals, and gels, whose characteristic sizes or domain sizes can span from nanometers to centimeters. The type and mix of the phases formed, their morphologies, and their states of dispersion or the nature of their further supra-assemblies dictate the underlying micromechanical structures of products, which, in turn, are responsible for their optical, structural, and theological properties. Developing processing guidelines to manipulate characteristic micromechanical structures is therefore key to obtaining the desired look, touch, feel, and function of these products. The article discusses a few illustrative examples of these structure- property relationships demonstrated by multiscale soap assemblies. Observations of some novel tertiary structures formed by crystallizing soap fibers at the air-water interface, serendipitously discovered by us in the recent past, are also discussed, to illustrate the richness and mysteries of the well-studied and so-called mature subject of soaps.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:04:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:04:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH,47(17)6347-6353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie0714753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14693</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1340</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st International Conference on Multiscale Structures and Dynamics of Complex Systems,Beijing, PEOPLES R CHINA,AUG 29-31, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>