<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1717</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Feasibility studies of a pilot tidal power plant at Saphale, India</dc:title><dc:creator>DEOKAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUKHATME, SP</dc:creator><dc:description>A small-scale site for tidal power generation is available near Saphale village in Thane district of Maharashtra State. The shorter construction time and local consumption of the power generated makes this site economically attractive for establishment of the first pilot tidal power plant in the country. The use of mathematical modeling in planning and design of tidal power plant is established and accepted practice world over. The one-dimensional model is used for studies, as this model combines the principal inertia, gravity and friction forces with the shape of estuary. The incorporation of these effects is a considerable advance over the 'horizontal surface' i.e. flat estuary models, which are used for initial estimation of energy. The paper gives preliminary feasibility-studies under some simplified assumption to introduce the technology in the country. The present study is based on spring tidal range only, as the more complex study is going on. In the study, it is assumed that the turbine starts and stops at the same minimum head, and the discharge through turbine is taken constant. As there will be infinite numbers of possible alternatives, one of which, for a given combination of variables i.e. sluicing area, turbine discharge etc., will give the maximum energy output, different combinations of parameters had been taken and analyzed accordingly. An analysis for turbine selection is also been reported which includes the selection of speed and runner diameter of turbine based on Hill chart under site constraints, however the optimized values of all parameters can be found latter as the study is going on.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER POWER CONFERENCE ILLINOIS INST TECHNOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T11:07:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T11:07:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE AMERICAN POWER CONFERENCE, VOL 61 - I AND II,61,226-231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0097-2126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14884</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1717</dc:identifier><dc:source>American Power Conference, at the 61st Annual Meeting of the Illinois-Institute-of-Technology on Innovation for Economy and Reliability,CHICAGO, IL,</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>