<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16987</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:27:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling and simulation of effect of ultrasonic vibrations on machining of Ti6Al4V</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>Machining</dc:subject><dc:subject>Titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ultrasonic vibrations</dc:subject><dc:subject>Finite element simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chip microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MACHINABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TI</dc:subject><dc:description>The titanium alloys cause high machining heat generation and consequent rapid wear of cutting tool edges during machining. The ultrasonic assisted turning (UAT) has been found to be very effective in machining of various materials; especially in the machining of "difficult-to-cut" material like Ti6Al4V. The present work is a comprehensive study involving 2D FE transient simulation of UAT in DEFORM framework and their experimental characterization. The simulation shows that UAT reduces the stress level on cutting tool during machining as compared to that of in continuous turning (CT) barring the penetration stage, wherein both tools are subjected to identical stress levels. There is a 40-45% reduction in cutting forces and about 48% reduction in cutting temperature in UAT over that of in CT. However, the reduction magnitude reduces with an increase in the cutting speed. The experimental analysis of UAT process shows that the surface roughness in UAT is lower than in CT, and the UATed surfaces have matte finish as against the glossy finish on the CTed surfaces. Microstructural observations of the chips and machined surfaces in both processes reveal that the intensity of thermal softening and shear band formation is reduced in UAT over that of in CT. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:27:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:27:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ULTRASONICS, 54(2)694-705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0041-624X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1874-9968</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ultras.2013.09.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16987</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>