<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12061</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Conjugative transfer of preferential utilization of aromatic compounds from Pseudomonas putida CSV86</dc:title><dc:creator>BASU, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>mobile genetic elements</dc:subject><dc:subject>sp. strain b13</dc:subject><dc:subject>genomic islands</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasmid dna</dc:subject><dc:subject>naphthalene</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>pathway</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>integration</dc:subject><dc:subject>metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>conjugative element</dc:subject><dc:subject>pseudomonas putida csv86</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon source preference</dc:subject><dc:subject>naphthalene and methylnaphthalene metabolism</dc:subject><dc:description>Pseudomonas putida CSV86 utilizes naphthalene (Nap), salicylate (Sal), benzyl alcohol (Balc), and methylnaphthalene (MN) preferentially over glucose. Methylnaphthalene is metabolized by ring-hydroxylation as well as side-chain hydroxylation pathway. Although the degradation property was found to be stable, the frequency of obtaining Nap(-)Sal(-)MN(-)Balc(-) phenotype increased to 11% in the presence of curing agents. This property was transferred by conjugation to Stenotrophomonas maltophilia CSV89 with a frequency of 7 x 10(-8) per donor cells. Transconjugants were Nap(+)Sal(+)MN(+)Balc(+) and metabolized MN by ring- as well as side-chain hydroxylation pathway. Transconjugants also showed the preferential utilization of aromatic compounds over glucose indicating transfer of the preferential degradation property. The transferred properties were lost completely when transconjugants were grown on glucose or 2YT. Attempts to detect and isolate plasmid DNA from CSV86 and transconjugants were unsuccessful. Transfer of degradation genes and its subsequent loss from the transconjugants was confirmed by PCR using primers specific for 1,2-dihydroxynaphthalene dioxygenase and catechol 2,3-dioxygenase (C23O) as well as by DNA-DNA hybridizations using total DNA as template and C23O PCR fragment as a probe. These results indicate the involvement of a probable conjugative element in the: (i) metabolism of aromatic compounds, (ii) ring- and side-chain hydroxylation pathways for MN, and (iii) preferential utilization of aromatics over glucose.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:56:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:56:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIODEGRADATION, 19(1), 83-92</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0923-9820</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10532-007-9117-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12061</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12061</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>