<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9895</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Finite element modelling of resistance spot welding of aluminium with spherical tip electrodes</dc:title><dc:creator>DE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>nugget growth</dc:subject><dc:description>A FEM based simulation model of the resistance spot welding process has been developed. The current simulation accounts for the non-uniform current density distribution in the sheet-electrode geometry and the clastoplastic deformation of the sheet due to electrode force, especially with spherical tip electrodes, since these effects are driven by and contribute to the main heat transfer analysis, which is governed by the internal heat generation within the sheet-electrode geometry as well as along the contact surfaces. The latent heat of transformation during melting or solidification, the variation of sheet/sheet contact resistance with temperature, and temperature dependent thermophysical material properties have been incorporated. The model also calculates the local time-temperature history of the sheet electrode geometry that cart he coupled with appropriate metallurgical reactions to determine metallurgical changes and subsequent mechanical properties in both the fusion zone and the HAZ.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MANEY PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T04:42:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T04:42:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF WELDING AND JOINING, 7(2), 119-124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1362-1718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1179/136217102225002998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9895</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9895</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>