<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2504</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>BriMon : a sensor network system for Railway bridge monitoring</dc:title><dc:creator>CHEBROLU, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>VALIVETI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>event detection</dc:subject><dc:subject>mobile data transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>power-efficient operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>wireless sensor applications</dc:subject><dc:subject>bottom-up design</dc:subject><dc:description>Railway systems are critical in many regions, and can consist of several tens of thousands of bridges, being used over several decades. It is critical to have a system to monitor the health of these bridges and report when and where maintenance operations are needed. This paper presents BriMon, a wireless sensor network based system for such monitoring. The design of BriMon is driven by two important factors: application requirements, and detailed measurement studies of several pieces of the architecture. In comparison with prior bridge monitoring systems and sensor network prototypes, our contributions are three-fold. First, we have designed a novel event detection mechanism that triggers data collection in response to an oncoming train. Next, BriMon employs a simple yet effective multi-channel data transfer mechanism to transfer the collected data onto a sink located on the moving train. Third, the BriMon architecture is designed with careful consideration of the interaction between the multiple requisite functionalities such as time synchronization, event detection, routing, and data transfer. Based on a prototype implementation, this paper also presents several measurement studies to show that our design choices are indeed quite effective.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T22:22:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T22:22:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MOBISYS'08: PROCEEDINGS OF THE SIXTH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON MOBILE SYSTEMS, APPLICATIONS, AND SERVICES,2-14</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-60558-139-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15833</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2504</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th International Conference on Mobile Systems, Applications, and Services,Breckenridge, CO,JUN 17-20, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>