<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17805</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:52:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Insight into the charge transport and degradation mechanisms in organic transistors operating at elevated temperatures in air</dc:title><dc:creator>NIGAM, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KABRA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>PREMARATNE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>FIELD-EFFECT TRANSISTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILM TRANSISTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOW-VOLTAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PENTACENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON</dc:subject><dc:subject>OFET</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pentacene</dc:subject><dc:subject>High temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Charge transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stability</dc:subject><dc:description>Operational stability of organic devices at above-room-temperatures in ambient environment is of imminent practical importance. In this report, we have investigated the charge transport and degradation mechanisms in pentacene based organic field effect transistors (OFETs) operating in the temperatures ranging from 25 degrees C to 150 degrees C under ambient conditions. The thin film characterizations techniques (X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, X-ray diffraction and atomic force microscopy) were used to establish the structural and chemical stability of pentacene thin films at temperatures up to 150 degrees C in ambient conditions. The electrical behavior of OFETs varies differently in different temperature bracket. Mobility, at temperatures below 110 degrees C, is found to be thermally activated in presence of traps and temperature independent in absence of traps. At temperatures above 110 degrees C mobility degrades due to polymorphism in pentacene or interfacial properties. The degradation of mobility is compensated with the decrease in threshold voltage at high temperatures and OFETs are operational at temperatures as high as 190 degrees C. 70 degrees C has been identified as the optimum temperature of operation for our OFETs where both device behavior and material properties are stable enough to ensure sustainable performance. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:52:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:52:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANIC ELECTRONICS, 22,202-209</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1566-1199</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1878-5530</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.orgel.2015.02.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17805</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>