<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-642</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigating the differences in acid separation behaviour on weak base ion exchange resins</dc:title><dc:creator>BHANDARI, VINAY M</dc:creator><dc:creator>YONEMOTO TOSHIKUNI</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VINAY A</dc:creator><dc:subject>ion exchange</dc:subject><dc:subject>effluents</dc:subject><dc:subject>sorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>acids</dc:subject><dc:description>Differences in acid separation behaviour on weak base ion exchange resins have been investigated in this work. Experimental data has been obtained on sorption equilibrium using various types of weak base resins and both inorganic and organic monobasic acids. A detailed analysis has been presented using the experimental data of present work and also that reported in the literature. Apart from acid concentration and type of acid, other factors such as resin type and basicity are also discussed. It was found that, resins with high basicity are most suitable for the acid removal applications. For resins with medium and weak basicity, large variation in the sorption capacity with concentration was observed. A new theoretical approach incorporating effect of resin basicity has been proposed and examined qualitatively and quantitatively using the sorption data. The results substantiate reversibility of sorption through lower values of protonation equilibrium constants and also indicate incomplete resin salt dissociation in some cases.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-14T16:43:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:51:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-14T16:43:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:51:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Chemical Engineering Science 55(24), 6197-6208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0009-2509(00)00212-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/642</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/642</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>