<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3948</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>MISO-structure-based control-relevant identification of MIMO systems with steady-state gain matching</dc:title><dc:creator>SHREESHA, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDI, RD</dc:creator><dc:subject>distillation-columns</dc:subject><dc:subject>predictive control</dc:subject><dc:subject>feedback-control</dc:subject><dc:subject>control design</dc:subject><dc:subject>siso</dc:subject><dc:description>The prefilter-based control-relevant identification (CRI) scheme proposed by Rivera et al. [IEEE Trans. Autom. Control 1992, 37 (7), 964-974] for single-input/single-output (SISO) systems estimates a model of the system that matches the true system dynamics in a range of frequencies that are important and relevant for closed-loop performance. In this paper, an extension of this approach is proposed for the CRI of multi-input/multi-output (MIMO) systems by partitioning the overall system into individual multi-input/single-output (MISO) structures. Furthermore, CRI methodologies proposed hitherto have not examined the issue of accurate identification of the steady-state gain. In this paper, the importance of achieving good steady-state gain match is emphasized, and a method is proposed to identify a control-relevant model that has a good match, at steady state (zero frequency), as well as in the control-relevant frequency band, with the true plant. The effect of the proposed control-relevant prefiltering on the identification of the high- and low-gain directions is also analyzed in this paper. The proposed methodology is validated using simulations on representative problems from the literature and on a paper machine problem.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T12:01:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T12:01:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 43(10), 2534-2547</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie020767v</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3948</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>