<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2596</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Integration of fired heaters into total site</dc:title><dc:creator>VARGHESE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>exchanger networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy savings</dc:subject><dc:subject>plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>total site</dc:subject><dc:subject>process integration</dc:subject><dc:subject>fired heater</dc:subject><dc:subject>site grand composite curve</dc:subject><dc:subject>intermediate fluid</dc:subject><dc:description>Total site integration across many process plants can result in substantial energy conservation. Indirect integration through an intermediate fluid to transfer heat from one process to the other is widely practiced. A simple methodology is proposed in this paper to establish maximum potential of indirect integration among multiple plants and establishes a site grand composite curve. The site grand composite curve represents the total utility requirement at any temperature after achieving maximum integration between different processes through intermediate fluid. However, the choice of intermediate fluid influences the overall site grand composite curve. Energy integration of fired heaters into the overall site depends on the site grand composite curve. A procedure is developed to target the number of fired heater, minimum fuel requirement, and appropriate air-preheat temperature. Effects of intermediate fluid flow rate on energy integration of fired heaters are also discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL TECHNICAL UNIV ATHENS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:40:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:40:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ECOS 2006: Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on Efficiency, Cost, Optimization, Simulation and Environmental Impact of Energy Systems, Vols 1-3,715-722</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-960-87584-2-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15997</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2596</dc:identifier><dc:source>19th International Conference on Efficiency, Cost, Optimization, Simulation and Environmental Impact of Energy Systems (ECOS 2006),Aghia Pelagia, GREECE,JUL 12-14, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>