<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1762</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Micro-crystalline phase formation in hot wire deposited Si : C : H alloy films from pure methane and silane mixtures</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMBHAR, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, RO</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAUER, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHRODER, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>amorphous-silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon carbon alloy films</dc:subject><dc:subject>hot wire technique</dc:subject><dc:subject>microcrystalline phase</dc:subject><dc:description>Attempts to prepare undoped microcrystalline (mu C) SiC:H alloy films by the recently developed hot wire chemical vapour deposition (HWCVD) technique have been made. Gas mixtures of SiH(4) + CH(4) and SiH(4) + C(2)H(2) with no hydrogen dilution have been used during deposition. A broad deposition parameter space of substrate temperature (T(s)), filament temperature (T(F)), and gas now has been spanned with a view to obtain a maximum band gap. The Fourier transform infrared spectra show that the Si-C alloy formation takes place under the silane starving conditions for films made from SiH(4) + CH(4) as indicated by the 780 cm(-1) band in the IR spectrum for these films. Consequently, the band gap of these films is also large as determined from ultra violet-visible spectrophotometry. However, the most interesting results are obtained from the Raman spectra and ellipsometry which indicate the presence of a micro-crystalline phase in the films prepared at T(F) = 1700 degrees C, T(s) congruent to 300 degrees C and under silane starving conditions. The possible gas phase reactions responsible for the formation of the micro-crystalline phase are discussed. Additionally, spectroscopic ellipsometry has been used to further measure the optical and microstructural properties of the films. First results on the dielectric function of the wide band gap material are presented. (C) 1998 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T00:32:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T00:32:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NON-CRYSTALLINE SOLIDS,227,452-455</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3093(98)00334-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1762</dc:identifier><dc:source>17th International Conference on Amorphous and Microcrystalline Semiconductors - Science and Technology (ICAMS 17),BUDAPEST, HUNGARY,AUG 25-29, 1997</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>