<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18239</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:09:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Accelerated Spatially Resolved Electrical Simulation of Photovoltaic Devices Using Photovoltaic-Oriented Nodal Analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>WU, XF</dc:creator><dc:creator>BLISS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BETTS, TR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOTTSCHALG, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>SILICON SOLAR-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUMINESCENCE CHARACTERIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODULES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Circuit simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nodal analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>numerical simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>parallel computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>photovoltaic (PV) cells</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents photovoltaic-oriented nodal analysis (PVONA), a general and flexible tool for efficient spatially resolved simulations for photovoltaic (PV) cells and modules. This approach overcomes the major problem of the conventional Simulation Program with Integrated Circuit Emphasis-based approaches for solving circuit network models, which is the limited number of nodes that can be simulated due to memory and computing time requirements. PVONA integrates a specifically designed sparse data structure and a graphics processing unit-based parallel conjugate gradient algorithm into a PV-oriented iterative Newton-Raphson solver. This first avoids the complicated and time-consuming netlist parsing, second saves memory space, and third accelerates the simulation procedure. In the tests, PVONA generated the local current and voltage maps of a model with 316 x 316 nodes with a thin-film PV cell in 15 s, i.e., using only 4.6% of the time required by the latest LTSpice package. The 2-D characterization is used as a case study and the potential application of PVONA toward quantitative analysis of electroluminescence are discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:09:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:09:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ELECTRON DEVICES, 62(5)1390-1398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9383</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9646</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TED.2015.2409058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18239</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>