<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18165</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:28:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Power- and polarization-dependent supercontinuum generation in alpha-BaB2O4 crystals by intense, near-infrared, femtosecond laser pulses</dc:title><dc:creator>VASA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOTA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHAVAH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>LIGHT CONTINUUM GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE-GUIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BK7 GLASS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ULTRASHORT PULSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPARENT MEDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILAMENTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR</dc:subject><dc:description>We report generation of a broadband supercontinuum (SC) in a birefringent crystal upon irradiation by intense, near-infrared, femtosecond laser pulses and investigate its dependence on incident laser power and the initial laser polarization. We choose as our sample alpha-BaB2O4 (alpha-BBO), a material in which the third order is the lowest order of nonvanishing nonlinear optical susceptibility. Three different SC generation mechanisms are identified under our experimental conditions; these are found to depend upon the pump power P-pu. Close to the critical power for self-focusing (P-pu similar to 5 MW), the spectrum is dominated by Kerr nonlinearity or self-phase modulation, whereas at intermediate pumping P-pu similar to 125 MW, Raman amplification on the Stokes side is a dominating mechanism. At higher pump power similar to 300 MW, significant asymmetric broadening extending up to similar to 570 nm is observed due to the coherent anti-Stokes Raman scattering. Our study provides an intuitive explanation for the observed power-and polarization-dependent SC generation in alpha-BBO crystals.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:28:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:28:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW A, 91(5)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1050-2947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1094-1622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.91.053837</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18165</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>