<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1606</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Secondary geochemical dispersion in the Precambrian auriferous Hutti-Maski schist belt, Raichur district, Karnataka, India. Part II. Application of factorial design in the analysis of secondary dispersion of As</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, NR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDALAI, HS</dc:creator><dc:subject>arsenic</dc:subject><dc:subject>drainage</dc:subject><dc:subject>groundwater resources</dc:subject><dc:subject>least squares approximations</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>polynomials</dc:subject><dc:subject>sampling</dc:subject><dc:description>The study uses the technique of factorial design for analysis of factors governing secondary dispersion of As in an auriferous Archean greenstone belt. Details of the sampling procedure and analytical techniques used for As in groundwater and soil of the Hutti-Maski schist belt are discussed in Part I of the paper in this issue. The main effects and interactions of topographic slope, drainage texture, proximity to lineament, depth of water table and soil types have been considered. The study shows that secondary dispersion of As is governed by proximity to lineament and factors that govern drainage and ground water movement. The factors retained were used to predict As values using a response surface model obtained by least square fitting using orthogonal polynomials. The goodness of fit of the model shows that the factors identified explain the secondary dispersion of As adequately.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-07-18T05:38:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:11:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-07-18T05:38:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:11:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Geochemical Exploration 71(3), 291-303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0375-6742</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0375-6742(00)00159-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1606</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>