<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4063</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Solid Suspension and Liquid Phase Mixing in Solid-Liquid Stirred Tanks</dc:title><dc:creator>SARDESHPANDE, MV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAGI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:creator>RANADE, VV</dc:creator><dc:subject>minimum agitation speed</dc:subject><dc:subject>critical impeller speed</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure-fluctuations</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>vessels</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>contactors</dc:subject><dc:description>Stirred tanks are widely used in chemical process industries for catalytic reactions, dissolution of solids, crystallization, and so oil. In designing and optimizing such processes, suspension quality Of Slurry is an important parameter. Suspension quality depends upon complex interactions of impeller generated flow, turbulence, and solid loading. Most of the earlier work on solid suspension focuses Oil identifying critical impeller speed for just suspension of solids (N(js)). In this study, apart from N(js) aspects like cloud height and liquid phase mixing in solid-liquid suspensions were also studied A new way of characterizing solid-liquid suspensions and liquid phase mixing using nonintrusive wall pressure fluctuation measurements has been developed. Systematic experimental data on N(js), cloud height, power consumption, mixing time, and circulation time over a range of solid volume fraction and impeller speeds have been presented here. The results and discussion presented here will have useful implications for designing solid-liquid stirred tanks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T20:44:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T20:44:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 48(21), 9713-9722</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie801858a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4063</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4063</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>