<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4510</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-12T06:04:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>7Li NMR studies on the triangular lattice system LiCrO2</dc:title><dc:creator>ALEXANDER, LK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTTGEN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>NATH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>LOIDL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>heisenberg-antiferromagnet</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-dimensional systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase-transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>vortices</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxides</dc:subject><dc:description>We report Li-7 NMR, magnetic susceptibility, and heat capacity measurements on the triangular lattice Heisenberg antiferromagnet compound LiCrO2. We find that in contrast to NaCrO2, magnetic properties of LiCrO2 have a more pronounced three dimensional character with sharp anomalies in the temperature variation of the Li-7 NMR intensity and the NMR spin-lattice relaxation rate 1/T-1. From heat capacity measurements we find that the total entropy related to the magnetic transition is in agreement with expectations. However, we find a significant contribution to the magnetic entropy in the range from the ordering temperature T-N to nearly 4T(N). This suggests the existence of magnetic correlations at temperatures well above T-N which might be due to the frustrated nature of the system. Based on the temperature dependence of 1/T-1, we discuss the possible occurrence of a Kosterlitz-Thouless-Berezinskii (KTB) transition taking place at T-KTB=54 K in LiCrO2. Heat capacity data at low temperatures (T &lt; T-N) exhibited a T-3 dependence and the ratio of interlayer to intralayer coupling constants, J(perpendicular to)/J in LiCrO2 was found to be similar to 10(-3). Lithium depletion has no significant effect on the magnetic properties and the behavior of Li0.5CrO2 is nearly unchanged from that of LiCrO2.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T19:25:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T19:25:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 76(6), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.76.064429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4510</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4510</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>