<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4660</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of a Motor-Based Differential Settlement Simulator Setup for a Geotechnical Centrifuge</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJESH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANADHAM, BVS</dc:creator><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>barriers</dc:subject><dc:subject>centrifuge</dc:subject><dc:subject>model test</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformability</dc:subject><dc:subject>clay barrier</dc:subject><dc:subject>differential settlement</dc:subject><dc:subject>distortion</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the design details of a motor-based differential settlement simulator (MDSS) setup for inducing differential settlement in a high gravity environment. The MDSS setup comprises of a motor, controller, screw jack, central platform, gear trains, connecting shaft, and bearings. Various features of the MDSS setup along with its design procedure are described. Calibration and performance tests were performed in a large beam geotechnical centrifuge facility available at Indian Institute of Technology Bombay for inducing differential settlement using the MDSS setup. A design chart was developed for obtaining prototype settlement rates from the speed of the motor and gravity level. The usage of this setup in assessing the deformation behavior of the clay barrier of landfill cover system under various settlement rates is briefly illustrated. The versatility of the developed setup for the applications involving ground loss or boundary displacement problems is highlighted.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC TESTING MATERIALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T07:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T07:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOTECHNICAL TESTING JOURNAL, 33(6), 507-513</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0149-6115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4660</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4660</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>