<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9682</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Silver-embedded granular activated carbon as an antibacterial medium for water purification</dc:title><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIVAIAH, MV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANKAR, PA</dc:creator><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>silver</dc:subject><dc:subject>granular activated carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>escherichia coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>antibacterial</dc:subject><dc:description>Silver (Ag) particle embedded granular activated carbon (GAC) was made for the first time to assess its ability in inhibiting the growth of Escherichia coli (E. coli), a water-borne bacterial pathogen. Ag-GAC was made by impregnating GAC with AgNO3 and then reducing it to metallic Ag. Plate assay showed slight inhibition of E. coli, even with Ag-GAC prepared from 0.005 mol L-1 AgNO3, but this and shake flask tests showed a conspicuous effect only for higher concentrations of 0.1-1 mol L-1 AgNO3. Flow tests further indicated that Ag-GAC made from 1.0 mol L-1 AgNO3 caused a desirable three orders of reduction in E. coli number concentration in less than 30 s. An optimum of 9-10.5 wt% of embedded Ag in the final Ag-GAC product was necessary for the requisite complete inhibition of E. coli, killing bacteria in the contact-mode for up to 350 L of flowing water. These results prove that Ag-GAC possesses antibacterial properties and can be used for disinfection to produce potable quality water. (C) 2008 Society of Chemical Industry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T00:38:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T00:38:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 83(8), 1177-1180</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-2575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jctb.1985</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9682</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>