<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5902</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study on ionic and electronic transport properties of calcium-doped GdAlO3</dc:title><dc:creator>SINHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAFE, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrolytes</dc:subject><dc:subject>laalo3</dc:subject><dc:subject>lagao3</dc:subject><dc:subject>cell</dc:subject><dc:description>Oxygen-permeation measurements were carried out on a Gd0.85Ca0.15AlO3-delta specimen in the temperature range of 400-900 degrees C as a function of the oxygen partial pressure from 1.01 x 10(5) to 18.85 Pa. Simultaneously, the open-circuit voltage of the permeation cell and the voltage upon partially short-circuiting the cell over external resistances were measured. As a result, the ionic conductivity of Gd0.85Ca0.15AlO3-delta between 650 and 900 degrees C and the electronic conduction parameter p(circle plus) of the hole conductivity were obtained as a function of temperature. The electrochemical performance as well as the stability of the electrolyte material were studied by carrying out cell-voltage measurements under Ar + 1000 ppm H-2 (anode) and air (cathode) environments. The present investigations suggest that Gd0.85Ca0.15AlO3-delta is predominantly an oxygen-ion conductor with an ionic conductivity slightly below that of yttria-stabilized zirconia. (C) 2008 The Electrochemical Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELECTROCHEMICAL SOC INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T15:07:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T15:07:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE ELECTROCHEMICAL SOCIETY, 155(3), B309-B314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-4651</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1149/1.2829877</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5902</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5902</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>