<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15728</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:59:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>PIP: A Multichannel, TDMA-Based MAC for Efficient and Scalable Bulk Transfer in Sensor Networks</dc:title><dc:creator>GABALE, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHEBROLU, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIJWE, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Design</dc:subject><dc:subject>Experimentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bulk data transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>throughput optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>TDMA</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAC</dc:subject><dc:subject>wireless sensor network applications</dc:subject><dc:subject>pipelining</dc:subject><dc:description>In this article, we consider the goal of achieving high throughput in a wireless sensor network. Our work is set in the context of those wireless sensor network applications which collect and transfer bulk data. We present PIP (Packets in Pipe), a MAC primitive for use by the transport module to achieve high throughput. PIP has a unique set of features: (a) it is a multihop connection-oriented primitive, (b) it is TDMA based, (c) it uses multiple radio channels, and (d) it is centrally controlled. This represents a significant shift from prior MAC protocols for bulk data transfer. PIP has several desirable properties: (a) its throughput degrades only slightly with increasing number of hops, (b) it is robust to variable wireless error rates, (c) it performs well even without any flow control, and (d) requires only small queue sizes to operate well. We substantiate these properties with a prototype implementation of PIP on the Tmote-Sky CC2420-based platform. PIP achieves about eleven times better throughput than the state-of-the-art prior work, over a network depth of 24 hops. We also show that PIP can be interagted with duty cycling, and that PIP can support streaming data from/to flash at little overhead.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:59:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:59:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACM TRANSACTIONS ON SENSOR NETWORKS, 8(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-4859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-4867</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2240116.2240117</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15728</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>