<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14121</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:21:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flow behaviour of autoclaved, 20% cold worked, Zr-2.5Nb alloy pressure tube material in the temperature range of room temperature to 800 degrees C</dc:title><dc:creator>DUREJA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRAVARTTY, JK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWASKAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>WT-PERCENT-NB</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZIRCONIUM ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERPLASTIC BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRAIN-RATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Pressure tube material of Indian Heavy Water Reactors is 20% cold-worked and stress relieved Zr-2.5Nb alloy. Inherent variability in the process parameters during the fabrication stages of pressure tube and also along the length of component have their effect on micro-structural and texture properties of the material, which in turn affect its strength parameters (yield strength and ultimate tensile strength) and flow characteristics. Data of tensile tests carried out in the temperature range from room temperature to 800 degrees C using the samples taken out from a single pressure tube have been used to develop correlations for characterizing the strength parameters' variation as a function of axial location along length of the tube and the test temperature. Applicability of Ramberg-Osgood, Holloman and Voce's correlations for defining the post yield behaviour of the material has been investigated. Effect of strain rate change on the deformation behaviour has also been studied. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:21:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:21:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MATERIALS,412(1)22-29</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2011.01.023</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14121</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>