<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17334</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:40:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismotectonic implications of strike-slip earthquakes in the Darjiling-Sikkim Himalaya</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKUL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>JADE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANSARI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATIN, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Darjiling-Sikkim Himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>dislocation modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Global Positioning System</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gish Transverse Fault</dc:subject><dc:subject>recess</dc:subject><dc:subject>salient</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEISMIC HAZARD</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEPTEMBER 2011</dc:subject><dc:subject>THRUST BELT</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEPAL HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLLISION ZONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORELAND BASIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>EASTERN NEPAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUB-HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:description>The Darjiling-Sikkim Himalaya (DSH) is located over the Dharan-Gorubathan salient recess pair and moderate thrust and strike slip earthquake occur here. The hypocentres cluster not only near the location of the Main Himalayan Thrust (MHT) or the basal decollement of the Himalayan wedge, but also well above and below it. The epicentres cluster over the mapped location of the Lesser Himalayan Duplex (LHD), suggesting that both MHT and LHD are active structures in DSH. The earthquakes below MHT can be related to transverse strike slip faulting in DSH associated with salient recess transition on both flanks of the Dharan salient. The 18 September 2011 (Mw 6.9) strike slip event suggests that the western flank of the Dharan salient is also likely to contain an active transverse strike slip fault like the Gish Transverse Fault (GTF) on its eastern flank. High-precision Global Positioning System measurements (1997-2006) indicate that a maximum of similar to 4 mm/year convergence is being accommodated in the Tista Half-Window or LHD west of the surface trace of GTF and DSH is locked south of 27 degrees N both east and west of GTF about 10 km north of the Himalayan mountain front. About 3-4 mm/year sinistral strike slip is postulated on GTF north of 27 degrees N. Dislocation based forward modelling using two thrust dislocations with oblique slip and a sinistral strike slip dislocation generated velocities that were closest to the measured back-slip velocity field in DSH.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:40:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:40:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 106(2)198-210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17334</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>