<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12145</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Probing Reliability of Transport Phenomena Based Heat Transfer and Fluid Flow Analysis in Autogeneous Fusion Welding Process</dc:title><dc:creator>BAG, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>pool convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>transfer model</dc:subject><dc:subject>laser</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:description>The transport phenomena based heat transfer and fluid flow calculations in weld pool require a number of input parameters. Arc efficiency, effective thermal conductivity, and viscosity in weld pool are some of these parameters, values of which are rarely known and difficult to assign a priori based on the scientific principles alone. The present work reports a bi-directional three-dimensional (3-D) heat transfer and fluid flow model, which is integrated with a real number based genetic algorithm. The bi-directional feature of the integrated model allows the identification of the values of a required set of uncertain model input parameters and, next, the design of process parameters to achieve a target weld pool dimension. The computed values are validated with measured results in linear gas-tungsten-arc (GTA) weld samples. Furthermore, a novel methodology to estimate the overall reliability of the computed solutions is also presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T17:24:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T17:24:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 41A(9), 2337-2347</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-010-0272-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12145</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12145</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>