<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1251</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of single-layer and bilayer InAs/GaAs quantum dots with a higher InAs coverage</dc:title><dc:creator>SENGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, SY</dc:creator><dc:creator>HALDER, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>optical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>gaas</dc:subject><dc:subject>islands</dc:subject><dc:subject>thickness</dc:subject><dc:subject>threshold</dc:subject><dc:subject>size</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:subject>bilayer</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication</dc:subject><dc:subject>high monolayer coverage</dc:subject><dc:description>Epitaxially grown self-assembled InAs quantum dots (QDs) have found applications in optoelectronics. Efforts are being made to obtain efficient quantum-dot lasers operating at longer telecommunication wavelengths, specifically 1.3 mu m and 1.55 mu m. This requires narrow emission linewidth from the quantum dots at these wavelengths. In InAs/GaAs single layer quantum dot (SQD) structure, higher InAs monolayer coverage for the QDs gives rise to larger dots emitting at longer wavelengths but results in inhomogeneous dot-size distribution. The bilayer quantum dot (BQD) can be used as an alternative to SQDs, which can emit at longer wavelengths (1.229 mu m at 8 K) with significantly narrow linewidth (similar to 16.7 meV). Here, we compare the properties of single layer and bilayer quantum dots grown with higher InAs monolayer coverage. In the BQD structure, only the top QD layer is covered with increased (3.2 ML) InAs monolayer coverage. The emission line width of our BQD sample is found to be insensitive towards post growth treatments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>VERSITA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T15:18:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T15:18:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>OPTO-ELECTRONICS REVIEW,18(3)295-299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1230-3402</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/s11772-010-1039-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1251</dc:identifier><dc:source>Symposium on IR and THz Electronics - From Materials to Devices,Warsaw, POLAND,SEP 14-18, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>