<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15396</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:58:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulation of time reversibility of Lamb wave in symmetric composite laminate</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Lamb wave</dc:subject><dc:subject>Time reversibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wavelets</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spectral finite element</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRAL ELEMENT METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROPAGATION ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DAMAGE DETECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATE STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FINITE-ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>REVERSAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>IDENTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELAMINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRACK</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a computationally efficient scheme to simulate Lamb wave propagation in symmetric laminated composite is presented and used to study time reversibility of Lamb wave. The technique proposed is a modified version of the wavelet spectral finite element (WSFE) which has been earlier developed for one-and two-dimensional wave propagation. The method follows a finite element procedure in the transformed frequency-wavenumber domain. The transformations are done using Daubechies scaling function approximation in time and one spatial dimension. Here, the modified WSFE method is used to simulate time domain Lamb wave response in doubly bounded, symmetric composite laminates. The results have been validated by comparing the wave velocities derived from these simulations with those obtained from experiments. The technique has also been used to emphasize and analyze the time reversibility phenomenon of Lamb wave. Finally, the constraint of the simulation in terms of wrap-around problem is explained with numerical examples. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:58:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:58:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MECHANICAL SCIENCES, 54(1)277-286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijmecsci.2011.11.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15396</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>