<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7503</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Surface engineering of metal-diamond composite coatings on steel substrates using chemical vapour deposition and electroplating routes</dc:title><dc:creator>SIKDER, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGHBAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRAVORTY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>nucleation</dc:subject><dc:subject>composite coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>cvd diamond</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrodeposition</dc:subject><dc:description>The-chemical vapour deposition (CVD) route has been employed, in-the present case, to enhance the bonding of diamond particles to the metal matrix in the Ni-diamond-composite-coated stainless steel CSS) substrate. The substrates were coated with various combinations of Ni-diamond composite coatings prior to CVD to suppress the diffusion of Fe on the deposition surface. Two CVD processes were then used for the growth of metal diamond composite and continuous diamond films on these buffer-layered substrates. Scanning electron microscopy, X-ray diffraction and Raman spectroscopy show the growth of high quality diamond films on the substrates. Energy dispersive X-ray analysis shows almost zero Fe content at the surface after CVD treatment. A modified Ni-diamond composite layer provides the mast suitable base to grow well-adhered and improved crystalline diamond on SS. (C) 1999 Elsevier Science S.A. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-28T21:41:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-28T21:41:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SURFACE &amp; COATINGS TECHNOLOGY, 114(40604), 230-234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0257-8972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0257-8972(99)00050-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7503</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7503</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>