<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14753</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:32:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Elastic stability analysis of cold-formed pallet rack structures with semi-rigid connections</dc:title><dc:creator>SANGLE, KK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJORIA, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALICOTTI, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>Finite element analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cold-formed steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semi-rigid connections</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPERIMENTAL VALIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NONLINEAR-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLUMNS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRAMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SWAY</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describe the three dimensional finite element modeling and elastic buckling analysis of single 2-D and 3-D frame (with semi-rigid connection) of conventional pallet racking system. Results from experimental study, effective length approach given by Rack Manufacturer's Institute (RMI) and finite element analysis of single 2-D frames of cold-formed steel pallet racking are compared. Finite element model used for single 2-D frame is further extended for 3-D frames with semi- rigid connection and results of these 3-D frames are also presented in the paper. Finite element analysis carried out on conventional pallet racks using the finite element program ANSYS with the 18 types of developed column sections. The principal aims were to find out the linear buckling load of single 2-D frames and to ascertain stability of 3-D frames of conventional pallet racking systems, made up of cold-formed sections with semi-rigid connection. Investigation into stability analysis of frames used in pallet rack structures by both experimental and finite element methods have shown that stiffening of the open upright sections using the spacer bar, channel and hat as external stiffeners will considerably increase the load carrying capacity of the frames. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:32:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:32:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CONSTRUCTIONAL STEEL RESEARCH, 71245-262</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcsr.2011.11.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14753</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>