<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13893</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T04:43:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cholesterol Biosensors Based on Oxygen Sensing Alginate-Silica Microspheres</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAYANT, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>OPTICAL BIOSENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLUCOSE-OXIDASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENCAPSULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMMOBILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESTERASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLVENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAMPLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENZYME</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>alginate-silica</dc:subject><dc:subject>microspheres</dc:subject><dc:subject>cholesterol biosensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>PtOEP dye</dc:subject><dc:description>Cholesterol determination in body is important in diagnosis of diseases like coronary heart disease, arteriosclerosis, diabetes, and obstructive jaundice. This research aims at developing fluorimetric cholesterol biosensors based on self-assembled mesoporous alginate-silica (Algilica) microspheres. For preparing the biosensor, Pt-(II)-octaethylporphine (PtOEP; oxygen sensitive metalloporphyrin) dye has been loaded in the Algilica microspheres using the solvent-mediated precipitation method. Cholesterol oxidase (ChOx) was then covalently conjugated to PtOEP/Algilica microspheres using EDC and NHS reagents. PtOEP dye and enzyme encapsulation, activity and stability were then analyzed. Layer-by-layer self-assembly was finally performed using PAH and PSS polyelectrolytes to minimize leaching of the biosensor components. The prepared biosensor exhibited linearity over a range of 0.77-2.5mM O(2) (KSV: 0.097/mM of O(2)) obtained using from Stern-Volmer plots. The biosensor response to standard cholesterol displayed a linear analytical range from 1.25 to 10mM of cholesterol with regression coefficient of 0.996 (1.25-3.75 mM), 0.976 (1.25-6 mM), and 0.959 (1.25-10mM) and response time of 10 min. Thus, the prepared cholesterol biosensor shows great potential in the diagnosis of hypercholesterolemia. Biotechnol. Bioeng. 2011; 108: 2011-2021. (C) 2011 Wiley Periodicals, Inc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:43:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:43:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOTECHNOLOGY AND BIOENGINEERING,108(9)2011-2021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-3592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/bit.23143</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13893</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>