<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2633</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance evaluation of security architecture for wireless local area networks by indexed based policy method</dc:title><dc:creator>NAYAK, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHATAK, DB</dc:creator><dc:creator>GULATI, VP</dc:creator><dc:subject>authentication time</dc:subject><dc:subject>eap</dc:subject><dc:subject>802.ix</dc:subject><dc:subject>policy index</dc:subject><dc:subject>security policies</dc:subject><dc:subject>wvpn</dc:subject><dc:subject>wvlan</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we investigated existing and proposed WLAN security technologies designed to improve 802.11 standard by applying security policies. We have extensively analyzed the effect of crypto parameters over WLAN based on packet level characteristics by applying security policy to individual packet. We have also analyzed the effect of TCP and LTDP traffic over our proposed WLAN testbed architecture. We found that TCP and UDP traffic behaves erratically, when policy index changes causing drastically degradation of system performance. In this paper, we present a detail study of performance overhead caused by the most widely used security protocols such as WEP, IEPSEC VPN and 801.1X. Furthermore, we analyze the effectiveness of such solution, based on measurement of policy indexing model implementation. Performance measurement indicates that 802.1X and VPN policy based method can be used based on the service time in future wireless systems, while it can simultaneously provide both the necessary flexibility to network operators and a high level of confidence to end users.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T14:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T14:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2005 IEEE SARNOFF SYMPOSIUM ON ADVANCES IN WIRED AND WIRELESS COMMUNICATION,122-125</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8853-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16037</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2633</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE Sarnoff Symposium on Advances in Wired and Wireless Communication,Princeton, NJ,APR 18-19, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>