<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16059</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:24:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hysteresis modeling of the grain-oriented laminations with inclusion of crystalline and textured structure in a modified Jiles-Atherton model</dc:title><dc:creator>BAGHEL, APS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>FERROMAGNETIC HYSTERESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACCOUNT HYSTERESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:description>Grain-oriented (GO) laminations owing to their crystalline and textured structure exhibit strong anisotropy in magnetic characteristics. GO laminations generally display highly steep, gooseneck, and narrow waist rolling direction (RD) hysteresis loops and complex-shaped transverse direction (TD) curves. The original Jiles-Atherton (JA) model needs improvisation while modeling such characteristics. The paper proposes a modified JA model for the hysteresis modeling of GO laminations with consideration of their crystalline and textured structure. The model is based on single crystal approximation of polycrystalline materials and modifies the anhysteretic magnetization on account of anisotropic energy. It takes into account the domain wall motion as well as domain magnetization rotation. The model provides a better prediction of RD hysteresis loops and also shows ability to characterize of TD hysteresis loops with reasonable accuracy. The model preserves simplicity of the original JA model. (C) 2013 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4788806]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:24:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:24:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 113(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4788806</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16059</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>