<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-963</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:55:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flexural analysis of laminated composites using refined higher-order C° plate bending elements</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDYA, BN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, TARUN</dc:creator><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>convergence of numerical method</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminates</dc:subject><dc:subject>bending</dc:subject><dc:description>A finite element formulation for flexure of a symmetrically laminated plate based on a higher-order displacement model and a three-dimensional state of stress and strain is presented here. The present higher-order theory incorporates linear variation of transverse normal strains and parabolic variation of transverse shear strains through the plate thickness, and as a result it does not require shear correction coefficients. A nine-noded Lagrangian parabolic isoparametric plate bending element is described. The applications of the element to bending of laminated plates with various loading, boundary conditions, and lamination types are discussed. The numerical evaluations also include the convergence study of the element used. The present solutions for deflections and stresses are compared with those obtained using the three-dimensional elasticity theory, closed-form solutions with another high-order shear deformation theory, and the Mindlin's theory. In addition, numerical results for a number of new problems, not available in the literature, are presented for future reference.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-18T09:09:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:18:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-18T09:09:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:18:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>1988</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computer methods in applied mechanics and engineering 66(2), 173-198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0045-7825</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0045-7825(88)90075-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/963</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/963</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>