<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14906</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:28:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>CXI-benzo-84 reversibly binds to tubulin at colchicine site and induces apoptosis in cancer cells</dc:title><dc:creator>RAI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KINI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNWAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUROLIA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Apoptosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anticancer drug</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benzimidazole Cell cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Checkpoint proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microtubule assembly dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROTUBULE DYNAMIC INSTABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETIC STABILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INHIBITS MIGRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTICANCER AGENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN-BOND</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BENZIMIDAZOLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOMAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>IDENTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Here, we have discovered CXI-benzo-84 as a potential anticancer agent from a library of benzimidazole derivatives using cell based screening strategy. CXI-benzo-84 inhibited cell cycle progression in metaphase stage of mitosis and accumulated spindle assembly checkpoint proteins Mad2 and BubR1 on kinetochores, which subsequently activated apoptotic cell death in cancer cells. CXI-benzo-84 depolymerized both interphase and mitotic microtubules, perturbed EB1 binding to microtubules and inhibited the assembly and GTPase activity of tubulin in vitro. CXI-benzo-84 bound to tubulin at a single binding site with a dissociation constant of 1.2 +/- 0.2 mu M. Competition experiments and molecular docking suggested that CXI-benzo-84 binds to tubulin at the colchicine-site. Further, computational analysis provided a significant insight on the binding site of CXI-benzo-84 on tubulin. In addition to its potential use in cancer chemotherapy, CXI-benzo-84 may also be useful to screen colchicine-site agents and to understand the colchicine binding site on tubulin. (C) 2013 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:28:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:28:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHEMICAL PHARMACOLOGY, 86(3)378-391</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bcp.2013.05.024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14906</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>