<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17907</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:15:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Unified Description of the Optical Phonon Modes in N-Layer MoTe2</dc:title><dc:creator>FROEHLICHER, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>LORCHAT, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNIQUE, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOLINA-SANCHEZ, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>WIRTZ, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERCIAUD, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL DICHALCOGENIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>MONOLAYER MOS2</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAND-GAP</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WSE2</dc:subject><dc:subject>BULK</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-MOTE2</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSISTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-dimensional materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>layered crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition metal dichalcogenides</dc:subject><dc:subject>MoTe2</dc:subject><dc:subject>Raman spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>interlayer breathing and shear modes</dc:subject><dc:subject>force constants</dc:subject><dc:subject>Davydov splitting</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface effects</dc:subject><dc:description>N-layer transition metal dichalcogenides provide a unique platform to investigate the evolution of the physical properties between the bulk (three-dimensional) and monolayer (quasi-two-dimensional) limits. Here, using high-resolution microRaman spectroscopy, we report a unified experimental description of the F-point optical phonons in N-layer 2H-molybdenum ditelluride (MoTe2). We observe series of N-dependent lowfrequency interlayer shear and breathing modes (below 40 cm(-1), denoted LSM and LBM) and well-defined Davydov splittings of the mid-frequency modes (in the range 100-200 cm(-1), denoted iX and oX), which solely involve displacements of the chalcogen atoms. In contrast, the high-frequency modes (in the range 200-300 cm(-1), denoted iMX and oMX), arising from displacements of both the metal and chalcogen atoms, exhibit considerably reduced splittings. The manifold of phonon modes associated with the in-plane and out-of-plane displacements are quantitatively described by a force constant model, including interactions up to the second nearest neighbor and surface effects as fitting parameters. The splittings for the iX and oX modes observed in N-layer crystals are directly correlated to the corresponding bulk Davydov splittings between the E-2u/E-1g and B-1u/A(1g) modes, respectively, and provide a measurement of the frequencies of the bulk silent E-2u and B-1u optical phonon modes. Our analysis could readily be generalized to other layered crystals.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:15:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:15:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANO LETTERS, 15(10)6481-6489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1530-6984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1530-6992</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b02683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17907</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>