<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-603</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Access mechanism for multihop cellular networks</dc:title><dc:creator>KANNAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>ofdm modulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>rayleigh channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>cellular radio</dc:subject><dc:subject>code division multiple access</dc:subject><dc:description>We propose a CDMA-OFDM access mechanism for Multihop Cellular Networks (MCN). We construct groups within the MCN, where each group comprises of a source node, a destination node, their intermediate relay nodes and assign a correlated PN sequence to each such group. Within a particular group, a single carrier is assigned to each intermediate hop. The sub carriers assigned to the intermediate hops in a given group are mutually orthogonal. Hence the proposed OFDM is FDMA in nature. The sub carriers and transmit power levels to the relay nodes are assigned in such a way as to maximize the end-to-end throughput. The end-to-end throughput is formulated by assuming a Rayleigh flat fading channel between nodes. We present a method to reuse the PN codes assigned to the groups in a particular cell. We also introduce a novel architecture for MCN. Simulation results show that the proposed access mechanism achieves better end-to-end throughput and bit error rate (BER) performance as compared to standard access mechanisms like CDMA and OFDM-FDMA. Furthermore the proposed access mechanism has considerably higher BER performance in the presence of multiple transmit sources.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-04T06:09:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:23:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-04T06:09:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:23:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the  IEEE 66th Vehicular Technology Conference, Baltimore, USA, 30 September-3 Octomber 2007, 279-283</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-0263-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/VETECF.2007.72</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/603</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/603</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>