<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6082</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental characterization of material removal in dry electrical discharge drilling</dc:title><dc:creator>GOVINDAN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>surface integrity</dc:subject><dc:subject>machining process</dc:subject><dc:subject>edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrode</dc:subject><dc:subject>gas</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>dry edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>material removal rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>tool wear rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>dimensional accuracy</dc:subject><dc:subject>single discharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>taguchi methods</dc:subject><dc:description>Dry electrical discharge machining is one of the novel EDM variants, which uses gas as dielectric fluid. Experimental characterization of material removal in dry electrical discharge drilling technique is presented in this paper. It is based on six-factor, three-level experiment using L(27) orthogonal array. All the experiments were performed in a 'quasi-explosion' mode by controlling pulse 'off-time' so as to maximize the material removal rate (MRR). Furthermore, an enclosure was provided around the electrodes with the aim to create a back pressure thereby restricting expansion of the plasma in the dry EDM process. The main response variables analyzed in this work were MRR, tool wear rate (TWR), oversize and compositional variation across the machined cross-sections. Statistical analysis of the results show that discharge current (I), gap voltage (V) and rotational speed (N) significantly influence MRR. TWR was found close to zero in most of the experiments. A predominant deposition of melted and eroded work material on the electrode surface instead of tool wear was evident. Compositional variation in the machined surface has been analyzed using EDAX; it showed migration of tool and shielding material into the work material. The study also analyzed erosion characteristics of a single-discharge in the dry EDM process vis-a-vis the conventional liquid dielectric EDM. It was observed that at low discharge energies, single-discharge in dry EDM could give larger MRR and crater radius as compared to that of the conventional liquid dielectric EDM.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T02:50:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T02:50:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MACHINE TOOLS &amp; MANUFACTURE, 50(5), 431-443</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0890-6955</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijmachtools.2010.02.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6082</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6082</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>