<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17542</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:51:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Surface and bulk electronic properties of low temperature synthesized InN microcrystals</dc:title><dc:creator>BARICK, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>INDIUM NITRIDE INN</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DECOMPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>X-ray diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nitrides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semiconducting III-V materials</dc:subject><dc:description>Structural and electronic properties of IaN microcrystals, which are synthesized by nitridation of LiInO2 with NaNH2 in a Teflon-lined autoclave at temperatures ranging between 170 and 240 degrees C. are studied as a function of the growth temperature using x-ray diffraction (XRD), high resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM), photo-absorption, Raman spectroscopy and x-ray photo-emission spectroscopy (XPS) techniques. Our study shows the formation of wurtzite InN crystals with an average size of 100 nm even at 170 degrees C. The study, furthermore, suggests an enhancement of electron concentration and a reduction of electron mobility in the crystal as the synthesis temperature (T-s) decreases. The density of certain defects lying very close to the band edge is also found to increase with the reduction of T-s. These defects are expected to act as donors, which can explain the enhancement of carrier concentration as the growth temperature decreases. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:51:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:51:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CRYSTAL GROWTH, 416,154-158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-0248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-5002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1010/j.jcrysgro.2015.01.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17542</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>