<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6158</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modal analysis of cold-formed pallet rack structures with semi-rigid connections</dc:title><dc:creator>BAJORIA, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANGLE, KK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALICOTTI, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>finite element modal analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>cold-formed steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>semi-rigid connections</dc:subject><dc:description>The three dimensional (3D) model of conventional pallet racking systems were prepared using the finite element program ANSYS and free vibration modal analysis carried out on conventional pallet racks with the 18 types of column sections developed along with semi-rigid connection. The stiffness of the connector was tested using the conventional cantilever method and also using a double cantilever method. Nonlinear finite element analysis of both the tests was carried out. From the experimental study on connection and finite element modal analysis, a simple analytical model that captures the seismic behavior of storage racks in their down aisle direction is proposed. The model is aimed at developing simplified equation for the fundamental period of storage racks in their down aisle direction. A parametric study was carried out to find out fundamental mode shape and time period. Finite element method is used for the accuracy and appropriateness of cold-formed steel frame. (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T07:55:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T07:55:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CONSTRUCTIONAL STEEL RESEARCH, 66(3), 428-441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0143-974X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcsr.2009.10.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6158</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>