<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9308</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Load transfer characteristics of socketed piles in Mumbai region</dc:title><dc:creator>BASARKAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEWAIKAR, DM</dc:creator><dc:subject>rock</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>base resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>load-displacement curves</dc:subject><dc:subject>load transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>pile load test</dc:subject><dc:subject>side shear resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>socketed pile</dc:subject><dc:description>This report uses load-transfer approach for analyzing the load-displacement response of piles socketed in weathered rocks typically found in Mumbai region. The field information used in the load-transfer analysis is obtained from conventional site investigations and does not necessitate elaborate tests. The load transfer behaviour of each stratum is expressed as a non-linear function. Empirical relations are used to express rock mass modulus and limiting values of unit side and base resistance in terms of unconfined compressive strength of intact socket material, which implicitly take into account the site-specific conditions. More than twenty pile load test data were back-analyzed before generalizing the governing parameters applicable to this region. This report demonstrates a wide range of applications of load transfer approach which includes the load-displacement behaviour and separation of elastic and net pile displacements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JAPANESE GEOTECHNICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T09:04:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T09:04:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOILS AND FOUNDATIONS, 46(2), 247-257</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0038-0806</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3208/sandf.46.247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9308</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9308</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>