<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17871</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T05:57:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of pedestrian crosswalk level of service (LOS) in perspective of type of land-use</dc:title><dc:creator>KADALI, BR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDAGIRI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>DECISIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAFETY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Level of service</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mid-block</dc:subject><dc:subject>Land-use type</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mixed traffic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Order probit</dc:subject><dc:description>In India pedestrians usually cross the road at mid-block crosswalks due to ease of access to their destination or the development of adjacent land use types such as shopping, business areas, school and residential areas. The behaviour of pedestrian will change with respect to different land use type and this change in behaviour of pedestrian further reflects change in perceived level of service (LOS). So, it is important to evaluate the quality of service of such crossing facilities with respect to different land-use type under mixed traffic conditions. In this framework, pedestrian perceived LOS were collected with respect to different land-use type such as shopping, residential and business areas. The ordered probit (OP) model was developed by using NLOGIT software package, with number of vehicles encountered, road crossing difficulty as well as safety considered as primary factors along with pedestrian individual factors (gender and age), land-use type and roadway geometry. From the model results, it has been concluded that perceived safety, crossing difficulty, land-use condition, number of vehicles encountered, median width and number of lanes have significant effect on pedestrian perceived LOS at unprotected (un-signalized) mid-block crosswalks in mixed traffic scenario. The inferences of these results highlights the importance of land use planning in designing a new set of pedestrian access facilities for unprotected mid-block crosswalks under mixed traffic conditions. Also the study results would be useful for evaluating pedestrian accessibility taking into account different land-use type and planning required degree of segregation with vehicular movement at unprotected mid-block crosswalk locations. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:57:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:57:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSPORTATION RESEARCH PART A-POLICY AND PRACTICE, 73,113-124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0965-8564</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tra.2015.01.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17871</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>