<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14024</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:16:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Attribution of aerosol radiative forcing over India during the winter monsoon to emissions from source categories and geographical regions</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOUCHER, O</dc:creator><dc:subject>SULFUR-DIOXIDE EMISSIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMBUSTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INVENTORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRODUCTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OCEAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Radiative effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Single scattering albedo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Emission sectors and geographical regions</dc:subject><dc:description>We examine the aerosol radiative effects due to aerosols emitted from different emission sectors (anthropogenic and natural) and originating from different geographical regions within and outside India during the northeast (NE) Indian winter monsoon (January-March). These studies are carried out through aerosol transport simulations in the general circulation (GCM) model of the Laboratoire de Meteorologie Dynamique (LMD). The model estimates of aerosol single scattering albedo (SSA) show lower values (0.86-0.92) over the region north to 10 degrees N comprising of the Indian subcontinent, Bay of Bengal, and parts of the Arabian Sea compared to the region south to 10 degrees N where the estimated SSA values lie in the range 0.94-0.98. The model estimated SSA is consistent with the SSA values inferred through measurements on various platforms. Aerosols of anthropogenic origin reduce the incoming solar radiation at the surface by a factor of 10-20 times the reduction due to natural aerosols. At the top-of-atmosphere (TOA), aerosols from biofuel use cause positive forcing compared to the negative forcing from fossil fuel and natural sources in correspondence with the distribution of SSA which is estimated to be the lowest (0.7-0.78) from biofuel combustion emissions. Aerosols originating from India and Africa-west Asia lead to the reduction in surface radiation (-3 to -8W m(-2)) by 40-60% of the total reduction in surface radiation due to all aerosols over the Indian subcontinent and adjoining ocean. Aerosols originating from India and Africa-west Asia also lead to positive radiative effects at TOA over the Arabian Sea, central India (CNI), with the highest positive radiative effects over the Bay of Bengal and cause either negative or positive effects over the Indo-Gangetic plain (IGP). (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:16:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:16:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT,45(26)4398-4407</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1352-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.atmosenv.2011.05.048</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14024</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>