<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7019</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T03:09:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>SUBSTRATE BIAS EFFECTS DURING INSITU GROWTH OF Y1BA2CU3O7-DELTA THIN-FILMS BY RF MAGNETRON SPUTTERING</dc:title><dc:creator>PINTO, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>POOTHRA, JI</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAI, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYARAGHAVAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>superconducting properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:description>Superconducting Y1Ba2Cu3O7-delta thin films have been grown in situ by RF magnetron sputtering using a planar YBaCuO target with and without RF bias on the substrate. RF bias on the substrate has been found to have a significant effect on the composition of the sputtered film. While the Y and Ba contents in the film have been found to slightly decrease with increasing RF bias on the substrate, the Cu content has been found to increase significantly and approach that of the target at - 30 V substrate bias. The increase in Cu content of the film with increasing substrate bias has been attributed to a decrease in secondary electron bombardment of the film which increases the sticking coefficient of Cu atoms and does not affect that of Ba atoms at the applied substrate bias and temperature range. Nevertheless, low substrate power levels of 20 W have given films of improved thickness and compositional uniformity. Films grown in situ at 650-degrees-C on &lt;100&gt; MgO and at 680-degrees-C on &lt;100&gt; SrTiO3 substrates have shown T(c0) values of 80-82 K and a critical current density of 10(5) A cm-2 at 70 K.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T20:49:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T20:49:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICA C, 175(3-4), 310-314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-4534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0921-4534(91)90602-U</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7019</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>