<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10236</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kinetics and mechanism of oxidation of ascorbic acid by cobalt(III) amino polycarboxylato complexes in weakly basic media</dc:title><dc:creator>MAKOTE, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>electron-transfer reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>aqueous-solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>ruthenium</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron</dc:subject><dc:description>The kinetics of outer-sphere oxidation of L-ascorbic acid ((H(2)A) by Co (nta)(gly)(-), Co(nta)(ox)(2-) and Co(nta)(pic)(-) complexes have been investigated in weakly basic aqueous media (pH = 7.6 to 9.6) at 30-46 degrees C. The pseudo-first order rate constant, k(obs) shows first order dependence on ascorbic acid concentration, and increases rapidly with decrease in hydrogen ion concentration. The experimental data fits the rate law. -d[complex]/dt = 2{(k(1)K(1) [H+] + k(2)K(1)K(2))/(K-1[H+] + K1K2 + [H+]2)}[complex] [H(2)A](tot). The observed inverse acid dependence suggests a mechanism involving HA(-) and A(2-) pathways, for which the specific rate and activation parameters have been determined. Comparison of second order rate constants reveals that the A(2-) is at least 10(3) times more reactive than HA(-) in the case of all the complexes used for the study. The higher redox reactivity is accompanied by a lowering of enthalpy of activation. The reactivity of metal complexes is greatly influenced by the ligand field effect of the coordinated groups and the presence of pi-acceptor ligand provides a low energy pathway for electron transfer from a pi-donor ascorbate anion leading to rate enhancement. Reduction potentials for the metal complexes have been estimated with the help of Marcus equation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T05:05:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T05:05:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF CHEMISTRY SECTION A-INORGANIC BIO-INORGANIC PHYSICAL THEORETICAL &amp; ANALYTICAL CHEMISTRY, 38(8), 783-791</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0376-4710</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10236</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10236</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>