<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1653</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Surface finish and integrity of machined surfaces on AI/SiCp composites</dc:title><dc:creator>DABADE, UA</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALASUBRAMANIAM, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANUPRASAD, VV</dc:creator><dc:subject>aluminum-matrix composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>challenges</dc:subject><dc:subject>mmc</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal matrix composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface finish</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface integrity</dc:subject><dc:subject>wiper insert</dc:subject><dc:description>The increasing applications of metal matrix composites (MMCs) for structural and wear resistant components in aerospace, automotive and recreational fields necessitated an in-depth analysis of quality of machined surfaces, which determines the ability of the material to withstand severe conditions of stress, temperature, corrosion, and controls its longevity and reliability. The introduction of compressive residual stresses in machined surface is known to alleviate the surface damage to some extent and help ensure better surface integrity. Based on this premise, this experimental work was carried out using CBN inserts with and without wiper on cutting edge and also by varying the other process parameters. During the experiments, cutting forces from the machining zone were monitored and after machining, surface finish, microstructure of the surface and the residual stresses in machined surfaces were measured. It was observed that the wiper geometry on the inserts reduces the surface damage and lowers the cutting forces. (C) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T19:51:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T19:51:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS PROCESSING TECHNOLOGY,192,166-174</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0924-0136</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2007.04.044</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14974</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1653</dc:identifier><dc:source>7th Asia Pacific Conference on Materials Processing (APCMP 2006),SINGAPORE,DEC 04-06, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>