<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16109</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:49:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Laminar Burning Velocity of Methane-Air Mixtures at Elevated Temperatures</dc:title><dc:creator>AKRAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAXENA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>NATURAL-GAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLAMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMBUSTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURES</dc:subject><dc:description>The measured and computed laminar burning velocities of methane-air mixtures at higher mixture temperatures are reported in this paper. The experiments and computations were performed for a wide range of mixture temperatures and equivalence ratios. The unburned mixture temperature ranges from 370 to 650 K. Computational predictions of burning velocities were carried out with GRI-Mech 3.0, San Diego mechanism, and Konnov mechanism for methane-air mixtures. The measured burning velocities match very well with the numerical predictions for all mixture temperatures and existing experimental results for mixtures at ambient temperature. Another contribution of the present work is the variation of the measured power-law temperature exponent with mixture equivalence ratios. The maximum burning velocity (even at high mixture temperatures) and minimum temperature exponent magnitudes were observed to exist for slightly richer mixtures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY &amp; FUELS, 27(6)3460-3466</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0887-0624</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-5029</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ef4009218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16109</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>