<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11994</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Allosteric NADP-glutamate dehydrogenase from aspergilli: purification, characterization and implications for metabolic regulation at the carbon-nitrogen interface</dc:title><dc:creator>NOOR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNEKAR, NS</dc:creator><dc:subject>ammonia assimilation</dc:subject><dc:subject>penicillium-chrysogenum</dc:subject><dc:subject>alpha-ketoglutarate</dc:subject><dc:subject>saccharomyces-cerevisiae</dc:subject><dc:subject>neurospora-crassa</dc:subject><dc:subject>gdha gene</dc:subject><dc:subject>nidulans</dc:subject><dc:subject>acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>fungi</dc:subject><dc:subject>involvement</dc:subject><dc:description>NADP-dependent glutamate dehydrogenase (NADP-GDH) mediates fungal ammonium assimilation through reductive synthesis of glutamate from 2-oxoglutarate. By virtue of its position at the interface of carbon and nitrogen metabolism, biosynthetic NADP-GDH is a potential candidate for metabolic control. In order to facilitate characterization, a new and effective dye-affinity method was devised to purify NADP-GDH from two aspergilli, Aspergillus niger and Aspergillus nidulans. The A. niger NADP-GDH was characterized at length and its kinetic interaction constants with glutamate (K-m 34(.)7 mM) and ammonium (K-m 1(.)05 mM; K-i 0(.)4 mM) were consistent with an anabolic role. Isophthalate, 2-methyleneglutarate and 2,4-pyridinedicarboxylate were significant inhibitors, with respective K-i values of 6(.)9, 9(.)2 and 202(.)0 mu M. The A. niger enzyme showed allosteric properties and a sigmoid response (n(H) = 2(.)5) towards 2-oxoglutarate saturation. The co-operative behaviour was a feature common to NADP-GDH from Aspergillus awamori, A. nidulans and Aspergillus oryzae. NADP-GDH may therefore be a crucial determinant in adjusting 2-oxoglutarate flux between the tricarboxylic acid cycle and glutamate biosynthesis in aspergilli.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC GENERAL MICROBIOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:23:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:23:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROBIOLOGY-SGM, 151(), 1409-1419</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-0872</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1099/mic.0.27751-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11994</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11994</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>