<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18277</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:41:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Traditional vs. non-traditional healing for minor and major morbidities in India: uses, cost and quality comparisons</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADHAVAN, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>RURAL BURKINA-FASO</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEALTH-SERVICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEDICINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>traditional healing</dc:subject><dc:subject>minor morbidity</dc:subject><dc:subject>major morbidity</dc:subject><dc:subject>use of health care</dc:subject><dc:subject>cost comparison</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality comparison</dc:subject><dc:subject>India</dc:subject><dc:description>ObjectivesTo examine the uses, cost and quality of care of traditional healing for short-term morbidities and major morbidities in India and to compare them with the non-traditional healing. MethodsWe used data from a nationally representative survey, the India Human Development Survey (2004-2005) and descriptive as well as bivariate analyses for the examination. ResultsUse of traditional healing is much less common than use of non-traditional healing in both rural and urban areas and across all socio-economic and demographic characteristics; it is slightly more common in rural than urban areas for short-term morbidities. Use of traditional healing is relatively more frequent for cataract (especially in rural areas), leprosy, asthma, polio, paralysis, epilepsy and mental illnesses; its total cost of care and mean waiting time (in the health facility) are substantially lower than for non-traditional healing. Among patients who use both traditional and non-traditional healing, a relatively higher proportion use traditional healing complemented by non-traditional healing for short-term illnesses, but vice versa for major morbidities. ConclusionThis is the first study which has investigated at the national level the uses, complementarities, cost and quality aspects of traditional and non-traditional healing in India. Traditional healing is more affordable and pro-poor. Relatively higher use of traditional healing in patients from poorly educated as well as poor households and suffering from diseases, such as, epilepsy and mental illnesses; and higher demand for traditional healing for the above diseases highlight the need for research/policy reorientation in India. ObjectifsExaminer le cout et la qualite des soins de la guerison traditionnelle pour les morbidites mineures et majeures en Inde et les comparer avec la guerison non-traditionnelle. MethodesNous avons utilise les donnees d'une enquete representative nationale, l'Enquete Indienne sur le Developpement Humain et des analyses descriptives et bivariees pour l'examen. Resultats et conclusionsL'utilisation de la medecine traditionnelle est beaucoup moins frequente que celle de la guerison non traditionnelle a la fois dans les zones rurales et urbaines et a travers toutes les caracteristiques socioeconomiques et demographiques; elle est legerement plus frequente dans les regions rurales que dans les zones urbaines pour les morbidites mineures. L'utilisation de la medecine traditionnelle est relativement plus frequente pour la cataracte (en particulier dans les zones rurales), la lepre, l'asthme, la poliomyelite, la paralysie, l'epilepsie et les maladies mentales; son cout total pour les soins et la duree moyenne d'attente sont sensiblement plus faibles que pour la guerison non traditionnelle. Parmi les patients qui utilisent les deux methodes, une proportion relativement plus elevee utilise la guerison traditionnelle complementee par la guerison non traditionnelle pour les maladies mineures, mais l'inverse pour les morbidites majeures. ObjetivosExaminar el coste y la calidad de los cuidados ofrecidos por la medicina tradicional para morbilidades de corta duracion y morbilidades graves en la India, y compararlas con las de practicas no tradicionales. MetodosHemos utilizado datos de una encuesta nacional representativa, la India Human Development Survey y se han realizado analisis descriptivos y bivariados para el estudio. Resultados y conclusionesEl uso de la medicina tradicional es mucho menos comun que el uso de practicas no tradicionales, tanto en areas rurales como urbanas, y a lo largo de todos los estratos socioeconomicos y caracteristicas demograficas. Es un poco mas comun en areas rurales que en areas urbanas en lo que respecta a las morbilidades de corta duracion. El uso de la medicina tradicional es relativamente mas frecuente para las cataratas (especialmente en areas rurales), lepra, asma, polio, paralisis, epilepsia y enfermedades mentales; los costes totales de los cuidados y el tiempo medio de espera eran sustancialmente menores que para practicas no tradicionales. Entre los pacientes que usaban ambos, una proporcion relativamente mayor utilizaba la medicina tradicional complementada con practicas no tradicionales para enfermedades de corta duracion, y al contrario para morbilidades mayores.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:41:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:41:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TROPICAL MEDICINE &amp; INTERNATIONAL HEALTH, 20(9)1223-1238</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1360-2276</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1365-3156</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/tmi.12540</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18277</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>