<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15138</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:20:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Studies of dynamic mass transfer at the slag-metal interface - Interfacial velocity measurements</dc:title><dc:creator>MUHMOOD, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEETHARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Interfacial phenomena</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interfacial velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Oxygen</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interfacial tension</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXYGEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON</dc:subject><dc:description>The dynamics of oxygen transport along the slag-metal interface of pure iron and alumina-saturated CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 slag was studied using high-temperature X-ray image analysis. The oscillations of the metal drop occurring due to the interfacial movement of oxygen atoms driven by Marangoni forces were studied in detail. The change in interfacial area during the oscillations was measured using a digitizing software and MATLAB. It was observed that the interfacial velocity as a function of oxygen exhibits insignificant variation with temperature. Further, the values obtained for the interfacial velocity using oxygen concentration difference at the interface were slightly lower in comparison to those using sulfur. The possible reason for this lower velocity could be that, although oxygen is a smaller atom compared to that of sulfur, the energy barrier at the free iron surface is higher for oxygen, thus hindering its motion along the interface.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CARL HANSER VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:20:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:20:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MATERIALS RESEARCH, 103(7)875-883</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3139/146.110705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15138</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>