<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14142</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:31:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Closed-loop identification using direct approach and high order ARX/GOBF-ARX models</dc:title><dc:creator>BADWE, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDI, RD</dc:creator><dc:subject>SYSTEM-IDENTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MPC</dc:subject><dc:subject>Model predictive control</dc:subject><dc:subject>Closed-loop identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARX models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Generalized orthonormal basis filters</dc:subject><dc:description>Model accuracy plays a key role in the performance of advanced, model predictive control algorithms. Model fidelity is usually affected by routine operating condition changes, which necessitate reidentification. From several theoretical and practical considerations, it is recommended that such re-identification be performed under closed-loop conditions. The direct approach for closed-loop identification, owing to its simplicity, is better suited for MPC. In order to yield unbiased and consistent parameter estimates, however, this approach requires the noise model to be sufficiently parameterized. Towards this objective, high order ARX models are the most suitable candidates from the viewpoint of ease of parameter estimation. For multivariable systems, however, the identification of high order ARX models would require longer experiments to be performed. This being undesirable from a practical viewpoint, there is a need for a parsimonious parameterization that would retain the benefits of high order ARX models. In this work, we propose to use generalized orthonormal basis filters (GOBFs) to achieve this parsimonous parameterization. Further, we propose an approach to obtain reduced order models by emphasizing important frequencies so as to suitably shape the bias. We also show that the choice of the GOBF parameterization has another important merit, viz, their ability to perform well even with minimal perturbation data or short experiment times. The efficacy of the proposed approach is demonstrated via simulations on the benchmark Shell Control Problem and a laboratory quadruple tank setup. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:31:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:31:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PROCESS CONTROL,21(7)1056-1071</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-1524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jprocont.2011.05.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14142</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>