<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12652</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Semi-active friction dampers for seismic control of structures</dc:title><dc:creator>KORI, JG</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>of-the-art</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy-dissipation</dc:subject><dc:subject>control-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>modal control</dc:subject><dc:subject>buildings</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural control</dc:subject><dc:subject>semi-active control</dc:subject><dc:subject>variable friction damper</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>control algorithm</dc:subject><dc:description>Semi-active control systems have attracted a great deal of attention in recent years because these systems can operate on battery power alone, proving advantageous during seismic events when the main power source of the structure may likely fail. The behavior of semi-active devices is often highly non-linear and requires suitable and efficient control algorithm. This paper presents the comparative study and performance of variable semi-active friction dampers by using recently proposed predictive control law with direct output feedback. In this control law, the variable slip force of semi-active variable friction damper is kept slightly lower than the critical friction force, which allows the damper to remain in the slip state during an earthquake, resulting in improved energy dissipation capability. This control algorithm is able to produce a continuous and smooth slip forces for a variable friction damper. The numerical examples include a structure controlled with multiple variable semi-active friction dampers and with multiple passive friction dampers. A parameter, gain multiplier defined as the ratio of damper force to critical damper control force, is investigated under four different real earthquake ground motions, which plays an important role in the present control algorithm of the damper. The numerically evaluated optimum parametric value is considered for the analysis of the structure with dampers. The numerical results of the variable friction dampers show better performance over the passive dampers in reducing the seismic response of structures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TECHNO-PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T08:36:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T08:36:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART STRUCTURES AND SYSTEMS, 4(4), 493-515</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1738-1584</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12652</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12652</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>