<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12135</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance Evaluation Model for Multipurpose Multireservoir System Operation</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>multiobjective analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance indicator indices</dc:subject><dc:subject>system performance index</dc:subject><dc:subject>multipurpose multireservoir system operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance evaluation</dc:subject><dc:subject>mandatory flow releases</dc:subject><dc:subject>system capability</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes the development of a performance evaluation based model for the operation of multipurpose multireservoir in a river basin system. The methodology developed in the present study has been evolved for (1) allocation of releases for multi-purpose from each reservoir, (2) fair allocation of mandatory flow releases in the river, and (3) the assessment of the system capability for multipurpose operation. The System Performance Index (SYSPI) has been introduced as a measure of the overall performance of the system. SYSPI is defined as a function of the performance indicator indices which are developed to measure each of the objectives of the multireservoir system, namely, reliability of water supply, hydropower production, revenue income, and spill prevention. The SYSPI is maximized using a search algorithm which is linked to the simulation module. The application of the developed methodology is demonstrated for the reservoirs on the Narmada River System, India. The application of the methodology should enable increasing the hydropower generation within the existing framework.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T16:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T16:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESOURCES MANAGEMENT, 24(12), 3051-3063</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0920-4741</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11269-010-9594-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12135</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>