<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17973</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:49:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Europium-doped LaF3 nanocrystals with organic 9-oxidophenalenone capping ligands that display visible light excitable steady-state blue and time-delayed red emission</dc:title><dc:creator>IRFANULLAH, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHULLIYIL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>LN(3+)-DOPED NAYF4 NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUMINESCENT PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>WHITE-LIGHT</dc:subject><dc:subject>LANTHANIDE COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FACILE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOWN-CONVERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EU3+ IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSITIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:description>Visible light excitable and color tunable similar to 5% Eu3+-doped LaF3 nanocrystals (NCs), containing 9-oxido-phenalenone ligands bound to the surface as visible light sensitizers for Eu3+ dopants, have been synthesized by a facile solution-based method. The crystalline phase structure, size, composition, morphology and luminescence properties of the NCs are characterized using X-ray diffraction, high-resolution transmission electron microscopy, energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy, and steady-state and time-resolved emission spectroscopy. The results show that these NCs are very small in size (&lt;10 nm), display high degree of crystallinity and have pure tysonite structure of LaF3 with P&lt;(3)over bar&gt;c1 space group. The visible light excitation of the capping ligands triggers an alternate display of steady-state, short-lived blue emission (tau &lt; 1 ns) and time-delayed, long-lived sensitized red Eu3+ emission (tau = 0.41 ms), allowing photoluminescence chromacity tuning as a function of delay time within a specific inorganic composition. The visible light sensitization of the dopant Eu3+ sites proves more efficient than direct excitation of 5% Eu3+-doped LaF3 NCs capped by citrate ligands. The dopant Eu3+ ions are well protected from non-radiative deactivation through high-energy vibrations of the organic capping ligands which is proved by the long lifetime of the sensitized Eu3+ emission. The time-resolved emission spectra collected over a period of several milliseconds reveal that the dopant Eu3+ ions occupy at least three different sites in the NC host. It is further inferred that the sensitized Eu3+ emission primarily comes from surface dopant sites and sites just underneath the surface of the NCs. We propose that some of the interior Eu3+ sites also display sensitized emission, which are indirectly populated via Eu3+-&gt; Eu3+ energy migration from surface-sensitized Eu3+ sites of the NCs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:49:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:49:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 44(7)3082-3091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4dt03249g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17973</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>