<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7792</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rapid tooling form accuracy estimation using region elimination adaptive search based sampling technique</dc:title><dc:creator>HANUMAIAH, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>rapid prototypes</dc:subject><dc:subject>sampling methods</dc:subject><dc:description>Purpose - The purpose of this paper is to present the results of an investigation on the straightness, flatness and circularity achievable on two direct RT methods: direct metal laser sintering (DMLS) and stereolithography (SLA). Design/methodology/approach - The steps included manufacturing of samples in eight custom designs with widely used geometric features, intelligent sampling of measurement data, and estimation of corresponding form tolerance by the least square method (LSM). The region elimination adaptive search-based sampling method involved selecting additional sampling points around the maximum deviation in both positive and negative directions from the corresponding reference feature. The LSM solutions, which are commonly used in metrology, are used to estimate the form tolerances considering the best points along with initial measurement data points. Findings - Application of the region elimination search-based sampling method enables form tolerance estimation from a limited number of sample measurements. The study of the DMLS and SLA processes suggested that form accuracy of SLA samples are relatively poor, though their dimensional accuracy is much better than DMLS. Research limitations/implications - This paper was focused on estimating the form tolerances based on limited number of measurement data using region elimination search-based sampling technique. it was assumed that build process parameters suggested by the material and RP systems vendors gives optimum results, presently it does not cover the effect of geometry and other causes of errors on form accuracy. Practical implications - There are two major applications of this investigation and the corresponding knowledge base: evaluating the process capabilities of different rapid tooling processes for comparison and for selecting an appropriate process; and allocating tolerance based on manufacturability considerations, so that the designs are compatible with the process, leading to fewer iterations. A similar approach can be used for updating the capabilities of an improved process as well as include newer processes to develop a comprehensive database of RT process capabilities. Originality/value - In most of the previous benchmarking studies, a given RT process is compared with conventional practice or a limited number of other RT processes, the capabilities in terms of dimensional accuracy, form tolerance, and surface properties (surface finish, wear, and scratch resistance) have not been studied very well. To the best of authors' knowledge, no efforts have been made to estimate form tolerances of the parts or tooling produced by rapid prototyping and tooling processes. Application of the region elimination search-based sampling technique enables estimation of form tolerances that saves costly experimentations. It appears to be completely new in the rapid prototyping and tooling domain.</dc:description><dc:publisher>EMERALD GROUP PUBLISHING LIMITED</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T18:36:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T18:36:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RAPID PROTOTYPING JOURNAL, 13(3), 182-190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1355-2546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/13552540710750933</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7792</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7792</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>