<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12300</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-14T15:22:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Metabolism of benzyl alcohol via catechol ortho-pathway in methylnaphthalene-degrading Pseudomonas putida CSV86</dc:title><dc:creator>BASU, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DIXIT, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>meta-cleavage pathway</dc:subject><dc:subject>tol plasmid pww0</dc:subject><dc:subject>xylene monooxygenase</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzaldehyde dehydrogenase</dc:subject><dc:subject>cunninghamella-elegans</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidative-metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>toluene dioxygenase</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic-compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>arvilla mt-2</dc:subject><dc:subject>crude-oil</dc:subject><dc:description>Pseudomonas putida CSV86 metabolizes 1- and 2-methylnaphthalene through distinct catabolic and detoxification pathways. In spite of the similarity in the steps involved in the methylnaphthalene detoxification and the toluene side-chain hydroxylation pathways, the strain failed to utilize toluene or xylenes. However, it could grow on benzyl alcohol, 2- and 4-hydroxybenzyl alcohol. Metabolic studies suggest that the benzyl alcohol metabolism proceeds via the benzaldehyde, benzoate, and catechol ortho-cleavage pathway, in contrast to the well established catechol meta-cleavage pathway. Carbon source-dependent enzyme activity studies suggest that the degradation of aromatic alcohol involves two regulons. Aromatic alcohol induces the upper regulon, which codes for aromatic alcohol- and aromatic aldehyde-dehydrogenase and converts alcohol into acid. The aromatic acid so generated induces the specific lower regulon and is metabolized via either the ortho- or the meta-cleavage pathway. CSV86 cells transform 1- and 2-methylnaphthalene to 1- and 2-hydroxymethyl naphthalene, which are further converted to the respective naphthoic acids due to the basal level expression and broad substrate specificity of the upper regulon enzymes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:41:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:41:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED MICROBIOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 62(5-6), 579-585</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0175-7598</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00253-003-1305-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12300</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12300</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>