<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1434</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improved matchmaking algorithm for semantic Web Services based on bipartite graph matching</dc:title><dc:creator>BELLUR, UMESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, ROSHAN</dc:creator><dc:subject>web services</dc:subject><dc:subject>graph theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>greedy algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>semantic web</dc:subject><dc:subject>software architecture</dc:subject><dc:description>The ability to dynamically discover and invoke a Web Service is a critical aspect of Service Oriented Architectures. An important component of the discovery process is the matchmaking algorithm itself. In order to overcome the limitations of a syntax-based search, matchmaking algorithms based on semantic techniques have been proposed. Most of them are based on an algorithm originally proposed by M. Paolucci, et al. [19]. In this paper, we analyze this original algorithm and identify some correctness issues with it. We illustrate how these issues are an outcome of the greedy approach adopted by the algorithm. We propose a more exhaustive matchmaking algorithm, based on the concept of matching bipartite graphs, to overcome the problems faced with the original algorithm. We analyze the complexity of both the algorithms and present performance results based on our implementation of both these algorithms. We show that the complexity of our algorithm is equivalent to that of the original algorithm in spite of the improvements we have made to address the correctness issues.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-05T06:53:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:08:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-05T06:53:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:08:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Web Services, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA, 9-13 July 2007, 86-93</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-2924-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICWS.2007.105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1434</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1434</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>