<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12942</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of alpha decay of super heavy elements using S-MATRIX and wkb methods</dc:title><dc:creator>PREMA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHADEVAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHASTRY, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAGWAT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAMBHIR, YK</dc:creator><dc:subject>relativistic mean-field</dc:subject><dc:subject>microscopic description</dc:subject><dc:subject>ground-state</dc:subject><dc:subject>half-lives</dc:subject><dc:subject>scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>nuclei</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>potentials</dc:subject><dc:subject>resonances</dc:subject><dc:subject>alpha decay</dc:subject><dc:subject>superheavy elements</dc:subject><dc:subject>wkb</dc:subject><dc:subject>s-matrix</dc:subject><dc:description>A comparative study of the S-matrix and the WKB methods for the calculation of the half widths of alpha decay of super heavy elements is presented. The extent of the reliability of the WKB methods is demonstrated through simple illustrative examples. Detailed calculations have been carried out using the microscopic alpha-daughter potentials generated in the framework of the double-folding model using densities obtained in the relativistic mean field theories. We consider alpha-nucleus systems appearing in the decay chains of super heavy parent elements having A = 277, Z = 112 and A = 269, Z = 110. For negative and small positive log T-1/2 values the results from both methods are similar even though the S-matrix results should be considered to be more accurate. However, when log inverted perpendicular(1/2) values are large and positive, the width associated with such state is infinitesimally small and hence calculation of such width by the S-matrix pole search method becomes a numerically difficult problem. We find that overall, the WKB method is reliable for the calculation of half lives of alpha decay from heavy nuclei.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-09-02T02:29:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-09-02T02:29:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MODERN PHYSICS E-NUCLEAR PHYSICS, 17(4), 611-629</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0218-3013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0218301308010039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12942</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12942</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>