<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16919</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:45:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biodegradation of pyrene by a Pseudomonas aeruginosa strain RS1 isolated from refinery sludge</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>JASMINE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>HMW PAHs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pyrene biodegradation kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Growth rate on pyrene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Degradation intermediates</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYCYCLIC AROMATIC-HYDROCARBONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MYCOBACTERIUM-VANBAALENII PYR-1</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENANTHRENE DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE HYDROPHOBICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BURKHOLDERIA STRAINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOAVAILABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>IDENTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOREACTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>METABOLITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTHRACENE</dc:subject><dc:description>High molecular weight (HMW) polynuclear aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs) with more than three rings are inherently difficult to degrade. Degradation of HMW PAHs is primarily reported for actinomycetes, such as, Rhodococcus and Mycobacterium. This study reports pyrene degradation by a Pseudomonas aeruginosa strain isolated from tank bottom sludge in a refinery. High cell surface hydrophobicity induced during growth on pyrene facilitated its utilization as sole carbon source. Specific growth rate (mu) in the range of 0.03-0.085 h(-1) could be achieved over the concentration range 25-500 mg/L. The specific growth rate and specific pyrene utilization rate increased linearly with increase in total pyrene concentration. Although various degradation intermediates were identified in the aqueous phase, accumulation of total organic carbon (TOC) in the aqueous phase was only a small fraction of TOC equivalents of pyrene lost from the cultures. The degradation pathway appears to be similar to that reported for Mycobacterium sp. PYR-I. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:45:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:45:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIORESOURCE TECHNOLOGY, 166548-558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-8524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2976</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biortech.2014.05.074</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16919</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>