<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1384</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-27T04:12:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Index design for dynamic personalized PageRank</dc:title><dc:creator>PATHAK, AMIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, SOUMEN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, MANISH</dc:creator><dc:subject>numerical analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>query processing</dc:subject><dc:description>Personalized PageRank, related to random walks with restarts and conductance in resistive networks, is a frequent search paradigm for graph-structured databases. While efficient batch algorithms exist for static whole-graph PageRank, interactive query-time personalized PageRank has proved more challenging. Here we describe how to select and build indices for a popular class of PageRank algorithms, so as to provide real-time personalized PageRank and smoothly trade off between index size, preprocessing time, and query speed. We achieve this by developing a precise, yet efficiently estimated performance model for personalized PageRank query execution. We use this model in conjunction with a query workload in a cost-benefit type index optimizer. On millions of queries from CITESEER and its data graphs with 74-320 thousand nodes, our algorithm runs 50-400x faster than whole-graph PageRank, the gap growing with graph size. Index size is 10-20% of a text index. Ranking accuracy is above 94%.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-19T09:11:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:06:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-19T09:11:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:06:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE 24th International Conference on Data Engineering, Cancún, Mexico, 7-12 April 2008, 1489-1491</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1836-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICDE.2008.4497599</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1384</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1384</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>