<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1637</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Wave propagation in multi-walled carbon nanotube</dc:title><dc:creator>MITRA, MIRA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAKRISHNAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>wave propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>fourier transforms</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, wave propagation in multi-walled carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) are studied by modeling them as continuum multiple shell coupled through van der Waals force of interaction. The displacements, namely, axial, radial and circumferential displacements vary along the circumferential direction. The wave propagation are simulated using the wavelet based spectral finite element (WSFE) method. This technique involves Daubechies scaling function approximation in time and spectral element approach. The WSFE method allows the study of wave properties in both time and frequency domains. This is in contrast to the conventional Fourier transform based analysis which are restricted to frequency domain analysis. Here, first, the wavenumbers and wave speeds of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) are studied to obtain the characteristics of the waves. These group speeds have been compared with those reported in literature. Next, the natural frequencies of a single-walled carbon nanotube (SWNT) are studied for different values of the radius. The frequencies of the first five modes vary linearly with the radius of the SWNT. Finally, the time domain responses are simulated for SWNT and three-walled carbon nanotubes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-12T08:52:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:25:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-12T08:52:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:25:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computational Materials Science 45(2), 411-418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-0256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2008.10.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1637</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1637</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>