<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10816</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Exact thermodynamic principles for dynamic order existence and evolution in chaos</dc:title><dc:creator>MAHULIKAR, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>HERWIG, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>maximum-entropy production</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluctuation theorem</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexity</dc:subject><dc:subject>states</dc:subject><dc:subject>time</dc:subject><dc:subject>law</dc:subject><dc:description>The negentropy proposed first by Schroedinger is re-examined, and its conceptual and mathematical definitions are introduced. This re-definition of negentropy integrates Schroedinger's intention of its introduction, and the Subsequent diverse notions in literature. This negentropy is further corroborated by its ability to state the two exact thermodynamic principles: negentropy principle for dynamic order existence and principle of maximum negentropy production (PMNEP) for dynamic order evolution. These principles are the counterparts of the existing entropy principle and the low Of maximum entropy production, respectively. The PMNEP encompasses the basic concepts in the evolution postulates by Darwin and de Vries. Perspectives of dynamic order evolution in literature point to the validity of PMNEP as the law of evolution. These two additional principles now enable unified explanation of order creation, existence, evolution, and destruction; using thermodynamics. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:18:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:18:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHAOS SOLITONS &amp; FRACTALS, 41(4), 1939-1948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-0779</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chaos.2008.07.051</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10816</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10816</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>