<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3959</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular sensors and sensor arrays based on polyaniline microtubules</dc:title><dc:creator>SUKEERTHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CONTRACTOR, AQ</dc:creator><dc:subject>conducting polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>fabrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>glucose</dc:subject><dc:subject>devices</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes the fabrication of microtubular biosensors and sensor arrays based on polyaniline with superior transducing ability. These sensors have been tested for the estimation of glucose, urea, and triglycerides. As compared to that of a macro sensor, the response of the microtubular sensor for glucose is higher by a factor of more than 10(3). Isoporous polycarbonate membranes have been used to fabricate inexpensive devices by simple thermal evaporation of gold using appropriate machined masks. Polyaniline deposition and enzyme immobilization have been done electrochemically.. Electrochemical potential control has been used to direct enzyme immobilization to the chosen membrane device and avoid cross talk with adjacent devices. This has enabled the immobilization of a set of three different enzymes on three closely spaced devices, resulting in a microtubule array that can analyze a sample containing a mixture of glucose, urea, and triglycerides in a single measurement. This, in essence, is an "electronic tongue".</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T12:57:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T12:57:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANALYTICAL CHEMISTRY, 71(11), 2231-2236</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-2700</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ac9810213</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3959</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3959</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>