<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3118</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-29T08:52:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Membrane current and potential change during neurotransmission in smooth-muscle</dc:title><dc:creator>MANCHANDA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>mouse vas-deferens</dc:subject><dc:subject>sympathetic neuroeffector junction</dc:subject><dc:subject>guinea-pig</dc:subject><dc:subject>neuromuscular-junction</dc:subject><dc:subject>transmitter action</dc:subject><dc:subject>time course</dc:subject><dc:subject>arterioles</dc:subject><dc:subject>transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>varicosities</dc:subject><dc:subject>secretion</dc:subject><dc:description>Smooth muscle cells are electrically coupled to one another in a syncytium, and this renders their electrophysiology during neurotransmission strikingly different from that at other synapses. The postjunctional depolarizing responses of sympathetically innervated smooth muscle such as the vas deferens, particularly, the excitatory junction potentials (EJPs), possess intriguing properties which for several years have resisted explanation. A principal issue has been the temporal relationship of transmitter-generated membrane current to the resulting potential change, which seems to differ depending upon whether transmitter release is spontaneous or is nerve-stimulation-evoked. Accordingly, smooth muscle electrical properties appear to change with different patterns of transmitter release. Until some years ago this relationship was an area of uncertainty, firstly because transmitter-activated membrane current could not be measured directly and secondly because intracellular membrane potential measurements gave rise to conflicting results. Many of the uncertainties have now been resolved with refinements in techniques of measurement that have allowed membrane current time course during neurotransmission to be estimated. As a result, our understanding of smooth muscle electrical properties has been clarified and deepened. These developments are outlined in this review, and it is shown how our comprehension of neurotransmission has at every stage been influenced strongly by the techniques adopted for investigation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CURRENT SCIENCE ASSN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-14T11:56:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-14T11:56:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE,69(2)140-150</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13915</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3118</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>