<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-562</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>A model-based approach to multiresolution fusion in remotely sensed images</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, MV</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRUZZONE, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHURI, SUBHASIS</dc:creator><dc:subject>geodesy</dc:subject><dc:subject>merging</dc:subject><dc:subject>textures</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameter estimation</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a model-based approach to multiresolution fusion of remotely sensed images is presented. Given a high spatial resolution panchromatic (Pan) image and a lowspatial resolution multispectral (MS) image acquired on the same geographical area, the presented method aims to enhance the spatial resolution of the MS image to the resolution of the Pan observation. The proposed fusion technique utilizes the spatial correlation of each of the high-resolution MS channels by using an autoregressive (AR) model, whose parameters are learnt from the analysis of the Pan data. Under the assumption that the parameters of the AR model for the Pan image are the same as those that represent the MS images due to spectral correlation, the proposed technique exploits the learnt parameter values in the context of a proper regularization technique to estimate the high spatial resolution fields for the MS bands. This results in a combination of the spectral characteristics of the low-resolution MS data with the high spatial resolution of the Pan image. The main advantages of the proposed technique are: 1) unlike standard methods proposed in the literature, it requires no registration between the Pan and the MS images; 2) it models effectively the texture of the scene during the fusion process; 3) it shows very small spectral distortion (as it is less affected, compared to standard methods, by the specific digital numbers of pixels in the Pan image, since it exploits the learnt parameters from the Pan image rather than the actual Pan digital numbers for fusion); and 4) it can be used in critical situations in which the Pan and the MS images are acquired (also by different sensors) in slightly different areas. Quantitative experimental results obtained using Landsat-7 Enhanced Thematic Mapper Plus (ETM+) and Quickbird images point out the effectiveness of the proposed method.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-01-21T06:44:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:30:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-01-21T06:44:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:30:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing 44 (9), 2549-2562</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-2892</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TGRS.2006.873340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/562</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/562</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>