<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2307</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interaction between heating-cooling cycles, sodium sulfate solution and external loading of concrete with and without polypropylene fiber reinforcement</dc:title><dc:creator>DAVE, UV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>exposure</dc:subject><dc:subject>monofilament polypropylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>heating-cooling cycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>wetting-drying cycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>combined cycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>external loading</dc:subject><dc:subject>workability</dc:subject><dc:subject>compressive strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>split tensile strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexure strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>upv testing</dc:subject><dc:description>Polypropylene fibers added to concrete are expected to contribute to its post peak ductility. They should be durable when exposed to environment to sustain composite action. Though protected inside concrete, are always susceptible due to cracking of concrete sections. They are popular and used in structural &amp; non-structural applications in India today. Looking to these issues, a study is planned to evaluate effects of environments on concrete incorporating monofilament polypropylene fibres. This paper presents results of experimental investigations to evaluate mechanical properties of 6 dinear 12 &amp; 20 mm length polypropylene fibre reinforced concretes with fibre contents as 0, 0.5 &amp; 3 kg/m(3) of concrete respectively. Specimens are given heating-cooling cycles, wetting-drying cycles to induce sulfate attack and combined cycles of temperature and sulphate attack. At 28-days, half of total specimens are given 40% external equivalent load before initiating above exposures, whereas remaining are given exposures without giving any loads. All mixes are exposed to 100 &amp; 200 temperature and chemical attack cycles and 50 &amp; 100 combined cycles respectively. Compressive, Split Tensile and Flexure strengths are evaluated. Slump, Compaction Factor, Change in weight, Ultra Pulse Velocity, Failure shapes, unit weights etc. is measured. Behaviour of mixes considering effects of temperature &amp; sulfate attack individually and combined is discussed. Performance of fibres at same and different dosages &amp; effect of loading is also evaluated. In general it is observed that all fibre mixes have exhibited superior performance compared to control mix at all stages of the experimentation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>DESTECH PUBLICATIONS, INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T04:04:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T04:04:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE FIRST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON RECENT ADVANCES IN CONCRETE TECHNOLOGY,635-646</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-932078-76-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15904</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2307</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st International Conference on Recent Advances in Concrete Technology,Washington, DC,SEP 19-21, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>