<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-692</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Attainable regions of reactive distillation. Part II: single reactant azeotropic systems</dc:title><dc:creator>AGARWAL, VISHAL</dc:creator><dc:creator>THOTLA, SUMAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAUR, RUPINDER</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SANJAY</dc:creator><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>conceptual design</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentration (process)</dc:subject><dc:description>In reactive distillation (RD) one can conveniently manipulate the concentration profiles on the reactive stages by exploiting the difference in volatility of the various components. This property of RD can be advantageously used to improve the selectivity toward the desired product in case of series or series parallel reactions, and obtain a performance superior to the network of conventional reactors. In the previous work [Agarwal, V., et al., 2008. Attainable regions of reactive distillation-Part I. Single reactant non-azeotropic systems. Chemical Engineering Science, submitted for publication], we introduced representative unit models of RD to obtain the attainable regions of RD for non-azeotropic systems. In this work, we extend the approach to a system involving single binary azeotrope. Design guidelines have been formulated based on the residue curve maps, to obtain the improved attainable region with the help of these representative RD models either alone or in the form of their network.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:31:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:10:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:31:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:10:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Chemical Engineering Science 63(11), 2928-2945</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2008.02.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/692</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/692</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>