<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16252</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T09:10:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular composition and paleobotanical origin of Eocene resin from northeast India</dc:title><dc:creator>RUDRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Eocene</dc:subject><dc:subject>northeast India</dc:subject><dc:subject>resin chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dipterocarpaceae</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOSSIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>COALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMBER</dc:subject><dc:subject>IDENTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOCHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROCARBONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEGHALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIOCENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BASINS</dc:subject><dc:description>The molecular composition of fossil resins from early to middle Eocene coal from northeast India, has been analyzed for the first time to infer their paleobotanical source. The soluble component of fossil resin was analyzed using gas chromatography mass spectrometry (GC-MS). The resin extracts are composed of cadalene-based C-15 sesquiterpenoids and diagenetically altered triterpenoids. The macromolecular composition was investigated using pyrolysis gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (Py-GC MS) and Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. The major pyrolysis products are C-15 bicyclic sesquiterpenoids, alkylated naphthalenes, benzenes and a series of C-17-C-34 n-alkene-n-alkane pairs. Spectroscopic analysis revealed the dominance of aliphatic components. The presence of cadalene-based sequiterpenoids confirms the resin to be Class II or dammar resin, derived from angiosperms of Dipterocarpaceae family. These sesquiterpenoids are often detected in many SE Asian fluvio-deltaic oils. Dipterocarpaceae are characteristic of warm tropical climate suggesting the prevalence of such climate during early Eocene in northeast India.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:10:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:10:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 123(5)935-941</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-774X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16252</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>