<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1384</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Aircraft spin recovery, with and without thrust vectoring, using nonlinear dynamic inversion</dc:title><dc:creator>RAGHAVENDRA, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHAI, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, PA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUHAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHKRISHNAN, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>flight control design</dc:subject><dc:subject>bifurcation methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>control law</dc:subject><dc:subject>maneuvers</dc:subject><dc:subject>continuation</dc:subject><dc:description>The present paper addresses the problem of spin recovery of an aircraft as a nonlinear inverse dynamics problem of determining the control inputs that need to be applied to transfer the aircraft from a spin state to a level trim flight condition. A stable, oscillatory, flat, left spin state is first identified from a standard bifurcation analysis of the aircraft model considered, and this is chosen as the starting point for all recovery attempts. Three different symmetric, level-flight trim states, representative of high, moderate, and low-angle-of-attack trims for the chosen aircraft model, are computed by using an extended-bifarcation-analysis procedure. A standard form of the nonlinear dynamic inversion algorithm is implemented to recover the aircraft from the oscillatory spin state to each of the selected level trims. The required control inputs in each case, obtained by solving the inverse problem, are compared against each other and with the standard recovery procedure for a modern, low-aspect-ratio, fuselage heavy configuration. The spin recovery procedure is seen to be restricted because of limitations in control surface deflections and rates and because of loss of control effectiveness at high angles of attack. In particular, these restrictions adversely affect attempts at recovery directly from high-angle-of-attack oscillatory spins to low-angle-of-attack trims using only aerodynamic controls. Further, two different control strategies are examined in an effort to overcome difficulties in spin recovery because of these restrictions. The first strategy uses an indirect, two-step recovery procedure in which the airplane is first recovered to a high- or moderate-angle-of-attack level-flight trim condition, followed by a second step where the airplane is then transitioned to the desired low-angle-of-attack trim. The second strategy involves the use of thrust-vectoring controls in addition to the standard aerodynamic control surfaces to directly recover the aircraft from high-angle-of-attack oscillatory spin to a low-angle-of-attack level-flight trim state. Our studies reveal that both strategies are successful, highlighting the importance of effective thrust management in conjunction with suitable use of all of the aerodynamic control surfaces for spin recovery strategies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUT ASTRONAUT</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T02:20:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T02:20:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF AIRCRAFT,42(6)1492-1503</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/1.12252</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14562</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1384</dc:identifier><dc:source>AIAA 42nd Aerospace Sciences Meeting and Exhibit,Reno, NV,JAN 05-08, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>