<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1516</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Novel high performance Al2O3/poly(ether ether ketone) nanocomposites for electronics applications</dc:title><dc:creator>GOYAL, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIWARI, AN</dc:creator><dc:creator>MULIK, UP</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEGI, YS</dc:creator><dc:subject>crystal microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>electronics engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyether ether ketones</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermodynamic stability</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper deals with the preparation and characterization of nanocomposites of poly(ether ether ketone) (PEEK) containing nano-aluminum oxide (n-Al2O3) filler up to 30 wt% (12 vol%) loading. Nanocomposites showed improved thermal stability, crystallization, and coefficient of thermal expansion (CTE). Thermogravimetric analysis showed enhanced thermal stability and char yield on increasing the n-Al2O3 loading in PEEK matrix. The peak crystallization temperature is increased up to 13 °C for the nanocomposites as compared to pure PEEK. The CTE is decreased to a value very close to the CTE of copper at 12 vol% Al2O3 loading. The CTE values obtained were compared with the theoretical equations in the literature. The X-ray diffraction showed that PEEK crystalline structure is unchanged with addition of n-Al2O3. The distribution of n-Al2O3 in the PEEK matrix was studied by transmission electron microscopy and scanning electron microscopy. The results show that the prepared n-Al2O3/PEEK nanocomposites may have potential applications in electronics.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-17T04:09:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:18:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-17T04:09:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:18:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Composites Science and Technology 67(9), 1802-1812</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0266-3538</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.compscitech.2006.10.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1516</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1516</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>