<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14496</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:15:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis and characterization of 3d and 4f metal complexes of Schiff base ligands</dc:title><dc:creator>UPADHYAY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAIDYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATASAI, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAYAPAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAM, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Schiff base</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lanthanide ion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transition metal complex</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DFT and TD-DFT calculations</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE-MAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>TARGETED STRUCTURAL DISTORTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION MAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NICKEL(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANISOTROPIC BARRIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Square planar complexes of monomeric [Cu(L1)(2)] (1) and [Ni(L1)(2)] (2) (where L1 is C20H24NO2) are isolated through the use of Schiff base ligands and characterized by X-ray diffraction, UV-Vis, electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) and DFT calculations. Effects of coordinating and non-coordinating solvent for 1 and 2 (UV-Vis) were studied in detail. The EPR spectra recorded for 1, confirms the rhombic nature of Cu(II) ion of 1 in the solid state, g = [2.185, 2.086, 2.036], and frozen fluid with the spin Hamiltonian parameters, g = [2.207, 2.079, 2.040]. The slight deviation in the g-tensor of 1 from its powder to frozen solution is attributed to the loss of intermolecular hydrogen bonding in fluid solution. UV-Vis (for 1 and 2) and EPR (for 1) parameters obtained from DFT calculations are consistent with the experimental data, and further confirms that the solid state structures of 1 and 2 are maintained in solution. Crystal structures of praseodymium and lanthanum monomeric complexes obtained with HL2 (C14H11NO2) are also reported. The X-ray crystal structure of the praseodymium complex solved in an orthorhombic crystal system with molecular formula [Pr(HL2)(2)(NO3)(3)] (3), whereas lanthanum in a triclinic system with molecular formula [La(HL2)(3)(NO3)(3)] (4) with multiple intermolecular hydrogen bonds. Complexes 3 and 4 are found to be in distorted bicapped square anti-prism and Icosahedron geometries respectively. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:15:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:15:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYHEDRON, 6687-96</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.poly.2013.02.039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14496</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>