<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4643</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of a novel nitro-derivative of noscapine for the potential treatment of drug-resistant ovarian cancer and t-cell lymphoma</dc:title><dc:creator>ANEJA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VANGAPANDU, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>LOPUS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, HC</dc:creator><dc:subject>microtubule dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>living cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>cem cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>tubulin</dc:subject><dc:subject>apoptosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>mitosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>agent</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>suppression</dc:subject><dc:description>We have shown previously that an antitussive plant alkaloid, noscapine, binds tubulin, displays anticancer activity, and has a safe pharmacological profile in humans. Structure-function analyses pointed to a proton at position-9 of the isoquinoline ring that can be modified without compromising tubulin binding activity. Thus, many noscapine analogs with different functional moieties at position-9 were synthesized. Those analogs that kill human cancer cells resistant to other antimicrotubule agents, vincas and taxanes, were screened. Here, we present one such analog, 9-nitro-noscapine (9-nitro-nos), which binds tubulin and induces apoptosis selectively in tumor cells ( ovarian and T-cell lymphoma) resistant to paclitaxel, vinblastine, and teniposide. 9-Nitro-nos treatment at doses as high as 100 mu M did not affect the cell cycle profile of normal human fibroblasts. This selectivity of 9-nitro-nos for cancer cells represents a unique edge over the other available antimitotics. 9-Nitro-nos perturbs the progression of cell cycle by mitotic arrest, followed by apoptotic cell death associated with increased caspase-3 activation and appearance of terminal deoxynucleotidyl transferase dUTP nick-end labeling-positive cells. Thus, we conclude that 9-nitro-nos has great potential to be a novel therapeutic agent for ovarian and T-cell lymphoma cancers, even those that have become drug-resistant to currently available chemotherapeutic drugs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC PHARMACOLOGY EXPERIMENTAL THERAPEUTICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T06:46:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T06:46:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MOLECULAR PHARMACOLOGY, 69(6), 1801-1809</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0026-895X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1124/mol.105.021899</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4643</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4643</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>