<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12326</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T07:27:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Momentum and heat transfer from a continuous moving surface to a power-law fluid</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHUR, MN</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATURANI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARATIYA, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>forced-convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>plate</dc:subject><dc:description>Momentum and heat transfer from a continuous moving surface with an arbitrary surface velocity distribution and uniform surface temperature in a power-law fluid have been considered. Using a coordinate transformation, the boundary layer equations are reduced to a simple form. Modified Merk's series method has been used for momentum equation and universal function approach for energy equation. The resulting equations have been integrated numerically by using fourth-order Runge-Kutta method and method of continuation. Two types of plate velocity distributions are considered: (i) surface velocity proportional to positive power of distance from the slot, (ii) linearly stretched velocity distribution with nonzero slot velocity. It is found that the displacement thickness is much thicker for pseudoplastic fluids than for Newtonian and dilatant fluids for both cases. The local Nusselt number, obtained by the universal function method, has been compared with non-similar results. The results are in good agreement.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG WIEN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T13:04:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T13:04:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA MECHANICA, 142(1-4), 119-131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0001-5970</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF01190014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12326</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12326</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>