<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3866</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Formation and aggregation of polymorphs in continuous precipitation .2. Kinetics of CaCO3 precipitation</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATIA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>calcium-carbonate crystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>monolayers</dc:subject><dc:subject>ions</dc:subject><dc:description>Experiments with the continuous precipitation of calcium carbonate are reported in this study. Particle size distributions were measured on-line and interpreted by means of the simultaneous nucleation and the transformation models developed in part 1 of this sequence. Three regimes of precipitation are reported in this study, governed by the supersaturation and liquid phase [Ca2+]/[CO32-] ionic ratio. These comprise of a heterogeneous regime involving calcite and vaterite nucleation at moderate [Ca2+]/[CO32-] ionic ratio in an unsealed reactor, homogeneous nucleation of vaterite followed by transformation to calcite in a scaled reactor at low and moderate [Ca2+]/[CO32-] ratio, and formation of stable vaterite at high [Ca2+]/[CO32-] ratio. The particle size distributions in the different regimes are well fitted by the applicable model from part 1 or earlier studies of single-species precipitation. Where appropriate, kinetic parameters obtained from the fits are correlated with supersaturation by power law models.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T05:21:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T05:21:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 35(6), 1995-2006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie950402t</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3866</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3866</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>