<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14286</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T09:27:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>A computational insight into a metal mediated pathway for the ring-opening polymerization (ROP) of lactides by an ionic {(NHC)(2)Ag}(+)X(-) (X = halide) type N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) complex</dc:title><dc:creator>STEPHEN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-ORBITAL METHODS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AB-INITIO PSEUDOPOTENTIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFECTIVE CORE POTENTIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIXED AQUEOUS-MEDIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SET MODEL CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPSILON-CAPROLACTONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRIMETHYLENE CARBONATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-ELEMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GOLD(I) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOTAL ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:description>A metal mediated coordination-insertion pathway for the ring-opening polymerization (ROP) of L-lactide by an ionic {(NHC)(2)Ag}(+)X(-) (X = halide) type silver complex of N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC) has been investigated using the density functional theory (DFT) method. A clear insight into the lactide insertion process could be obtained by modeling two consecutive monomer addition steps with the first one mimicking chain initiation with the second representing a propagation step. In particular, in each of the cycles, the reaction initiates with the formation of a lactide coordinated species, [1+LL] and [2+LL] that transforms into a metal bound cyclic lactide intermediate, I([1+LL] -&gt; 2) and I([2+LL] -&gt; 3), which subsequently ring opens to give the lactide inserted products, 2 and 3. The estimated overall activation barrier for the initiation step is 42.0 kcal mol(-1) while the same for the propagation step is 31.5 kcal mol(-1). Studies on higher monomer insertions showed a decrease in the relative product energies as anticipated for an addition polymerization pathway.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:27:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:27:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS,40(39)10156-10161</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c1dt10345h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14286</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>