<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15709</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:50:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Sediment Yield Assessment of a Large Basin using PSIAC Approach in GIS Environment</dc:title><dc:creator>GARG, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOTHIPRAKASH, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sediment yield</dc:subject><dc:subject>Erosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pacific Southwest Inter-Agency Committee model (PSIAC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geomorphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geographical Information System (GIS)</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOIL-EROSION MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRAINAGE BASINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATCHMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCALE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AREAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>RIVER</dc:subject><dc:description>Reservoirs are the key infrastructure for the socio-economic development of a country. The reservoirs are proven to be a remedial solution of highly erratic spatial and temporal availability of water. The growth in population and consequent developmental activities within a catchment area has shown to aggravate the problem of sedimentation which comprised of erosion, sediment transport and its deposition in these reservoirs. Among all above mentioned, reservoir sediment deposition is most important as it reduces its useful life and impairs the purposes of these vast water resource. The sediment yield has been considered as comprehensive index for assessing sustainability of such resources. The present study investigates the suitability of Pacific Southwest Inter-Agency Committee (PSIAC) model in determining the sediment yield rate for a drainage basin considering nine basin factors in geographical information system (GIS) environment. For the analysis, a large river basin at the foothill of Himalayas in India has been considered as case study. It was realized that the GIS approach made large basin characteristic sampling very easy and efficient for this hilly basin. A regression equation between specific sediment yield and effective model factors was established based on geomorphic features for this basin. It was observed that most of the basin area is falling under moderate to high sediment yielding potential zone, leading to high sediment yield.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:50:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:50:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESOURCES MANAGEMENT, 26(3)799-840</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11269-011-9945-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15709</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>