<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17169</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:15:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>UV photo-ionization based asymmetric field differential ion mobility sensor for trace gas detection</dc:title><dc:creator>SURESH, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASA, NJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDAPILLAI, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>Differential ion mobility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Asymmetric wave electric field</dc:subject><dc:subject>UV photo-ionization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Volatile organic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trace gas sensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>FA-IMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MASS-SPECTROMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREATH ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXHALED BREATH</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPOSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>MS</dc:subject><dc:description>A high-field Asymmetric Waveform Ion Mobility Spectrometry (FA-IMS) with ultra-violet (UV) photo-ionization source is proposed and demonstrated for measurement of trace amounts of volatile organic compound (VOC) gases. Experimental studies performed with the sensor using a high frequency asymmetrical waveform differential field for detection of acetone, hexane and acetone-hexane mixture in trace concentrations are discussed. The detection limit as estimated for a signal-to-noise ratio of 3 is of the order of 100 ppb for acetone and hexane. Experimental studies clearly show that selective sensing of a gas in a mixture of gases is also possible by appropriate value for the compensation voltage. Numerical Simulation is also performed using two-dimensional fluid-flow equations to estimate the motion of ions in an electric field. The study also demonstrated influence of parameters such as flow velocity, duty-ratio, on compensation voltage for detection of trace VOC gases with asymmetrical high-frequency electric field. Results based on theoretical study are in agreement with the experimental studies. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:15:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:15:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSORS AND ACTUATORS B-CHEMICAL, 19544-51</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-4005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2014.01.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17169</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>