<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11456</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis, characterization, biotoxicity and antifouling study of a new organotin monomer and polymer</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>methyl-methacrylate</dc:subject><dc:subject>butyl acrylate</dc:subject><dc:subject>copolymers</dc:subject><dc:description>A new organotin monomer, p-acryloamino tibutyltin benzoate, has been synthesized by the reaction of p-amino tributyltin benzoate and acryloyl chloride in the presence of dry pyridine. The monomer is polymerized by free radical polymerization using azobisisobutyronitrile as initiator in dimethylformamide and 1-4 dioxane at 55 +/- 0.1 degrees C. The monomer and the unfractionated homopolymer have been characterized by tin analysis, solubility, i.r. and NMR spectral studies and viscosity measurements. The thermal properties were examined by thermogravimetry (TG), and differential thermal analysis (DTA). Biotoxicity testing of the premonomer, monomer and homopolymer was performed with two bacterial and one larval species. The antifouling property of the homopolymer was tested in a marine environment. The newly developed monomer and its homopolymer were compared with tributyltin acrylate (TBTA), tributyltin methacrylate (TBTMA), tributyltin alpha-chloroacrylate (TCA) and alpha-methyl p-acryloxy tributyltin benzoate (MATB) and their homopolymers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T22:43:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T22:43:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN POLYMER JOURNAL, 32(5), 613-616</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0014-3057</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0014-3057(95)00175-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11456</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>