<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17293</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:19:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Crystallization and preliminary X-ray crystallographic analysis of an artificial molten-globular-like triosephosphate isomerase protein of mixed phylogenetic origin</dc:title><dc:creator>GOYAL, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>YADAV, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAKDE, RD</dc:creator><dc:subject>SEQUENCE STATISTICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TPR MOTIF</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSENSUS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOLD</dc:subject><dc:subject>TIM</dc:subject><dc:description>A bioinformatics-based protein-engineering approach called consensus design led to the construction of a chimeric triosephosphate isomerase (TIM) protein called ccTIM (curated consensus TIM) which is as active as Saccharomyces cerevisiae TIM despite sharing only 58% sequence identity with it. The amino-acid sequence of this novel protein is as identical to native sequences from eukaryotes as to those from prokaryotes and shares some biophysical traits with a molten globular protein. Solving its crystal structure would help in understanding the physical implications of its bioinformatics-based sequence. In this report, the ccTIM protein was successfully crystallized using the microbatch-under-oil method and a full X-ray diffraction data set was collected to 2.2 angstrom resolution using a synchrotron-radiation source. The crystals belonged to space group C222(1), with unit-cell parameters a = 107.97, b = 187.21, c = 288.22 angstrom. Matthews coefficient calculations indicated the presence of six dimers in the asymmetric unit, with an approximate solvent content of 46.2%.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:19:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:19:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA CRYSTALLOGRAPHICA SECTION F-STRUCTURAL BIOLOGY COMMUNICATIONS, 701521-1525</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1744-3091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1107/S2053230X14020755</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17293</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>