<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8551</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design and analysis of full pitch winding and concentrated stator pole winding three-phase flux reversal machine for low speed application</dc:title><dc:creator>MORE, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALLURU, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>flux reversal machine (frm)</dc:subject><dc:subject>full pitch winding</dc:subject><dc:subject>doubly salient permanent magnet electrical machine</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite-element method (fem) analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>The flux reversal machine (FRM) is a doubly-salient stator permanent magnet machine with flux linkage reversal in the stator concentrated winding. The existing machines at low speed, low power (2.4 kW, 300 rpm) range are not economical. FRM topology is best suited for this application. An attempt has been made to improve the power density of machine by introducing full pitch winding. Full pitch winding FRM (FPFRM) has higher power density than the conventional concentrated stator pole winding FRM (CSPFRM). Design and comparative analysis of FPFRM and CSPFRM are made. Both machines are designed for 88-58 Nm and 300 rpm. Design details of both machines are presented. Finite Element Method (FEM) analysis is carried out to evaluate and compare the performance of CSPFRM and FPFRM. Series capacitive compensation is provided for better voltage regulation of both machines.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T21:35:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T21:35:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SADHANA-ACADEMY PROCEEDINGS IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES, 33(5), 671-687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-2499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8551</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8551</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>