<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14669</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:21:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Physical Insight Toward Heat Transport and an Improved Electrothermal Modeling Framework for FinFET Architectures</dc:title><dc:creator>SHRIVASTAVA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOSSNER, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHULZ, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>BEOL reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrothermal modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESD</dc:subject><dc:subject>extremely thin silicon on insulator (SOI) (ETSOI)</dc:subject><dc:subject>fin-shaped field-effect transistor (FET) (FinFET)</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal fail</dc:subject><dc:subject>BULK FINFETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOSFETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:description>We report on the thermal failure of fin-shaped field-effect transistor (FinFET) devices under the normal operating condition. Pre- and postfailure characteristics are investigated. A detailed physical insight on the lattice heating and heat flux in a 3-D front end of the line and complex back end of line-of a logic circuit network-is given for bulk/silicon-on-insulator (SOI) FinFET and extremely thin SOI devices using 3-D TCAD. Moreover, the self-heating behavior of both the planar and nonplanar devices is compared. Even bulk FinFET shows critical self-heating. Layout, device, and technology design guidelines (based on complex 3-D TCAD) are given for a robust on-chip thermal management. Finally, an improved framework is proposed for an accurate electrothermal modeling of various FinFET device architectures by taking into account all major heat flux paths.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:21:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:21:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ELECTRON DEVICES, 59(5)1353-1363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TED.2012.2188296</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14669</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>