<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15128</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:15:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Higher Himalaya in the Bhagirathi section (NW Himalaya, India): its structures, backthrusts and extrusion mechanism by both channel flow and critical taper mechanisms</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Ductile shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>Brittle shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>Higher Himalayan Crystalline</dc:subject><dc:subject>Backthrusting</dc:subject><dc:subject>South Tibetan Detachment System</dc:subject><dc:subject>Channel flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Critical taper mechanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Exhumation</dc:subject><dc:subject>CENTRAL THRUST ZONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GARHWAL HIGHER HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>DUCTILE SHEAR ZONES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CENTRAL NEPAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXHUMATION HISTORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTINENTAL SUBDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRUSTAL ARCHITECTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION FEATURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMAL EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DETACHMENT SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:description>The Higher Himalayan Crystalline (HHC) in the Bhagirathi river section (India) on fieldwork reveals two extensional ductile top-to-N/NE shear sub-zones-the 'South Tibetan Detachment System' and the 'Basal Detachment'aEuro"besides a preceding top-to-S/SW ductile shear. A top-to-N/NE brittle shear was identified as backthrusts from the HHC (except its northern portion) that occur repeatedly adjacent to numerous top-to-S/SW brittle shears as fore-thrusts. The northern portion of the HHC-the Gangotri Granite-exhibits infrequent total six extensional and compressional brittle shear senses. The backthrusts could be due to a low friction between the lower boundary of the HHC (i.e. the Main Central Thrust-Zone) and the partially molten hot rock materials of the HHC. Subduction of the Eurasian plate towards S/SW below the Indian plate more extensively in the Garhwal sector could be the second possible reason. Presence of two ductile extensional shear sub-zones may indicate channel flow (or several exhumation mechanisms) of the HHC in a shifting mode (similar to Mukherjee et al. in Int J Earth Sci 101:253-272, 2012). The top-to-S/SW extensional brittle shear exclusively within the upper (northern portion) of the HHC and a top-to-S/SW brittle shear within the remainder of it is a possible indicator of critical taper deformation mechanism. Thus, this work provides the field evidences of possibly both channel flow and critical taper conditions from a Higher Himalayan section, besides that by Larson et al. (Geol Soc Am Bull 122:1116-1134, 2010).</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:15:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:15:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES, 102(7)1851-1870</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00531-012-0861-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15128</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>