<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3601</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stacking of multilayer InAs quantum dots with combination capping of InAlGaAs and high temperature grown GaAs</dc:title><dc:creator>SUSEENDRAN, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>HALDER, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHIMA, TD</dc:creator><dc:creator>STANLEY, CR</dc:creator><dc:subject>1300 nm</dc:subject><dc:subject>layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>islands</dc:subject><dc:subject>strain</dc:subject><dc:subject>emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>mbe</dc:subject><dc:subject>multilayer qds</dc:subject><dc:subject>rheed</dc:subject><dc:subject>xtem</dc:subject><dc:description>We are reporting the growth of multilayer stacks of quantum dots (10 periods) with a combination capping of In(0.21)Al(0.21)Ga(0.58)As (30 angstrom) and GaAs (70-180 angstrom) grown by solid source molecular beam epitaxy (MBE). Reflection high energy electron diffraction (RHEED) has been used for the insitu monitoring of quantum dot (QD) formation in heterostructure samples. The samples were also characterized by other exsitu techniques like cross sectional transmission electron microscopy (XTEM) and photoluminescence measurements (PL). For a heterostructure sample with thin barrier thickness (&lt;100 angstrom), an XTEM image showed the stacking of QDs only up to the 5th layer and in the upper layers there was hardly any formation of dots. We presume the stoppage of dot formation is due to the uneven surface of the InAlGaAs alloy overgrown on the InAs QDs, as a result of the local compositional deviations of the Group-III atoms. Samples grown with thicker barriers (&gt; 100 angstrom of GaAs) showed good stacking of islands until the tenth layer. The thick GaAs layer overgrown on the InAlGaAs at 590 degrees C is believed to remove the surface modifications of the quaternary layer thereby creating a smoother surface front for the growth of subsequent QD layers. (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SUPERLATTICES AND MICROSTRUCTURES, 46(6), 900-906</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0749-6036</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.spmi.2009.10.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3601</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>