<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17929</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:26:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Engineering Micro/Nanoparticles by PPRGEL Process through Parametric Analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>MONDAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON-DIOXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERCRITICAL ANTISOLVENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>SECONDARY NUCLEATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO2-EXPANDED LIQUIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERSATURATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOLUMES</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work investigates the formation of micro/nanoparticles by precipitation by pressure reduction of gas-expanded liquid (PPRGEL) using carbon dioxide (CO2). Rapid depressurization of the GEL solution results in very rapid evolution of CO2 bubbles and a concomitant large temperature drop (similar to 50-70 K). Consequently, the solid solubility is lowered, leading to heterogeneous nucleation at the CO2 bubble-GEL interface. A thermodynamic model based on the total entropy change of the depressurizing system is used for computing the time-variant reduction of the CO2 mole fraction in GEL for the CO2-acetone-cholesterol system. This, in turn, is used in a combination with a kinetic model for predicting the variation of nucleation rate and the resultant solute particle size. The model is used to analyze the effects of the pre-depressurization pressure and the depressurization time, the key process parameters, on the average particle size. The predicted particle size compares well with reported experimental data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:26:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:26:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 54(13)3451-3461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie504960u</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17929</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>