<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14907</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:29:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Equation of state and the nucleon optical potential with three-body forces</dc:title><dc:creator>RAFI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PACHOURI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAIDER, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAMBHIR, YK</dc:creator><dc:subject>BRUECKNER THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HOT</dc:subject><dc:description>We report microscopic calculations of the equation of state of symmetric nuclear matter and the nucleon-nucleus optical potential in the Brueckner-Hartree-Fock approach. The calculations use several internucleon (NN) potentials, such as the Hamada-Johnston, Urbana v14, Argonne v14, Argonne v18, Reid93, and Nijm II along with and without two types of three-body forces (TBFs): the Urbana IX model and the phenomenological density-dependent three-nucleon interaction model of Lagris and Pandharipande [Nucl. Phys. A 359, 349 (1981)] and Friedman and Pandharipande [Nucl. Phys. A 361, 502 (1981)]. The inclusion of TBFs helps to reproduce the saturation properties for symmetric nuclear matter rather well as expected. The proton-nucleus optical potential has been calculated by folding the calculated reaction matrices (with and without three-body forces) over the nucleon density distributions obtained from the relativistic mean-field theory. The results show that the inclusion of TBFs reduces the strength of the central part of the optical potential in the nuclear interior and affects the calculated spin-orbit potential only marginally. As a test of the calculated potential, we have analyzed proton differential elastic scattering, analyzing power, and spin-rotation data from Ca-40 and Pb-208 at 65 and 200 MeV. It is observed that the inclusion of TBFs improves the agreement with the experiment especially for the polarization data. DOI: 10.1103/PhysRevC.87.014003</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:29:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:29:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW C, 87(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevC.87.014003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14907</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>