<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7158</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Anisotropy measurements in the boundary layer over a flat plate with suction</dc:title><dc:creator>DJENIDI, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANTONIA, RA</dc:creator><dc:subject>concentrated wall suction</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulent</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulent boundary layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentrated suction</dc:subject><dc:subject>laser doppler velocimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>anistropy</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulence modeling</dc:subject><dc:description>Laser Doppler velocity measurements are carried out in a turbulent boundary layer subjected to concentrated wall suction (through a porous strip). The measurements are taken over a longitudinal distance of 9 x the incoming boundary layer thickness ahead of the suction strip. The mean and rms velocity profiles are affected substantially by suction. Two-point measurements show that the streamwise and wall-normal autocorrelations of the streamwise velocity are reduced by suction. It is found that suction alters the redistribution of the turbulent kinetic energy k between its components. Relative to the no-suction case, the longitudinal Reynolds stress contributes more to k than the other two normal Reynolds stresses; in the outer region, its contribution is reduced which suggests structural changes in the boundary layer. This is observed in the anisotropy of the Reynolds stresses, which depart from the non-disturbed boundary layer. With suction, the anisotropy level in the near-wall region appears to be stronger than that of the undisturbed layer. It is argued that the mean shear induced by suction on the flow is responsible for the alteration of the anisotropy. The variation of the anisotropy of the layer will make the development of a turbulence model quite difficult for the flow behind suction. In that respect, a turbulence model will need to reproduce well the effects of suction on the boundary layer, if the model is to capture the effect of suction on the anisotropy of the Reynolds stresses. (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T07:34:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T07:34:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTAL THERMAL AND FLUID SCIENCE, 33(7), 1106-1111</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0894-1777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2009.06.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7158</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>