<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-388</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tractability of bilateral transactions considering multiplicity of solution space in real power tracing</dc:title><dc:creator>ABHYANKAR, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOMAN, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:subject>sparse matrices</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric power generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>linear programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>load flow</dc:subject><dc:description>Most of the tracing algorithms proposed so far are the variants of proportionality based tracing algorithm. However, proportional sharing is not an inherent characteristic of the system. It is a rule enforced to attain uniqueness of the solution in a fair manner. Under proportionate tracing regime, the bilateral transactions can be classified as tractable, partially tractable or intractable, based on degree of tractability. In this paper, we develop the concept of optimal tracing whose objective is to enforce maximum tractability of bilateral transactions, while attaining least deviation from the proportionate sharing results, using multiplicity of solution space. The resulting optimization formulation is shown to be a sparse linear programming (LP) problem. A unified formulation that models lossy MW flow network and provides consistent results for generation and load tracing is presented. The maximum tractability is modeled as soft constraint in the formulation. Illustrative examples and simulation results on IEEE-30 bus system demonstrate the claims.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-18T04:49:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T17:21:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-18T04:49:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T17:21:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE Power India Conference, New Delhi, India, 10-12 April 2006, 1-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-9525-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/POWERI.2006.1632491</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/388</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>