<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-683</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of soil-structure interaction on response of adjacent SDOF structures connected by viscous damper</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, CHIRAG C</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>viscous damper</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimum damper damping</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil structure interaction</dc:subject><dc:description>When two adjacent single degree of freedom (SDOF) structures  dynamically well separated,  connected by appropriate viscous damper (Passive Control), their response to the horizontal loads reduced significantly. The soil-structure interaction  change the performance of connected structure system.  In this paper the influence of soil properties and damping characteristics on connected structure system is analyzed. The introduction of soil-structure interaction requires a mathematical model for the foundation and surrounding soil.   The governing equation of  equilibrium have been formulated. A range of soil properties and soil damping characteristics are chosen  which gives broad picture of connected structure system  behavior  on influence of  soil-structure interaction.  The soil damping  characteristics  have major influence, but  poisson’s ratio has a minor influence.  It is concluded  that the response of connected structure system on soft soil are more critical  than those supported on  very stiff soils. Various other energy dissipating systems  to connect the adjacent structures to control the response are suggested.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:29:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:29:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG: Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 2774-2781</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/683</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>