<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15805</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:38:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Benzimidazole Conjugate of 1,1 '-Thiobis(2-naphthol) as Switch-On Fluorescence Receptor for Ag+ and the Complex as Secondary Recognition Ensemble toward Cys, Asp, and Glu in Aqueous Methanolic Solution: Synthesis, Characterization, Ion and Amino Acid Recognition, Computational Studies, and Microscopy Features</dc:title><dc:creator>DESSINGOU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>TABBASUM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHEL, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>SILVER ION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>METALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEDIA</dc:subject><dc:description>A new 1,1'-thiobis(2-naphthoxy)-based receptor molecule (L) containing a benzimidazole moiety has been synthesized and characterized by H-1 NMR, ESI-MS, and elemental analysis. The selectivity of L has been explored in aqueous methanol, resulting in selective (7.5 +/- 0.5)-fold switch-on fluorescence response toward Ag+ among 14 different transition, alkali, and alkaline earth metal ions studied. The complexation of Ag+ by L has been addressed by ESI-MS, H-1 NMR, and UV-vis spectra. Microstructural features of L and its Ag+ complex have been measured by AFM and TEM. The morphological features of L alone and L in the presence of Ag+ differ dramatically both in shape and size, and the ion induces the formation of chains owing to its coordinating ability toward benzimidazole. Further, the in situ [Ag+-L] complex was titrated against 20 naturally occurring amino acids and found that this complex acts as a secondary recognition ensemble toward Cys, Asp, and Glu by switch-off fluorescence.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:38:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:38:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 77(1)371-378</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo201926q</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15805</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>