<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7206</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>q-Analogs of distance matrices of 3-hypertrees</dc:title><dc:creator>SIVASUBRAMANIAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>theorem</dc:subject><dc:subject>tree</dc:subject><dc:subject>q-analog</dc:subject><dc:subject>distance matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>determinant</dc:subject><dc:subject>pfaffian</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider the distance matrix of trees in 3-uniform hypergraphs (which we call 3-hypertrees). We give a formula for the inverse of a few q-analogs of distance matrices of 3-hypertrees T. Some results are analogs of results by Bapat et al. for graphs. We give an alternate proof of the result that the determinant of the distance matrix of a 3-hypertree T depends only on n, the number of vertices of T. Further, we give a Pfaffian identity for a principal submatrix of some (skew-symmetrized) distance matrices of 3-hypertrees when we fix an ordering of the vertices and assign signs appropriately. A result of Graham, Hoffman and Hosoya relates the determinant of the distance matrix of a graph and the determinants of its 2-connected blocks. When the graph has as blocks a fixed connected graph H which satisfy some conditions, we give a formula for the inverse of its distance matrix. This result generalises a result of Graham and Lovasz. When each block of G is a fixed graph G, we also give some corollaries about the sum of the entries of the inverse of the distance matrix of G and some of its analogs. (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T10:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T10:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LINEAR ALGEBRA AND ITS APPLICATIONS, 431(8), 1234-1248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0024-3795</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.laa.2009.04.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7206</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7206</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>