<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1346</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interfacial phenomena in some slag-metal reactions</dc:title><dc:creator>JAKOBSSON, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DU, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEETHARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>surface-tension</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present work, the change of the interfacial tension at the slag-metal interface for sulfur transfer between molten iron, slag, and gas phases was monitored by X-ray sessile drop method in dynamic mode in the temperature range of 1830 to 1891 K. The experiments were carried out with pure iron samples immersed partly or fully in the slag phase. The slag consisted of 30 wt pet CaO, 50 wt pet Al2O3, and 20 wt pet SiO2 (alumina saturated at the experimental temperatures) with additions of FeO. Metal and slag samples contained in alumina crucibles were exposed to a CO-CO2-SO2-Ar gas mixture with defined oxygen and sulfur partial pressures, and the change of the shape of the metal drop was determined as a function of time. The equipment and the technique were calibrated by measurements of the surface tensions of the pure Cu, Ni, and Fe containing two different amounts of dissolved oxygen. A theoretical model was developed to determine the sulfur content of the metal as a function of time on the basis of sulfur diffusion in the slag and metal phases as well as surface tension-induced flow on the metal drop surface. Attempts were made to compute the interfacial tensions on the basis of force balance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MINERALS METALS MATERIALS SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T22:51:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T22:51:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS B-PROCESS METALLURGY AND MATERIALS PROCESSING SCIENCE,31(5)973-980</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5615</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11663-000-0073-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1346</dc:identifier><dc:source>Geoffrey Belton Memorial Symposium,SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA,JAN, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>