<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11655</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Strength statistics of adhesive contact between a fibrillar structure and a rough substrate</dc:title><dc:creator>PORWAL, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HUI, CY</dc:creator><dc:subject>gecko foot-hair</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhanced adhesion</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoscale</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>interfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>force</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibrillar interfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>adhesion strength statistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>random attachment strengths</dc:subject><dc:subject>random fibril lengths</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface roughness</dc:subject><dc:subject>size effects</dc:subject><dc:description>Equal distribution of load among fibrils in contact with a substrate is an important characteristic of fibrillar structures used by many small animals and insects for contact and adhesion. This is in contrast with continuum systems where stress concentration dominates interfacial failure. In this work, we study how adhesion strength of a fibrillar system depends on substrate roughness and variability of the fibril structure, which are modelled using probability distributions for fibril length and fibril attachment strength. Monte Carlo simulations are carried out to determine the adhesion strength statistics where fibril length follows normal or uniform distribution and attachment strength has a power-law form. Our results indicate that the strength distribution is Gaussian ( normal) for both the uniform and the normal distributions for length. However, the fibrillar structure having normally distributed lengths has higher strength and lower toughness than one having uniformly distributed lengths. Our simulations also show that an increase in the compliance of the fibrils can compensate for both the substrate roughness and the attachment strength variation. We also show that, as the number of fibrils n increases, the load-carrying efficiency of each fibril goes down. For large n, this effect is found to be small. Furthermore, this effect is compensated by the fact that the standard deviation of the adhesive strength decreases as 1/root n.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T11:45:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T11:45:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL SOCIETY INTERFACE, 5(21), 441-448</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-5689</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2007.1133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11655</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11655</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>