<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15751</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:11:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Secular changes in sedimentation systems and sequence stratigraphy</dc:title><dc:creator>ERIKSSON, PG</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CATUNEANU, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>CORCORAN, PL</dc:creator><dc:creator>ERIKSSON, KA</dc:creator><dc:creator>HIATT, EE</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAFLAMME, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LENHARDT, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>LONG, DGF</dc:creator><dc:creator>MIALL, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MINTS, MV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUFAHL, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIMPSON, EL</dc:creator><dc:creator>WILLIAMS, GE</dc:creator><dc:subject>Fragmentary sedimentary record</dc:subject><dc:subject>Actualism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Secular change in rates and intensities of processes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Earth mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Palaeoatmospheric evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Great oxidation events</dc:subject><dc:subject>Global magmatic slowdown</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glacial events</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biological evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sequence stratigraphy</dc:subject><dc:subject>BILLION YEARS AGO</dc:subject><dc:subject>BARBERTON GREENSTONE-BELT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERMIAN MASS EXTINCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GREAT OXIDATION EVENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEROZOIC KAIMUR FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SNOWBALL EARTH HYPOTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOW-LATITUDE GLACIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOUNT BRUCE SUPERGROUP</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOLOGICAL SOIL CRUSTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARCHAEAN MOODIES GROUP</dc:subject><dc:description>The ephemeral nature of most sedimentation processes and the fragmentary character of the sedimentary record are of first-order importance. Despite a basic uniformity of external controls on sedimentation resulting in markedly similar lithologies, facies, fades associations and depositional elements within the rock record across time, there are a number of secular changes, particularly in rates and intensities of processes that resulted in contrasts between preserved Precambrian and Phanerozoic successions. Secular change encompassed (1) variations in mantle heat, rates of plate drift and of continental crustal growth, the gravitational effects of the Moon, and in rates of weathering, erosion, transport, deposition and diagenesis; (2) a decreasing planetary rotation rate over time; (3) no vegetation in the Precambrian, but prolific microbial mats, with the opposite pertaining to the Phanerozoic; (4) the long-term evolution of the hydrosphere-atmosphere-biosphere system. A relatively abrupt and sharp turning point was reached in the Neoarchaean, with spikes in mantle plume flux and tectonothermal activity and possibly concomitant onset of the supercontinent cycle. Substantial and irreversible change occurred subsequently in the Palaeoproterozoic, whereby the dramatic change from reducing to oxidizing volcanic gases ushered in change to an oxic environment, to be followed at ca. 2.4-2.3 Ga by the "Great Oxidation Event" (GOE); rise in atmospheric oxygen was accompanied by expansion of oxygenic photosynthesis in the cyanobacteria. A possible global tectono-thermal "slowdown" from ca. 2.45-2.2 Ga may have separated a preceding plate regime which interacted with a higher energy mantle from a ca. 2.2-2.0 Ga Phanerozoic-style plate tectonic regime; the "slowdown" period also encompassed the first known global-scale glaciation and overlapped with the GOE. While large palaeodeserts emerged from ca. 2.0-1.8 Ga, possibly associated with the evolution of the supercontinent cycle, widespread euxinia by ca. 1.85 Ga ushered in the "boring billion" year period. A second time of significant and irreversible change, in the Neoproterozoic, saw a second major oxidation event and several low palaeolatitude Cryogenian (740-630 Ma) glaciations. With the veracity of the "Snowball Earth" model for Neoproterozoic glaciation being under dispute, genesis of Pre-Ediacaran low-palaeolatitude glaciation remains enigmatic. Ediacaran (635-542 Ma) glaciation with a wide palaeolatitudinal range contrasts with the circum-polar nature of Phanerozoic glaciation. The observed change from low latitude to circum-polar glaciation parallels advent and diversification of the Metazoa and the Neoproterozoic oxygenation (ca. 580 Ma), and was succeeded by the Ediacaran-Cambrian transition which ushered in biomineralization, with all its implications for the chemical sedimentary record. (C) 2012 International Association for Gondwana Research. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:11:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:11:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GONDWANA RESEARCH, 24(2)468-489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1342-937X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1878-0571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gr.2012.09.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15751</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>