<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15801</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:36:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Binary Complexes of Ammonia with Phenylacetylenes: A Combined Experimental and Computational Approach to Explore Multiple Minima on Intermolecular Potentials</dc:title><dc:creator>DEY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MONDAL, SI</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:subject>ab initio calculations</dc:subject><dc:subject>ammonia</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen bonds</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenylacetylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>substituent effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOUBLE-RESONANCE SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ULTRAVIOLET DOUBLE-RESONANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN-BONDED COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:description>The hydrogen-bonded complexes of phenylacetylene, 4-fluorophenylacetylene, 2-fluorophenylacetylene, and 2,6-difluorophenylacetylene with ammonia are investigated using IRUV double resonance spectroscopy in combination with high-level ab initio calculations at the CCSD(T)/CBS level of theory. The CHN hydrogen-bonded complex, which involves an interaction of ammonia with the acetylenic CH group is the global minimum and is observed in all four cases investigated. In addition, phenylacetylene and 4-fluorophenylacetylene form a quasi-planar cyclic complexes with ammonia incorporating NH and CHN hydrogen bonds, wherein the -electron density of the acetylenic CC bond acts as an acceptor to the NH group of ammonia. A third ammonia complex is observed for 4-fluorophenylacetylene in which ammonia interacts with the fluorine atom once again, leading to the formation of a quasi-planar cyclic complex. The substitution of the fluorine atom on the phenyl ring of phenylacetylene modulates the intermolecular potentials, which are dependent on the position of the substitution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:36:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:36:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMPHYSCHEM, 14(4)746-753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/cphc.201200797</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15801</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>