<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10056</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dielectric properties characterization of La- and Dy-doped BiFeO3 thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>PETROV, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALKAR, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>TAGANTSEV, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHIEN, HI</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASHANTHI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>AXELSSON, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALFORD, NM</dc:creator><dc:description>The dielectric response of La- and Dy- doped BiFeO3 thin films at microwave frequencies (up to 12 GHz) has been monitored as a function of frequency, direct current (dc) electric field, and magnetic field in a temperature range from 25 to 300 degrees C. Both the real and imaginary parts of the response have been found to be non-monotonic (oscillating) functions of measuring frequency. These oscillations are not particularly sensitive to a dc electric field; however, they are substantially dampened by a magnetic field. The same effect has been observed when the volume of the characterized sample is increased. This phenomenon is attributed to the presence of a limited number of structural features with a resonance type response. The exact origin of these features is unknown at present. Leakage current investigations were performed on the whole set of films. The films were highly resistive with low leakage current, thereby giving us confidence in the microwave measurements. These typically revealed 'N'-type I-V characteristics.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MATERIALS RESEARCH SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T15:17:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T15:17:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS RESEARCH, 22(8), 2179-2184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0884-2914</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1557/jmr.2007.0287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10056</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10056</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>