<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7933</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>DIMENSIONAL ANALYSIS OF HEAT AND MASS-TRANSFER CORRELATIONS USING MICRO-SCALES AND MACRO-SCALES</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRAVARTI, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHENOY, UV</dc:creator><dc:subject>dimensional analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat transfer correlations</dc:subject><dc:subject>mass transfer correlations</dc:subject><dc:subject>forced convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>free convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>power-law fluid</dc:subject><dc:description>A new kind of dimensional analysis, which uses two kinds of scales, provides a powerful tool for analyzing heat and mass transfer correlations as has been demonstrated by Ruckenstein (1986) in the case of forced convection of Newtonian fluids. In this work, the approach based on micro- and macro-scales is extended to free convection of Newtonian fluids, as well as to forced and free convection of power-law fluids. As the micro-participation and macro-participation dominate in laminar and turbulent flow respectively, bounds on the exponents of the Reynolds number Re and the Grashof number Gr can be established in the case of forced and free convection respectively. An upper bound is obtained for laminar flow and a lower bound for turbulent flow. Thus, for free convection in Newtonian fluids, it is demonstrated that the bounds on the exponent of Gr for laminar and turbulent flow are 0.25 and 0.375 respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GORDON BREACH SCI PUBL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-30T10:18:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-30T10:18:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING COMMUNICATIONS, 124(), 29-37</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-6445</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00986449308936175</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7933</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7933</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>