<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1223</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Determination of flexibility of beam-to-column connectors used in thin walled cold-formed steel pallet racking systems</dc:title><dc:creator>BAJORIA, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALIKOTI, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>cantilever bridges</dc:subject><dc:subject>connectors (structural)</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexible structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>pallets</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes a new test to determine flexibility of beam-to-column connectors used in conventional pallet racking systems. In this study, two different ways were used to find the flexibility of a connector. The connector developed was tested using the conventional cantilever method [Bajoria, KM. Three dimensional progressive collapse of warehouse racking, PhD Thesis, University of Cambridge, UK 1986], and then also using a newly proposed double cantilever method. To verify the results obtained from both the tests, a full scale frame test was carried out. In the double cantilever test the connector is subjected to three types of forces namely moment, shear and the axial pull by the beams, thereby giving behavior close to practical usage of connectors. Non-linear finite element analysis of both the tests and also of the full scale test were carried out using ANSYS [ANSYS 7.0—User's Manual, ANSYS Inc., 2005] software. The results obtained from the double cantilever test were found to match well with the full scale frame test. The experimental results and the finite element results are compared in this paper.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Thin-Walled Structures 44(3), 372-380</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.tws.2006.01.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1223</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>