<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17520</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:39:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Constrained tensile stretching of steel strips under different lubrication: predicting macroscopic strain distributions with microstructural inputs</dc:title><dc:creator>BASAVARAJ, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHEKHAWAT, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>FRICTION MEASUREMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>STAINLESS-STEEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEET</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Friction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lubrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bending under tension testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strain distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crystallographic texture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strain hardening exponent</dc:subject><dc:subject>Normal anisotropy</dc:subject><dc:description>Drawing Quality (DQ) and Interstitial Free (IF) steel strips, of identical specimen geometry, were uniaxially stretched using two servo hydraulic actuators moving in opposite directions at the same speed. Two strain levels were achieved, in a bending under tension testing setup, using a rigid cylindrical pin at the center of the respective strips. Different lubrication conditions brought into differences in microstructural developments and in macroscopic strain distributions. The latter was measured from digital image correlations, while measurements of in-grain misorientations and crystallographic textures were extrapolated into strain hardening exponent of Hollomon law (n) and normal anisotropy coefficient ((r) over bar). Finite element simulations were used to predict macroscopic strain distributions, assuming constant and varying (with strain) material properties of n and . Predictions with variable material properties, as estimated from experimental microstructural data, were superior, having the least mean squared error (MSE). This study not only reiterates clear possibilities of incorporating microstructural inputs in a continuum model, but establishes efficacy of the same in relatively complex forming environment.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER FRANCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:39:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:39:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MATERIAL FORMING, 8(2)327-339</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1960-6206</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1960-6214</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12289-014-1172-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17520</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>