<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9846</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>DEVELOPMENT AND VALIDATION OF COUPLED DYNAMICS CODE 'TRIKIN' FOR VVER REACTORS</dc:title><dc:creator>OBAIDURRAHMAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOSHI, JB</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAGANNATHAN, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>approximation</dc:subject><dc:subject>space-time kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>iqs method</dc:subject><dc:subject>coupled analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>vver reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal hydraulics</dc:subject><dc:subject>safety analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>New generation nuclear reactors are designed using advanced safety analysis methods. A thorough understanding of different interacting physical phenomena is necessary to avoid underestimation and overestimation of consequences of off-normal transients in the reactor safety analysis results. This feature requires a multiphysics reactor simulation model. In this context, a coupled dynamics model based on a multiphysics formulation is developed indigenously for the transient analysis of large pressurized VVER reactors. Major simplifications are employed in the model by making several assumptions based on the physics of individual phenomenon. Space and time grids are optimized to minimize the computational bulk. The capability of the model is demonstrated by solving a series of international (AER) benchmark problems for VVER reactors. The developed model was used to analyze a number of reactivity transients that are likely to occur in VVER reactors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KOREAN NUCLEAR SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T11:16:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T11:16:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY, 42(3), 259-270</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1738-5733</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9846</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9846</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>