<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17433</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T11:06:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Primary sewage sludge-derived activated carbon: characterisation and application in wastewater treatment</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>SURFACE-CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADSORBENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>REMOVAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMODYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITROPHENOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sewage sludge-derived adsorbents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phenol adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adsorption kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Equilibrium isotherm</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adsorption thermodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adsorbent regeneration</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study deals with the characterization of primary sewage sludge-derived activated carbons which were used for phenol adsorption from the synthetic wastewater. The waste-derived adsorbents were prepared by a two-step process: chemical activation (with ZnCl2 and KOH) followed by pyrolysis. The mesoporous adsorbents were found to have BET surface area comparable to commercial activated carbon (surface area = 495-515 m(2)/g). The adsorption runs were performed in orbital shaker with synthetic phenolic wastewater (phenol concentration = 50-250 mg/L) to investigate the effect of various reaction parameters. The equilibrium phenol adsorption data could be described by Redlich-Peterson isotherm model and the pseudo first-order kinetic model exhibited the best fit to time-based adsorption data. The phenol adsorption was endothermic for all adsorbents. The performance of the thermally regenerated waste-derived adsorbents in the wastewater treatment was found to reduce significantly.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T11:06:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T11:06:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CLEAN TECHNOLOGIES AND ENVIRONMENTAL POLICY, 17(6)1619-1631</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1618-954X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1618-9558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10098-014-0895-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17433</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>