<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1278</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tertiary butylation of phenol over mesoporous MeMCM-48 and MeMCM-41 (Me = Ga, Fe, Al or B) solid acid catalysts</dc:title><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAPURKAR, SE</dc:creator><dc:subject>promising heterogeneous catalysts</dc:subject><dc:subject>(cr)mcm-48 molecular-sieves</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray-diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminum sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>mcm-48</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolites</dc:subject><dc:subject>gallium</dc:subject><dc:subject>h-almcm-41</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesoporous materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular sieve catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>gamcm-48</dc:subject><dc:subject>tertiary-butyl phenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkylation</dc:subject><dc:description>Mesoporous Na-GaMCM-48 molecular sieves having a silicon-to-gallium (molar) ratio of 30-90 were synthesized hydrothermally, and the structure; coordination geometry of the gallium, acidic properties, and catalytic activity were systematically investigated using a number of analytical and spectroscopic techniques. XRD, TEM and N-2 sorption investigations indicate an MCM-48 structure with highly ordered mesoporosity. Ga-17 MAS-NMR studies reveal that gallium substitutes isomorphously in the mesoporous silicate framework of MCM-48. The NH3-TPD profiles suggest the presence of high concentrations of moderate-to-strong Bronsted acid sites in H-GaMCM-48. The catalytic performance of this protonated catalyst was evaluated for the t-butylation of phenol. The results indicate that the H-GaMCM-48 catalysts are highly active for the chosen reaction, and show much higher substrate conversion than many other catalyst systems. However, compared to the analogous H-GaMCM-41, the H-GaMCM-48 shows a slight decrease in p-t-butyl phenol selectivity owing to the formation of 2,4-di-t-butyl phenol. On the other hand, the deactivation is very minimal on account of the three-dimensional pore system of the MCM-48 structure compared to the one-dimensional pore opening of the MCM-41 structure. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T17:07:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T17:07:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>CATALYSIS TODAY,96(3)135-141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0920-5861</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2004.06.114</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14466</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1278</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Materials for Advanced Technologies,Singapore, SINGAPORE,DEC 07-12, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>