<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5159</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Axisymmetric black hole accretion in the Kerr metric as an autonomous dynamical system</dc:title><dc:creator>GOSWAMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAN, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, TK</dc:creator><dc:subject>rankine-hugoniot shocks</dc:subject><dc:subject>relativistic accretion</dc:subject><dc:subject>flows</dc:subject><dc:subject>disks</dc:subject><dc:subject>accretion, accretion discs</dc:subject><dc:subject>black hole physics</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrodynamics</dc:subject><dc:description>In a stationary, general relativistic, axisymmetric, inviscid and rotational accretion flow, described within the Kerr geometric framework, transonicity has been examined by setting up the governing equations of the flow as a first-order autonomous dynamical system. The consequent linearized analysis of the critical points of the flow leads to a comprehensive mathematical prescription for classifying these points, showing that the only possibilities are saddle points and centre-type points for all ranges of values of the fixed flow parameters. The spin parameter of the black hole influences the multitransonic character of the flow, as well as some of its specific critical properties. The special case of a flow in the space-time of a non-rotating black hole, characterized by the Schwarzschild metric, has also been studied for comparison and the conclusions are compatible with what has been seen for the Kerr geometric case.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BLACKWELL PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T03:23:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T03:23:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MONTHLY NOTICES OF THE ROYAL ASTRONOMICAL SOCIETY, 378(4), 1407-1417</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0035-8711</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2966.2007.11869.x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5159</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5159</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>