<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7159</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>beta-Hairpins with native-like and non-native hydrogen bonding patterns could form during the refolding of staphylococcal nuclease</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SISTA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAJI, PV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SASIDHAR, YU</dc:creator><dc:subject>molecular-dynamics simulations</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyproline ii helix</dc:subject><dc:subject>short linear peptide</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle mesh ewald</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein-g</dc:subject><dc:subject>folding simulations</dc:subject><dc:subject>aqueous-solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>atom depth</dc:subject><dc:subject>exchange</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>atom depth</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen-deuterium exchange</dc:subject><dc:subject>peptide</dc:subject><dc:subject>gromacs</dc:subject><dc:subject>gromos96</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein folding</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen bonds</dc:subject><dc:description>Refolding of staphylococcal nuclease has been studied recently by hydrogen-deuterium exchange and NMR spectroscopy. These studies infer that beta-hairpin formed by strand 2 and strand 3 connected by reverse turn forms early during the refolding of nuclease. Typically, hydrogen-deuterium exchange NMR techniques are usually carried out on a time scale of milliseconds whereas beta-hairpins are known to fold on a much shorter time scale. It follows that in the experiments, the hydrogen-deuterium exchange protection patterns could be arising from a significant population of fully formed hairpins. In order to demonstrate it is the fully formed hairpins which gives rise to the hydrogen-deuterium exchange protection patterns, we have considered molecular dynamics simulation of the peptide (21)DTVKLMYKGQPMTFR(35) from staphylococcal nuclease corresponding to the beta-hairpin region, using GROMOS96 force field under NVT conditions. Starting from unfolded conformational states, the peptide folds into hairpin conformations with native-like and non-native hydrogen bonding patterns. Subsequent to folding, equilibrium conditions prevail. The computed protection factors and atom depth values, at equilibrium, of the various amide protons agree qualitatively with experimental observations. A collection of molecules following the trajectories observed in the simulations can account for experimental observations. These simulations provide a molecular picture of the formed hairpins and their conformational features during the refolding experiments on nuclease, monitored by hydrogen-deuterium exchange. (c) 2005</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T07:39:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T07:39:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MOLECULAR GRAPHICS &amp; MODELLING, 25(1), 103-115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1093-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmgm.2005.11.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7159</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7159</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>