<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17789</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:44:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>IR 820 dye encapsulated in polycaprolactone glycol chitosan: Poloxamer blend nanoparticles for photo immunotherapy for breast cancer</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>LIPID-POLYMER NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDOCYANINE GREEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOTHERMAL THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUG-DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>APOPTOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICACY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IR 820</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photothermal therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>TNF-alpha</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poloxamer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biocompatibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reactive oxygen species</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, we have fabricated biocompatible and biodegradable monodisperse IR 820 encapsulated polycaprolactone (PCL) glycol chitosan (GC): Poloxamer blend nanoparticles (PP-IR NPs) for imaging and effective photo-immunotherapy. IR 820 has been used as an imaging and photothermal agent whereas glycol chitosan (GC) as an immunostimulatoty agent. The combination of IR 820, poloxamer, and GC can be used effectively for photoimmunotherapy for cancer, drug-resistant and TNF-alpha resistant estrogen positive breast cancer. PP-IR NPs are stable in aqueous solution. The uniform size of 100-220 nm with a high zeta value of +38 +/- 2 mV led them to accumulate in cancer cells. Laser treatment did not affect the morphology of PP-IR NPs as observed under the transmission electron microscope (TEM). In vitro cytotoxicity studies on MCF-7 cells showed enhanced toxicity upon laser treatment. Further, we validated the cell death by reactive oxygen species (ROS) production. Our studies thus showed that PP-IR NPs are effective in suppressing metastatic cancer as the combinational therapy leads to the formation of apoptotic bodies in MCF-7 cells. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:44:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:44:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; ENGINEERING C-MATERIALS FOR BIOLOGICAL APPLICATIONS, 57,321-327</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0928-4931</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-0191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msec.2015.08.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17789</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>