<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14220</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:47:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Isomeric Complexes of [Ru(II)(trpy)(L)Cl] (trpy=2,2 ':6 ',2 ''-Terpyridine and HL = Quinaldic Acid): Preference of Isomeric Structural Form in Catalytic Chemoselective Epoxidation Process</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>IRSHAD, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>ASYMMETRIC ALKENE EPOXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXYGEN-TRANSFER REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN-PEROXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RUTHENIUM(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION-ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDOX PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AB-INITIO</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work deals with the isomeric complexes of the molecular composition [Ru(II)(trpy)(L)Cl] in 1 and 2 (trpy = 2, 2':6',2 ''-terpyridine, L = deprotonated form of quinaldic acid, HL). Isomeric identities of 1 and 2 have been established by their single-crystal X-ray structures, which reveal that under the meridional configuration of trpy, O(-) and N donors of the unsymmetrical L are in trans, cis and cis, trans configurations, respectively, with respect to the Ru-Cl bond. Compounds 1 and 2 exhibit appreciable differences in bond distances involving Ru-Cl and Ru-O1/Ru-N1 associated with L on the basis of their isomeric structural features. In relation to isomer 2, the isomeric complex 1 exhibits a slightly lower Ru(II)-Ru(III) oxidation potential [0.35 (1), 0.38 (2) V versus SCE in CH(3)CN] as well as lower energy MLCT transitions [559 nm and 417 nm (1) and 533 nm and 378 nm (2)1 This has also been reflected in the DFT calculation where a lower HOMO-LUMO gap of 2.59 eV in 1 compared to 2.71 eV in 2 is found. The isomeric structural effect in 1 and 2 has also been prominent in their (1)H NMR spectral profiles. The relatively longer Ru-Cl bond in 1 (2.408(2) angstrom) as compared to 2 (2.3813(9) angstrom) due to the trans effect of the anionic O(-) of coordinated L makes it labile, which in turn facilitates the transformation of [Ru(II)(trpy)(L)(Cl)] (1) to the solvate species, [Ru(II)(trpy)(L)(CH(3)CN)](Cl) (1a) while crystallizing 1 from the coordinating CH(3)CN solvent. The formation of la has been authenticated by its single-crystal X-ray structure. However, no such exchange of "Cl(-)" by the solvent molecule occurs in 2 during the crystallization process from the coordinating CH(3)CN solvent. The labile Ru-Cl bond in 1 makes it a much superior precatalyst for the epoxidation of alkene functionalities. Compound 1 is found to function as an excellent precatalyst for the epoxidation of a wide variety of alkene functionalities under environmentally benign conditions using H(2)O(2) as an oxidant and EtOH as a solvent, while isomer 2 remains almost ineffective under identical reaction conditions. The remarkable differences in catalytic performances of 1 and 2 based on their isomeric structural aspects have been addressed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY,50(5)1775-1785</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic102195w</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14220</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>