<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8831</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Wear resistance of RS-D2 steel reinforced aluminium composites</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIWARI, AN</dc:creator><dc:subject>resin-matrix composite</dc:subject><dc:subject>rapid solidification</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>ribbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloy</dc:subject><dc:description>Rapidly solidified (RS) D2 steel particle reinforced aluminium matrix composites have been fabricated using powder metallurgy technique involving sintering and hot pressing. Density of the composites has been found to be almost 100% that of the theoretical value. The composite containing even 0.9 vol% particles could exhibit a hardness of 116 BHN as against 40 BHN of aluminium matrix. EDX analysis and microhardness measurements indicate the presence of (Fe,Cr)(2)Al-5 at the particle-matrix interface. The effect of RS-D2 particles on the wear resistance of aluminium against 600 grit bonded SiC countersurface has been studied using Pin-on-Disc type wear set up. The wear resistance of the composites has been found to increase remarkably with the concentration of RS-D2 particles. The abrasive wear resistance (Omega) shows a positive deviation from the rule of mixture. A five fold improvement in Omega with respect to aluminium matrix has been achieved by incorporating only 2.8 vol% of RS-D2 reinforcement.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN INST METALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T14:35:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T14:35:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN INSTITUTE OF METALS, 58(5), 827-833</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-493X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8831</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8831</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>