<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16790</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:46:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nonlinear analysis of a thin pre-twisted and delaminated anisotropic strip</dc:title><dc:creator>GURUPRASAD, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>THEJASVI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARURSAMPATH, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>SECTIONAL ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATRIX CRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEAMS</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work is aimed at the development of an efficient mathematical model to assess the degradation in the stiffness properties of an anisotropic strip due to delamination. In particular, the motive is to capture those nonlinear effects in a strip that arise due to the geometry of the structure, in the presence of delamination. The variational asymptotic method (VAM) is used as a mathematical tool to simplify the original 3D problem to a 1D problem. Further simplification is achieved by modeling the delaminated structure by a sublaminate approach. By VAM, a 2D nonlinear sectional analysis is carried out to determine compact expression for the stiffness terms. The stiffness terms, both linear and nonlinear, are derived as functions of delamination length and location in closed form. In general, the results from the analysis include fully coupled nonlinear 1D stiffness coefficients, 3D strain field, 3D stress field, and in-plane and warping fields. In this work, the utility of the model is demonstrated for a static case, and its capability to capture the trapeze effect in the presence of delamination is investigated and compared with results available in the literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER WIEN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:46:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:46:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA MECHANICA, 225(10)2815-2832</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0001-5970</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1619-6937</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00707-014-1203-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16790</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>