<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14999</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:25:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulation of Hypersonic Shock/Turbulent Boundary-Layer Interactions Using Shock-Unsteadiness Model</dc:title><dc:creator>PASHA, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>NAVIER-STOKES EQUATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TURBULENCE MODELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINE RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE</dc:subject><dc:description>In hypersonic flows, the interaction of a shock wave with a turbulent boundary layer can result in flow separation and high aerothermal loads. In this paper, cone flare configurations with different flare angles and freestream Mach numbers are simulated using Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes method, and results are compared with experimental data. The standard Spalart-Allmaras and k-omega turbulence models do not predict flow separation at the cone flare junction, and therefore yield a large deviation from the surface pressure measurements. Sinha et al. ("Modeling Shock-Unsteadiness in Shock/Turbulence Interaction," Physics of Fluids, Vol. 15, No. 8, 2003, pp. 2290-2297) proposed a shock-unsteadiness model to account for the effect of unsteady shock motion in a steady mean flow. The shock-unsteadiness correction damps turbulence amplification at the shock and results in significant improvement in predicting flow separation and reattachment. The flow topology in the interaction region, in terms of the pattern of shocks and expansion waves, is predicted correctly by the modified turbulence models. The resulting surface pressure distribution matches experimental data well.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUTICS  ASTRONAUTICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:25:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:25:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PROPULSION AND POWER, 28(1)46-60</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/1.B34191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14999</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>