<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17156</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:09:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Implementation and validation of the condensation model for containment hydrogen distribution studies</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVVA, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>IYER, KN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAIKWAD, AJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>CFD CODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMAL-HYDRAULICS</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper aims at the implementation details of a condensation model in the CFD code FLUENT and its validation so that it can be used in performing the containment hydrogen distribution studies. In such studies, computational fluid dynamics simulations are necessary for obtaining accurate predictions. While steam condensation plays an important role, commercial CFD codes such as FLUENT do not have an in-built condensation model. Therefore, a condensation model was developed and implemented in the FLUENT code through user defined functions (UDFs) for the sink terms in the mass, momentum, energy and species balance equations together with associated turbulence quantities viz., kinetic energy and dissipation rate. The implemented model was validated against the ISP-47 test of TOSQAN facility using the standard wall functions and enhanced wall treatment approaches. The best suitable grid size and the turbulence model for the low density gas (He) distribution studies are brought out in this paper. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:09:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:09:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 27034-47</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2013.12.047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17156</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>