<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15915</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:34:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Wavelet Analysis of Geophysical Well-log Data of Bombay Offshore Basin, India</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHAR, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VE</dc:creator><dc:subject>Well-log data</dc:subject><dc:subject>Continuous wavelet transformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bombay offshore basin, India</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOGGING DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESERVOIR</dc:subject><dc:description>Geophysical well-log (bore-hole) data facilitate understanding of the physical properties of the subsurface formations as a function of depth measured in a well. In the present study, the wavelet transformation technique was applied to the well-log data of three wells in the Bombay High oil field, India, in order to identify depths to the tops of oil and/or gas formation zones (pay zones). Continuous wavelet transformation (CWT) was performed on gamma-ray, resistivity, neutron porosity and velocity log data sets in order to determine the space-localization of the oil and/or gas formation zones. The choice of a mother wavelet is important and largely depends on the data under investigation. We have applied a variety of wavelets to the different log data sets to not only identify the depths to the tops of formation zones, but also to determine the optimum wavelet that best characterizes the pay zones. On examination of scalogram plots of each log corresponding to each wavelet for their better resolution in identifying the formation boundaries, we have found that the scalograms corresponding to the Gaus1 wavelet appeared to give the best resolution in identifying the depths of pay zones in all the well-log data sets of all three wells. To further validate the above observation, a histogram analysis of CWT coefficients is made. This showed that, of all the wavelets considered for the present study, Gaus1 wavelet is the most appropriate and optimum for determining the space-localization of pay zones in all the well-log data sets considered in the present study. The depths of pay zones estimated from scalogram plots of logs agree well with those provided by the Oil and Natural Gas Corporation Ltd., India.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:34:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:34:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATHEMATICAL GEOSCIENCES, 44(8)901-928</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11004-012-9423-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15915</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>