<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14312</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T09:40:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Approximation Techniques for Transportation Network Design Problem under Demand Uncertainty</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, TV</dc:creator><dc:creator>UKKUSURI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VARIANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Demand uncertainty</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transportation network design</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sampling techniques</dc:subject><dc:subject>Single-point approximation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genetic algorithm</dc:subject><dc:description>Conventional transportation network design problems treat origin-destination (OD) demand as fixed, which may not be true in reality. Some recent studies model fluctuations in OD demand by considering the first and the second moment of the system travel time, resulting in stochastic and robust network design models, respectively. Both of these models need to solve the traffic equilibrium problem for a large number of demand samples and are therefore computationally intensive. In this paper, three efficient solution-approximation approaches are identified for addressing demand uncertainty by solving for a small sample size, reducing the computational effort without much compromise on the solution quality. The application and the performance of these alternative approaches are reported. The results from this study will help in deciding suitable approximation techniques for network design under demand uncertainty. DOI: 10.1061/(ASCE)CP.1943-5487.0000091. (C) 2011 American Society of Civil Engineers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:40:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:40:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COMPUTING IN CIVIL ENGINEERING,25(4)316-329</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0887-3801</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)CP.1943-5487.0000091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14312</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>