<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9306</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Computation of bearing capacity factor N-gamma-Prandtl's mechanism</dc:title><dc:creator>DEWAIKAR, DM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>foundations</dc:subject><dc:subject>bearing capacity</dc:subject><dc:subject>limit equilibrium</dc:subject><dc:subject>passive thrust</dc:subject><dc:subject>point of application</dc:subject><dc:subject>pole of log spiral</dc:subject><dc:subject>shallow foundation (igc : e3)</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, an analysis based on Prandtl's failure mechanism is proposed for the evaluation of bearing capacity factor, N-gamma, using the limit equilibrium approach, coupled with Kotter's equation. Except for shape of the failure surface, no other assumptions are needed in the analysis. A methodology based on Mitter's equation and force equilibrium conditions is developed to identify the correct location of pole of the log spiral and hence the unique failure surface. Using moment equilibrium condition, the point of application of passive thrust is determined. The proposed N-gamma values are compared with other available theoretical predictions and experimental results. They show a good agreement with some existing theoretical results and also show a better agreement with available experimental results. The analysis shows that pole of the log spiral lies at the footing edge for general shear failure conditions and the point of application of the passive thrust is strongly influenced by angle of soil internal friction.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JAPANESE GEOTECHNICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T08:59:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T08:59:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOILS AND FOUNDATIONS, 43(3), 1-10</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0038-0806</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9306</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>