<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14855</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:02:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Signal-Driven Window-Length Adaptation for Sinusoid Detection in Polyphonic Music</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GADDIPATI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Signal sparsity</dc:subject><dc:subject>sinusoid detection</dc:subject><dc:subject>window adaptation</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUDIO</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOCODER</dc:subject><dc:description>Audio processing applications that use short-time signal analysis techniques typically utilize fixed window duration single-or multi-resolution analyses. However, different real-world signal conditions such as polyphony and non-stationarity, manifested as musical accompaniment and pitch-modulations, respectively, in the context of music content analysis, require varying data window lengths for reliable processing. In this paper, we investigate the use of signal sparsity for adapting analysis window lengths. Adaptive-window analysis driven by different measures of sparsity applied to the local spectrum, such as kurtosis and Gini index, is evaluated and shown to be superior to fixed-window analysis in terms of sinusoid detection and frequency estimation for simulated and real signals. A window main-lobe matching method for sinusoid detection is also shown to be more robust to signal conditions such as polyphony and frequency modulation relative to other methods.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:02:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:02:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON AUDIO SPEECH AND LANGUAGE PROCESSING, 20(1)342-348</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TASL.2011.2162319</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14855</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>