<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16329</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:13:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interaction of homologous series of amino acids with sarcosine in presence of denaturant: Volumetric and calorimetric approach</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>PARTIAL MOLAR VOLUMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRIMETHYLAMINE N-OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN STABILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORGANIC-COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>UREA</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>OSMOLYTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPRESSIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMODYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COUNTERACTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Densities (rho) and speeds of sound (u) of homologous serious of five amino acids: glycine, L-alanine, DL-alpha-amino- n-butyric acid, L-valine, and L-leucine were measured in aqueous 1.0 mol . dm(-3) sarcosine and (1.0 mol . dm(-3) sarcosine + 1.0 mol . dm(-3) urea) solutions. The values of corresponding apparent molar volume (V-2,V-phi), apparent molar compressibility (K-S,K-2,K-phi) were calculated from the density and speed of sound data at T 298: 15 K. Enthalpies of dilution (q) of amino acids from water to 1.0 mol . dm(-3) sarcosine and (1.0 mol . dm(-3) sarcosine + 1.0 mol . dm(-3) urea) solution were also measured. By linear regression fitting, the values of standard partial molar volume (V-2,m(0)) and partial molar compressibility (K-S,2,m(0)) and standard enthalpy of dilution (DtrDdilH0) were determined. The contribution of zwitterionic and hydrophobic groups of amino acids to V-2,m(0) were also calculated from linear regression fitting of V-2,V-phi values. The different cosolvent interactions were interpreted on the basis of cosphere overlap model. The results suggest the dominance of ionic-ionic and hydrophilic-ionic group interactions over hydrophobic- hydrophilic and ionic-hydrophobic interactions. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:13:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:13:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL THERMODYNAMICS, 68244-252</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9614</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1096-3626</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jct.2013.09.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16329</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>