<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-554</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-26T06:39:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Distributed PC based routers: bottleneck analysis and architecture proposal</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIRKE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANJUNATH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHOO, ANIRUDHA</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIANCO, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>routers</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric network topology</dc:subject><dc:subject>general purpose computers</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent research in the different functional areas of modern routers have made proposals that can greatly increase the efficiency of these machines. Most of these proposals can be implemented quickly and often efficiently in software. We wish to use personal computers as forwarders in a network to utilize the advances made by researchers. We therefore examine the ability of a personal computer to act as a router. We analyze the performance of a single general purpose computer and show that I/O is the primary bottleneck. We then study the performance of distributed router composed of multiple general purpose computers. We study the performance of a star topology and through experimental results we show that although its performance is good, it lacks flexibility in its design. We compare it with a multistage architecture. We conclude with a proposal for an architecture that provides us with a forwarder that is both flexible and scalable.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-01-12T11:57:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:04:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-01-12T11:57:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:04:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on High Performance Switching and Routing, Shanghai, China, 15-17 May 2008, 57-62</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1982-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/HSPR.2008.4734421</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/554</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>