<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1816</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Vapor-liquid-solid growth of vertically aligned InP nanowires by metalorganic vapor phase epitaxy</dc:title><dc:creator>BHUNIA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAWAMURA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>FUJIKAWA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAKASHIMA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>FURUKAWA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>TORIMITSU, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>WATANABE, Y</dc:creator><dc:subject>heterostructures</dc:subject><dc:subject>gaas</dc:subject><dc:subject>inp</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanowires</dc:subject><dc:subject>au catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>movpe</dc:subject><dc:subject>sem</dc:subject><dc:subject>tem</dc:subject><dc:description>In this study, a detailed investigation of the growth of vertically oriented and surface mounted InP nanowires has been carried out. They were grown by metal organic vapor phase epitaxy on semi-insulating &lt;111&gt; B-oriented InP wafers using An nanoparticle-assisted vapor-liquid-solid growth technique. The proper conditions for the stable nanowire growth were obtained by systematic variation of the pre-growth annealing and the growth temperatures and were found to be 540 and 440 degreesC, respectively. The variation in the length of the nanowires was also studied as a function of time. Transmission electron diffraction studies carried out on the single nanowires revealed the &lt;111&gt; growth direction with the presence of rotational twin structures, the axis of rotation being the growth direction. Analysis of the high-resolution transmission electron microscopic images shows that the orientation and kinks on the nanowires were controlled by the distribution of these twin structures. (C) 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T07:08:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T07:08:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS,464,244-247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2004.06.101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15065</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1816</dc:identifier><dc:source>7th International Symposium on Atomically Controlled Surfaces, Interfaces and Nanostructures,Nara, JAPAN,NOV 16-20, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>