<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17100</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:40:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Model Tests on Geocell Walls Under Strip Loading</dc:title><dc:creator>LAL, BRR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, JN</dc:creator><dc:subject>fly ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>environment</dc:subject><dc:subject>backfill</dc:subject><dc:subject>geocell</dc:subject><dc:subject>water bottles</dc:subject><dc:subject>lateral deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>settlement</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOFT CLAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RETAINING WALLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>REINFORCED SAND</dc:subject><dc:description>Thermal power stations in India produce an enormous quantity of fly ash as a by-product. Fly ash utilization and disposal in an environmental friendly manner is a foremost concern in India. In the present study, an attempt has been made for proper utilization of fly ash as an alternative backfill material in geocell walls. This study also provides an approach for the use of waste plastic water bottles as geocells. The geocell diameter and height used in the model testing is 70 mm. Two types of structural geometry were considered in the study: gravity wall type and facing wall type. The lateral deformation of geocell wall and settlement of the backfill were studied under strip loading by varying facing angle of the wall, with and without reinforcement in the backfill. For both the type of walls, model testing results show that the maximum lateral deformation of geocell wall, backfill settlement, and failure surcharge pressures increased with decreasing facing angle of wall. For the reinforced case, the lateral deformation of the geocell wall was reduced considerably. When the reinforcement placed at top and total layers, the maximum lateral deformation of the geocell wall occurred at mid height of the wall. However, for bottom layers reinforced backfill, the maximum lateral deformation occurred at the top.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC TESTING MATERIALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:40:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:40:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOTECHNICAL TESTING JOURNAL, 37(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0149-6115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1945-7545</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1520/GTJ20130094</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17100</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>