<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15215</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:59:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Oxygen plasma assisted end-opening and field emission enhancement in vertically aligned multiwall carbon nanotubes</dc:title><dc:creator>MATHUR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAZRA, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>WADHWA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MCLAUGHLIN, JA</dc:creator><dc:subject>Nanostructures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Raman spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Field emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasma etching</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLOW-DISCHARGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CF4 PLASMA</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUNCTIONALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMITTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper highlights the changes in micro-structural and field emission properties of vertically aligned carbon nanotubes (VACNTs) via oxygen plasma treatment. We find that exposure of very low power oxygen plasma (6 W) at 13.56 MHz for 15-20 min, opens the tip of vertically aligned CNTs. Scanning electron microscopy and transmission electron microscopy images were used to identify the quality and microstructural changes of the nanotube morphology and surfaces. Raman spectra showed that the numbers of defects were increased throughout the oxygen plasma treatment process. In addition, the hydrophobic nature of the VACNTs is altered significantly and the contact angle decreases drastically from 110 degrees to 40 degrees. It was observed that the electron field emission (EFE) characteristics are significantly enhanced. The turn-on electric field (ETOE) of CNTs decreased from similar to 0.80 V mu m(-1) (untreated) to similar to 0.60 V mu m(-1) (oxygen treated). We believe that the open ended VACNTs would be immensely valuable for applications such as micro/nanofluidic based filtering elements and display devices. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:59:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:59:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS CHEMISTRY AND PHYSICS, 134(1)425-429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2012.03.012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15215</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>