<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14545</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:16:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Computation of feed-paths for casting solidification using level-set-method</dc:title><dc:creator>SUTARIA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GADA, VH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>Feed-path</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hot-spot</dc:subject><dc:subject>Level-set</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liquid-solid interface</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shrinkage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solidification</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-PHASE FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NUMERICAL-SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISTANCE RULES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPE</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of the present work is to compute feed-paths and hot-spots by combining level-set-method based sharp interface and feed-path model. The model is based on the solution of energy and level-set equations in solid and liquid, with Stefan condition on the interface. The energy and level-set equation are discretized using finite-volume and finite-difference method, respectively. Feed-path is computed by tracking mass-less particles along the liquid-solid interface during solidification using combined Eulerian-Lagrangian framework. The proposed model is benchmarked on six test cases, where temperature contours and solidification time are compared with a finite-element-method based commercial software. The capability to predict the temporal evolution of interface and to identify multiple hot-spots is validated with an industrial aluminum-alloy lug casting. The numerical as well as experimental validations demonstrate the effectiveness of level-set-method for feed-path calculation. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:16:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:16:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS PROCESSING TECHNOLOGY, 212(6)1236-1249</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmatprotec.2012.01.019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14545</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>