<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18205</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:50:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Build strategies for rapid manufacturing of components of varying complexity</dc:title><dc:creator>SIMHAMBHATLA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARUNAKARAN, KP</dc:creator><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rapid manufacturing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Layered manufacturing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Manufacturing technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Process planning</dc:subject><dc:description>Purpose - This paper aims to develop build strategies for rapid manufacturing of components of varying complexity with the help of illustration. Design/methodology/approach - The build strategies are developed using a hybrid layered manufacturing (HLM) setup. HLM, an automatic layered manufacturing process for metallic objects, combines the best features of two well-known and economical processes, viz., arc weld-deposition and milling. Depending on the geometric complexity of the object, the deposition and/or finish machining may involve fixed (3-axis) or variable axis (5-axis) kinematics. Findings - Fixed axis (3-axis) kinematics is sufficient to produce components free of undercuts and overhanging features. Manufacture of components with undercuts can be categorized into three methods, viz., those that exploit the inherent overhanging ability, those that involve blinding of the undercuts in the material deposition stage and those that involve variable axis kinematics for aligning the overhang with the deposition direction. Research limitations/implications - Although developed using the HLM setup, these generic concepts can be used in a variety of metal deposition processes. Originality/value - This paper describes the methodology for realizing undercut features of varying complexity and also chalks out the procedure for their manufacture with the help of case studies for each approach.</dc:description><dc:publisher>EMERALD GROUP PUBLISHING LIMITED</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:50:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:50:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RAPID PROTOTYPING JOURNAL, 21(3)340-350</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1355-2546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1758-7670</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/RPJ-07-2012-0062</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18205</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>