<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16521</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:27:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Sensitivity of a Strained C-C Single Bond to Charge Transfer: Redox Activity in Mononuclear and Dinuclear Ruthenium Complexes of Bis(arylimino)acenaphthene (BIAN) Ligands</dc:title><dc:creator>MONDAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWALA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANA, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>PLEBST, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GRUPP, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>EHRET, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAIM, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIDENTATE NITROGEN LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR LIGHT SWITCH</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIXED-VALENT COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION-ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COORDINATION MODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-AZOCARBONYL</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATION-STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIIMINE LIGAND</dc:subject><dc:description>The new compounds [Ru(acac)(2)(BIAN)], BIAN = bis(arylimino)acenaphthene (aryl = Ph (1a), 4-MeC6H4 (2a), 4-OMeC6H4 (3a), 4-ClC6H4 (4a), 4-NO2C6H4 (5a)), were synthesized and structurally, electrochemically, spectroscopically, and computationally characterized. The alpha-dine sections of the compounds exhibit intrachelate ring bond lengths 1.304 angstrom &lt; d(cN) &lt; 1.334 and 1.425 angstrom &lt; d(cc) &lt; 1.449 angstrom, which indicate considerable metal-to-ligand charge transfer in the ground state, approaching a Ru-III(BIAN(center dot-)) oxidation state formulation. The particular structural sensitivity of the strained pen-connecting C-C bond in the BIAN ligands toward metal-to-ligand charge transfer is discussed. Oxidation of [Ru(acac)(2)(BIAN)] produces electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) and UV-vis-NIR (NIR = near infrared) spectroelectrochemically detectable Ru-III species, while the reduction yields predominantly BIAN-based spin, in agreement with density functional theory (DFT) spin-density calculations. Variation of the substituents from CH3 to NO2 has little effect on the spin distribution but affects the absorption spectra. The dinuclear compounds {(mu-tppz)[Ru(Cl)(BIAN)](2)}(ClO4)(2), tppz = 2,3,5,6-tetrakis(2-pyridyl)pyrazine; aryl (BIAN) = Ph ([1b](ClO4)(2)), 4-MeC6H4 ([2b](ClO4)(2)), 4-OMeC6H4 ([3b](ClO4)(2)), 4-ClC6H4 ([4b](ClO4)(2)), were also obtained and investigated. The structure determination of [2b](ClO4)(2) and [3b](ClO4)(2) reveals trans configuration of the chloride ligands and unreduced BIAN ligands. The DFT and spectroelectrochemical results (UV-vis-NIR, EPR) indicate oxidation to a weakly coupled (RuRuII)-Ru-III mixed-valent species but reduction to a tppz-centered radical state. The effect of the pi electron-accepting BIAN ancillary ligands is to diminish the metal-metal interaction due to competition with the acceptor bridge tppz.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:27:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:27:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 53(14)7389-7403</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-510X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic500730m</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16521</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>