<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17883</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:03:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Impact of Wall Heat Transport on Formation of Transversal Hot Zones in Shallow, Non-adiabatic Packed-Bed Reactors</dc:title><dc:creator>NARENDIRAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, GA</dc:creator><dc:subject>CO OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HETEROGENEOUS CATALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTRAPOLATION METHODS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE PATTERNS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OSCILLATORY KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREATHING PATTERNS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGENATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:description>Transversal hot zones have been reported to form in packed-bed reactors Used to conduct exothermic reactions. Packed bed reactors are usually operated under non adiabatic conditions. Previous attempts to predict the formation of transversal hot zones have been made on both shallow and long reactors under adiabatic conditions; that is, wall heat transport is zero. We show that a rich variety of slowly oscillating transversal hot zones, such as rotating patterns, targets, and spirals, may form in shallow, non adiabatic reactors. Under certain conditions, azimuthally symmetric target patterns coexist with azimuthally non symmetric rotating patterns. Surprisingly, a small wall heat transport can force a traveling wave or band motion observed pricier adiabatic conditions into a rotating pattern. A transition from the rotating patterns and/or target patterns to spiral waves depends on the residence time, the reactor length scale, and the wall heat transfer coefficient. A shallow reactor model predicts that the spatiotemporal patterns oscillate at 4 very low frequency (order of 10(-5) Hz), which is in agreement with predictions based on laboratory experiments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:03:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:03:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 54(30)7352-7363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.5b01048</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17883</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>