<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15977</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:42:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Temperature Characteristics and Analysis of Monolithic Microwave CMOS Distributed Oscillators With G(m)-Varied Gain Cells and Folded Coplanar Interconnects</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SZYMANSKI, TH</dc:creator><dc:subject>CMOS</dc:subject><dc:subject>coplanar waveguides</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed oscillator</dc:subject><dc:subject>microwave integrated circuits (ICs)</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal phenomena</dc:subject><dc:subject>traveling wave amplifier</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMPLIFIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:description>The performance of a novel Monolithic Microwave CMOS Distributed Oscillator is reported over a temperature range of -25 degrees C to 75 degrees C for the first time, along with an analysis of its design characteristics and its temperature stability. The oscillator is stable over the entire temperature range of 100 degrees C. The monolithic distributed oscillator (DO) is designed and fabricated in an industry standard 0.18 mu m CMOS process, using an n-FET-based traveling wave amplifier (TWA), coplanar waveguides (CPW), and a new coplanar interconnect structure called a 'folded CPW'. The measured loss of the "folded CPW" is 1.259 dB at 10 GHz. The distributed oscillator uses a novel architecture of G(m)-varied gain cells and operates at a bias of 1.8 V. The measured oscillation frequency is 11.7 GHz with 6.1 dBm output power and the measured phase noise is -116.02 dBc/Hz at 1 MHz offset, which represent the best reported power and one of the best phase noise results for silicon DOs with temperature stability.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:42:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:42:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON VERY LARGE SCALE INTEGRATION (VLSI) SYSTEMS, 20(7)1332-1336</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TVLSI.2011.2148130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15977</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>