<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1984</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tracking dynamic boundary fronts using range sensors</dc:title><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOUDGALYA, KM</dc:creator><dc:subject>lidar</dc:subject><dc:description>We examine the problem of tracking dynamic boundaries occurring in natural phenomena using range sensors. Two main challenges of the boundary tracking problem are energy-efficient boundary estimations from noisy observations and continuous tracking of the boundary. We propose a novel approach which uses a regression-based spatial estimation technique to determine discrete points on the boundary and estimates a confidence band around the entire boundary. In addition, a Kalman Filter-based temporal estimation technique is used to selectively refresh the estimated boundary to meet the accuracy requirements. Our algorithm for dynamic boundary tracking (DBTR) combines temporal estimation with an aperiodically updated spatial estimation and provides a low overhead solution to track boundaries without requiring prior knowledge about the dynamics of the boundary. Experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of our algorithm and estimated confidence bands achieve loss of coverage of less than 2 - 5% for a variety of boundaries with different spatial characteristics.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T23:16:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T23:16:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>WIRELESS SENSOR NETWORKS,4913,125-140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-540-77689-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15264</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1984</dc:identifier><dc:source>5th European Conference on Wireless Sensor Networks,Bologna, ITALY,JAN 30-FEB 01, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>