<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1491</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-26T04:56:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Using rule based expert system to wrap procedural code of integrated watershed model</dc:title><dc:creator>GODSE, MANISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SONAR, RAJENDRA</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, EP</dc:creator><dc:subject>graphical user interfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>administrative data processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>artificial intelligence</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer graphics</dc:subject><dc:subject>decision support system</dc:subject><dc:subject>watersheds</dc:subject><dc:description>Graphical User interface (GUI) is an integral part of any software system. It provides communication media between software program and human being. It usually consists of commands, menus, icons, images, graphs, tables, texts etc. The proper GUI presentation is influential in human-computer interaction. The present age commonly used GUIs are windows or web, which has improved usability compared to earlier text based UI. The usual way of GUI development is based on use of GUI builders, which needs understanding, and knowledge of using them. IT professionals more commonly use them. For other professional who are developing algorithms in their own domain may have to spend more time on development of GUI rather than spending more on their domain algorithm work. The novel way of using expert systems for GUI development can reduce a GUI development efforts and time for other domain professionals. In this paper a rule-based expert system is presented for use of GUI development of integrated watershed model (IWM).</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:21:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:24:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:21:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:24:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 1st International Conference on Emerging Trends in Engineering and Technology, ICETET, Nagpur, Maharashtra, India, 16-18 July 2008, 332-336</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>9780769532677</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICETET.2008.32</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1491</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1491</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>