<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1525</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intelligent vehicular transportation system (InVeTraS)</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGHAI, RAHUL</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHOO, ANIRUDHA</dc:creator><dc:subject>global positioning system</dc:subject><dc:subject>information dissemination</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed computer systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>wireless telecommunication systems</dc:subject><dc:description>InVeTraS (Intelligent Vehicular Transportation System) is proposed as a Vehicle-to-Vehicle (V2V) anti-collision mechanism that determines, estimates and absolves collision courses between two or more vehicles based on a correlative and cooperative wireless networking concept. The problem of collision avoidance is abstracted to the generic problem of location awareness and subsequent periodic information exchange (between vehicles). To enable location awareness, the mechanism uses one of two techniques: a Global Positioning System (GPS) receiver aided with dead-reckoning sensors or a RADAR based measurement system. Two nearby vehicles periodically exchange information about their own movement in terms of exact position and local clock time. Using these inputs, vehicles determine whether or not they are on a collision course with each another. A Communication Cluster (based on the concept of mobile ad-hoc peer-to-peer networking) is formed, that facilitates the development of a vehicular network characterized by self-organization, fault-tolerance, scalability, cooperation and cost efficiency. These characteristics enable avoidance of collision between vehicles in an adaptive and dynamic set up. The paper simulates the proposed InVeTraS concept over a torus topology emulating the streets of Manhattan.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-19T03:54:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:40:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-19T03:54:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:40:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Australasian Telecommunication Networks and Applications Conference, Christchurch, New Zealand, 2-5 December 2007, 58-63</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1557-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ATNAC.2007.4665283</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1525</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1525</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>