<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13911</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T04:52:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>SLOPE-STABILITY-CONSTRAINED DESIGN OF IRRIGATION CANALS USING PARTICLE SWARM OPTIMIZATION</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ADARSH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>WATER-RESOURCES MANAGEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRITICAL SLIP SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESERVOIR OPERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>irrigation canal design</dc:subject><dc:subject>slope stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle swarm optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>geometric constraints</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a practical methodology for optimal design of open channels considering the slope-stability aspects and other requirements, and propounds the solution of particle swarm optimization (PSO) for solving nonlinear optimization problems. The proposed methodology handles site-specific conditions such as restrictions on allowable top width and water depths. To ensure the stability of canals under field conditions, a slope-stability constraint is incorporated into the channel design. This constraint is handled through an optimization sub-routine for computing stability of the canals using PSO. The results of the model show that, for all the cases considered in the study, the PSO-based solutions are found to perform well, and in some cases better than the traditional solutions. The PSO method provides lot of flexibility in its usage for solving complex channel design problems, and it can be used to handle various system requirements in a better way. Copyright (C) 2011 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:52:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:52:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IRRIGATION AND DRAINAGE,60(5)590-599</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1531-0353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ird.611</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13911</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>