<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6756</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetotelluric and aeromagnetic investigations for assessment of groundwater resources in Parnaiba basin in Piaui State of North-East Brazil</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHAR, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>FONTES, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>FLEXOR, JM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANAND, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>magnetic interpretation</dc:subject><dc:subject>soundings</dc:subject><dc:subject>aquifer</dc:subject><dc:subject>inversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>shift</dc:subject><dc:subject>decomposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>mexico</dc:subject><dc:subject>tem</dc:subject><dc:subject>parnaiba basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>ne brazil</dc:subject><dc:subject>groundwater</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetotellurics</dc:subject><dc:subject>aeromagnetics</dc:subject><dc:description>In an attempt to locate the presence of possible groundwater resource regions in the semi-arid North-East Brazil, an integrated survey including aeromagnetic and magnetotelluric (MT) studies have been undertaken in the Guaribas region and only MT survey in the Caracol region. In the Guaribas region the aeromagnetic data, its analytic signal and Euler solutions reveal several subsurface small-scale faults and intrusives that are conducive to be potential groundwater resource regions. A total of about 22 broad-band magnetotelluric (MT) soundings in the period range of 0.006-300 s along two profiles on the marginal arcs of the intracratonic sedimentary Parnaiba basin in North-East Brazil have been made across the regional geological strike. the Senador Pompeu Lineament (SPL). SPL trends N40 degrees E and marks a basement high reflecting an irregularity in the original basin geometry. While one of the MT profiles traverses across the SPL, the other lies only in the aeromagnetically surveyed sedimentary region. Two-dimensional inversion of MT data of both profiles shows that the sedimentary basin is conductive (100-150 Omega m) and shows as a thin graben with an average thickness of about 2-3 km beneath both profiles. The basin is located to be at shallow depths (from surface to about 500 m). Based on the facts that the study region falls on sedimentary region having low-to-very low permeability and also in accordance with the Subsurface lithology around the study region, the mapped sedimentary basin largely manifests the zone of potential sedimentary aquifer having moderate resistivity of 50-250 Omega m and is located at relatively shallow depths. The identified aquifer zone is believed to have links with the Parnaiba River flowing at a distance of about 300 km NW from the study region. We discuss interpretation of our results of MT and aeromagnetic data sets in the light of hydrological features of the study region. (c) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T18:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T18:57:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED GEOPHYSICS, 68(2), 269-281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0926-9851</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jappgeo.2008.12.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6756</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6756</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>