<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16633</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:57:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Generalized Relationship for Determination of Tensile Strength of Fine-Grained Soils from Shrinkage Characteristics</dc:title><dc:creator>UDAY, KV</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAYANTHI, PNV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Tensile strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fine-grained soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>Linear shrinkage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Moisture content</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRACTURE-TOUGHNESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUANTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESICCATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYCLES</dc:subject><dc:description>Tensile strength of fine-grained soils has been extensively investigated by earlier researchers and several methodologies have been evolved for its determination. However, either most of these methods are not valid/applicable for a wide range of moisture contents or they involve tedious sample/specimen preparation. In this context, the methodology of determining tensile strength by employing thin films, which is available in the literature, has been found to be quite handy and useful. It has been observed that a unique relationship exists among the tensile strength, moisture content, and shrinkage characteristics of fine-grained soils. This methodology is appreciable due to its applicability to a wide range of moisture contents, comparable ease of sample preparation and testing, and the obtained results lack generalization. Exhaustive tests were conducted on fine-grained soils of entirely different characteristics and generalized relationships have been proposed between the percentage linear shrinkage, tensile strength, and moisture content (defined as liquid to solid ratio). Based on a critical analysis of the results available in the literature, the efficiency of such relationships for determination of tensile strength of fine-grained soils has been demonstrated. In the authors' opinion, such relationships would be quite useful for determining tensile strength of fine-grained soils from their linear shrinkage, which can easily be measured in a conventional geotechnical engineering laboratory.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:57:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:57:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DRYING TECHNOLOGY, 32(7)869-876</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0737-3937</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1532-2300</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/07373937.2013.873804</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16633</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>