<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10221</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Conformational features of reduced and disulfide intact forms of hen egg white lysozyme in aqueous solution in presence of 3-chloro-1, 2-propanediol and dioxane: Implications for protein folding intermediates</dc:title><dc:creator>SASIDHAR, YU</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHA, CR</dc:creator><dc:subject>molten globule state</dc:subject><dc:subject>secondary structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>alpha-lactalbumin</dc:subject><dc:subject>trifluoroethanol</dc:subject><dc:subject>bonds</dc:subject><dc:description>Conformational features of reduced and disulfide intact hen egg white lysozyme in aqueous 1,4-dioxane and 3-chloro-1, 2-propanediol solutions have been examined using circular dichroism and fluorescence spectroscopy. We find that in presence of 1, 4-dioxane, reduced lysozyme assumes a relatively compact conformational form with secondary structure closer to native state and no tertiary structure as judged by peptide and aromatic CD spectra and ANS binding studies monitored by fluorescence. Further, in presence of 40% (v/v) 3-chloro-1, 2-propanediol, disulfide intact lysozyme (DI-lysozyme) assumes a conformational form with native like secondary structure and no tertiary structure akin to a molten globule state. We correlate our results to kinetic hydrogen- deuterium exchange NMR results of the refolding of lysozyme available in literature and suggest that the conformational forms observed in our study could be models for kinetic intermediates in the refolding of lysozyme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T04:09:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T04:09:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY &amp; BIOPHYSICS, 37(2), 97-106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-1208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10221</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10221</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>