<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17832</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T05:06:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Changes in spectrochemical and catalytic properties of biopolymer anchored Cu(II) and Ni(II) catalysts by electron beam irradiation</dc:title><dc:creator>ANTONY, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MINI, PSSP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANICKAM, STD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANJEEV, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITU, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAKUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BASE MODIFIED CHITOSAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCHIFF-BASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYCLOHEXANE OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUNCTIONALIZED CHITOSAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>COORDINATION CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPPORTED CATALYST</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN-PEROXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO(II)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chitosan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Schiff base</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electron beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scanning electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cyclohexane</dc:subject><dc:description>Chitosan (a biopolymer) anchored Cu(II) and Ni(II) Schiff base complexes, [M(OIAC)Cl-2] (M: Cu/Ni and OIAC: ([2-oxo-1H-indo1-3-ylidene]amino)chitosan) were electron beam irradiated by different doses (100 Gy, 1 kGy and 10 kGy). The electron beam has shown potential impact on biopolymer's support, in detail chain linking and chain scissoring, as evidenced by viscosity studies, FT-IR and X-ray diffraction spectroscopic techniques. Due to these structural changes, thermal properties of the complexes were found to be changed. The surface of these heterogeneous complexes was also effectually altered by electron beam. As a consequence, pores and holes were created as probed by SEM technique. The catalytic activity of both non-irradiated and irradiated complexes was investigated in the aerobic oxidation of cyclohexane using hydrogen peroxide oxidant. The catalytic ability of the complexes was enhanced significantly after irradiation as the result of surface changes. The reusability of the complexes was also greatly affected because of the structural variations in polymeric support. In terms of both better catalytic activity along with the reusability, 1 kGy is suggested as the best dose to attain adequate increase in catalytic activity and good reusability. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:06:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T05:06:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SPECTROCHIMICA ACTA PART A-MOLECULAR AND BIOMOLECULAR SPECTROSCOPY, 149,550-557</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1386-1425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.saa.2015.04.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17832</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>