<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4729</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-12T06:32:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Correlated theory of triplet photoinduced absorption in phenylene-vinylene chains</dc:title><dc:creator>SHUKLA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>pi-conjugated polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>excited-states</dc:subject><dc:subject>singlet</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>excitations</dc:subject><dc:subject>stilbene</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectra</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, the results of large-scale correlated calculations of the triplet photoinduced-absorption (PA) spectrum of oligomers of poly-(para)phenylenevinylene (PPV) containing up to five phenyl rings are presented. In particular, the high-energy features in the triplet PA spectrum of oligo-PPV's are the focus of this study, which, to our knowledge, have not been investigated theoretically or experimentally. The calculations were performed using the Pariser-Parr-Pople model Hamiltonian and many-body effects were taken into account by means of the multireference singles-doubles configuration-interaction procedure without neglecting any molecular orbitals. The computed triplet PA spectrum of oligo-PPV's exhibits rich structure consisting of alternating peaks of high and low intensities. The predicted higher-energy features of the triplet spectrum can be tested in future experiments. Additionally, theoretical estimates of exciton binding energy are also presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T12:31:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T12:31:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 65(12), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.65.125204</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4729</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4729</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>