<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6574</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhancement of hydrogen oxidation activity at a nickel coated carbon beads electrode by cobalt and iron</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>alkaline fuel-cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon beads</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen electrode</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel-coated ceramic</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron and cobalt catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkaline fuel cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrocatalyst</dc:subject><dc:description>The electrochemical characteristics of a porous ceramic that is coated with carbon beads, impregnated with Ni, Fe and Co catalyst and operated as a hydrogen electrode for an alkaline fuel cell (AFC) are studied. To improve the catalytic activity and electrode performance, Ni is bimetallized with Co as well as Fe. Chemical vapour deposition (CVD) of turpentine oil, a renewable natural precursor, is used to grow the carbon beads. Various compositions of Ni-Co and Ni-Fe (10:90, 50:50, 90:10) are electroplated over the carbon-coated ceramic substrate. The detailed surface profile and elemental composition of the electrodes are studied by SEM, TEM, XRD and XRF analysis. Vander-Pauw resistivity measurements of the electrodes showed an increase in the conductivity of Ni electrode by addition of Co and Fe. The electrochemical performance is investigated by measuring hydrogen dissociation voltage, half-cell and full-cell current-potential characteristics and chrono-potentiometry in 30% KOH solution. The activity of the NI electrode is improved by addition of small amounts of Co and Fe. The best performance is obtained using an electrode coated with 90: 10 ratios of Ni-Co and Ni-Fe bimetallic composition. (C) 2004</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T00:05:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T00:05:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF POWER SOURCES, 137(2), 216-221</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0378-7753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2004.05.061</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6574</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6574</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>