<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-316</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Wireless e-jacket for multiparameter biophysical monitoring and telemedicine applications</dc:title><dc:creator>NAG, SUDIP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:subject>electrocardiography</dc:subject><dc:subject>health care</dc:subject><dc:subject>oximetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>patient monitoring</dc:subject><dc:subject>power conversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>telemedicine</dc:subject><dc:description>A widespread requirement exists for a low cost and reliable health monitor in the clinical as well as home environment. The e-jacket presented here is an example of a smart clothing system with multiple bioparameter acquisition of electrocardiogram (ECG), pulse oximetry, body motion/tilt and skin temperature. The battery operated circuit has an integrated graphic liquid crystal display (LCD) screen and a 2.4 GHz wireless link. An RS232 interface provides a plug-in port for easy accessibility to remote telemedicine applications. The system incorporates an efficient ARM7 microcontroller to coordinate a list of software tasks with associated time stamp. Comfort analysis and reliability aspects have been carefully studied along with intelligent power conservation schemes. A low cost and reliable tele-medical network is proposed using an innovative e-textile solution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-15T09:11:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:30:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-15T09:11:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:30:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 3rd IEEE-EMBS International Summer School and Symposium on Medical Devices and Biosensors MIT, Boston, USA, 4-6 September 2006, 40-44</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-9787-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ISSMDBS.2006.360092</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/316</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>