<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15637</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:13:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spo0A positively regulates epr expression by negating the repressive effect of co-repressors, SinR and ScoC, in Bacillus subtilis</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>DIXIT, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, KK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Anti-repressor</dc:subject><dc:subject>co-repressors</dc:subject><dc:subject>epr</dc:subject><dc:subject>ScoC (Hpr)</dc:subject><dc:subject>SinR</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spo0A</dc:subject><dc:subject>SWARMING MOTILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SERINE-PROTEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPORULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROMOTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>APRE</dc:subject><dc:description>Bacillus subtilis under nutritional deprivation exhibits several physiological responses such as synthesis of degradative enzymes, motility, competence, sporulation, etc. At the onset of post-exponential phase the global response regulator, Spo0A, directly or indirectly activates the expression of genes involved in the above processes. These genes are repressed during the exponential phase by a group of proteins called transition state regulators, e.g. AbrB, ScoC and SinR. One such post-exponentially expressed gene is epr, which encodes a minor extracellular serine protease and is involved in the swarming motility of B. subtilis. Deletion studies of the upstream region of epr promoter revealed that epr is co-repressed by transition state regulators, SinR and ScoC. Our study shows that Spo0A positively regulates epr expression by nullifying the repressive effect of co-repressors, SinR and ScoC. We demonstrate via in vitro mobility shift assays that Spo0A binds to the upstream region of epr promoter and in turn occludes the binding site of one of the co-repressor, SinR. This explains the mechanism behind the positive regulatory effect of Spo0A on epr expression.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:13:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:13:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOSCIENCES, 38(2)291-299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12038-013-9309-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15637</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>