<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15288</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T17:07:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Mechanical Arc Oscillation on the Grain Structure of Mild Steel Weld Metal</dc:title><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIRADAR, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Gas tungsten arc welding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mechanical arc oscillation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mild steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Weld metal grain structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH MAGNETIC-FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINUM-ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>REFINEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLIDIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WELDMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FE-0.52C</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERRITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZONE</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of mechanical arc oscillation on the weld metal grain structure in mild steel gas tungsten arc welds has been studied. For welds made without arc oscillation, columnar grains were observed in the weld metal; however, for the same welding parameters, the weld made with arc oscillation had smaller sized relatively equiaxed grains in the weld metal. The strengths for weld made with arc oscillation was higher than that for weld made without arc oscillation, with appreciable increase in ductility; this could be attributed to the reduction in grain size diameter due to arc oscillation. Lower weld metal hardness and increase in heat affected zone hardness was observed in weld made with arc oscillation; this could be attributed to increase in pro-eutectoid ferrite formation with absence of Widmanstatten ferrite structures in the weld metal and less coarsening of grains in the heat affected zone due to increased cooling rate.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:07:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:07:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN INSTITUTE OF METALS, 65(2)171-177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12666-012-0118-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15288</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>