<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2568</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Susceptibility studies on an 8051 microcontroller mounted on single- and multi-layer printed circuit boards</dc:title><dc:creator>TALWALKER, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRAMOULI, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAVEEN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper describes the susceptibility measurement studies performed on Intel's 8051 microcontroller based controller circuit against Radio Frequency (RF) signals. Several versions of the 8051 architecture have been mounted on single and multi-layer Printed Circuit Boards (PCB) and the effect of RF noise coupling to their Reset, Clock and Power pins have been observed and analyzed. This study assumes significance in today's world which is experiencing a boom in automation, communication and control areas, where such microcontrollers are extensively used. The results of this study are expected to be useful to a design engineer who has to frequently confront the question "which microcontroller to use?" and "what kind of PCB to design?" The results may also be useful in interpreting the various international EMC standards and their implications in electronic systems. All the results of this study are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC EMC ENGINEERS (INDIA)</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T01:54:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T01:54:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INCEMIC 2008: 10TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ELECTROMAGNETIC INTERFERENCE AND COMPATIBILITY, PROCEEDINGS,155-160</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-81-903575-1-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15877</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2568</dc:identifier><dc:source>10th International Conference on Electromagnetic Interference and Compatibility,Bangalore, INDIA,NOV 26-27, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>