<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14001</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:05:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characteristics of an open coast tidal flat: Example from Daman, west coast of India</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARASWATI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BURLEY, SD</dc:creator><dc:subject>SEA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEDIMENTOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RIVER</dc:subject><dc:subject>GULF</dc:subject><dc:subject>Open coast</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tidal flat</dc:subject><dc:subject>Older beach</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beach rock</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foraminifera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Western India</dc:subject><dc:description>This study highlights lithofacies and biofacies characteristics of the open coast tidal flat near Daman on the eastern flank of Gulf of Khambhat. Sedimentological and biological observation record six facies within the tidal flat area including older beach, beach face, sand flat, mud flat/mixed flat, sand bar and beach rock. Distinct sedimentary structures, foraminiferal assemblage and bioturbation intensity characterize each facies. A wide variety of wave and current generated sedimentary features characterize the sand flat facies. Semiconsolidated sands of older beach running parallel the coastline at a level higher than the present beach face possibly records the latest sea level highstand. The beach rock reflects early cementation of sands in tropical environments. Foraminifera are widely distributed in sand flats, mixed flats and mud flats and grouped into two biofacies - Ammonia-Elphidium-Quinqueloculina biofacies (sand flat and mixed flat) and Trochammina-Miliammina biofacies (mud flats). The beach face and sand bar facies contain forminifera reworked from sand flat and mud/mixed flat. Seasonal variation in depositional style is marked by deposition of fresh mud deposited over large areas of the intertidal flat during monsoon time, most of which is washed away by waves and current actions well before the onset of the next monsoon.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:05:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:05:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA,77(5)409-418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12594-011-0050-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14001</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>