<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11336</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Source apportionment of suspended particulate matter at two traffic junctions in Mumbai, India</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAMBI, KSV</dc:creator><dc:subject>elemental characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>atmospheric aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>bombay</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>traffic junctions</dc:subject><dc:subject>suspended particulate matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>lead</dc:subject><dc:subject>factor analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple regression</dc:subject><dc:description>Very high concentration of suspended particulate matter (SPM) is observed at traffic junctions in India. Factor analysis-multiple regression (FA-MR), a receptor modelling technique has been used for quantitative apportionment of the sources contributing to the SPM at two traffic junctions (Sakinaka and Gandhinagar) in Mumbai, India. Varimax rotated factor analysis identified (qualitative) five possible sources: road dust, vehicular emissions, marine aerosols, metal industries and coal combustion. A quantitative estimation by FA-MR model indicated that road dust contributed to 41%, vehicular emissions to 15%. marine aerosols to 15%, metal industries to 6% and coal combustion to 6% of the SPM observed at Sakinaka traffic junction. The corresponding figures for Gandhinagar traffic junction are 33%, 18%. 15% 8% and 11%, respectively. Due to limitation in source marker elements analysed about 16% of the remaining SPM at these two traffic junctions could not be apportioned to any possible sources by this technique. Of the observed lead in the SPM, FA-MR apportioned 62% to vehicular emissions, 17% to road dust, 11% to metal industries, 7% to coal combustion and 3% to marine aerosols at Gandhinagar traffic junction and about a similar apportionment for lead in SPM at Sakinaka traffic junction. (C) 2001 . .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T14:13:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T14:13:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT, 35(25), 4245-4251</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1352-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1352-2310(01)00258-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11336</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11336</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>