<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17307</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:26:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>High-performance hardware architectures for multi-level lifting-based discrete wavelet transform</dc:title><dc:creator>DARJI, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAH, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, AN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Clock gating</dc:subject><dc:subject>DWT</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dual-scan architecture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Folding</dc:subject><dc:subject>FPGA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lifting</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENT ARCHITECTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>VLSI ARCHITECTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-D DWT</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCHEME</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPLEMENTATION</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, three hardware efficient architectures to perform multi-level 2-D discrete wavelet transform (DWT) using lifting (5, 3) and (9, 7) filters are presented. They are classified as folded multi-level architecture (FMA), pipelined multi-level architecture (PMA), and recursive multi-level architecture (RMA). Efficient FMA is proposed using dual-input Z-scan block (B1) with 100% hardware utilization efficiency (HUE). Modular PMA is proposed with the help of block (B1) and dual-input raster scan block (B2) with 60% to 75% HUE. Block B1 and B2 are micro-pipelined to achieve critical path as single adder and single multiplier for lifting (5, 3) and (9, 7) filters, respectively. The clock gating technique is used in PMA to save power and area. Hardware-efficient RMA is proposed with the help of block (B1) and single-input recursive block (B3). Block (B3) uses only single processing element to compute both predict and update; thus, 50% multipliers and adders are saved. Dual-input per clock cycle minimizes total frame computing cycles, latency, and on-chip line buffers. PMA for five-level 2-D wavelet decomposition is synthesized using Xilinx ISE 10.1 for Virtex-5 XC5VLX110T field-programmable gate array (FPGA) target device (Xilinx, Inc., San Jose, CA, USA). The proposed PMA is very much efficient in terms of operating frequency due to pipelining. Moreover, this approach reduces and totals computing cycles significantly as compared to the existing multi-level architectures. RMA for three-level 2-D wavelet decomposition is synthesized using Xilinx ISE 10.1 for Virtex-4 VFX100 FPGA target device.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INTERNATIONAL PUBLISHING AG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:26:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:26:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EURASIP JOURNAL ON IMAGE AND VIDEO PROCESSING,</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1687-5281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1687-5281-2014-47</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17307</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>