<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4650</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>A study to investigate the influence of soil properties on suction</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEDEEP, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>silty soil</dc:subject><dc:subject>clay</dc:subject><dc:subject>suction</dc:subject><dc:subject>insertion tensiometer</dc:subject><dc:subject>laboratory investigations</dc:subject><dc:description>Various models that incorporate the influence of soil suction on different engineering properties of unsaturated soils have been developed. However, a systematic study of various physical parameters of the soil mass such as type of soil. particle size distribution. and the state of compaction (i.e., water content, dry unit weight, and saturation) is required to understand the influence of these parameters on soil;suction. directly or indirectly. This would be of great help in understanding the unsaturated properties of the soil mass. With this in view, an effort has been made in this technical note to measure the suction of locally available silty soil and commercially available white clay, compacted at different water contents and dry unit weights, using an insertion tensiometer. Efforts have been made to determine the influence of various parameters. as stated earlier, on the soil suction. Details of the test setup used for these studies are also presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC TESTING MATERIALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T07:08:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T07:08:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF TESTING AND EVALUATION, 33(1), 61-66</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0090-3973</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4650</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4650</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>