<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16976</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:21:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of beta phase fraction on deformation of grains in and around shear bands in machining of titanium alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>Titanium alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>beta phase fraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shear bands</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grain deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Machining affected zone</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TI-6AL-4V</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERPLASTICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TI6AL4V</dc:subject><dc:description>In machining of titanium alloys, beta phase fraction influences their temperature stability and consequently the material deformation in and around shear bands in chips. To understand the influence, chips and chip roots generated during orthogonal machining of these titanium alloys with increasing beta phase fraction viz, alpha, alpha+beta, beta rich alpha+beta alloys were collected. Analysis of shear band characteristics and micro-mechanism of deformation of the material during machining shows that an increase in beta phase fraction limits the spread of material deformation around the shear bands, reduces the spacing between them and prevents recovery micro-mechanism. Larger depth of machining affected zone in case of a and alpha+beta alloy as compared to beta rich alloy is attributed to their coarse grain size. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:21:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:21:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING, 61871-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2014.08.076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16976</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>