<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6383</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analytical solution in 2D domain for nonlinear response of piezoelectric slabs under weak electric fields</dc:title><dc:creator>SAMAL, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHU, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>longitudinal vibrations</dc:subject><dc:subject>static analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>analytical solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoceramic</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>perturbation method</dc:subject><dc:description>Piezoceramic materials exhibit different types of nonlinearities depending upon the magnitude of the mechanical and electric field strength in the continuum. Some of the nonlinearities observed under weak electric fields are: presence Of superharmonics in the response spectra and jump phenomena etc. especially if the system is excited near resonance. In this paper, an analytical Solution (in 2D plane stress domain) for the nonlinear response of a rectangular piezoceramic slab has been obtained by use of Rayleigh-Ritz method and perturbation technique. The eigenfunction obtained from Solution of the differential equation of the linear problem has been Used as the shape function in the Rayleigh-Ritz method. Forced vibration experiments have been conducted oil a rectangular piezoceramic slab by applying varying electric field strengths across the thickness and the results have been compared with those of analytical Solution. The analytical solutions compare well with those of experimental results. These solutions should serve as a method to validate the FE formulations as well as help in the determination of nonlinear material property coefficients for these materials. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T09:21:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T09:21:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMMUNICATIONS IN NONLINEAR SCIENCE AND NUMERICAL SIMULATION, 14(6), 2817-2826</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1007-5704</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cnsns.2008.09.033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6383</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6383</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>