<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15820</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:46:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Efficiency enhancement in DSSC using metal nanoparticles: A size dependent study</dc:title><dc:creator>DEEPA, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEKHA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINDHU, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>DSSC</dc:subject><dc:subject>Au nanoparticle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extinction cross-section</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface plasmon scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cyclic voltammetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLAR-ENERGY CONVERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GOLD NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERMI-LEVEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TIO2</dc:subject><dc:description>The photoelectrode of Eosin-Y sensitised DSSC was modified by incorporating Au-nanoparticles to enhance the power conversion efficiency via scattering from surface plasmon polaritons. Size dependence of Au nanoparticle on conversion efficiency was performed in DSSC for the first time by varying the particle size from 20 to 94 nm. It was found that, the conversion efficiency is highly dependent on the size of the Au nanoparticles. For larger particles (&gt;50 nm), the efficiency was found to be increased due to constructive interference between the transmitted and scattered waves from the Au nanoparticle while for smaller particles, the efficiency decreases due to destructive interference. Also a reduction in the V-oc was observed in general, due to the negative shifting of the TiO2 Fermi level on the adsorption of Au nanoparticle. This shift was negligible for larger particles. When 94 nm size particles were employed the conversion efficiency was doubled from 0.74% to 1.52%. This study points towards the application of the scattering effect of metal nanoparticle to enhance the conversion efficiency in DSSCs. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:46:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:46:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLAR ENERGY, 86(1)326-330</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.solener.2011.10.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15820</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>