<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1636</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mechanical behaviour of acrylic under high strain rate tensile loading</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PERLA, YERNAMMA</dc:creator><dc:subject>organic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress-strain relations</dc:subject><dc:subject>tensile strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>young's modulus</dc:subject><dc:subject>elastic moduli</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical testing</dc:subject><dc:description>An investigation of the effect of strain rate on tensile properties of acrylic is presented. Experimental studies were carried out on tensile split Hopkinson pressure bar (SHPB) apparatus in the strain rate range of 200–330 s−1. It is observed that the tensile strength and Young's modulus are enhanced and the ultimate strain is decreased at high strain rate loading compared with those at quasi-static loading. Studies were carried out with end-threaded cylindrical specimens. During tensile SHPB testing of the specimens, it was observed that the peak force obtained from the strain gauge mounted on the transmitter bar is lower than the peak force obtained from the strain gauge mounted on the incident bar. Further, an analytical method is presented based on a variable rate power law for the prediction of high strain rate tensile strength of acrylic. Using the analytical method, high strain rate tensile stress–strain behaviour is presented up to a strain rate of 2000 s−1.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-12T08:51:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:24:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-12T08:51:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:24:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Polymer Testing 27(4), 504-512</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0142-9418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.polymertesting.2008.02.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1636</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1636</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>