<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3116</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of both steric effects and te center dot center dot center dot n intramolecular nonbonded interactions on the stabilization of organotellurium compounds incorporating [2-[1-(3,5-dimethylphenyl)-2-naphthyl]-4,5-dihydro-4,4-dimethyloxazole]</dc:title><dc:creator>KANDASAMY, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>WOLMERSHAUSER, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>molecular-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthetic applications</dc:subject><dc:subject>tellurolato complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>thioredoxin reductase</dc:subject><dc:subject>12-te-5 pertelluranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-&gt;te coordination</dc:subject><dc:subject>organochalcogen se</dc:subject><dc:subject>tellurium</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactivity</dc:subject><dc:description>A series of novel low-valent organotellurium compounds incorporating [2-[1-(3,5-dimethylphenyl)-2-naphthyl]-4,5-dihydro-4,4-dimethyloxazole] (1) stabilized by (TeN)-N-... nonbonded interactions have been synthesized. The synthesis has been achieved by the ortholithium route. The lithium arenetellurolate 3 was obtained by direct metalation of 1 with 1.6 M of n-BuLi in hexane followed by the insertion of tellurium into the Li-C bond. Oxidation of 3 then afforded the desired ditelluride 4. The reaction of 4 with a stoichiometric amount of sulfuryl chloride yielded stable tellurenyl(II) chloride 5, whereas the addition of an excess sulfuryl chloride led to the formation of tellurium(IV) trichloride 6. The stable bromo compound 7 was obtained by the controlled bromination of 4 with bromine. No tellurium tribromide formation was observed when the ditelluride was treated with an excess of bromine. Compound 4 under-went facile reaction with a stoichiometric amount of iodine to give a stable mono iodo compound (8). The phenyltelluride derivative 9 was obtained by the treatment of lithiated product 2 with PhTeBr at low temperature. Attempts to synthesize the symmetrical telluride of the type R2Te (10) by the reaction of 2 with Te(dtc)(2) (dtc = diethyldithiocarbamate) or TeI2 were unsuccessful. All compounds were characterized by elemental analysis, multinuclear (H-1, C-13, Te-125) NMR, and mass spectrometry techniques. The presence of strong (TeN)-N-... intramolecular nonbonded interactions in all the compounds was confirmed by single-crystal X-ray crystallographic studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-14T11:50:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-14T11:50:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORGANOMETALLICS,22(24)5069-5078</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0276-7333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/om0340948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13913</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3116</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>