<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7370</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of curing temperature, silica nanoparticles- and cerium on surface morphology and corrosion behaviour of hybrid silane coatings on mild steel</dc:title><dc:creator>PHANASGAONKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>sol-gel coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>galvanized steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon-steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemical-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>bis-silane</dc:subject><dc:subject>al 2024-t3</dc:subject><dc:subject>m nacl</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>protection</dc:subject><dc:subject>pretreatments</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>silanes</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrosion and oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>cerium</dc:subject><dc:subject>mild steel</dc:subject><dc:description>This work is aimed at developing and investigating silane based organic-inorganic hybrid coatings possessing unique properties, which can be used to improve the performance of steel structures subjected to marine corrosion. These silane based sol-gel coatings were prepared by dip coating planar samples of mild steel in solution of an organically modified silica sol made from hydrolysis and polycondensation of tetraethylorthosilicate (TEOS) and methyltriethoxysilane (MTES) in acid catalysis condition. Crack-free coatings were obtained on curing at 200 degrees C. On increasing the curing temperature to 400 degrees C, however, cracks developed in the plain organic-inorganic hybrid coatings. This observation was consistent with the visual observations where appearance of the coated specimen changed from colourless metallic to brownish grey on curing from 200 degrees C to 400 degrees C temperature. The coatings were further modified using SiO(2) nanoparticles and cerium. The effect of change in the - temperature as well as - composition on the microstructural properties of the coatings was determined using optical microscopy, scanning electron microscopy and atom force microscopy. Additionally, Attenuated Total Reflectance-Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy (ATR/FTIR) was carried out to show the formation of the Si-O-Si structural backbone of the hybrid material with the organic CH(3) group incorporated into the silica network. The corrosion protection performance of these coatings was examined using potentiodynamic polarisation technique and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy in aerated 3.5 wt.% NaCl solution. The polarization curves and corrosion resistance as measured by the bode plots suggested that the plain hybrid coatings offer good protection against corrosion. However, the SiO(2) and cerium modified nano hybrid coatings exhibited superior performance to that displayed by plain hybrid coatings. (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-28T09:57:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-28T09:57:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SURFACE &amp; COATINGS TECHNOLOGY, 203(16), 2260-2271</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0257-8972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2009.02.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7370</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7370</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>