<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7796</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T04:56:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Work-family enrichment as a mediator between organizational interventions for work-life balance and job outcomes</dc:title><dc:creator>BARAL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>citizenship behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>positive-spillover</dc:subject><dc:subject>conflict</dc:subject><dc:subject>facilitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>support</dc:subject><dc:subject>satisfaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>commitment</dc:subject><dc:subject>culture</dc:subject><dc:subject>impact</dc:subject><dc:subject>predictors</dc:subject><dc:subject>family friendly organizations</dc:subject><dc:subject>job enrichment</dc:subject><dc:subject>expectation</dc:subject><dc:subject>organizational performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality of life</dc:subject><dc:description>Purpose This paper aims to examine the role of work-family enrichment in the relationships between organizational interventions for work-life balance (job characteristics, work-life benefits and policies, supervisor support and work-family culture) and job outcomes (job satisfaction, affective commitment and organizational citizenship behaviour). It is hypothesized that organizational interventions for work-life balance will be positively related to job outcomes and work-to-family enrichment will mediate these relationships. Design/methodology/approach Data were collected from 216 managerial employees through a structured questionnaire from four organizations in India representing manufacturing and information technology (IT) sectors. Analysis was done using multiple regressions. Findings - Job characteristics were positively related to all the measures of job outcomes. Supervisor support and work-family culture were positively related to job satisfaction and affective commitment. No significant association was found between work-life benefits and policies (WLBPs) and any of the job outcome measures. Job characteristics and supervisor support were positively related to work-to-family enrichment. Work-to-family enrichment mediated the relationships between job characteristics and all job outcomes and between supervisor support and affective commitment. Research limitations/implications The correlational design prevents conclusions about causality. Practical implications The findings have implications for designing jobs, developing supportive work-family culture and managing employee work-family interface for maximizing individual and organizational outcomes. Originality/value The study reflected on the work-family domain relationships in a novel socio-cultural context and demonstrated the mediating role of work-family enrichment in the relationships between organizational interventions for work-life balance and job outcomes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>EMERALD GROUP PUBLISHING LIMITED</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T18:48:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T18:48:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MANAGERIAL PSYCHOLOGY, 25(3-4), 274-300</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-3946</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1108/02683941011023749</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7796</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7796</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>