<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17545</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:52:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization of algal and microbial community growth in a wastewater treating batch photo-bioreactor inoculated with lake water</dc:title><dc:creator>KRUSTOK, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>ODLARE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHABIIMAM, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRUU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRUU, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIGI, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEHRENHEIM, E</dc:creator><dc:subject>BACTERIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CULTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOBIOREACTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUANTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIODIESEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Algal cultivation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biomass production</dc:subject><dc:subject>Community analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photo-bioreactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wastewater treatment</dc:subject><dc:description>Microalgae grown in photo-bioreactors can be a valuable source of biomass, especially when combined with wastewater treatment. While most published research has studied pure cultures, the consortia of algae and bacteria from wastewater have more complex community dynamics which affect both the biomass production and pollutant removal. In this paper we investigate the dynamics of algal and bacterial growth in wastewater treating batch photo-bioreactors. The photo-bioreactors were inoculated with water from a nearby lake. Lake water was obtained in August, November and December in order to add native algal species and study the effects of the season. The photo-bioreactors inoculated with lake water obtained in August and November produced more biomass and grew faster than those that only contained the algae from wastewater. The results indicated a rapid decline in bacterial abundance before algae began to multiply in reactors supplemented with lake water in November and December. The reactors were also successful in removing nitrogen and phosphorous from wastewater. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:52:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:52:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ALGAL RESEARCH-BIOMASS BIOFUELS AND BIOPRODUCTS, 11,421-427</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2211-9264</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.algal.2015.02.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17545</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>