<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15686</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:38:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rhenium(I) Tricarbonyl Complexes of 5,10,15,20-Tetraphenyl-21-thia and 21-Oxaporphyrins</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>N-FUSED TETRAPHENYLPORPHYRIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL-CHARACTERIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNUSUAL METALLOPORPHYRINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>21-THIAPORPHYRIN COMPLEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NICKEL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PORPHYRINS</dc:subject><dc:description>The hexa-coordinated rhenium(I) tricarbonyl complexes of 5,10,15,20-tetraphenyl-21-thiaporphyrin 1 and S,10,15,20-tetraphenyl-21-oxaporphyrin 2 have been synthesized by thermal reaction of corresponding free base porphyrin with Re-2(CO)(10). The compounds 1 and 2 are characterized by HR-MS mass, H-1, and C-13 NMR, FTIR, UV-vis, and electrochemical techniques and the structures are determined by X-ray single crystal analysis. The X-ray analysis revealed different coordination behavior of Re(CO)(3) with 21-thiaporphyrin and 21-oxaporphyrin. Interestingly, the Re(CO)(3) coordinates to two of the three inner nitrogens and one sulfur instead of three inner nitrogens as generally expected to produce unique compound 1 whereas it coordinates to three inner nitrogens but not with loran oxygen to form compound 2. The 21-thiaporphyrin ring is more distorted in compound 1 compared to 21-oxaporphyrin ring in compound 2 on complexation with Re(CO)(3). The presence of three carbonyl groups in compounds 1 and 2 are verified by C-13 NMR and IR spectroscopy. The absorption spectra of compounds 1 and 2 showed ill-defined Q-bands along with broad Soret band and the extinction coefficients are much lower than their corresponding free base porphyrins. The compounds 1 and 2 showed two reversible porphyrin ring based reductions supporting their electron deficient nature. The compound 1 is very stable under protonation conditions, and the protonation occurs at the uncoordinated pyrrole ring whereas the compound 2 undergoes decomplexation under same conditions. Furthermore, compound 1 showed the fluxional behavior in coordination mode of binding in solution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:38:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:38:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 51(12)6700-6709</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic300344g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15686</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>