<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18350</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:30:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Application of Intelligent Compaction Technology for Estimation of Effective Modulus for a Multilayered Asphalt Pavement</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEAINY, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>COMMURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZAMAN, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>HOT-MIX ASPHALT</dc:subject><dc:subject>intelligent compaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>stiffness</dc:subject><dc:subject>FWD</dc:subject><dc:subject>Witczak model</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a procedure for estimation of effective modulus of a multilayered hot mix asphalt (HMA) pavement using intelligent compaction (IC) is investigated. The study is conducted during the construction of an interstate highway (I-35) in Norman, OK. A complete coverage of the level of compaction of each of the asphalt pavement layers was recorded using the intelligent asphalt compaction analyzer (IACA). The collected IACA data allow determination of the level of compaction (density) at any selected location, for each layer, and provided a set of global positioning system (GPS) coordinates. Calibration procedures have previously been tested and validated by the authors to estimate the density of different types of pavements from IACA data. In this paper, a different calibration procedure is used to measure the dynamic modulus instead of the density of a pavement using IACA. Considering the IACA estimated density, the dynamic modulus of each of the selected locations for an individual pavement layer was measured from laboratory developed master curves. Thereafter, an effective modulus of the three-layer pavement system was calculated for all of the selected locations using Odemark's method. The proposed technique was verified by conducting falling-weight deflectometer (FWD) tests at these selected locations. Analyses of the results show that the proposed intelligent compaction technique may be promising in estimating the effective modulus of the pavement layers in a non-destructive manner. In addition, the Witczak model was used to estimate moduli of each of the pavement layers. The comparison of the Witczak model with FWD revealed that the model over-predicted the modulus significantly.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC TESTING MATERIALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:30:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:30:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF TESTING AND EVALUATION, 43(2)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0090-3973</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1945-7553</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1520/JTE20130305</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18350</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>