<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5409</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kinetics and mechanism of the cobalt(III) tetraammine complex-promoted hydrolysis of 4-nitrophenyl glycinate</dc:title><dc:creator>PHULAMBRIKAR, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>amino-acid esters</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphate diesters</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel(ii)</dc:subject><dc:subject>copper(ii)</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactivity</dc:subject><dc:description>The kinetics of the hydrolysis of 4-nitrophenyl glycine ester (PNPG) catalysed by [Co(OH)(trien)(OH2)](2+), [Co(OH)(tren)(OH2)](2+) and [Co(OH)(en)(2)(OH2)](2+) complexes has been studied spectrophotometrically in weakly basic aqueous media (pH = 6.5 to 7.4). Kinetic experiments were carried out as a function of the pH, complex concentration and temperature. The rate of hydrolysis increases linearly with the complex concentration with a trend to wards rate saturation, suggesting the formation of associative species in a pre-equilibrium step. The pseudo-first order rate constant, k(obs), increases rapidly with a decrease in the hydrogen-ion concentration. The complexes promote the hydrolysis of 4-nitrophenyl glycinate significantly, and the acceleration rate is about 400-600. An attack of external OH- on the chelated ester is suggested as a probable mechanism for the hydrolysis. The lower rate enhancements observed in the present study could probably be ascribed to a weaker cobalt(III) alkoxy carbonyl interaction in the chelate, owing to a decreased nucleophilicity of the carbonyl oxygen in the p-nitrophenyl ester. The activation parameters for all three complex-promoted reactions are found to be comparable, thus suggesting a common mechanism operative in all complex catalysed reactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CHEMICAL SOC JAPAN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-20T08:26:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-20T08:26:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF THE CHEMICAL SOCIETY OF JAPAN, 75(7), 1515-1519</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2673</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1246/bcsj.75.1515</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5409</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5409</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>