<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3836</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Example of highly stereoregulated ruthenium amidine complex formation: Synthesis, crystal structures, and spectral and redox properties of the complexes [Ru-II(trpy) {NC5H4-CH = N-N(C6H5)C(CH3)=NH}](ClO4)(2) (1) and [Ru-II(trpy)(NC5H4-CH = N-NH-C6H5)Cl]ClO4 (2) (trpy=2,2 ': 6 ',2 ''-terpyridine)</dc:title><dc:creator>MONDAL, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANIK, VG</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>ortho-cyanobenzyl complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>terpyridine complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>platinum metals</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>nucleophilic-attack</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectroelectrochemical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>polypyridyl complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>coordinated nitriles</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-metals</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of Ru(trpy)Cl-3 (trpy = 2,2':6',2"-terpyridine) with the pyridine-based imine function NpC5H4-CH=NiNH-C6H5 (L), incorporating an NH spacer between the imine nitrogen (N) and the pendant phenyl ring, in ethanol medium followed by chromatographic work up on a neutral alumina column using CH3CN/CH2Cl2 (1:4) as eluent, results in complexes of the types [Ru(trpy)(L')](ClO4)(2) (1) and [Ru(trpy)(L)Cl]ClO4 (2). Although the identity of the free ligand (L) has been retained in complex 2, the preformed imine-based potentially bidentate ligand (L) has been selectively transformed into a new class of unusual imine-amidine-based tridentate ligand, NpC5H4-CH= N-i-N(C6H5)C(CH3)=NaH (L'), in 1. The single-crystal X-ray structures of the free ligand (L) and both complexes 1 and 2 have been determined. In 2, the sixth coordination site, that is, the Cl- function, is cis to the pyridine nitrogen (N-p) of L which in turn places the NH spacer away from the Ru-Cl bond, whereas, in 1, the corresponding sixth position, that is, the Ru-N-a (amidine) bond, is trans to the pyridine nitrogen (N-p) of L'. The trans configuration of N-a with respect to the N-p of L' in 1 provides the basis for the selective L --&gt; L' transformation in 1. The complexes exhibit strong Ru(II) --&gt; pi* (trpy) MLCT transitions in the visible region and intraligand transitions in the UV region. The lowest energy MLCT band at 510 nm for 2 has been substantially blue-shifted to 478 nm in the case of 1. The reversible Ru(III)-Ru(II) couples for 1 and 2 have been observed at 0.80 and 0.59 V versus SCE, respectively. The complexes are weakly luminescent at 77 K, exhibiting emissions at lambda(max), 598 nm [quantum yield (Phi) = 0.43 x 10(-2)] and 574 nm (Phi = 0.28 x 10(-2)) for 1 and 2, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T02:32:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T02:32:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 41(22), 5831-5836</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic020351+</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3836</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3836</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>