<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-258</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Operating strategies for generation deficient power system</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, ANJAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENTAYYA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUSHPA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>demand side management</dc:subject><dc:subject>frequency control</dc:subject><dc:subject>power generation dispatch</dc:subject><dc:subject>power markets</dc:subject><dc:subject>power system security</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage control</dc:subject><dc:description>Power systems of many developing countries have to face sustained generation deficiency, large frequency fluctuations and are susceptible to even small disturbances. Operating such system is an onerous task and innovative solutions are needed to deal with the situation. To overcome the situation, India has adopted commercial mechanism known as availability based tariff (ABT) which has a component linked with frequency. The frequency and in turn price signal is available throughout the system with no additional infrastructure. The commercial mechanism has brought in a paradigm shift in the operating strategies from the conventional frequency control and dispatch techniques affecting many operational policies. The dispatch methods are also linked with the frequency as a consequence of the mechanism. One can compare the mechanism with the real time balancing market operation which has similar principle of operation for the restructured power market. The frequency control and voltage control mechanisms are revisited in the context of the generation deficiency covering normal, abnormal, and emergency system conditions. The contingency management, demand management etc. are also given a fresh look. The security strategies adopted by the Western Regional Load Dispatch Center, Bombay, India along with some countermeasures are described. The strategies are implemented on the Indian grid and are working in satisfactory manner.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-10T09:32:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:11:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-10T09:32:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:11:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE Power Engineering Society General Meeting (V 3), San Francisco, USA, 12-16 June 2005, 2738-2745</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-9157-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/PES.2005.1489149</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/258</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>