<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14084</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:02:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flexible open architecture design for power system control centers</dc:title><dc:creator>PRADEEP, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHURAJU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Open architecture design</dc:subject><dc:subject>Common information model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Event driven architecture</dc:subject><dc:subject>Complex event processing</dc:subject><dc:description>That the new generation power system control centers need a paradigm shift in their architectural design to meet new challenges, is an established conclusion of many researchers. However, literature on comprehensive architectural design towards this direction is scarce. In this paper, an information architecture design is proposed for the power system control centers. Appropriate adoption of open standards such as the common information model (CIM) is endorsed. Further, initial development of an event information model for modeling high level power system events is mentioned. Proposed architecture focuses on the desired features such as openness, interoperability, flexibility, scalability, vendor independence and event orientation. The architecture comprises services arranged in layers, viz., data integration and access, event processing and plug-in services. The details of this architecture along with the intricate relationships between various layers and services depicting how the technologies could be integrated into a coherent whole are described in this paper. An illustrative example, from the Indian power sector domain has been used to demonstrate the usefulness of the proposed architecture. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:02:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:02:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ELECTRICAL POWER &amp; ENERGY SYSTEMS,33(4)976-982</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0142-0615</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijepes.2011.01.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14084</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>