<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1246</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhanced nonlinear optical responses in metal-glass nanocomposites</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>absorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>colloids</dc:subject><dc:subject>silica</dc:subject><dc:subject>laser</dc:subject><dc:subject>gold</dc:subject><dc:subject>ion implantation</dc:subject><dc:subject>glass</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-glass nanocomposites</dc:subject><dc:subject>third-order optical responses</dc:subject><dc:subject>z-scan</dc:subject><dc:subject>arins</dc:subject><dc:description>The "engineered'' nonlinear nanocomposite materials with extremely large values of optical Kerr susceptibility and fast temporal responses that can be precisely tuned to satisfy the requirements of switching applications is of current interest in photonics. Metal quantum-dot composite glasses can exhibit enhanced optical susceptibility, chi(3), whose real and imaginary parts are related to the intensity-dependent refractive index and two-photon absorption coefficient, respectively. Classical (dielectric) and quantum confinement effects come into play in the nonlinear optical responses of these nanocomposites. Metal nanocluster-glass composites have been synthesized by 200 keV Cu(+) and 1.5 MeV Au(+) ion implantations in fused silica glasses at a dose of 3 x 10(16) ions/cm(2), followed by thermal annealing in reducing atmosphere to promote cluster growth. UV-Visible spectroscopy has revealed prominent linear absorption bands at characteristic surface plasmon resonance (SPR) frequencies signifying appreciable formation of copper and gold colloids in glass matrices. Third-order optical properties of the composite materials have been studied by Z-Scan and Anti-Resonant Interferometric Nonlinear Spectroscopy (ARINS) measurements. The sign of nonlinear refraction is readily obtained from the Z-Scan signatures. The ARINS technique utilizes the dressing of two unequal-intensity counter-propagating pulsed light beams with differential nonlinear phases, which occur upon traversing the sample if it exhibits nonlinear optical response. This difference in phase manifests itself in the intensity-dependent transmission. The nonlinear refractive index, nonlinear absorption coefficient, the real and imaginary parts of the third-order optical susceptibility have been extracted. (C) 2009 Elsevier B. V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T14:40:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T14:40:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED SURFACE SCIENCE,256(2)389-394</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0169-4332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2009.05.093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14436</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1246</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Conference on Physics at Surfaces and Interfaces (PSI2009),Puri, INDIA,FEB 23-27, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>