<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14349</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T09:59:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>On a Novel Dual-Grid Level-Set Method for Two-Phase Flow Simulation</dc:title><dc:creator>GADA, VH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>OF-FLUID METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRONT-TRACKING METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>NUMERICAL-SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE-TENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOLUME-TRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPUTATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLIDIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, a hypothesis is proposed for two-phase flow simulation: The number of grid points required for the grid-independent solution of the flow field is lesser than that required to capture the grid-independent interface. Based on this, a dual-grid level-set(LS) method (DGLSM) is proposed, where the LS and energy equations are solved on a uniform grid which is twice finer than the continuity and momentum equations. This novel grid arrangement is aimed at improving interface resolution with only a slight increase in computational time. Qualitative and quantitative results of the DGLSM are compared against analytical, experimental, and numerical results on three stringent test problems: dam break, Rayleigh-Taylor instability, and film boiling. The results show that the DGLSM is accurate and robust, even for surface tension-dominant flows. Moreover, the hypothesis is corroborated by showing that the DGLSM is nearly as accurate as the completely refined traditional LS method at substantially less computational expense.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUMERICAL HEAT TRANSFER PART B-FUNDAMENTALS,59(1)26-57</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1040-7790</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10407790.2011.540956</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14349</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>