<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8469</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Robust neural-network-based data association and multiple model-based tracking of multiple point targets</dc:title><dc:creator>ZAVERI, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>expectation-maximization algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>maneuvering targets</dc:subject><dc:subject>maximum-likelihood</dc:subject><dc:subject>em algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>pmht</dc:subject><dc:subject>data association</dc:subject><dc:subject>expectation maximization (em)</dc:subject><dc:subject>interacting multiple model</dc:subject><dc:subject>neural network (nn)</dc:subject><dc:description>Data association and model selection are important factors for tracking multiple targets in a dense clutter environment without using a priori information about the target dynamic. We propose a neural-network-based tracking algorithm, incorporating a interacting multiple model and show that it is possible to track both maneuvering and nonmaneuvering targets simultaneously in the presence of dense clutter. Moreover, it can be used for real-time application. The proposed method overcomes the problem of data association by using the method of expectation maximization and Hopfield network to evaluate assignment weights. All validated observations are used to update the target state. In the proposed approach, a probability density function (pdf) of an observed data, given target state and observation association, is treated as a mixture pdf. This allows to combine the likelihood of an observation due to each model, and the association process is defined to incorporate an interacting multiple model, and consequently, it is possible to track any arbitrary trajectory.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T15:20:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T15:20:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON SYSTEMS MAN AND CYBERNETICS PART C-APPLICATIONS AND REVIEWS, 37(3), 337-351</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1094-6977</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TSMCC.2007.893281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8469</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8469</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>