<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12294</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biodegradation of phenanthrene by Psuedomonas sp strain PP2: novel metabolic pathway, role of biosurfactant and cell surface hydrophobicity in hydrocarbon assimilation</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHU, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>polycyclic aromatic-hydrocarbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>pseudomonas-putida ous82</dc:subject><dc:subject>rhamnolipid biosurfactant</dc:subject><dc:subject>microbial surfactants</dc:subject><dc:subject>escherichia-coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>gene-cluster</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>aeruginosa</dc:subject><dc:subject>kp7</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhancement</dc:subject><dc:description>Pseudomonas sp. strain PP2 isolated in our laboratory efficiently metabolizes phenanthrene at 0.3% concentration as the sole source of carbon and energy. The metabolic pathways for the degradation of phenanthrene, benzoate and p-hydroxybenzoate were elucidated by identifying metabolites, biotransformation studies, oxygen uptake by whole cells on probable metabolic intermediates, and monitoring enzyme activities in cell-free extracts. The results obtained suggest that phenanthrene degradation is initiated by double hydroxylation resulting in the formation of 3,4-dihydroxyphenanthrene. The diol was finally oxidized to 2-hydroxymuconic semialdehyde. Detection of 1-hydroxy-2-naphthoic acid, a-naphthol, 1,2-dihydroxy naphthalene, and salicylate in the spent medium by thin layer chromatography; the presence of 1,2-dihydroxynaphthalene dioxygenase, salicylaldehyde dehydrogenase and catechol-2,3-dioxygenase activity in the extract; 02 uptake by cells on alpha-naphthol, 1,2-dihydroxynaphthalene, salicylaldehyde, salicylate and catechol; and no 02 uptake on o-phthalate and 3,4-dihydroxybenzoate supports the novel route of metabolism of phenanthrene via 1-hydroxy-2-naphthoic acid --&gt; [alpha-naphthol] --&gt; 1,2-dihydroxy naphthalene --&gt; salicylate --&gt; catechol. The strain degrades benzoate via catechol and cis,cis-muconic acid, and p-hydroxybenzoate via 3,4-dihydroxybenzoate and 3-carboxy-cis,cis-muconic acid. Interestingly, the culture failed to grow on naphthalene. When grown on either hydrocarbon or dextrose, the culture showed good extracellular biosurfactant production. Growth-dependent changes in the cell surface hydrophobicity, and emulsification activity experiments suggest that: (1) production of biosurfactant was constitutive and growth-associated, (2) production was higher when cells were grown on phenanthrene as compared to dextrose and benzoate, (3) hydrocarbon-grown cells were more hydrophobic and showed higher affinity towards both aromatic and aliphatic hydrocarbons compared to dextrose-grown cells, and (4) mid-log-phase cells were significantly (2-fold) more hydrophobic than stationary phase cells. Based on these results, we hypothesize that growth-associated extracellular biosurfactant production and modulation of cell surface hydrophobicity plays an important role in hydrocarbon assimilation/uptake in Pseudomonas sp. strain PP2.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:13:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T11:13:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED MICROBIOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 61(4), 342-351</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0175-7598</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00253-002-1218-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12294</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12294</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>