<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-688</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>CFD modeling of pilot-scale pump-mixer: single-phase head and power characteristics</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, KK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SANJAY</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHENOY, KT</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, AW</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>computational fluid dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>impellers</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbines</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work involves single-phase computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations of continuous flow pump-mixer employing top-shrouded Rushton turbines with trapezoidal blades. Baffle—impeller interaction has been modeled using sliding mesh and multiple reference frame approaches. Standard k–ε model has been used for turbulence modeling. Several CFD runs representing different combinations of geometric and process parameters have been carried out. Results of CFD simulations have been used to find out two macroscopic performance parameters of pump-mixer—power consumption and head generated by the impeller. The simulation results have been compared with the experimental data obtained on a pilot-scale setup. Good agreement between CFD predictions and experimental results is observed. In most cases, sliding mesh approach is found to perform better than multiple reference frame approach. Details from CFD simulations have been used to have an insight into the pumping action of the impeller.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:30:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:09:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-18T05:30:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:09:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Chemical Engineering Science 62(5), 1308-1322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2006.10.028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/688</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/688</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>