<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16658</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T13:04:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhancement in Electrical Conductance of Pt Decorated Multiwalled Carbon Tubes Using Electron Beam-Induced Deposition Technique</dc:title><dc:creator>DHALL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAIDYA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAGGI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>EBID technique</dc:subject><dc:subject>I-V characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>lithography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pt nanoclusters</dc:subject><dc:description>We propose a direct-write approach to decorate the hanging multiwalled carbon tubes (MWCNTs), at the selected sites with platinum (Pt) metal, using electron beam-induced deposition (EBID) technique. As prepared nanostructure is investigated by scanning electron microscopy (SEM), confirming the deposition of Pt nanoclusters on tube surface. The conductance of the individual tube enhances significantly due to Pt deposition at desired locations on the tubes. The value of conductance (in terms of quanta) of the same tube is increased from 3.2 G(0) to 11.7 G(0) at zero bias after Pt deposition. This enhancement in conductance is explained in terms of change in density of states (DOS) at the Fermi level which results in charge transfer between tubes and nanoclusters. This approach can be used for the applications of tubes in nano-devices which is dependent on the distribution of metal nanostructures, nano gas sensors, and in the interconnections.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:04:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:04:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FULLERENES NANOTUBES AND CARBON NANOSTRUCTURES, 23(4)371-375</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1536-383X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1536-4046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/1536383X.2014.902372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16658</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>