<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4532</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-12T04:57:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>High-frequency dynamics of spin-polarized carriers and photons in a laser</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASU, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:subject>injection</dc:subject><dc:subject>gaas</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor</dc:subject><dc:description>The high-frequency dynamics of spin-polarized carriers and photons in a spin laser have been studied. The transient response of the device obtained from the rate equations is characterized by two sets of relaxation oscillations in the carrier and photon distributions corresponding to the two polarization modes. Consequently two distinct resonant peaks are observed in the small-signal modulation response. The calculated transient characteristics indicate that the best results are obtained from a spin laser when only the favored polarization mode, with lower threshold, is operational. Under this condition the small-signal modulation bandwidth is higher than that in a conventional laser, the threshold current is lower and the output polarization can be 100% with appropriate bias conditions, independent of the spin polarization of carriers in the active region. Measurements were made at 230 K on a InAs/GaAs quantum dot spin vertical cavity surface emitting laser. A time-averaged output polarization of 55% is measured with an active region spin polarization of 5-6 %. The experimental results are in good agreement with calculated data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T21:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T21:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 82(20), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.82.205309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4532</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4532</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>