<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16928</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:50:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Morphology controlled synthesis of layered NH4V4O10 and the impact of binder on stable high rate electrochemical performance</dc:title><dc:creator>SARKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VELURI, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Ammonium vanadate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Binder</dc:subject><dc:subject>High rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lithium-ion Battery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanobelts</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROTHERMAL SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LITHIUM BATTERIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATHODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALGINATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANODE</dc:subject><dc:description>Rich electrochemistry of vanadium based compounds in terms of high lithium storage capability along with low cost prompted us to study NH4V4O10 as cathode material for lithium ion batteries. Herein, we report for the first time, a high rate and high energy density cathode based on intercalated ammonium vanadate. The present strategy of making such high rate cathode is mainly based on the use of interactive binder like carboxy methyl cellulose (CMC) or alginate binder instead of poly(vinylidene difluride) (PVDF) binder along with 2D morphology. A detailed study shows the dependency of morphology, reaction pH and binder selection on electrochemical performance. In brief, we have demonstrated NH4V4O10-CMC/alginate based cathode as superior candidate for next generation lithium-ion batteries. The as synthesized NH4V4O10 along with CMC/alginate binder delivers discharge capacity of 200 mAh g(-1) at very high current rate of 1000 mA g(-1) and completely retains its original discharge state at low current rate of 100 mA g(-1) rate, whereas PVDF-based cathode delivers discharge capacity of 125 mAh g(-1) at same current rate. Based on morphological and FT-IR studies, we have revealed interactions between active materials and binder particles (CMC and alginate) which play a crucial role in determining the electrochemical performance. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:50:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:50:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ELECTROCHIMICA ACTA, 132448-456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-4686</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-3859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2014.03.144</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16928</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>