<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4560</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-17T10:58:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Resolving the mass hierarchy with atmospheric neutrinos using a liquid argon detector</dc:title><dc:creator>GANDHI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSHAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOSWAMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANKAR, SU</dc:creator><dc:subject>oscillations</dc:subject><dc:subject>theta(13)</dc:subject><dc:subject>tpc</dc:subject><dc:description>We explore the potential offered by large-mass liquid argon detectors for determination of the sign of Delta m(31)(2), or the neutrino mass hierarchy, through interactions of atmospheric neutrinos. We give results for a 100 kT sized magnetized detector which provides separate sensitivity to nu(mu), (nu)overbar(mu) and, over a limited energy range, to nu(e), (nu)overbar(e). We also discuss the sensitivity for the unmagnetized version of such a detector. After including the effect of smearing in neutrino energy and direction and incorporating the relevant statistical, theoretical, and systematic errors, we perform a binned chi(2) analysis of simulated data. The chi(2) is marginalized over the presently allowed ranges of neutrino parameters and determined as a function of theta(13). We find that such a detector offers superior capabilities for hierarchy resolution, allowing a &gt; 4 sigma determination for a 100 kT detector over a 10-year running period for values of sin(2)2 theta(13)&gt;= 0.05. For an unmagnetized detector, a 2.5 sigma hierarchy sensitivity is possible for sin(2)2 theta(13)=0.04.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T23:34:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T23:34:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW D, 78(7), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-7998</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.78.073001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4560</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4560</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>