<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17455</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:06:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biocorrosion and biodegradation behavior of ultralight Mg-4Li-1Ca (LC41) alloy in simulated body fluid for degradable implant applications</dc:title><dc:creator>NENE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>ESTRIN, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>AL-SAMMAN, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>MAGNESIUM-LITHIUM ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MG-CA ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORROSION-RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>REFINEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTRUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIVO</dc:subject><dc:description>Biocorrosion and biodegradation behavior of Mg-4Li-1Ca alloy were investigated for industrially important end product conditions, namely the homogenized, rolled, and rolled + annealed ones. Among the three, homogenized material showed the highest corrosion rate (27.2 mm/year) in a simulated body fluid (SBF) owing to its coarse grain structure containing long dumbbell-shaped eutectic phase. Rolled + annealed material exhibited the lowest corrosion rate (0.94 mm/year) corresponding to the highest corrosion resistance (1.854 k Omega cm(2)) in SBF. This higher corrosion resistance is associated with a uniform distribution of corrosion sites and a lower occurrence of twins in the microstructure. However, the rolled material showed a greater corrosion rate due to an appreciable volume fraction of {101} compression twins, {102} tension twins, and {101}-{102} double twins, which form galvanic couples with the adjacent grains that enhances localized corrosion. A mechanism of biodegradation at the alloy/SBF interface is proposed. It involves the formation of bone-like hydroxyapatite and metastable octa calcium phosphate, along with other degradation products, such as magnesium hydroxide and lithium hydroxide.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:06:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:06:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 50(8)3041-3050</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-2461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-4803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10853-015-8846-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17455</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>