<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7233</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>The polytope of degree sequences of hypergraphs</dc:title><dc:creator>MURTHY, NLB</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASAN, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>degree sequences</dc:subject><dc:subject>hypergraphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>polytopes</dc:subject><dc:subject>threshold graphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>threshold sequences</dc:subject><dc:description>Let D-n(r) denote the convex hull of degree sequences of simple r-uniform hypergraphs on the vertex set {1, 2,..., n}. The polytope D-n (2) is a well-studied object. Its extreme points are the threshold sequences (i.e., degree sequences of threshold graphs) and its facets are given by the Erdos-Gallai inequalities. In this paper we study the polytopes D-n(r) and obtain some partial information. Our approach also yields new, simple proofs of some basic results on D-n (2). Our main results concern the extreme points and facets of D-n (r). We characterize adjacency of extreme points of D-n (r) and, in the case r = 2, determine the distance between two given vertices in the graph of D-n (2). We give a characterization of when a linear inequality determines a facet of D-n (r) and use it to bound the sizes of the coefficients appearing in the facet defining inequalities; give a new short proof for the facets of D-n(2); find an explicit family of Erdos-Gallai type facets of D-n (r); and describe a simple lifting procedure that produces a facet of Dn+1 (r) from one of D-n (r). (C) 2002 Elsevier Science Inc. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T13:25:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T13:25:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LINEAR ALGEBRA AND ITS APPLICATIONS, 350(), 147-170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0024-3795</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7233</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>