<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18134</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:11:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Instability investigations of basaltic soil slopes along SH-72, Maharashtra, India</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMAD, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANSARI, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:description>Mahabaleshwar is one of the most attractive and important destinations for tourists in Maharashtra, India, which experiences frequent slope failure due to high-intensity rain and complex geological conditions. The litho unit of the area is the Deccan Trap Basalt, the most famous consecutive basaltic flows during the late Cretaceous to Tertiary periods. The area is very susceptible to weathering, different degrees of alteration, formation of soils and occurrences of bole beds in between two consecutive basaltic flows. Soil formation process in this area is one of the most influencing factors for slope failure; in addition to this, joints, sub-vertical-to-vertical slopes, heavy rainfalls, etc. also play a pivotal role in instability. These transformed soils create instability on the slopes and ultimately converge to slope failures. Five types of soils have been identified during field investigations, petrographic study and X-ray diffraction that indicate change in composition and colour variations. Geomechanical properties viz. bulk density, grain size analysis, Atterberg limit, uniaxial compressive strength, cohesion and angle of internal friction were calculated for five types of soil samples. Effects of these soils on slope stability have been depicted with the help of numerical program Slide 6.0 based on limit equilibrium method.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:11:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:11:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOMATICS NATURAL HAZARDS &amp; RISK, 6(2)115-130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1947-5705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1947-5713</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/19475705.2013.826740</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18134</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>