<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12053</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biodegradation of pyridine by an isolated bacterial consortium/strain and bio-augmentation of strain into activated sludge to enhance pyridine biodegradation</dc:title><dc:creator>LODHA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADANE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATEL, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KILLEDAR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>microbial-metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>derivatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>biokinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>quinoline</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil</dc:subject><dc:subject>bio-augmentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>biokinetic</dc:subject><dc:subject>activated sludge</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-heterocyclic compound</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyridine</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth kinetics</dc:subject><dc:description>Pyridine and pyridine based products are of major concern as environmental pollutants due to their recalcitrant, persistent, toxic and teratogenic nature. In this study, we describe biodegradation of pyridine by an isolated consortium/strain under aerobic condition. Batch experiment results reveal that at lower initial pyridine concentrations (1-20 mg l(-1)), almost complete degradation was observed whereas at higher concentration (30-50 mg l(-1)), the degradation efficiency was dropped significantly. This may be due to inhibitory effect of pyridine at higher concentrations. The value of decay and yield coefficient was also determined. Furthermore, the bio-augmentation of isolated consortium/strain into the activated sludge consortium in different quantity has been also done and the effect of bio-augmentation on degradation has been studied. The results reveal that as the quantity of bio-augmentation increases, the degradation of pyridine increases. At 25% bio-augmentation, complete degradation of 20 mg l(-1) of pyridine can be achieved within 96 h of incubation. Thus, the study concluded that the bio-augmentation of the isolated consortium/strain into the sludge enhances the pyridine degradation efficiency of the biomass.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:22:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:22:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIODEGRADATION, 19(5), 717-723</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0923-9820</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10532-008-9176-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12053</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12053</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>