<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16703</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:03:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic properties and heat capacity of the three-dimensional frustrated S=1/2 antiferromagnet PbCuTe2O6</dc:title><dc:creator>KOTESWARARAO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHUNTIA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHOWAL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAHMAN, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASGUPTA, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAENITZ, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, KH</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOU, FC</dc:creator><dc:subject>GADOLINIUM GALLIUM GARNET</dc:subject><dc:description>We report magnetic susceptibility (chi) and heat capacity (C-p) measurements along with ab initio electronic structure calculations on PbCuTe2O6, a compound made up of a three-dimensional (3D) network of corner-shared triangular units. The presence of antiferromagnetic interactions is inferred from a Curie-Weiss temperature (theta(CW)) of about -22 K from the chi(T) data. The magnetic heat capacity C-m data show a broad maximum at T-max similar or equal to 1.15 K (i.e., T-max/theta(CW) similar or equal to 0.05), which is analogous to the the observed broad maximum in the C-m/T data of a hyper-kagome system, Na4Ir3O8. In addition, C-m data exhibit a weak kink at T* similar or equal to 0.87 K. While the T-max is nearly unchanged, the T* is systematically suppressed in an increasing magnetic field (H) up to 80 kOe. For H &gt;= 80 kOe, the C-m data at low temperatures exhibit a characteristic power-law (T-alpha) behavior with an exponent alpha slightly less than 2. Hopping integrals obtained from the electronic structure calculations show the presence of strongly frustrated 3D spin interactions along with non-negligible unfrustrated couplings. Our results suggest that PbCuTe2O6 is a candidate material for realizing a 3D quantum spin liquid state at high magnetic fields.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:03:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:03:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 90(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-235X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.90.035141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16703</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>