<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16016</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:02:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>A detailed investigation on the impact of variation in growth rate, monolayer coverage and barrier thickness on the optical characteristics of InAs/GaAs bilayer quantum dot heterostructures</dc:title><dc:creator>BASU, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>KABI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SENGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Nanostructures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Epitaxial growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERSUBLEVEL TRANSITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAIN</dc:subject><dc:description>We examined self-organized InAs/GaAs bilayer quantum dot (BQD) structures grown by solid source molecular beam epitaxy. The two layers had an intermediate GaAs barrier/spacer layer (SL) varying between 75 angstrom and 200 angstrom thicknesses. The photoluminescence (PL) characteristics of the InAs/GaAs BQDs were investigated by varying three growth parameters: (i) growth rate (monolayers per second, ML/s) of active dot layer, (ii) deposition amount (ML) of InAs on active dot layer while keeping that on the seed layer constant, and (iii) GaAs SL thickness (angstrom). Analysis of temperature-dependent PL data indicated an optimum SL thickness of similar to 100 angstrom, for which the low-temperature PL emission peak is at similar to 1.3 mu m with a full width at half-maximum of similar to 24.5 meV. BQD optimization was achieved with a slow (similar to 0.03 ML/s) rather than fast (similar to 0.3 ML/s) growth rate, and with a larger (3.2 ML) rather than smaller (2.5 ML) deposition of InAs on the active dot layer. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:02:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:02:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SUPERLATTICES AND MICROSTRUCTURES, 57150-157</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.spmi.2013.02.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16016</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>