<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11313</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simultaneous carbon and nitrogen removal from high strength domestic wastewater in an aerobic RBC biofilm</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, AB</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>rotating biological contactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>thiosphaera-pantotropha</dc:subject><dc:subject>simultaneous nitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrifying biofilm</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic-matter</dc:subject><dc:subject>denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxygen</dc:subject><dc:subject>reductases</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerobic denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>autotrophic nitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>biofilm</dc:subject><dc:subject>heterotrophic nitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>high strength domestic sewage</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrogen removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>thiosphaera pantotropha</dc:subject><dc:description>High strength domestic wastewater discharges after no/partial treatment through sewage treatment plants or septic tank seepage held systems have resulted in a large build-up of groundwater nitrates in Rajasthan, India. The groundwater table is very deep and nitrate concentrations of 500-750 mg/l (113-169) as NO3--N) are commonly found. A novel biofilm ill a 3-stage lab-scale rotating biological contactor (RBC) was developed by the incorporation of a sulphur oxidising bacterium Thiosphaera pantotropha which exhibited high simultaneous removal of carbon and nitrogen in Fully aerobic conditions. T. pantotropha has been shown to be capable of simultaneous heterotrophic nitrification and aerobic denitrification thereby helping the steps of carbon oxidation, nitrification and denitrification to be carried out concurrently. The first stage having T. pantotropha dominated biofilm showed high carbon and NH4+-N removal rates of 8.7-25.9 g COD/m(2) d and 0.81-1.85 g N/m(2) d for the corresponding loadings of 10.0-32.0 g COD/m(2) d and 1.0-3.35 g N/m(2) d. The ratio of carbon removed to nitrogen removed was close to 12.0. The nitrification rate increased from 0.81 to 1.8 g N/m(2) d with the increasing nitrogen loading rates despite a high simultaneous organic loading rate. However, it fell to 1.53 g N/m(2) d at a high load of 3.35 g N/m(2) d and 32 g COD/m(2) d showing a possible inhibition of the process. A simultaneous 44-63% removal of nitrogen was also achieved without any significant NO2--N or NO3--N build-up. The second and third stages. almost devoid of any organic carbon, acted only as autotrophic nitrification units, converting the NH4+ -N from stage 1 to nitrite and nitrate. Such a system would not need a separate carbon oxidation step to increase nitrification rates and no external carbon source for denitrification, The alkalinity compensation during denitrification for that destroyed in nitrification may also result in a high economy. (C) 2001 . .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T12:48:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T12:48:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESEARCH, 35(7), 1714-1722</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0043-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0043-1354(00)00442-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11313</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11313</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>