<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16356</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:26:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental study for selection of electrode material for ZnO-based memristors</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:description>The fabrication and characterisation of 400 nm-thick zinc oxide (ZnO)-based memristor devices with platinum (Pt), chromium (Cr) and gold (Au) metal electrodes are presented. The effect of these electrode materials on the performance of ZnO-based memristors has been experimentally studied. Metal/ZnO contact limits the memristor switching mechanism, dominating during the resistive switching. It is observed that the ZnO-based memristor with the Pt electrode shows a better hysteresis compared to Cr and Au metal electrodes. In the case of the Pt electrode, a current ratio of six times in magnitude is observed between the high resistive state and low resistive state at 1 V, where a maximum current density value of 1.25 A/cm(2) is measured. The capacitance of these devices strongly depends on the charge distributed on the surface. Therefore, the capacitance-voltage (C-V) behaviour can be used to understand the charge distribution, under various bias conditions. The C-V behaviour of the Pt memristor, so as to understand the contact interface, where the maximum capacitance of 2.3 x 10(-7) F/cm(2) is obtained at 0 V, is also explained.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:26:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:26:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ELECTRONICS LETTERS, 50(21)1547-1548</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-5194</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-911X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/el.2014.1491</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16356</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>