<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1670</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>On control plane for service provisioning in light-trail WDM optical ring networks</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDARANA, JANAK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAFNA, PARESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, VISHAL</dc:creator><dc:subject>multicast communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical fibre networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication control</dc:subject><dc:subject>wavelength division multiplexing</dc:subject><dc:description>A light-trail is a generalized lightpath that enables multiple nodes to statistically share an optical communication path (wavelength bus). A light-trail is different from a lightpath on account of its unique node architecture - that enables formation of unidirectional wavelength buses. A node in a light-trail supports signal flow characteristics of drop-and-continue as well as passive addition leading to formation of the bus. Apart from the node architecture, another differentiation between light-trails and lightpaths is in the use of out-of-band control channel (Optical Supervisory Channel - OSC) for dynamic communication. The combined effect of a unique node architecture and out-of-band control channel enables light-trails to provide capability of sub-wavelength grooming, dynamic provisioning and optical multicasting. These features offered by light-trails are critical for next generation emerging applications such as VoIP, Video-on-demand (VoD), Triple-play and Pseudo-Wire Edge-to-Edge Emulation (PWE3). Current OSC based control channel requires engineering enhancement to provision dynamic and bandwidth efficient services over light-trails. We investigate into the control channel hierarchies in light-trail networks to provision these emerging services. Centralized, distributed, static and dynamic control mechanisms are proposed. Light-trail control for provisioning next generation services is considered through theory and simulation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:08:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:59:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:08:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:59:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Communications, Glasgow, UK, 24-28 June 2007, 2442-2449</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0353-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICC.2007.353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1670</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1670</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>