<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15255</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:51:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental measurement of effective thermal conductivity of packed lithium-titanate pebble bed</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYAMOORTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>VINJAMUR, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Pebble bed</dc:subject><dc:subject>Effective thermal conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lithium-titanate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solid-breeder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusion-reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PACKINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLANKET</dc:subject><dc:description>Lithium titanate is a promising solid breeder material for the fusion reactor blanket. Packed lithium titanate pebble bed is considered for the blanket. The thermal energy; that will be produced in the bed during breeding and the radiated heat from the reactor core absorbed must be removed. So, the experimental thermal property data are important for the blanket design. In past, a significant amount of works were conducted to determine the effective thermal conductivity of packed solid breeder pebble bed, in helium atmosphere, but no flow of gas was considered. With increase in gas flow rate, effective thermal conductivity of pebble bed increases. Particle size and void fraction also affect the thermal propel ties of the bed significantly. An experimental facility with external heat source was designed and installed. Experiments were carried out with lithium-titanate pebbles of different sizes at variable gas flow rates and at different bed wall temperature. It was observed that effective thermal conductivity of pebble bed is a function of particle Reynolds number and temperature. From the experimental data two correlations have been developed to estimate the effective thermal conductivity of packed lithium-titanate pebble bed for different particle Reynolds number and at different temperatures. The experimental details and results are discussed in this paper. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:51:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:51:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FUSION ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 87(1)67-76</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fusengdes.2011.09.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15255</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>