<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11494</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermoeconomic optimization of combined cycle power plants</dc:title><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERA, NC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>output</dc:subject><dc:subject>efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>engine</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermoeconomics</dc:subject><dc:subject>combined cycle</dc:subject><dc:subject>irreversible carnot engine</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat exchanger inventory</dc:subject><dc:description>Recognition and acceptance of irreversibility in the design and operation of any power plant is essential due to the constraints in finite resources (such as finite time of operation, finite size of plant, finite capital investment, finite power production, etc.). Thermoeconomic optimization of a combined cycle power plant, comprised of an arbitrary number of internally irreversible Carnot-like heat engines, is studied in this paper considering finite resource constraints. The efficiency of a multistage endoreversible combined cycle power plant corresponding to maximum power production or minimum operating cost is observed to be identical to that of a single endoreversible heat engine under the same operating conditions. An increase in the number of stages reduces power production but increases total annualized cost of the plant. Inventory control of heat exchanger surface areas or their thermal conductances and the directions for heat transfer augmentation to get maximum benefits are also discussed in this work. Flexibility in selecting different working fluids at different operating pressures is identified for optimal design and operation of the combined cycle power plant. (. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T01:29:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T01:29:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY CONVERSION AND MANAGEMENT, 42(3), 359-371</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-8904</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0196-8904(00)00056-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11494</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11494</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>