<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15536</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:23:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimum oxide thickness for dye-sensitized solar cells-effect of porosity and porous size. A numerical approach</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, PH</dc:creator><dc:creator>KORFIATIS, DP</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTAMIANOU, SF</dc:creator><dc:creator>THOMA, KAT</dc:creator><dc:subject>Modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solar cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON-TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>POTENTIAL DISTRIBUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TIO2 FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOCURRENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECOMBINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROGRESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RANGE</dc:subject><dc:description>The microstructure of the metal semiconductor oxide which forms the heart of a dye-sensitized solar cell (DSSC) has proved to play a key role in the enhancement of photoelectric conversion efficiency of the cell. In this work, a numerical simulation of the system TiO2 photo-sensitive dye of a TiO2 DSSC focuses on the effect that the oxide porosity and the size of the pores have on the cell's performance. The steady-state numerical model used is based on the continuity and transport equations for charge species involved in the system, in connection to Poisson's equation. Light absorption coefficient is set dependent on both porosity and the size of pores in TiO2. At a first approximation, electron mobility is considered dependent upon porosity following an iteration procedure dependent also upon local field in the oxide. An effective dielectric constant dependent upon the porosity of TiO2, as well, is used in the model. Electron lifetime in the bulk is set dependent upon electron distribution following the iteration procedure with electron lifetime at the surface taking into consideration surface recombination. Results for different values of TiO2 porosity and pores' size in connection to the oxide thickness are discussed and found in accordance with results reported in the literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:23:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:23:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IONICS, 19(3)571-576</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11581-012-0755-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15536</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>