<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15084</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:18:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Growth of CdS nanocrystallites on graphene oxide Langmuir-Blodgett monolayers</dc:title><dc:creator>NARAYANAM, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOTCHA, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUTAR, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALWAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJOR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>GRAPHITE OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTOR NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ONE-STEP</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISPERSIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:description>Large area GO-Cd composite Langmuir-Blodgett monolayers were transferred onto Si substrate by introducing Cd2+ ions into the subphase. The changes in the behaviour of the Langmuir monolayer isotherm in the presence of Cd2+ ions are attributed to changes in the microstructure and density of the GO sheets on the subphase surface. The uptake of Cd onto the GO monolayers and the effect of subsequent sulphidation were investigated by AFM, FTIR, Raman, XPS and HRTEM techniques. The incorporation of Cd into the GO monolayers causes some overlapping of sheets and extensive formation of wrinkles. Sulphidation of the GO-Cd sheets results in the formation of uniformly distributed CdS nanocrystallites on the entire basal plane of the GO monolayers. The de-bonding of Cd with oxygen functional groups results in a reduction of the wrinkles. The GO sheets function primarily as a platform for the interaction of metal ions with oxygen functionalities and their structure and characteristic features are not affected by either uptake of Cd or formation of CdS.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:18:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:18:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 23(32)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/23/32/325605</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15084</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>