<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15574</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:42:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improved functionalization of electrospun PLLA/gelatin scaffold by alternate soaking method for bone tissue engineering</dc:title><dc:creator>JAISWAL, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KADAM, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SONI, VP</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Biomaterials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biomimetic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrospinning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mineralization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cell proliferation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Complement activation</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALCOHOL) HYDROGEL MATRICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLUTARALDEHYDE CROSS-LINKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>OSTEOGENIC DIFFERENTIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROXYAPATITE DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GELATIN SCAFFOLDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>APATITE FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEM-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MINERALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Biomimetic biomaterials are widely being explored as scaffold for bone regeneration. In this study, we prepared poly-l-lactic acid/hydroxyapatite (PLLA/HA) and poly-L-lactic acid/gelatin/hydroxyapatite (PLLA/Gel/HA) scaffold by electrospinning of poly-L-lactic acid (PLLA) and a blend of poly-l-lactic acid/gelatin (PLLA/Gel) followed by hydroxyapatite (HA) mineralization via alternate soaking in calcium and phosphate (Ca-P) solutions. HA growth on scaffold after each soaking cycle was confirmed by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and X-ray diffraction (XRD). The functional groups (COO and -NH2) of gelatin in the PLLA/Gel scaffold facilitated the surface nucleation of HA as compared to the PLLA scaffold. Leaching study showed HA in PLLA/Gel/HA scaffold acts as binder of gelatin and eliminates use of toxic crosslinking agents. In vitro cell attachment on these scaffolds was assessed by using human osteosarcoma cells (MG-63). Cell proliferation on scaffolds was examined by MTT assay. MTT results clearly indicated that mineralized scaffolds did not inhibit the eventual cell proliferation. Alkaline phosphatase (ALP) activity of MG-63 cells was found to be the highest on PLLA/Gel/HA at day 7 compared to all other scaffolds. Complement activation study revealed minimum terminal complement complex (TCC) concentration for PLLA/Gel and PLLA/Gel/HA (617.33 and 654.13 ng/mL respectively). These results demonstrate the proficiency of PLLA/Gel/HA scaffold in better osteostimulation with lesser immune response, which attributed to synergistic role of gelatin and HA. Thus, by mimicking the natural microenvironment PLLA/Gel/HA scaffolds can become the choice of material in bone tissue engineering. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:42:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:42:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED SURFACE SCIENCE, 268477-488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2012.12.152</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15574</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>