<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1059</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Platinum carbonyl derived catalysts on inorganic and organic supports: a comparative study</dc:title><dc:creator>PAUL, HIMADRI</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASU, SUSMIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, SUMIT</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GOUTAM KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:subject>platinum carbonyl cluster</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogenation</dc:subject><dc:subject>catalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>polystyrene</dc:subject><dc:subject>inorganic oxides</dc:subject><dc:description>Fumed silica, silica gel, silica–alumina and cross-linked (5.5%) polystyrene have been functionalized with quaternary ammonium groups and the Chini cluster [Pt12(CO)24]2− has been anchored onto these functionalized materials by ion pairing. A catalyst has also been prepared by the adsorption of Na2[Pt12(CO)24] on unfunctionalized fumed silica. The catalytic activities of the resultant materials, and that of commercially purchased 5% platinum on alumina have been studied for the hydrogenation of a variety of unsaturated compounds. The substrates studied are: α-acetamidocinnamic acid, cyclohexanone, acetophenone, methyl pyruvate, ethyl acetoacetate, nitrobenzene and benzonitrile. Compared to the polystyrene supported catalyst, the inorganic oxide supported catalysts have higher surface areas and for most of the substrates have notably higher activities. The functionalized fumed silica-based catalyst gives higher conversions than functionalized silica gel and silica–alumina-based catalysts. In the hydrogenation of acetophenone and ethyl acetoacetate, the functionalized fumed silica-based catalyst show superior activity compared to the commercial platinum catalyst, and the catalyst made by conventional adsorption method. In benzonitrile hydrogenation with all the cluster-derived catalysts a hydrazine derivative is selectively formed, but when the commercial platinum catalyst is used benzyl amine is the main product.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-23T05:12:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:05:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-23T05:12:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:05:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Organometallic Chemistry 689(2), 309-316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-328X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jorganchem.2003.10.017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1059</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>