<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14164</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:42:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Auditory event-related potentials show altered hemispheric responses in dyslexia</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAMALAINEN, JA</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEPPANEN, PHT</dc:creator><dc:creator>LYYTINEN, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>FAMILIAL RISK</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEVELOPMENTAL DYSLEXIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>READING-DISABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOKED-POTENTIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHILDREN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASYMMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISCRIMINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATTERNS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INFANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Auditory processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Children</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dyslexia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inter-stimulus interval</dc:subject><dc:subject>Source localization</dc:subject><dc:description>Dyslexia is characterized by deficits in phonological processing abilities. However, it is unclear what the underlying factors for poor phonological abilities or speech sound representations are. One hypothesis suggests that individuals with dyslexia have problems in basic acoustic perception which in turn can also cause problems in speech perception. Here basic auditory processing was assessed by auditory event-related potentials recorded for paired tones presented in an oddball paradigm in 9-year-old children with dyslexia and a familial background of dyslexia, typically reading children at familial risk for dyslexia and control children without risk for dyslexia. The tone pairs elicited a P1-N250 complex with emerging N1-P2 complex. Control children showed larger responses over the left-than-right hemisphere at the P1 and P2 time windows for both short and long within-pair intervals (WPI; 10 and 255 ms) whereas children with dyslexia showed this pattern only for the tone pairs with the long WPI. The response for the pairs with the short WPI showed equal amplitudes over both hemispheres in children with dyslexia. The findings indicate that individuals with dyslexia process basic auditory information differently when the tones are within the temporal window of integration. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ireland Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER IRELAND LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:42:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:42:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NEUROSCIENCE LETTERS,498(2)127-132</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3940</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2011.04.074</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14164</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>