<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14086</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:03:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Local heat transfer distribution on a smooth flat plate impinged by a slot jet</dc:title><dc:creator>NIRMALKUMAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KATTI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>AIR-JET</dc:subject><dc:subject>NOZZLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Impinging jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>Slot jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Local heat transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coefficient of pressure</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental investigation of local heat transfer distribution on a smooth flat plate impinged by a normal slot jet is conducted. Present study concentrates on the influence of jet-to-plate spacing (z/b) and Reynolds number on the fluid flow and heat transfer distribution. A single slot jet with an aspect ratio (l/b) of about 50 is chosen to get the fully developed flow at the nozzle exit. Reynolds number based on slot width is varied from 4200 to 12,000 and jet-to-plate spacing (z/b) is varied from 0.5 to 12. The local heat transfer coefficients are estimated from the thermal images obtained from infrared thermal imaging camera. Measurement for the static wall pressure is carried out for various jet-to-plate spacings at a Reynolds number of 12,000. Normalized value of turbulence and velocity are measured using hot wire anemometer along the streamwise direction (x/b) for jet-to-plate spacings (z/b) of 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 and 12. The entire flow field is divided into three regimes namely stagnation region (laminar boundary layer associated with favorable pressure gradient), transition region (associated with increase in turbulence intensities and heat transfer) and turbulent wall jet region. Semi-empirical correlation for the Nusselt number in the stagnation region is proposed. Heat transfer characteristics in the transition region are explained based on the fluid dynamic behavior from the hot wire measurements. Semi-empirical correlation for the Nusselt number in the wall jet region is presented using the velocity profile obtained from the hot wire measurements. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:03:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:03:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER,54(1-3)727-738</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2010.09.030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14086</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>