<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12572</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Rapid tooling manufacturability evaluation using fuzzy-AHP methodology</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGAHANUMAIAH</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, NP</dc:creator><dc:subject>extent analysis method</dc:subject><dc:subject>part shrinkage</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal parts</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>dfm</dc:subject><dc:subject>rapid tooling</dc:subject><dc:subject>manufacturability evaluation</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuzzy-ahp</dc:subject><dc:subject>injection molding</dc:subject><dc:description>Rapid tooling (RT) processes driven by rapid prototyping (such as stereolithography and selective laser sintering) can reduce mold development lead-time by 50% or more, though there are certain limitations in terms of mold materials, accuracy, and surface finish. This paper presents a systematic approach for manufacturability analysis of molds produced by rapid tooling methods, based on three aspects: mold feature manufacturability, secondary elements compatibility, and cost effectiveness. The geometric features of functional elements of the mold (core, cavity, side core, etc.) are evaluated for manufacturability using fuzzy-analytic hierarchy process (Fuzzy-AHP) methodology. The secondary elements of mold (parting surface, ejectors, cooling lines, etc.) are checked for compatibility with RT mold properties (machinability, wear resistance, and surface evenness). Finally, the cost of RT mold is estimated using a semi-empirical model based on cost drivers and cost modifiers, and compared with that of a conventional mold. The methodology has been demonstrated with an experimental mold. It is useful not only for RT mold process selection, but also for identifying minor modifications to a mold design to improve its manufacturability and economy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T03:51:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T03:51:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION RESEARCH, 45(5), 1161-1181</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7543</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00207540600622431</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12572</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12572</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>