<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14704</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:38:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Context enhancement to reveal a camouflaged target and to assist target localization by fusion of multispectral surveillance videos</dc:title><dc:creator>SHAH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, BCS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>Video fusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multispectral surveillance video</dc:subject><dc:subject>Context enhancement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Camouflaged target discrimination</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGE FUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSFORM</dc:subject><dc:subject>CURVELET</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVELET</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:description>Camouflage is an attempt to conceal a target by making it look similar to the background to make the detection and recognition of the target difficult for the observer (a man or a machine or both). Detecting a camouflaged target in a video, captured in visible band is a big challenge. One can use the infrared (IR) video where the visibility of the same target is much better, but the problem with IR band is that most of the contrast, color, and edge information about the background are lost and thus localizing the target becomes difficult. The objective of this work is to fuse registered videos, captured in visible and IR band such that the target is no longer camouflaged and hence clearly visible to the human monitor. More importantly, this should be done without losing the background details. We have proposed four different video fusion methods. All the proposed methods are intensity invariant so that camouflaged targets are detected independent of the illumination conditions. The performance of these methods has been compared using Wang-Bovik and Petrovic-Xydeas fusion metric along with other information theoretic indices. Experimental video results show that the proposed methods improve the perception and thus facilitates detection and localization of a camouflaged target. Moreover, the fused video has minimum artefacts as indicated by the highest peak signal-to-noise ratio, which is one of the most desired quality of a good fusion method.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER LONDON LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:38:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:38:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SIGNAL IMAGE AND VIDEO PROCESSING, 7(3)537-552</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11760-011-0257-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14704</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>