<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15541</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:25:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>A biochemical correlate of dimorphism in a zygomycete Benjaminiella poitrasii: characterization of purified NAD-dependent glutamate dehydrogenase, a target for antifungal agents</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, CV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATHAN, EK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNEKAR, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TUPE, SG</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAPADNIS, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESHPANDE, MV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Antifungal agent</dc:subject><dc:subject>Benjaminiella poitrasii</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biochemical correlate of dimorphism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Candida albicans</dc:subject><dc:subject>NAD-GDH activity regulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Yarrowia lipolytica</dc:subject><dc:subject>Yeast-hypha reversible transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>MORPHOLOGY-ASSOCIATED EXPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>YEAST-MYCELIUM TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SACCHAROMYCES-CEREVISIAE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN-KINASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-LACTAM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PURIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEUROSPORA</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUNGUS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The fungal organisms, especially pathogens, change their vegetative (Y, unicellular yeast and H, hypha) morphology reversibly for survival and proliferation in the host environment. NAD-dependent glutamate dehydrogenase (NAD-GDH, EC 1.4.1.2) from a non-pathogenic dimorphic zygomycete Benjaminiella poitrasii was previously reported to be an important biochemical correlate of the transition process. The enzyme was purified to homogeneity and characterized. It is a 371 kDa native molecular weight protein made up of four identical subunits. Kinetic studies showed that unlike other NAD-GDHs, it may act as an anabolic enzyme and has more affinity towards 2-oxoglutarate than l-glutamate. Chemical modifications revealed the involvement of single histidine and lysine residues in the catalytic activity of the enzyme. The phosphorylation and dephosphorylation study showed that the NAD-GDH is present in active phosphorylated form in hyphal cells of B. poitrasii. Two of the 1,2,3 triazole linked beta-lactam-bile acid conjugates synthesized in the laboratory (B18, B20) were found to be potent inhibitors of purified NAD-GDH which also significantly affected Y-H transition in B. poitrasii. Furthermore, the compound B20 inhibited germ tube formation during Y-H transition in Candida albicans strains and Yarrowia lipolytica. The possible use of NAD-GDH as a target for antifungal agents is discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:25:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:25:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANTONIE VAN LEEUWENHOEK INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF GENERAL AND MOLECULAR MICROBIOLOGY, 104(1)25-36</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10482-013-9921-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15541</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>