<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1470</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-20T05:12:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>A tracing-based realistic state space selection method for composite power system reliability assessment in the restructured scenario</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENU, VIJAY</dc:creator><dc:subject>reliability analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality assurance</dc:subject><dc:subject>state-space methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>power transmission</dc:subject><dc:subject>potential energy surfaces</dc:subject><dc:description>Electric power industry deregulation has brought about the unbundling of generation, transmission and distribution services and as such, new techniques for reliability assessment are being developed to account for the consequent structural changes in the restructured environment through direct analytical techniques or stochastic simulation. To this end, reliability equivalent techniques have been proposed in recent literature and are continuously being improvised upon, especially for the multi-bilateral contracts market structure. Power flow tracing, a potential tool that has so far only been effectively employed in transmission pricing in the open access environment, is deemed to be equally effective in capturing the effect of structural and economic alterations for the purpose of reliability evaluation in the liberalized regime. This paper elaborates on the idea that when used in tandem with reliability equivalent methods, tracing is bound to improve the accuracy of the indices in vogue. The contribution of individual generators and loads to line flows is obtained using a graph theoretic approach, relying on the proportional sharing principle. This information is then proposed to be used in the transmission line Failure Modes and Effects Analysis (FMEA) phase of the established procedure of reliability network equivalents. Comparisons are drawn to highlight the computational as well as accuracy benefits accrued in doing so.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-12T09:13:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:16:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-12T09:13:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:16:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE Power and Energy Society General Meeting: Conversion and Delivery of Electrical Energy in the 21st Century, Pittsburgh, PA, United states, 20-24 July 2008, 1-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>9781424419067</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/PES.2008.4596380</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1470</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1470</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>