<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10386</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>3D object recognition using Bayesian geometric hashing and pose clustering</dc:title><dc:creator>SEHGAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>geometric hashing</dc:subject><dc:subject>pose clustering</dc:subject><dc:subject>object recognition</dc:subject><dc:description>Geometric hashing (GH) and partial pose clustering are well-known algorithms for pattern recognition. However, the performance of both these algorithms degrades rapidly with an increase in scene clutter and the measurement uncertainty in the detected features. The primary contribution of this paper is the formulation of a framework that unifies the GH and the partial pose clustering paradigms for pattern recognition in cluttered scenes. The proposed scheme has a better discrimination capability as compared to the GA algorithm, thus improving recognition accuracy. The scheme is incorporated in a Bayesian MLE framework to make it robust to the presence of sensor noise. It is able to handle partial occlusions, is robust to measurement uncertainty in the data features and to the presence of spurious scene features (scene clutter). An efficient hash table representation of 3D features extracted from range images is also proposed. Simulations with real and synthetic 2D/3D objects show that the scheme performs better than the GH algorithm in scenes with a large amount of clutter. (C) 2002  on behalf of Pattern Recognition Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-22T09:08:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-22T09:08:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PATTERN RECOGNITION, 36(3), 765-780</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0031-3203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0031-3203(02)00102-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10386</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10386</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>