<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14505</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:20:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurement of yaw, pitch and side-force on a lifting model in a hypersonic shock tunnel</dc:title><dc:creator>TRIVEDI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENEZES, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>Balance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Force</dc:subject><dc:subject>Moment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Accelerometer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hypersonic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shock tunnel</dc:subject><dc:subject>BALANCE SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>INSTRUMENTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BODIES</dc:subject><dc:description>Yawing moment, pitching moment and side-force on a blunt, triangular, lifting model were measured in a shock tunnel using an accelerometer balance at a hypersonic Mach number of 8. The measurements were carried out at different angles of incidence of the model with the freestream. The balance was instrumented with accelerometers to sense the model acceleration in the desired directions, and was equipped with a soft suspension system such that the model had a free flight during the tests in the shock tunnel. Pressure measurements on the surfaces of the model were carried out using high frequency pressure transducers to validate the output of the force balance. The moment and force coefficients obtained through both the measurement techniques have a good agreement reciprocally. The force and moment coefficients for the test model were analytically estimated using Newtonian theory to compare with the measured coefficients. The comparison between theory and experiments has been found quite encouraging. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:20:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:20:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MEASUREMENT, 45(7)1755-1764</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.measurement.2012.04.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14505</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>