<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5231</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>OPTIMIZATION OF DESIGN PARAMETERS OF STIRLING CYCLE MACHINE</dc:title><dc:creator>ATREY, MD</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAPAT, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANKHEDKAR, KG</dc:creator><dc:subject>cryocoolers</dc:subject><dc:subject>stirling cycle cryocoolers</dc:subject><dc:subject>design considerations</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:description>The performance of a Stirling cryocooler is governed by six principal design parameters, namely speed, pressure limits, the temperature of the working fluid in the compression and expansion spaces, the ratio of the compression and expansion space swept volumes, the ratio of total dead volume and expansion space swept volume and the phase angle between the volume variations of the expansion space and compression space. For optimizing the performance of a cryocooler, its cyclic analysis should be considered along with a loss analysis. The present paper attempts to find out the optimum combination of these design parameters for machines PLN-106 and PLN-108s, for which design data are known. The objective functions of optimization can be based on COP maximization or any design constraints such as the total volume or space taken up by the machine, maximum pressure generation, etc. This paper first applies the optimization routine to the Philips machine and identifies the optimization function for which the machines are designed. The routine is then further extended to develop a generalized procedure for designing a cryocooler of any capacity. The procedure is applied to determine the different dimensions of machines with a liquid nitrogen producing capacity of 8 dm3 h-1. The design developed using this procedure is then compared with the actual existing design.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BUTTERWORTH-HEINEMANN LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T08:35:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T08:35:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CRYOGENICS, 33(10), 951-957</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-2275</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0011-2275(93)90223-B</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5231</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>