<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14651</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:11:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of simultaneous reduction and nitrogen doping of graphene oxide Langmuir-Blodgett monolayer sheets by ammonia plasma treatment</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUTAR, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOTCHA, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAM, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALWAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJOR, SS</dc:creator><dc:description>Graphene oxide (GO) monolayer sheets, transferred onto Si by the Langmuir-Blodgett technique, were subjected to ammonia plasma treatment at room temperature with the objective of simultaneous reduction and doping. Scanning electron microscopy and atomic force microscopy studies show that plasma treatment at a relatively low power (similar to 10 W) for up to 15 min does not affect the morphological stability and monolayer character of GO sheets. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy has been used to study de-oxygenation of GO monolayers and the incorporation of nitrogen in graphitic-N, pyrrolic-N and pyridinic-N forms due to the plasma treatment. The corresponding changes in the valence band electronic structure, density of states at the Fermi level and work function have been investigated by ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy. These studies, supported by Raman spectroscopy and electrical conductivity measurements, have shown that a short duration plasma treatment of up to 5 min results in an increase of sp(2)-C content along with a substantial incorporation of the graphitic-N form, leading to the formation of n-type reduced GO. Prolonged plasma treatment for longer durations results in a decrease of electrical conductivity, which is accompanied by a substantial decrease of sp(2)-C and an increase in defects and disorder, primarily attributed to the increase in pyridinic-N content.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:11:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:11:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 24(35)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/24/35/355704</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14651</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>