<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13928</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:07:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Response of wind-excited benchmark building installed with dampers</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, VB</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>SEMIACTIVE FRICTION DAMPERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEISMIC STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISCOUS DAMPER</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODAL CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:description>The response of the benchmark building is investigated under across-wind loads. The governing equations of motion are solved by employing state space theory. Generally, the dampers are connected to successive floors of a building (Type-I arrangement). As the relative velocity and inter-storey drift between the alternate floors would be larger, the performance of dampers is studied by connecting them to alternate stories with two innovative (Type-II and Type-III) arrangements, and the comparison of response is made with that of the conventional (Type-I) arrangement. Optimization of location and number of dampers is also carried out with the help of a controllability index, which is obtained with the help of root-mean-square value of the inter-storey drift. Further, a parametric study of semi-active variable friction dampers and linear viscous dampers by varying gain multiplier and damping ratio, respectively, is carried out. From the numerical study, it is observed that Type-II and Type-III arrangements are found to be quite effective in reducing the response quantities. It is also found that a considerable amount of economy is achieved by optimization of location of dampers. Copyright (C) 2009 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:07:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:07:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STRUCTURAL DESIGN OF TALL AND SPECIAL BUILDINGS,20(4)497-514</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1541-7794</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/tal.523</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13928</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>