<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1227</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of real-world driving cycle: case study of Pune, India</dc:title><dc:creator>KAMBLE, SANGHPRIYA H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, TOM  V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>development system</dc:subject><dc:subject>regulatory compliance</dc:subject><dc:subject>frequency</dc:subject><dc:description>The critical component of all emission models is a driving cycle representing the traffic behaviour. Although Indian driving cycles were developed to test the compliance of Indian vehicles to the relevant emission standards, they neglects higher speed and acceleration and assume all vehicle activities to be similar irrespective of heterogeneity in the traffic mix. Therefore, this study is an attempt to develop an urban driving cycle for estimating vehicular emissions and fuel consumption. The proposed methodology develops the driving cycle using micro-trips extracted from real-world data. The uniqueness of this methodology is that the driving cycle is constructed considering five important parameters of the time–space profile namely, the percentage acceleration, deceleration, idle, cruise, and the average speed. Therefore, this approach is expected to be a better representation of heterogeneous traffic behaviour. The driving cycle for the city of Pune in India is constructed using the proposed methodology and is compared with existing driving cycles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:43:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:43:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment 14(2), 132-140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-9209</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.trd.2008.11.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1227</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>