<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16773</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:38:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fyn kinase regulates type II PtdIns 4-kinases in RBL 2H3 cells</dc:title><dc:creator>BOJJIREDDY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAHMANYAM, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>Fc epsilon RI receptor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate</dc:subject><dc:subject>SH2 domain</dc:subject><dc:subject>beta-Hexosamindase</dc:subject><dc:subject>FC-EPSILON-RI</dc:subject><dc:subject>AFFINITY IGE RECEPTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAT SPLENIC LYMPHOCYTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SRC FAMILY KINASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHATIDYLINOSITOL 4-KINASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAST-CELL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TYROSINE KINASES</dc:subject><dc:subject>KEY COMPONENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>RBL-2H3 CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Type II phosphatidylinositol 4-kinases are implicated in Fc epsilon RI-mediated signaling cascades leading to release of inflammatory molecules. Cross-linking of Fc epsilon RI on RBL 2H3 cells results in protein tyrosine phosphorylation and activation of type II PtdIns 4-kinase activity. Protein tyrosine kinase(s) that phosphorylate type II PtdIns 4-kinase(s) in RBL 2H3 cells remains elusive and is being addressed in this manuscript. Anti-Fyn kinase antibodies co-immunoprecipitated type II PtdIns 4-kinase activity from Fc epsilon RI cross-linked RBL 2H3 cells. In reciprocal assays, His-tagged types II PtdIns 4-kinases were shown to pull down Fyn kinase. Further, anti-Fyn immunoprecipitates were shown to phosphorylate type II PtdIns 4-kinase alpha and beta in in vitro assays. Pull down studies with GST-Fyn-SH2 and GST-Fyn-SH3 domains showed that type II PtdIns 4-kinases associate with Fyn-SH2 domain. Knockdown of Fyn kinase in RBL 2H3 cells abrogated activation of type II PtdIns 4-kinase activity in response to Fc epsilon RI cross-linking and type II PtdIns 4-kinase activity in anti-phosphotyrosine immunoprecipitates. Knockdown of Fyn kinase was also strongly correlated with a reduction in beta-hexosaminidase release in response to Fc epsilon RI cross-linking. These results suggest that type II PtdIns 4-kinases act downstream of Fyn kinase in Fc epsilon RI signaling cascades and are regulated by Fyn kinase.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:38:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:38:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MOLECULAR AND CELLULAR BIOCHEMISTRY, 387(1/2)63-70</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-8177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-4919</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11010-013-1871-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16773</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>