<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5316</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>A comparative assessment of the impact of different occupations on workers' static musculoskeletal fitness</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRA, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>IQBAL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SADHU, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>standing postures</dc:subject><dc:subject>discomfort</dc:subject><dc:subject>load</dc:subject><dc:subject>intervention</dc:subject><dc:subject>workplaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>symptoms</dc:subject><dc:subject>occupations</dc:subject><dc:subject>repetitive movements</dc:subject><dc:subject>static muscular forces</dc:subject><dc:subject>musculoskeletal disorders</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamometry</dc:subject><dc:description>An ergonomic assessment of the involvement of static muscular forces like back strength, grip strength and pinch strength in different occupations was made. A study was conducted on 45 normal adult males (15 subjects per group) which included video display terminal (VDT) operators, industrial workers and safety inspectors. Their maximum back strength, handgrip strength and pinch strength were measured with dynamometers. The observed values of back strength were significantly lower in VDT operators while significantly higher in safety inspectors and moderate in industrial workers. The values of grip strength and pinch strength of all sample groups were more or less similar. The findings clearly indicate that static muscular strength varies significantly in different occupations. Heavy static muscular load might lead to an accumulation of metabolic waste and toxins on the back resulting in lower back strength in VDT operators and industrial workers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CENTRAL INST LABOUR PROTECTION-NATL RESEARCH INST</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T13:40:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T13:40:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND ERGONOMICS, 13(3), 271-278</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1080-3548</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5316</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>