<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4398</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-05T08:34:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nonlinear spin wave magnetization of solution synthesized Ni nanoparticles</dc:title><dc:creator>VITTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>molecular-beams</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>fe</dc:subject><dc:subject>co</dc:subject><dc:description>The magnetic properties of Ni nanoparticles synthesized using a soft chemical method followed by heat treatment in H-2 atmosphere have been studied in detail. The powder consists of pure Ni with no additional phase and the average crystallite size is 30 +/- 5 nm, determined using the modified Scherer relation. The crystallites tend to agglomerate into large particles of sizes 50-100 nm, as observed by transmission electron microscopy. The saturation magnetization is found to be 46.42 emu g(-1) at 5 K, about 80% of the bulk magnetization value. The temperature dependence of saturation magnetization for T &lt; 0.5T(C) is found to deviate from the linear Bloch's T-3/2 law indicating that spin wave interactions needs to be considered to understand the behavior. The spin wave stiffness constant obtained by fitting the saturation magnetization decay to a nonlinear spin wave model is lower by an order of magnitude compared to that of bulk Ni. The coercivity on the other hand decreases from 67 Oe at 5 K to 36 Oe at 300 K with a temperature dependence slower than the T-1/2 behavior predicted for noninteracting superparamagnetic particles. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T10:04:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T10:04:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 101(6), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.2710437</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4398</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4398</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>