<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14438</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T12:45:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of water-repellent organic-inorganic hybrid sol-gel coatings on aluminum using short chain perfluoro polymer emulsion</dc:title><dc:creator>WANKHEDE, RG</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOREY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIRBILIS, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sol-gel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluoro</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrophobicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Organic-inorganic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Corrosion resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORINATED SILICA NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLUTION-IMMERSION PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPER-HYDROPHOBIC SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERHYDROPHOBIC SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORROSION PROTECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITE COATINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>INHIBITION</dc:subject><dc:description>The development of an organic-inorganic sol-gel coating system (thickness similar to 2 mu m) on aluminum is reported. The coating uses glycidoxytrimethoxysilane (GPTMS) and methyltrimethoxysilane (MTMS) as silane precursors, crosslinked with hexamethylmethoxymelamine (HMMM) and followed by hydrophobic modification using a water base short chain per-fluoro emulsion (FE). Such coating resulted in enhanced hydrophobicity with a contact angle of about 120 degrees and sliding angle of 25 degrees for a 20 mu L water droplet. Potentiodynamic polarization and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) measurements showed reduced corrosion upon coated substrates than the bare; correlated with both a higher degree of water repellency and formation of low permeable crosslinked sol-gel network. The structure of the coatings deposited was analyzed using Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) and X-ray photoelectron (XPS) spectroscopy, revealing replacement of hydrophillic surface hydroxyls groups with low energy per-fluoro groups. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:45:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:45:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED SURFACE SCIENCE, 2831051-1059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2013.07.066</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14438</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>