<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18044</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:25:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>A supercapacitor based on longitudinal unzipping of multi-walled carbon nanotubes for high temperature application</dc:title><dc:creator>SIVARAMAN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTPHODE, DD</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAKUR, AP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHASHIDHARA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMUI, AB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>DOUBLE-LAYER CAPACITORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINA TEMPLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIVATED CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:description>Multi-walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) were partially unzipped longitudinally by a chemical method. Unzipped multi-walled carbon nanotubes (UZ-MWCNTs) were characterized by transmission electron microscopic analysis, X-ray diffraction and Raman spectroscopic analyses. UZ-MWCNTs were utilized for electrode preparation and the electrodes were used in the fabrication of a supercapacitor. At room temperature, the UZ-MWCNTs based supercapacitor showed a specific capacitance of similar to 41 F g(-1), while pristine MWCNTs based supercapacitor exhibited 22 F g(-1) at the scan rate of 25 mV s(-1). The increase in specific capacitance was attributed to an increase in effective specific surface area of UZ-MWCNTs due to partial unzipping. UZ-MWCNTs based supercapacitor exhibited an increase in specific capacitance with increase in temperature. It showed a specific capacitance of similar to 74 F g(-1) at 100 degrees C at the scan rate of 25 mV s(-1), while the pristine MWCNTs based supercapacitor did not show any appreciable change in specific capacitance as a function of temperature. UZ-MWCNTs exhibited three-fold increase in specific capacitance as compared to pristine MWCNTs at 100 degrees C. Impedance spectroscopic analysis of the supercapacitors revealed that the UZ-MWCNTs based supercapacitor exhibited higher internal resistance and lower leakage resistance than pristine MWCNTs based supercapacitor. Continuous 'charge-discharge' cycling behaviour indicated that the UZ-MWCNTs based supercapacitor exhibited less stability during initial cycles even though it depicted higher specific capacitance as compared to the pristine MWCNTs based supercapacitor.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:25:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:25:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 5(102)83546-83557</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5ra13136g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18044</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>