<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9182</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Scale and twist effects on the strength of nanostructured yarns and reinforced composites</dc:title><dc:creator>BEYERLEIN, IJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>PORWAL, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHU, YT</dc:creator><dc:creator>HU, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>XU, XF</dc:creator><dc:subject>carbon-nanotube fibers</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibrous composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>statistical-theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>tensile failure</dc:subject><dc:subject>bundles</dc:subject><dc:subject>technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrays</dc:subject><dc:subject>cables</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work we investigate the effects of yarn diameter and gauge length on the statistical strength of yarns spun from carbon nanotubes (CNTs). Tensile tests are conducted on a large sample set of nanostructured CNT yarns. The data show that strength varies substantially and both strength and statistical dispersion in strength decreases as yarn diameter increases. To explain these phenomena and forecast their effects on larger-scale structures, a hierarchical set of Monte Carlo simulation models is developed: the lower-scale model aims to predict the relationship between yarn nanostructure and tensile strength and the higher-scale model aims to relate the strength of CNT yarns to the strength of composites reinforced with unidirectionally aligned CNT yarns. Predictions indicate that, for both structures, the mean and statistical variation in strength will decrease as the surface twist angle, number of CNTs in cross section and gauge length of the yarn increases. The predicted reductions in variability due to yarn nanostructure will be important for determining ways to minimize the detrimental effects of increasing length scale on strength.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T00:19:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T00:19:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 20(48), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-4484</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/20/48/485702</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9182</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9182</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>