<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1543</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>A 2-stage mapping technique for interactive domain discretization</dc:title><dc:creator>DHARAP, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHEVARE, GR</dc:creator><dc:description>The discretization of the physical domain approximates the continuous variable by a set of discrete values defined at a set of points in the domain called the grid points. Grid generation is basically the overall management of this data in discrete form for use in computational methods. This paper is based on the premise that multi-block grids can be effectively used to control the grid density globally and therefore only a set of simple mechanisms are required to control the grid density within a block. Since the grid density and grid properties in general vary from problem to problem, grid generation is required to be highly interactive and computationally inexpensive. In our work this is being achieved by separating the mapping of geometry and grid density control within each block. These ideas have been implemented end shown to meet the demands of interactive grid generation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE PUBL B V</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:33:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:33:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>GRAPHICS, DESIGN AND VISUALIZATION,9,233-240</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-444-81564-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0926-5481</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14755</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1543</dc:identifier><dc:source>IFIP TC5/WG5.2/WG5.10 CSI International Conference on Computer Graphics - ICCG3,BOMBAY, INDIA,FEB 24-26, 1993</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>