<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15248</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:47:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fabrication and characterization of tunable multiferroic Bi0.7Dy0.3FeO3 based on-chip micro-inductor</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALKAR, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Multiferroics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microinductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORE</dc:subject><dc:description>An optical lithographic process is developed to realize Si compatible on-chip micro-inductor using single phase room temperature multiferroic system like Bi0.7Dy0.3FeO3 (BDFO) as a core material. On-chip inductor is characterized for inductance and Q factor in the frequency range of 1 kHz-1 MHz. The properties are studied at different values of current passing through the coil and also bias applied directly across the BDFO core. Tunability goes on increasing with current and reaches as high as similar to 90% at 0.07 A of DC current passing through the coil whereas similar to 30% tunability is obtained at 10 V of DC voltage applied across the core. It indicates that substantial change in permeability occurs even at low fields due to presence of magnetoelectric (ME) coupling in BDFO system. The use of the single layer multiferroic BDFO core simplifies the on-chip fabrication process. In addition it helps to avoid the formation of defects that are normally formed at the interface of hetero-structures. Consequently it makes the process more reliable. The integration of the on-chip multiferroic micro-inductor would be useful in miniaturizing the inductive components in electronic device circuit. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROELECTRONIC ENGINEERING, 10638-42</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mee.2013.02.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15248</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>