<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1421</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>PLD growth of CuAlO2</dc:title><dc:creator>NEUMANN-SPALLART, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAI, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PINTO, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>copper aluminium oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>delafossite</dc:subject><dc:subject>pulsed laser deposition</dc:subject><dc:description>Copper aluminium oxide, CuAlO2 ("CAO") films were deposited by pulsed laser deposition ("PLD") on a variety of substrates. As-deposited films were X-ray amorphous. Films formed at 200 degrees C were insulating, whereas films formed on sapphire at 720 degrees C were conducting. Specific conductivity and light transmittance were optimized for CAO/sapphire. Best values for the conductivity of around 0.3 S/cm for 280 nm thick films on sapphire were obtained for 3.5 J/cm(2)/pulse, substrate to target distance 6.5 cm, 400 mTorr oxygen and 720 degrees C, deposition time 90 min at 10 Hz. Films obtained under these conditions were specular and had a refractive index around 2.1 as derived from reflectivity measurements. Transmission spectra showed an onset around 400 nm and a non-negligible unspecific absorption above. Annealing of as-deposited, X-ray amorphous films on sapphire at 1050 degrees C in air for 5 min led to crystallization in combination with disruption of film continuity (and therefore loss of conductivity) as seen by optical microscopy, where hexagonal platelets could be clearly distinguished. X-ray analysis showed highly preferential orientation (&lt; 003 &gt;, &lt; 006 &gt;, &lt; 009 &gt;, &lt; 0012 &gt;). Post-annealing in situ (15 min-8 h) at 720 degrees C had no effect on film properties. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:53:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:53:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS,515(24)8641-8644</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2007.03.109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14704</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1421</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st International Symposium on Transparent Conducting Oxides,Crete, GREECE,OCT 23-25, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>