<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13991</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:00:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Some Investigations into the Dynamic Mass Transfer at the Slag-Metal Interface Using Sulfur: Concept of Interfacial Velocity</dc:title><dc:creator>MUHMOOD, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEETHARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>SURFACE-TENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIQUID-METALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON</dc:subject><dc:description>In the current work, dynamic studies of mass transfer of sulfur from the gas phase to the metal phase of pure iron through CaO-SiO(2)-Al(2)O(3)-FeO quaternary slag were carried out. X-ray videos were taken that were later processed to identify the oscillation of the metal drop occurring during the mass transfer. It was observed that the metal drop had hybrid oscillations. Each of these oscillations could be identified as composed of a symmetric and an asymmetric element, which was attributed to the changes in the shape of the droplet. The latter (asymmetric part) could be identified by the deviation of the left and right contact angles from the stable configuration. The symmetric oscillations were traced to the surface movement of sulfur at the interface, which created an instantaneous area change at the slag-metal interface. This area change was due to the combined effect of Marangoni flow and interface dilatation. The velocity of sulfur at the interface was calculated from the area change and had a maximum order of magnitude as 10(-4) m/s. It was also observed that the interfacial velocity increased with increase in temperature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:00:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:00:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS B-PROCESS METALLURGY AND MATERIALS PROCESSING SCIENCE,42(3)460-470</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5615</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11663-011-9482-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13991</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>