<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16030</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:09:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Substrate control on formation and maturation of glauconites in the Middle Eocene Harudi Formation, western Kutch, India</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTORAJ, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARASWATI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>Authigenic glauconite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pellets</dc:subject><dc:subject>Infillings</dc:subject><dc:subject>Foraminifera</dc:subject><dc:subject>Maturity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cerium anomaly</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sub-oxic micro-environments</dc:subject><dc:subject>RARE-EARTH-ELEMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTINENTAL-SHELF</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOCHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEDIMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENVIRONMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MINERALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORIGIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSTRAINTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRAMEWORK</dc:subject><dc:description>Formation and maturation of glauconites within the early Middle Eocene Harudi Formation, built up in a lagoon to shelf transition in western Kutch. India is addressed taking recourse to a combined sedimentological, micropalaeontological and mineralogical investigation. The glauconite is authigenic and its occurrence coincides with maximum flooding. The glauconite is more matured within the fecal pellets and is less matured within the intra-particle pores of bioclasts namely, foraminifera, ostracoda, gastropoda and bryozoa. SEM-EDS, XRD and geochemical studies clearly document that the infilling within the intra-particle pores of bioclasts belong to nascent to slightly evolved glauconite (&lt;5 wt% K2O), while the pellet belongs to slightly evolved to evolved glauconite (5-7 wt% K2O). Based on chemical characteristics and SEM investigations the glauconitization process can be best explained by the 'verdissement theory'. The glauconite possibly formed as initial authigenic glauconitic smectite precipitates; while the pellet matured subsequently by addition of K, the process was hindered in case of infillings. The maturation process also involved addition of Si and release of Al, with or without release of Mg. The glauconite maturation was facilitated in case of fecal pellets because of higher porosity, inter-granular nature of pores and availability of necessary elements in semi-confined micro-environments. In contrast, the maturation was aborted at an early stage in case of infillings because of the minute, closed nature of the pores and prevalent alkaline conditions not allowing dissolution of calcitic tests. A low negative cerium anomaly suggests glauconite formation in sub-oxic micro-environments, created by decay of organic matters within the fecal pellets and bioclasts. A clear case of substratum control on glauconitization becomes apparent. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:09:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:09:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MARINE AND PETROLEUM GEOLOGY, 30(1)144-160</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0264-8172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4073</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2011.10.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16030</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>