<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5016</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling of a single resistance capacitance pulse discharge in micro-electro discharge machining</dc:title><dc:creator>DHANIK, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>theoretical-models</dc:subject><dc:subject>material removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>erosion model</dc:subject><dc:subject>edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>breakdown</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquids</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasma</dc:subject><dc:description>Micro-EDM (electro discharge machining) is a derived form of EDM process especially evolved for micro-machining. The use of resistance capacitance pulse generator, an advanced controller for machining in smaller interelectrode gaps and with lower discharge energies than in EDM, makes the material removal characteristics of a single discharge in micro-EDM different from that of the EDM. A comprehensive model predicting the material removal in a single discharge in micro-EDM is conceptualized. The model incorporates various phenomena in the prebreakdown period. It considers plasma as a time-variable source of energy to the cathode and anode to evaluate material removal at the electrodes. The plasma temperature and radius of the crater at the cathode (work-piece) predicted using the model were found to agree well with the experimental data in the literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASME-AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T18:28:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T18:28:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MANUFACTURING SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING-TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASME, 127(4), 759-767</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1087-1357</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/1.2034512</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5016</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>