<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16096</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:43:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Unique Power Electronics and Drives Experimental Bench (PEDEB) to Facilitate Learning and Research</dc:title><dc:creator>ANAND, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>FARSWAN, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Do-it-yourself</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric drives</dc:subject><dc:subject>laboratory course</dc:subject><dc:subject>power conversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>power electronics</dc:subject><dc:subject>reconfigurable</dc:subject><dc:subject>teaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIGITAL-CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EDUCATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MACHINES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COURSES</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimentation is important for learning and research in the field of power electronics and drives. However, a great deal of equipment is required to study the various topologies, controllers, and functionalities. Thus, the cost of establishing good laboratories and research centers is high. To address this problem, the authors have developed a "Power Electronics and Drives Experimental Bench" (PEDEB), whose details are given in this paper. This unique kit includes reconfigurable hardware modules, which can be interconnected to achieve more than 14 different circuit topologies. Moreover, the software (controller) is accessible to users, thereby facilitating quick verification and testing of new ideas. A 2-kVA prototype of the PEDEB was developed and tested for various possible modes of operation. The kit is being used for a first-semester post-graduate laboratory course on "Power Electronics and Drives." This paper includes observations and learning from experiments on dc-dc buck converter, an induction motor drive, and a grid feeding inverter conducted using the PEDEB.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:43:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:43:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON EDUCATION, 55(4)573-579</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TE.2012.2200681</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16096</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>