<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18290</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:47:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Observation of quantum oscillation of work function in ultrathin-metal/semiconductor junctions</dc:title><dc:creator>TAKHAR, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEER, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHACHARIYA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>THIN METAL-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:description>Quantization in energy level due to confinement is generally observed for semiconductors. This property is used for various quantum devices, and it helps to improve the characteristics of conventional devices. Here, the authors have demonstrated the quantum size effects in ultrathin metal (Ni) layers sandwiched between two large band-gap materials. The metal work function is found to oscillate as a function of its thickness. The thermionic emission current bears the signature of the oscillating work function, which has a linear relationship with barrier heights. This methodology allows direct observation of quantum oscillations in metals at room temperature using a Schottky diode and electrical measurements using source-measure-units. The observed phenomena can provide additional mechanism to tune the barrier height of metal/semiconductor junctions, which are used for various electronic devices. (C) 2015 American Vacuum Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A V S AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:47:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:47:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VACUUM SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY A, 33(5)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0734-2101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-8559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1116/1.4928413</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18290</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>