<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3053</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of anti-corrosion behavior of waterborne organosilane-polyester coatings for aa6011 aluminum alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>PATHAK, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>sol-gel</dc:subject><dc:subject>waterborne</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>hmmm</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyester</dc:subject><dc:subject>inorganic hybrid coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>sol-gel</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrosion protection</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>silane</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>316l</dc:subject><dc:description>Thermal-cured, sol-gel derived, waterborne organosilane-polyester coatings (SiE) have been developed using methyltrimethoxysilane, 3-glycidoxytrimethoxysilane and polyester resin for corrosion protection of aluminum AA6011. The structural and morphological features of the coatings were analyzed by Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR) and atomic force microscopy (AFM). Results show that the coatings on aluminum were smooth, continuous and defect-free. Performance of the SiE coatings were investigated and cornpared with pure organosilane coating and polyester coating using potentiodynamic polarization studies. contact angle measurement and pencil hardness test. Results from polarization studies have shown that the SiE coated substrate (4.6-13.1 x 10(-7) A/cm(2)) provided a better corrosion protection than the polyester coated substrate (7.8 x 10(-6) A/cm(2)) due formation of aluminum-oxygen-silicon covalent bond at aluminum-coating interface. Furthermore, SiE coatings provided better hydrophobicity and hardness than the polyester coating. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T20:42:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T20:42:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROGRESS IN ORGANIC COATINGS,65(2)288-294</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-9440</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.porgcoat.2008.12.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13845</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3053</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>