<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8593</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>An extension of modified-operational-due-date priority rule incorporating job waiting times and application to assembly job shop</dc:title><dc:creator>AWATE, PG</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAPH, PV</dc:creator><dc:subject>dispatching rules</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequencing rules</dc:subject><dc:subject>scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>assembly job shops</dc:subject><dc:subject>queueing</dc:subject><dc:subject>waiting times</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic priorities</dc:subject><dc:description>The well-known priority dispatching rule MOD (Modified Operational Due Date) in job shop scheduling considers job urgency through ODD (Operational Due Date) and also incorporates SPT(Shortest Processing Time)-effect in prioritising operationally late jobs; leading to robust behaviour in Mean Tardiness (MT) with respect to tightness/looseness of due dates. In the present paper, we study an extension of the MOD rule using job-waiting-time based discrimination among operationally late jobs to protect long jobs from excessive delays by incorporating an 'acceleration property' into the scheduling rule. Formally, we employ a weighted-SPT dispatching priority index of the form: (Processing time)/(Waiting time)(alpha) for operationally late jobs, while the priority index is ODD for operationally non-late jobs; and the latter class of jobs has a lower priority than the former class. In the context of Assembly Job Shop scheduling, some existing literature includes considerable focus around the concept of 'Staging Delay', i.e., waiting of components or sub-assemblies for their counterparts for assembly. Some existing approaches attempt dynamic anticipation of staging delay problems and re-prioritisation of operations along converging branches. In the present paper, rather than depending on such a centralised and largely backward scheduling approach, we consider a partially decentralised approach, endowing jobs with a priority index yielding an 'acceleration property' based on a 'look-back' in terms of waiting time, rather than 'look-ahead'. For the particular case, in our proposed rule, when alpha is set at zero and when all jobs at a machine are operationally late, our rule agrees with MOD as both exhibit the SPT effect. In simulation tests of our priority scheme for assembly job shops, in comparison with leading heuristics in literature, we found our rule to be particularly effective in: (1) minimising conditional mean tardiness, (2) minimising 99-percentile-point of the tardiness distribution, through proper choice of alpha. We also exploit an interesting duality between the scheduling and queueing control versions of the problem. Based on this, some exact and heuristic analysis is given to guide the choice of alpha, which is also supported by numerical evidence.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T00:35:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T00:35:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SADHANA-ACADEMY PROCEEDINGS IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES, 22(), 83-100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-2499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02744128</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8593</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8593</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>