<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7488</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stress ratio and fatigue damage map study of hot rolled 7020-T6 aluminum alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>THAKUR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALHOTRA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>crack growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress ratio</dc:subject><dc:subject>short cracks</dc:subject><dc:subject>7020</dc:subject><dc:subject>fatigue damage map</dc:subject><dc:description>The fatigue damage map (FDM) is used to establish the domains of different crack growth regimes including microstructural dependent (short cracks), microstructural independent (long) and non-propagating cracks. The FDM is applied over a wide range of applied stresses to determine the extent of each domain from crack instability to crack arrest. Two important boundaries of the FDM are examined in this paper. The crack arrest curve and the transition from short to long crack growth. The accuracy of the model predictions are evaluated through crack arrest experiments and fractographic examination of failure cracks. In this paper, an experimental matrix designed to verify the modelling is presented. The obtained experimental data consist of crack growth rates, S-N curves, crack arrest curves and an extensive fractographic analysis to measure Stage I to Stage II and Stage II to Stage III transitions. Comparisons between the experimental data and the modelling confirmed that the concept of the fatigue damage map can be used to predict the effect of the stress ratio on the fatigue behaviour of the 7020 aluminium alloy. Prediction error in the case of the crack arrest behaviour is also acknowledged. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-28T20:19:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-28T20:19:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING, 454(), 552-557</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2006.11.080</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7488</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>