<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10761</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of shock and mixed nitrophenolic loadings on the performance of UASB reactors</dc:title><dc:creator>KARIM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>sludge</dc:subject><dc:subject>transformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>biotransformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>toxicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of nitrophenolic shock loads on the performance of three bench-scale upflow anaerobic sludge blanket (UASB) reactors was studied using synthetic wastewater. Reactors R1, R2 and R3 were fed with 30mg/L concentration of 2-nitrophenol (2-NP), 4-nitrophenol (4-NP) and 2,4-dinitrophenol (2,4-DNP), respectively, along with methanol (COD = 2000 mg/ L), sodium nitrate (NO3--N=200mg/L), and other nutrients. The reactors were in continuous operation for more than 2 years before the shock loading study was performed. Five nitrophenolic shock loadings of 45, 60, 75, 90 and 120mg/Ld were administrated by increasing the influent nitrophenolic concentration to 45, 60, 75, 90 and 120mg/L, respectively, while keeping hydraulic retention time as 24h. The shocks were given continuously for a period of 4 days before switching back to normal nitrophenolic loading (30mg/Ld). The reactors were allowed to recover to normal performance level before administrating the next nitrophenolic shock load. The study showed that the nitrophenolic shock load of as high as 120mg/Ld did not affect the reactors performance irreversibly. After resuming the normal nitrophenolic loading, it took almost 3-18 days for the reactors to recover from the shock effect. The study was further extended to assess the maximum possible mixed nitrophenolic loading (2NP:4NP:2,4:DNP = 1:1:1) to which 2,4-DNP acclimated granular sludge containing reactor (R3) can be exposed without hampering the reactor (R3) performance irreversibly. The reactor was able to achieve pseudo-steady-state at a mixed nitrophenolic loading of 180 mg/L d with more than 90% removal of all the three nitrophenols, but failed at a mixed nitrophenolic loading of 225 mg/L d. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T04:44:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T04:44:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESEARCH, 40(5), 935-942</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0043-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2005.12.030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10761</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10761</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>