<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17410</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:54:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kant and the simulation hypothesis</dc:title><dc:creator>KAUR, GD</dc:creator><dc:subject>IMAGINED HAND MOVEMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERNAL SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERCEPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSCIOUSNESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHARE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computational imagination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Simulation hypothesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Modal imagination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kant</dc:subject><dc:description>Computational imagination (CI) conceives imagination as an agent's simulated sensorimotor interaction with the environment in the absence of sensory feedback, predicting consequences based on this interaction (Marques and Holland in Neurocomputing 72: 743-759, 2009). Its bedrock is the simulation hypothesis whereby imagination resembles seeing or doing something in reality as both involve similar neural structures in the brain (Hesslow in Trends Cogn Sci 6(6): 242-247, 2002). This paper raises two-forked doubts: (1) neural-level equivalence is escalated to make phenomenological equivalence. Even at an abstract level, many imagined and real actions turn out to be dissimilar. More so, some imagined actions have no corresponding real actions and vice versa, even though neural regions involved in imaginings and real action-perception are the same (Sect. 1). (2) At the implementation level, the hypothesis presents a mutually exclusive view of imagination and perception whereby imagination functions in the absence of the sensory feedback and is action based. Both these issues are contested here: Neither imagination functions in the absence of perception nor all forms of imaginings are action based; it is, rather, about conceiving possibilities which emerge during the perceptual stage itself (Sect. 2). For the modal aspect to arise, it is submitted that an integrative framework is required which Kant can provide for whom imagination is an indispensable part of perception. Kant's views on concept- formation are presented here to illustrate this aspect (Sect. 3). The Paper is concluded with emphasizing the relevance of Kant's views to the problems identified in the two sections.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:54:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:54:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AI &amp; SOCIETY, 30(2)183-192</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0951-5666</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1435-5655</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00146-013-0495-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17410</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>