<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15716</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:53:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of kinetics and thermal decomposition of ammonia borane in presence of silicon nanoparticles</dc:title><dc:creator>GANGAL, AC</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>EDLA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANNA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Ammonia borane</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silicon nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogen storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ball milling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN STORAGE MATERIAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL-ORGANIC FRAMEWORK</dc:subject><dc:subject>N-H COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NH3BH3</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>REACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODELS</dc:subject><dc:description>Ammonia borane (AB, NH3BH3) is a promising material by virtue of its high gravimetic hydrogen storage capacity of 19.6 wt%. Hydrogen release from AB initiates at around 100 degrees C and as such is compatible to meet the present-day requirements of a PEM fuel cell. The thermal decomposition of AB is a complex process involving several reactions. Major issues include poor reaction kinetics, leading to delayed commencement of hydrogen generation i.e. long induction period, and the small amount of hydrogen released at optimal temperature. In the current paper the thermal decomposition of AB is studied at different temperatures. Further the effect of Si nanoparticles on the induction period and kinetics as well as the gas release reaction is studied in detail using different characterization techniques. It was found that the induction period reduced and the amount of gas released increased as a result of Si nanoparticle addition. This was facilitated by a reduction in the activation energy of decomposition and improved kinetics with the addition of silicon nanoparticles. Copyright (C) 2012, Hydrogen Energy Publications, LLC. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYDROGEN ENERGY, 37(8)6741-6748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2012.01.017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15716</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>