<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16366</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:31:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cluster spin glass behavior in geometrically frustrated Zn3V3O8</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTY, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>geometric frustration</dc:subject><dc:subject>cluster spin-glass</dc:subject><dc:subject>memory effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORDERED PHASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUSCEPTIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:description>We report the bulk magnetic properties of a yet unexplored vanadium-based multi-valenced spinel system, Zn3V3O8. A Curie-Weiss fit of our dc magnetic susceptibility chi(T) data in the temperature region of 140-300 K yields a Curie constant C = 0.75 cm(3) K mole(-1) V-1, theta(CW) = -370 K. We have observed a splitting between the zero field cooled (ZFC) and field cooled (FC) susceptibility curves below a temperature T-irr of about 6.3 K. The value of the 'frustration parameter' (vertical bar theta(CW)vertical bar/T-N similar to 100) suggests that the system is strongly frustrated. From the ac susceptibility measurements we find a logarithmic variation of freezing temperature (T-f) with frequency nu attesting to the formation of a spin glass below T-f. However, the value of the characteristic frequency obtained from the Vogel-Fulcher fit suggests that the ground state is closer to a cluster glass rather than a conventional spin glass. We explored further consequences of the spin glass behavior and observed aging phenomena and memory effect (both in ZFC and FC). We found that a positive temperature cycle erases the memory, as predicted by the hierarchical model. From the heat capacity C-P data, a hump-like anomaly was observed in C-P/T at about 3.75 K. Below this temperature the magnetic heat capacity shows a nearly linear dependence with T which is consistent with the formation of a spin glass state below T-f in Zn3V3O8.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:31:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:31:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 26(40)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-648X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/26/40/405601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16366</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>