<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2997</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Selectivities in the 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition of nitrile oxides to dicyclopentadiene and its derivatives</dc:title><dc:creator>NAMBOOTHIRI, INN</dc:creator><dc:creator>RASTOGI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>COJOCARU, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>nitrile oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>1,3-dipolar cycloaddition</dc:subject><dc:subject>dicyclopentadiene</dc:subject><dc:subject>thiele's ester</dc:subject><dc:subject>diels-alder reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron correlation</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzonitrile oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclo-additions</dc:subject><dc:subject>fulminic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>nucleophilic-addition</dc:subject><dc:subject>facial selectivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>carboxylic esters</dc:subject><dc:subject>bicyclic olefins</dc:subject><dc:subject>ab-initio</dc:subject><dc:description>The 1,3-dipolar cycloaddition of nitrile oxides, generated from aldoximes and nitroalkanes, to dicyclopentadiene proceeds with complete chemo- and stereoselectivity. The approach of the dipole takes place exclusively from the exo-face of the bicycloheptane, moiety providing a mixture of regioisomers in approximately 55:45 ratio. On the other hand, nitrile oxide cycloaddition to dimethyldicyclopentadiene dicarboxylate (Thiele's ester), besides exhibiting chemo- and stereoselectivity as in the case of dicyclopentadiene, exhibits complete regioselectivity as well providing a single isomer in good yield. The Influence of remote substituents, including sterically 'sterile' ones, on 19 the regioselectivity has also been investigated using 8-hydroxy and 1-keto derivatives of dicyclopentadiene. These experimental observations have been investigated through gas phase and solvent model MO calculations on the transition state geometries at semiempirical (PM3) and hybrid ab initio-DFT levels of theory. The Computational methods employed in this study were rigorously tested by performing model calculations on well-established experimental observations. (C) 2003 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T19:19:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T19:19:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>TETRAHEDRON,60(7)1453-1462</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-4020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tet.2003.12.026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13826</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2997</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>