<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15829</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:50:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Unusual Binding of a Potential Biomarker with Human Serum Albumin</dc:title><dc:creator>DE, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAUR, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>albumin</dc:subject><dc:subject>biaryls</dc:subject><dc:subject>competition experiments</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>interfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOUBLE-PROTON-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACTANT INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUTOMATED DOCKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BOVINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SITES</dc:subject><dc:description>This study investigates the specific binding of a potential biomarker, [2,2-bipyridyl]-3,3-diol (BP(OH)2), with human serum albumin (HSA). The binding of BP(OH)2 at the two primary drug-binding sites on HSA (Sudlows sitesI and II) is explored by a competitive-binding study and monitored by considering the green-light emission from its diketo tautomer. Warfarin is used as a marker for siteI and dansyl-L-proline (DP) as a competitor for siteII. Steady-state and time-resolved fluorescence measurements affirm that neither of Sudlows sites is the binding locus of BP(OH)2. To gain an idea regarding the probable binding site of BP(OH)2, we perform molecular-docking studies, which reveal a close proximity of the probe to Trp-214 in subdomain IIA of HSA. Confirmation of this contention is achieved by studying the quenching of the fluorescence of Trp-214 in the presence of BP(OH)2. Moreover, static quenching seems to be responsible for the depletion of the fluorescence of Trp-214, as manifested by the invariance of the intrinsic fluorescence lifetime of Trp-214, as a function of the concentration of BP(OH)2. Based on displacement and quenching studies, supported by molecular docking, we propose that BP(OH)2 binds in a cleft that separates subdomains IIIA and IIB, which is in close proximity to Trp-214.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:50:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:50:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMISTRY-AN ASIAN JOURNAL, 8(4)728-735</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/asia.201201060</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15829</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>