<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9824</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-13T16:35:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Attitudes towards work and family roles and their implications for career growth of women: A report from India</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATNAGAR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJADHYAKSHA, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>family roles</dc:subject><dc:subject>indian culture</dc:subject><dc:subject>career development</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper explored attitudes towards work and family roles of professional men and women in India. Ninety-two husband-wife pairs from salaried, upper middle class, dual-career families in India participated in the study. Propositions based on adult development theories of men and women, regarding reward value derived from and commitment made to occupational, parental, marital, and homemaker roles over the life cycle, were tested. Results indicated that there was no change with age, in attitudes towards occupational and homemaker roles. Instead, gender-based differences in attitudes towards these roles were observed. Attitudes towards the marital and parental role varied across the life cycle, although not in keeping with propositions based oil the adult development theories of men and women. There was no reversal in attitudes towards work and family roles of men and women after midlife. Rather, some reversal in attitudes appeared to occur between the marital and parental role, over the life span of both men and women. Results are reviewed within the Indian cultural context and their implications for the career development of women are discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC/PLENUM PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T09:22:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T09:22:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SEX ROLES, 45(7-8), 549-565</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0360-0025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1014814931671</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9824</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9824</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>