<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2593</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>On the hybrid automaton models and control synthesis of a single inductor, double output boost converter</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEKUMAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>sido boost converter</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage regulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid automaton</dc:subject><dc:subject>inner product</dc:subject><dc:subject>continuous current mode</dc:subject><dc:subject>discontinuous current mode</dc:subject><dc:description>In a Single Inductor Double Output (SIDO) boost converter, power is fed to both the outputs through the same inductor and hence the control requirements on output voltages are inter-dependent, causing complexity in modeling and control design of such converters. But, there is some flexibility in disguise due to the increased number of controlled devices and storage elements. This is utilized in this paper, to arrive at different hybrid automaton models for representing the SIDO boost converter. The features of each representation are highlighted. For these models, a safe spherical region around the required set point is identified using the stability requirements for a given set of disturbances. Inside the safe region, hybrid control laws are proposed to regulate the two different outputs at their required levels. Simulation studies are carried out in MATLAB/SIMULINK and the results are presented. The response of the SIDO converter, under various disturbances, is found to be satisfactory under the proposed control scheme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:32:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:32:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IPEMC 2006: CES/IEEE 5TH INTERNATIONAL POWER ELECTRONICS AND MOTION CONTROL CONFERENCE, VOLS 1-3, CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS,281-285</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0448-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15995</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2593</dc:identifier><dc:source>CES/IEEE 5th International Power Electronics and Motion Control Conference,Shanghai, PEOPLES R CHINA,AUG 14-16, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>