<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5208</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>A SELECTIVE ENUMERATION BASED HEURISTIC FOR RULE ALLOCATION</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHANIA, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARDA, NL</dc:creator><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>deductive databases</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed databases</dc:subject><dc:subject>rulebase</dc:subject><dc:subject>dependency graph</dc:subject><dc:subject>clustering</dc:subject><dc:description>A distributed deductive database system consists of many autonomous deductive database systems connected by a computer network to facilitate sharing of both database and rules. The design of a distributed deductive database system differs from the design of conventional nondistributed deductive database systems. The former requires design of distribution of both the database and rulebase, whereas the latter requires design of data distribution. The paper addresses the problem of allocating rules in a distributed deductive database system, where rulebase (a collection of rules) and database are shared across autonomous sites. The problem is relevant and challenging in applications involving large rulebases. We have identified communication cost as the primary consideration in allocation of rules. The optimal allocation of rules over a set of sites is an NP-complete problem. It has prohibitive execution time for large rulebases. In this paper, we propose an efficient heuristic algorithm for non-replicated rule allocation and study its performance vis-a-vis the enumerative algorithm for optimal allocation. A heuristic for replicated allocation of rules is also presented which starts from the non-replicated allocation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BUTTERWORTH-HEINEMANN LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T07:11:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T07:11:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INFORMATION AND SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY, 36(10), 625-636</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0950-5849</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0950-5849(94)90022-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5208</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>