<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-750</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ballistic impact behaviour of thick composites: parametric studies</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOSHI, AV</dc:creator><dc:subject>ballistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy balance</dc:subject><dc:subject>impact strength</dc:subject><dc:description>Ballistic impact behaviour of typical woven fabric E-glass/epoxy thick composites is presented in this paper. Specifically, energy absorbed by different mechanisms, ballistic limit velocity and contact duration are determined. The studies are carried out using the analytical method presented for the prediction of ballistic impact behaviour of thick composites in our earlier work [Naik NK, Doshi AV. Ballistic impact behaviour of thick composites: analytical formulation. AIAA J 2005;43(7):1525–36.]. The analytical method is based on wave theory and energy balance between the projectile and the target. The inputs required for the analytical method are: diameter, mass and velocity of the projectile; thickness and material properties of the target. Analytical predictions are compared with typical experimental results. A good match between analytical predictions and experimental results is observed. Further, effect of incident ballistic impact velocity on contact duration and residual velocity, effect of projectile diameter and mass on ballistic limit velocity and effect of target thickness on ballistic limit velocity and contact duration are studied. It is observed that shear plugging is the major energy absorbing mechanism.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-21T11:38:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:28:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-21T11:38:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:28:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Composite Structures 82(3), 447-464</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compstruct.2007.01.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/750</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/750</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>