<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16781</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:42:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparative studies on co-extraction of uranium(VI) and different mineral acid from aqueous feed solutions using TBP, TOPO and TOA</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Co-extraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>mineral acids and uranium(VI) extraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>TBP</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOPO</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iso-decanol</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bulk liquid membrane</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liquid emulsion membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>3RD PHASE-FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BUTYL PHOSPHATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>URANYL-NITRATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>N-OCTANE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECOVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIXTURES</dc:subject><dc:description>Equilibrium and kinetics of co-extraction of hexavalent uranium and mineral acids from aqueous solutions into a hydrocarbon phase (paraffin) using tri n-butyl phosphate (TBP), tri-n-octyl phosphine oxide (TOPO) and tri-n-octyl amine (TOA) has been studied. Relative rates of extraction of uranium(VI) and mineral acid by different complexing ligands were measured simultaneously using bulk-liquid membrane system. Acid extraction by complexing ligands was found to be significant. Wherever there was a possibility of the formation of the third phase, isodecanol was used as an organic phase modifier. Study revealed that isodecanol promotes acid extraction and substantially reduces distribution coefficient of U(VI) into the hydrocarbon phase. The rate of acid extraction by different ligand was in the order of TOPO &gt; TOA &gt; TBP-isodecanol &gt; TBP, whereas the rate of extraction of uranium(VI) was in the order TOPO &gt; TOA &gt; TBP &gt; TBP-isodecanol. A kinetic model was developed to predict concentration of acid and U(VI) in the feed, organic and the strip phase during extraction. The mass transfer coefficients for acid and metal were determined by fitting the model to the observed concentration-time data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:42:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF RADIOANALYTICAL AND NUCLEAR CHEMISTRY, 300(1)333-343</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0236-5731</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1588-2780</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10967-014-2932-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16781</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>