<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1475</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Advanced Look-ahead Based Approach (ALBA) for distributed simulation of supply chain</dc:title><dc:creator>TAMMINENI, SATISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESWARAN, JAYENDRAN</dc:creator><dc:subject>supply chains</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>discrete event simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributed computer systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>synchronization</dc:subject><dc:description>Distributed simulation is an emerging technique for simulation of supply chains consisting of multiple independent detailed discrete-event models. Time synchronization is one of the critical issues that affect the accuracy of results, network load and execution time. An Advanced Look-ahead Based Approach (ALBA), a hybrid conservative approach for time synchronization, is proposed that allows the models to run as-fast-as-possible to the nearest interaction event. This is achieved using an improved supply chain domain specific look-ahead algorithm that handles multiple types of interactions. The effect of stochasticity of the models on the performance of the look-ahead algorithm is discussed. Also, the performance of ALBA is appraised against two other hybrid time synchronization approaches in literature. Experimental results using a four player distributed supply chain simulation show that ALBA functions better than the other approaches in terms of network communication load and execution time.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-12T09:44:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:17:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-12T09:44:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:17:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Industrial Engineering and Engineering Management, Singapore, 2-4 December 2007, 1838-1842</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1424415292</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/IEEM.2007.4419510</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1475</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1475</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>