<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6287</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tribological study of elastomeric bearings for marine propeller shaft system</dc:title><dc:creator>HIRANI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>journal bearings</dc:subject><dc:subject>lubrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>misalignment</dc:subject><dc:subject>marine shaft bearing</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluid film thickness</dc:subject><dc:subject>coefficient of wear</dc:subject><dc:subject>bearing life</dc:subject><dc:description>Elastomeric compounds, due to their favourable properties like sufficient hardness, toughness and natural resistance to abrasion and corrosion, are commonly used as bearing material for propeller shaft system of Indian Coast Guard Ships. Recently unequal and non-uniform wear of these bearings has resulted in unscheduled lay off of the Coast Guard Ships. To solve this problem of bearing wear, a mixed lubrication analysis of sea-water lubricated journal bearing has been attempted in the present study. A computer code was written to estimate lubricating film thickness for a given set of load and speed condition, and to predict the lubrication regime for the specified surface roughness parameters. To validate the theoretical analysis performed in the present study, the results obtained from the computer simulation have been compared with the established studies on the water lubricated bearing. To understand the uneven wear of marine bearings, actual geometric clearances of new and worn out bearings recorded by the ship maintenance team, and the operational data (load, speed and operating hours), obtained from the log books of ICGS Sangram (AOPV) of Indian Coast Guard, are listed in the present paper. The dynamic viscosity of sea water, surface roughness of propeller shaft and bearings, and particulate contamination has been measured. Finally, the suggestions have been enlisted for proper operation of shaft-bearing system so as to maintain the wear within the permissible limits during ship's operational cycle. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T16:23:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T16:23:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRIBOLOGY INTERNATIONAL, 42(2), 378-390</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-679X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2008.07.014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6287</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>