<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13940</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:13:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Local heat transfer distribution between smooth flat surface and impinging air jet from a circular nozzle at low Reynolds numbers</dc:title><dc:creator>KATTI, VV</dc:creator><dc:creator>YASASWY, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>GAS</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental investigation is performed to study the effect of jet to plate spacing and low Reynolds number on the local heat transfer distribution to normally impinging submerged circular air jet on a smooth and flat surface. A single jet from a straight circular nozzle of length-to-diameter ratio (l/d) of 83 is tested. Reynolds number based on nozzle exit condition is varied between 500 and 8,000 and jet-to-plate spacing between 0.5 and 8 nozzle diameters. The local heat transfer characteristics are obtained using thermal images from infrared thermal imaging technique. It was observed that at lower Reynolds numbers, the effect of jet to plate distances covered during the study on the stagnation point Nusselt numbers is minimal. At all jet to plate distances, the stagnation point Nusselt numbers decrease monotonically with the maximum occurring at a z/d of 0.5 as opposed to the stagnation point Nusselt numbers at high Reynolds numbers which occur around a z/d of 6.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:13:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:13:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER,47(3)237-244</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-7411</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00231-010-0716-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13940</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>