<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17078</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:29:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dual Angle Control for Line-Frequency-Switched Static Synchronous Compensators Under System Faults</dc:title><dc:creator>BABAEI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARKHIDEH, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, MC</dc:creator><dc:creator>FARDANESH, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Angle-control</dc:subject><dc:subject>dual angle control (DAC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>fault operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>line-frequency-switched inverter</dc:subject><dc:subject>STATCOM</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNBALANCED OPERATING-CONDITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INPUT VOLTAGE CONDITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PWM AC/DC CONVERTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTROL SCHEME</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER-GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRID CONDITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMIC-MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>HVDC SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECTIFIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSMISSION</dc:subject><dc:description>Voltage-sourced converter (VSC)-based static synchronous compensators (STATCOMs) are used for voltage regulation in transmission and distribution systems. Unlike PWM-controlled STATCOMs, angle-controlled STATCOMs are switched at line frequency to limit the system losses. In recent years, angle-controlled STATCOMs have been deployed by utilities for the purpose of transmission system voltage regulation, voltage stability improvement, and increasing operational functionality. Despite the superior feature on voltage waveform quality and efficiency, the practical angle-controlled STATCOMs suffer from the overcurrent (and trips) and possible saturation of the interfacing transformers caused by negative sequence current during unbalanced conditions and faults in the utility. This paper specifically proposes a control structure to improve the angle-controlled STATCOMs performance under unbalanced conditions and faults. The main improvement is a substantial decrease in the negative sequence current and dc-link voltage oscillations under power system faults by the proposed control. This eliminates the need to redesign the STACOM power components to operate under fault current and dc-link voltage oscillations. The proposed control structure is designed based on adding appropriate oscillations to the conventional angle-controller output that is the control angle by which the VSC voltage vector leads/lags the line voltage vector. Since this control structure uses two angles for controlling the VSC output voltage, it is called dual angle control (DAC). PSCAD/EMTDC and experimental results verify the validity of the proposed control structure under unbalanced system conditions and faults. The experiments were conducted on a transient network analyzer, a unique hardware-based flexible ac transmission system simulator which was designed to study system faults and transients for a 2 x 100 MVA STATCOM field installation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:29:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:29:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER ELECTRONICS, 29(6)2723-2736</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8993</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1941-0107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPEL.2013.2273799</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17078</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>