<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15835</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:53:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Variation Tolerant Current-Mode Signaling Scheme for On-Chip Interconnects</dc:title><dc:creator>DAVE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Current-mode circuit</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic overdriving</dc:subject><dc:subject>on-chip global interconnects</dc:subject><dc:subject>process variation</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH-SPEED</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMMUNICATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Current-mode signaling (CMS) with dynamic overdriving is one of the most promising scheme for high-speed low-power communication over long on-chip interconnects. However, they are sensitive to parameter variations due to reduced voltage swings on the line. In this paper, we propose a variation tolerant dynamic overdriving CMS scheme. The proposed CMS scheme and a competing CMS scheme (CMS-Fb) are fabricated in 180-nm CMOS technology. Measurement results show that the proposed scheme offers 34% reduction in energy/bit and 42% reduction in energy-delay-product over CMS-Fb scheme for a 10 mm line operating at 0.64 Gbps of data rate. Simulations indicate that the proposed CMS scheme consumes 0.297 pJ/bit for data transfer over the 10 mm line at 2.63 Gb/s. Measurements indicate that the delay of CMS-Fb becomes 2.5 times its nominal value in the presence of intra-die variations whereas the delay of the proposed scheme changes by only 5% for the same amount of intra-die variations. Measurement and simulation results show that both the schemes are robust against inter-die variations. Experiments and simulations also indicate that the proposed CMS scheme is more robust against practical variations in supply and temperature as compared to CMS-Fb scheme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:53:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:53:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON VERY LARGE SCALE INTEGRATION (VLSI) SYSTEMS, 21(2)342-353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TVLSI.2012.2185835</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15835</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>