<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14538</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:12:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structure-property relationship studies in amine functionalized multiwall carbon nanotubes filled polypropylene composite fiber</dc:title><dc:creator>TAMBE, PB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAMATH, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SREEKUMAR, TV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAV, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, KUB</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIU, YD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISPERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORIENTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MORPHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Amine functionalized multiwalled carbon nanotubes (a-MWNT) based polypropylene (PP) composite fibers were prepared in the presence of polypropylene-g-maleic anhydride (PP-g-MA) by melt-mixing followed by melt-spinning with subsequent post-drawing of the as-spun fibers of varying draw ratio (DR). In order to enhance the interfacial interaction, a-MWNT were utilized in combination with PP-g-MA during melt-mixing. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopic analysis revealed the formation of imide bonds between MA functionality of PP-g-MA and amine functional group of a-MWNT. Higher tensile properties of PP/a-MWNT/PP-g-MA composite fibers were registered with varying DR of the as-spun fiber. Orientation factors of a-MWNT and PP chains along the fiber axis were correlated with the higher tensile modulus and tensile strength of PP/a-MWNT/PP-g-MA composite fiber of varying DR. Crystallization studies indicated the role of hetero-nucleating action of a-MWNT in PP/a-MWNT/PP-g-MA composite fiber. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 2012. (C) 2011 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:12:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:12:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE, 52(6)1183-1194</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.22186</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14538</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>