<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-663</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling core–shell nanoparticle formation using three reactive microemulsions</dc:title><dc:creator>VISWANADH, BANDLA</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIKKU, SONIA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHILAR, KC</dc:creator><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthesis (chemical)</dc:subject><dc:subject>reaction kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>microemulsions</dc:subject><dc:description>Core and shell nanoparticle formation in reverse microemulsions has been formulated by taking the post-core method of synthesis, using population balance equations. The formation of core nanoparticle was done by a modified model [B. Viswanadh, Core and Shell Nanoparticle Formation by Using Water in Oil Microemulsions, M.Tech. Thesis, Department of Chemical Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay, 2005] of Kumar et al. [A.R. Kumar, G. Hota, A. Mehra, K.C. Khilar, Modeling of nanoparticles formation by mixing of two reactive microemulsions, AIChE J. 50 (2004) 1556]. Formation of core and shell nanoparticles was followed there after by considering the probabilities of micelles of core nanoparticle formation, which were most significant. The study provides an insight into the effect of the concentration of reactants on the shell coating and shows that there exist nanoparticles which are completely coated, partially coated as well as particles with no coating too, with large fraction of partially coated nanoparticles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T04:38:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:01:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T04:38:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:01:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects 298(3), 149-157</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-7757</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2006.10.046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/663</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/663</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>