<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18247</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:13:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Technique for Simultaneous Visualization and Segmentation of Hyperspectral Data</dc:title><dc:creator>MEKA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHURI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>IMAGE FUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALGORITHMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLASSIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MINIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>REMOVAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hyperspectral visualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>segmentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>TV-norm</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we propose an optimization-based method for simultaneous fusion and unsupervised segmentation of hyperspectral remote sensing images by exploiting redundancy in the data. The hyperspectral data set is visualized as a single image obtained by weighted addition of all spectral points at each pixel location in the data set. The weights are optimized to improve those statistical characteristics of the fused image, which invoke an enhanced response from a human observer. A piecewise-constant smoothness constraint is imposed on the weights instead of the fused image by minimization of its 3-D total-variation norm, thus preventing the fused image from blurring. The optimal recovery of the weight matrix additionally provides useful information in segmenting the hyperspectral data set spatially. We provide ample experimental results to substantiate the usefulness of the proposed method.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:13:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:13:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING, 53(4)1707-1717</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-2892</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-0644</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TGRS.2014.2346653</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18247</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>