<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9958</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of extrusion parameters on structure and properties of 2124 aluminum alloy matrix composites</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, VVB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, BVR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, YR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>cast</dc:subject><dc:subject>2124 aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>dra composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>elastic modulus</dc:subject><dc:subject>extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>extrusion ratio</dc:subject><dc:subject>matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>matrix stringers</dc:subject><dc:subject>necklace structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>powder metallurgy</dc:subject><dc:subject>ram speed</dc:subject><dc:subject>reinforcement</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon carbide</dc:subject><dc:subject>tensile strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>vacuum hot pressing</dc:subject><dc:description>Discontinuously reinforced aluminum matrix composites (DRA) have been attracting attention because of their amenability to undergo deformation processing by conventional metalworking techniques. Extrusion is used in processing of DRA composites for consolidation, redistribution of reinforcements, and shape forming. The important parameters that control the extrusion process are temperature and strain rate, which is a function of several equipment/extrusion parameters. Vacuum hot-pressed (VHP) 2124 Al/30 SiCP composite billets were extruded at different ram speeds (1, 10, 100 mm sec(-1)) and using different extrusion ratios (4: 1, 10: 1, and 20: 1). The extruded samples were studied for their integrity, microstructure, and mechanical properties. The integrity of the extruded composite rod was very good at minimum extrusion speed of 1 mm sec(-1), whereas 100 mm sec(-1) extrusion speed resulted in extensive fir tree cracking. Extrusion of VHP billets, with necklace structure, resulted in elongated alternate stringers of matrix and SiCp in the extrusion direction. Matrix stringer width and aspect ratio were found to vary with extrusion ratio. Because of the microstructural refinement, both the strength and ductility of the metal matrix composites (MMCs) were improved. Microhardness of the matrix stringers was found to be a function (power relation) of their width, irrespective of the location and extrusion ratio.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MARCEL DEKKER INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T09:22:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T09:22:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS AND MANUFACTURING PROCESSES, 16(6), 841-853</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1042-6914</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1081/AMP-100108703</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9958</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9958</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>