<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9266</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>MATHEMATICAL-MODELING OF SINGLE ROLL CONTINUOUS STEEL STRIP CASTER BASED ON FLUID-FLOW AND HEAT-TRANSFER CONSIDERATIONS</dc:title><dc:creator>MALLIK, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHROTRA, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>casting process</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>near-net-shape-casting</dc:subject><dc:subject>continuous casting</dc:subject><dc:subject>steel sheets strips</dc:subject><dc:subject>single roll sheet caster</dc:subject><dc:description>The Single Roll Continuous Strip Casting Process has been quantitatively analysed using a mathematical model based on fluid flow and heat transfer considerations. The process is divided into four distinct zones: (1) liquid metal reservoir, (2) liquid metal pool, (3) solid strip zone, and (4) caster drum. Model equations are formulated using a control volume approach and setting up equations representing balances of mass, momentum and energy for these various zones. These equations, which are coupled by the thermophysical properties and various interfaces, are solved using an iterative finite difference technique. It has been possible to simulate the process and predict the effect of various process parameters on the process performance using the model. The parameters examined include: (1) liquid steel head in the tundish, (2) speed of rotation of the caster drum, (3) superheat of melt in the tundish, (4) gap between the caster drum and the tundish, (5) cooling conditions prevailing at the inner surface of the drum, (6) drum geometry, and (7) drum material. While the speed of rotation of the caster drum and the physical dimensions of the liquid metal pool affect the process strongly, the cooling conditions prevailing at the inner surface of the drum only marginally affect the process as far as the final strip thickness is concerned. These, however, along with the drum material affect the temperature distribution in the drum which may have a direct bearing on the microstructure of the product.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IRON STEEL INST JAPAN KEIDANREN KAIKAN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T06:00:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T06:00:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ISIJ INTERNATIONAL, 33(5), 595-604</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0915-1559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2355/isijinternational.33.595</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9266</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9266</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>