<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8499</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-22T06:33:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Taguchi Based Performance and Reliability Improvement of an Ion Chamber Amplifier for Enhanced Nuclear Reactor Safety</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>gamma-radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>circuits</dc:subject><dc:subject>ion chamber amplifier</dc:subject><dc:subject>nuclear power plant</dc:subject><dc:subject>reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>safety</dc:subject><dc:subject>taguchi method</dc:subject><dc:description>An Ion Chamber Amplifier (ICA) is used as a safety device for neutronic power (flux) measurement in regulation an protection systems of nuclear reactors. Therefore, performance reliability of an ICA is an important issue. Appropriate quality, engineering is essential to achieve a robust design and performance of the ICA circuit. It is observed that the low input bias current operational amplifiers used in the input stage of the ICA circuit are the most critical devices for proper functioning of the ICA. They are very sensitive to the gamma radiation present in their close vicinity. Therefore, the response of the ICA deteriorates with exposure to gamma radiation resulting in a decrease in the overall reliability, unless desired performance is ensured under all conditions. This paper presents a performance enhancement scheme for an ICA operated in the nuclear environment. The Taguchi method, which is a proven technique for reliability enhancement, has been used in this work. It is demonstrated that if a statistical, optimal design approach, like the Taguchi method is used, the cost of high quality and reliability, may be brought down drastically. The complete methodology and statistical calculations involved are presented, as are the experimental and simulation results to arrive at a robust design of the ICA.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T17:35:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T17:35:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON NUCLEAR SCIENCE, 55(4), 2303-2314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TNS.2008.2001124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8499</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>