<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2264</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-21T04:20:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel high power density segmented switched reluctance machine</dc:title><dc:creator>VANDANA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VATTIKUTI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:description>In switched reluctance machine (SRM), the power density can be increased by using full pitched winding instead of concentrated winding. It is reported that full pitched segmented switched reluctance machine (SSRM) can give 40% higher torque than conventional SRM for the same frame size. In this paper, it is shown that SSRM can give approximately double the torque for the same frame size. This is because flux in the magnetic circuit of SSRM is approximately double that in VRSRM. But, in order to operate both machines at the same degree of saturation, the yoke dimensions of SSRM need to be doubled. This leads to increase in weight. In this paper, a novel high power density segmented switched reluctance machine with circular slots (CSSSRM) is proposed. Making the slots circular confines the flux to circular paths, resulting in reduction of active iron weight. Further, geometric parameters affecting the torque of CSSSRM are determined. Optimal ranges of these parameters to get maximum torque are found out using search method. Finally, efficiency and radial forces of CSSSRM are estimated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T08:45:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T08:45:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2008 IEEE INDUSTRY APPLICATIONS SOCIETY ANNUAL MEETING, VOLS 1-5,1174-1180</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2278-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0197-2618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15663</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2264</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE Industry-Applications-Society Annual Meeting,Alberta, CANADA,OCT 05-09, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>