<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13915</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T04:55:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>A SIMPLE U-SHAPED PRINTED ULTRA-WIDEBAND ANTENNA WITH WLAN BAND REJECTION</dc:title><dc:creator>MISHRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>MONOPOLE ANTENNA</dc:subject><dc:subject>UWB</dc:subject><dc:subject>SLOT</dc:subject><dc:subject>planar monopole antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>printed antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>ultra-wideband antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>WLAN band</dc:subject><dc:subject>radiation characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Omnidirectional radiation pattern</dc:subject><dc:description>In this article, a novel printed ultra-wideband (UWB) antenna with band stop characteristics is proposed. The proposed antenna is a simple U-shaped monopole structure where a rectangular strip is placed on both sides at the top of semi annular ring monopole structure. The band rejection characteristic is achieved by introducing a pair of L-shaped slots in the ground plane to prevent interference due to wireless local area network (WLAN) systems operating within ultra-wideband. To achieve the desired UWB response with WLAN band notched characteristics, the dimensions of rectangular strip, L-shaped slot, symmetrical step slot on the both edge of ground plane, a single slot in the center of the ground plane and the gap between the ground plane and the radiating structure are optimized. Frequency rejection characteristics depend on the dimension of L-shaped slot and can be fine controlled using other parameters. The antenna structure is designed, fabricated and tested. The simulation and measurement results show that the return loss = -10 dB from 3.09 to 10.6 GHz with band stop characteristics in 5.11-6.14 GHz frequency band. The radiation characteristics show its suitability for indoor wireless communication. (C) 2011 Wiley Periodicals, Inc. Microwave Opt Technol Lett 53:1645-1649, 2011; View this article online at wileyonlinelibrary.com. DOI 10.1002/mop.26091</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:55:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:55:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROWAVE AND OPTICAL TECHNOLOGY LETTERS,53(7)1645-1649</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0895-2477</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/mop.26091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13915</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>