<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6572</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhanced heat dissipation of V-trough PV modules for better performance</dc:title><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANGANI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUNASHEKAR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANTONY, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>concentrators</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>pv</dc:subject><dc:subject>2 suns</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentrator module</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat dissipation</dc:subject><dc:description>A concentrator photovoltaic (PV) module, in which solar cells are integrated in V-troughs, is designed for better heat dissipation. All channels in the V-trough channels are made using thin single Al metal sheet to achieve better heat dissipation from the cells under concentration. Six PV module strips each containing single row of 6 mono-crystalline Si cells are fabricated and mounted in 6 V-trough channels to get concentrator V-trough PV module of 36 cells with maximum power point under standard test condition (STC) of 44.5 W. The V-trough walls are used for light concentration as well as heat dissipation from the cells which provides 4 times higher heat dissipation area than the case when V-trough walls are not used for cooling. The cell temperature in the V-trough module remains nearly same as that in a flat plate PV module, despite light concentration. The controlled temperature and increased current density in concentrator V-trough cells results in higher V-oc of the module. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T23:53:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T23:53:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLAR ENERGY MATERIALS AND SOLAR CELLS, 92(12), 1634-1638</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-0248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2008.07.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6572</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6572</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>