<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16858</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:20:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>H- ion implantation induced ten-fold increase of photoluminescence efficiency in single layer InAs/GaAs quantum dots</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEKUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>PL efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>InAs/GaAs quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ion implantation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Defect passivation</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTON-IMPLANTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUMINESCENCE EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRRADIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENHANCEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFECTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LASERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DAMAGE</dc:subject><dc:description>We demonstrate a ten-fold increase in photoluminescence (PL) efficiency from 50 keV H- ion-implanted InAs/GaAs quantum dots (QDs) at a temperature of 8 K and/or 145 K. Enhancement occurred without post-annealing treatment. PL efficiency increased with increasing implantation fluence from 6 x 10(12) ions/cm(2) up to an optimum value of 2.4 x 10(13) ions/cm(2), beyond which PL efficiency decreased drastically (up to a fluence of 2.4 x 10(15) ions/cm(2)). Passivation of non-radiative recombination centres (due to direct interaction of H- ions with lattice defects) and de-excitation of photo-generated carriers to QDs through quantum mechanical tunnelling via H- ion-induced defects (e-traps) that are created near the QD-cap layer interface, resulted in PL efficiency enhancement. Shallow e-traps with activation energy similar to 90 meV and 30 meV created near the conduction band of GaAs cap layer for the samples implanted with H- of fluence 6 x 10(12) and 2.4 x 10(13) ions/cm(2) respectively are identified using low temperature PL study. Contribution of de-trapped electrons from the e-traps to the QDs enhanced the PL efficiency at 145 K. Cross-section transmission electron microscopy and X-ray diffraction study revealed that the structural damage created by H- ions at the high fluence level of 2.4 x 10(15) ions/cm(2), caused the degradation in PL efficiency. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:20:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:20:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF LUMINESCENCE, 153109-117</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-2313</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-7883</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jlumin.2014.03.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16858</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>