<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16978</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:22:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis of Cu2NiSnS4 nanoparticles by hot injection method for photovoltaic applications</dc:title><dc:creator>KAMBLE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOKURALA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALLICK, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hot injection</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solar energy materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>CU2ZNSNS4</dc:subject><dc:description>Quaternary chalcopyrite semiconductors are being considered as an attractive class of materials for thin film solar cells. The present study reports the synthesis of quaternary chalcopyrite Cu2NiSnS4 (CNTS) nanoparticles by hot injection method for the first time. The wurtzite structured CNTS nanoparticle formation was confirmed by X-ray diffraction (XRD). The nanoparticles were characterized by transmission electron microscopy (FEG-TEM), scanning electron microscopy (FEG-SEM) and energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS). Light absorption in the visible region was confirmed with the help of UV-vis spectroscopy. Optical band gap as calculated from the absorption spectrum was found to be 1.38 eV. Films prepared from the nanoparticle suspension displayed photoresponse behavior under illumination, suggesting the potential use of CNTS as an active layer in low-cost thin-film solar cells. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:22:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:22:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS LETTERS, 137440-443</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-577X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2014.09.065</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16978</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>