<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11661</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>A dinuclear bis(bipyridine)ruthenium(II) complex, [(bpy)2Ru(II){L2-}Ru-II(bpy)(2)](2+), incorporating an unusual non-innocent bridging ligand containing a p-benzoquinonediimine fragment: synthesis, structure, redox, and UV/VIS/NIR and EPR spectroelectrochemical properties</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAYE, RH</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAUL, RL</dc:creator><dc:creator>GONNADE, RG</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANIK, VG</dc:creator><dc:creator>WARD, MD</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>electron-transfer properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-metal complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>selective aromatic thiolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>r = h</dc:subject><dc:subject>ruthenium complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectroscopic characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemical-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>luminescence properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>quaterpyridine ligand</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of [Ru(bpy)(2)(EtOH)(2)](2+) (bpy = 2,2'-bipyridine) with the symmetrical binucleating phenolatodiimine ligand HOC6H4N=CHC6H4CH=NC6H4OH (H2L1) in ethanol under dinitrogen results in the unexpected formation of the diruthenium complex [(bpy)(2)Ru-II{OC6H4N=C6H3(=NH)O}Ru-II(bpy)(2)](ClO4)(2) 1. In this complex, the bridging ligand (L-sq,L-sq)(2-) contains two inequivalent o-iminophenolate N,O-chelating binding sites, each formally at the semiquinone oxidation level, linked such that there is a p-benzoquinonediimine bridge between the two Ru centres. The crystal structures of H2L1 and of 1 have been determined. Complex 1 is electrochemically active and undergoes two reversible oxidations and two reversible reductions which, on the basis of UV/VIS/NIR and EPR spectroelectrochemical evidence, comparison with related systems and consideration of the redox potentials, we assign as centred on the bridging ligand. The two oxidations (at +0.12 and +0.35 V versus SCE) result in formation of a neutral, fully quinonoidal bridging ligand L-q,L-q; in the 'mixed-valence' mono-oxidised state, a near-IR transition (1570 nm) is ascribed to an intra-ligand charge transfer from the non-oxidised (semiquinone-like) to the oxidised (quinone-like) terminus. The two reductions (at -0.98 and -1.38 V versus SCE) are localised on the central p-benzoquinonediimine unit of the bridging ligand, affording the p-benzosemiquinone radical and then a p-diamide unit. In addition, at more extreme potentials, two oxidations at +1.49 and +1.70 V versus SCE are ascribed to Ru(II)/Ru(III) couples, and the reduction at -1.81 V versus SCE is bpy-based.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T12:27:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T12:27:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE CHEMICAL SOCIETY-DALTON TRANSACTIONS, (6), 1172-1179</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1472-7773</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b107307a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11661</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11661</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>