<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16859</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:21:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Increased photoluminescence of hydrogen-implanted ZnO thin films deposited using a pulsed laser deposition technique</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Zinc oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogen implantation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thermally stimulated current</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC-OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL CHARACTERISTICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION-IMPLANTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DONOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Low-energy (50 key) hydrogen implantation at a dose of 5 x 10(12) ions/cm(2) was performed on pulsed laser-deposited ZnO thin films. The films were subsequently rapid thermal annealed at 750 degrees, 800, 850 degrees and 900 degrees C in ambient oxygen to remove any implantation-related defects. X-ray diffraction study confirmed deposition of highly c-axis-oriented (0 0 2) ZnO films in all of the samples. Hydrogen implantation did not have any effect on the carrier concentrations or Hall mobility of the samples. A low temperature photoluminescence study showed dominant donor-bound exciton peaks around 3.36 eV along with a shoulder at 337 eV corresponding to the free exciton peak for all of the samples. However, the integrated photoluminescence peak intensity revealed an enhanced intensity of the implanted sample ( x 4 times) and annealed samples (up to 100 x) compared to the as-deposited sample. This enhanced luminescence from the hydrogen-implanted samples may be useful in fabricating highly efficient optoelectronic devices. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:21:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:21:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF LUMINESCENCE, 153307-311</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-2313</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-7883</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jlumin.2014.03.052</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16859</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>