<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12205</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Role of the salt phase in GDC and alumina-based composites</dc:title><dc:creator>JAIN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOBADE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GULWADE, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>fuel-cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionic-conduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrolytes</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuel cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>sofcs</dc:subject><dc:subject>o conductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed conductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>gdc</dc:subject><dc:description>In ceria-salt composite systems, the reasons for a two-order enhancement in conductivity relative to that for doped ceria are still unclear. In our attempt to gain further insight in the phenomenon of conduction, we have investigated two different sets of composites: alumina-salt and ceria-salt. Various compositions in the two-phase composite system involving gadolinium-doped ceria (GDC) and alkali carbonates were prepared and characterized. Later, GDC was replaced with alumina, and similar compositions were prepared and characterized to examine the contribution of the GDC phase to the overall conductivity. The conductivity curves, in spite of variations in composition, exhibited a transition at about 500A degrees C, which also corresponds to the melting temperature of the salt phase. From an analysis of the conductivity data, it is observed that at high temperatures, the salt phase plays a significant role in the conduction enhancement. However, at lower temperatures, GDC primarily appears to contribute significantly to the conductivity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T05:20:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T05:20:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IONICS, 16(6), 487-496</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-7047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11581-010-0432-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12205</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>