<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9658</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Numerical investigation of the effects of sluice spillway roof profiles on the hydraulic characteristics</dc:title><dc:creator>BHAJANTRI, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEOLALIKAR, PB</dc:creator><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sluice spillway</dc:subject><dc:subject>roof profile</dc:subject><dc:subject>weakly compressible flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite volume method</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>cavitation</dc:subject><dc:description>There is a need for evolving hydraulically efficient roof profile of bellmouth for high head sluice spillways, as sluice roof is Susceptible to cavitation damage. In this paper, formulation and development of a numerical model for simulating the spillway flow and its application to a sluice spillway are presented. The main focus of the Simulation Study is to apply the developed model to investigate the effects of sluice roof profile geometry on the pressure distribution, the discharge coefficient and the nature of flow regime within the sluice bellmouth. From the analysis of results for eight different roof profiles by varying the entry and exit angles of elliptic bellmouth transition, some important observations have been suggested, which are of practical relevance to hydraulic design engineers. The numerical model results are compared for one profile with physical model study. The simulated results are in close agreement with the measured values. Copyright (C) 2007 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T23:16:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T23:16:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL FOR NUMERICAL METHODS IN FLUIDS, 57(7), 839-859</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0271-2091</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/fld.1648</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9658</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9658</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>