<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15034</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:53:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Theoretical Investigation of Stilbene as Photochromic Spin Coupler</dc:title><dc:creator>PAL, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HANSDA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>ILLAS, F</dc:creator><dc:subject>INTRAMOLECULAR MAGNETIC INTERACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL DIMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITRONYL-NITROXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMINO-NITROXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AB-INITIO</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOMETRY OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MO CALCULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREE-RADICALS</dc:subject><dc:description>Density functional theory (DFT) based calculations are used here to investigate the magnetic behavior, spectroscopic transitions, and possible photomagnetic properties of stilbene derivatives using photochromicity of cis- and trans-forms of the parent molecule. Nitronyl nitroxide (NN), iminonitroxide (IN), tetrathiafulvalene cation (TTF), and verdazyl (VER) are used as monoradical centers at the p, p positions. The B3LYP functional with the usual broken symmetry approach and a sufficiently large basis set is chosen to obtain reliable estimates of the intramolecular exchange coupling constants W. It is found that, with stilbene as a spacer, the coupling of TTF with NN, IN, and VER is always antiferromagnetic with J being generally large and negative. Although J values obtained for cis- and transforms are both negative, the difference in J values is quite large. Spectroscopic transition energies and corresponding oscillator strengths of cis- and trans-stilbene diradicals are estimated by time dependent (TD)-DFT calculations using the same functional Interestingly, the spectral features of the diradicals are similar to those of cis- and trans-stilbene, which suggests that stilbene diradicals would have good photoswitching properties. Finally, we show that, when these diradicals are placed in a matrix, photochromicity would be accompanied by a significant change in paramagnetic susceptibility.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:53:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:53:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 117(8)1773-1783</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp306715y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15034</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>