<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10583</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>BLOOD-VISCOSITY PATTERN IN ABO BLOOD-GROUPS IN HYPERTENSION</dc:title><dc:creator>AJMANI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAISWAL, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>antigens</dc:subject><dc:subject>blood groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>blood viscosity</dc:subject><dc:subject>hypertension</dc:subject><dc:description>Hemorheological and biochemical investigations were performed in 274 patients with hypertension. Whole blood viscosity was measured at 8 different shear rates and was categorized as per individual's blood group. Plasma viscosity, red cell rigidity, platelet aggregation, erythrocyte sedimentation rate, hematocrit, fibrinogen, and serum triglyceride were also studied. We have found that in case of blood group "O" increase in the whole blood viscosity was maximum while in blood group "B" it was minimum. There was no significant difference in the plasma viscosity among different blood group. It shows that red blood cell is one of the major contributing factor for change in whole blood viscosity. This change in the whole blood viscosity among different blood groups could be due to difference in the charge density of different blood groups and/or particular blood group is more susceptible for change in the blood viscosity. When whole blood viscosity, plasma viscosity, red cell rigidity, fibrinogen and triglyceride parameters were compared with normal controls, they were found to be significantly elevated. There was no significant difference in hematocrit and platelet aggregation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T16:58:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T16:58:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CLINICAL HEMORHEOLOGY, 12(4), 579-586</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0271-5198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10583</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10583</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>