<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14551</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:19:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of reliability of fibre Bragg grating fibre optic strain sensors for field-test applications</dc:title><dc:creator>SURRE, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCOTT, RH</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASHEER, PAM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUN, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>GRATTAN, KTV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Fiber optical sensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Strain sensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fiber Bragg grating</dc:subject><dc:subject>BRIDGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONCRETE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEAMS</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, the reliability and thus the suitability of optical fibre strain sensors for surface strain measurement in concrete structures was investigated. Two different configurations of optical strain sensors were used each having different mountings making them suitable for different uses in various structures. Due to the very limited time available to install the sensors and take result, commercially packaged sensors were used. In the tests carried out each sensor was mounted onto a concrete beam which was then subjected to a range of known and calibrated loadings. The performance of the optical strain sensors thus evaluated was compared with the results of conventional techniques. This comparison allows for selecting the best performing combination of sensor/mounting, i.e. long-gauge sensor with mounts bolted to threaded rods glued into the concrete for use in future work in a field test where a limited time window was available for installation, testing and post-test demounting. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:19:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:19:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSORS AND ACTUATORS A-PHYSICAL, 1858-16</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sna.2012.06.026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14551</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>