<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6593</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental evaluation of V-trough (2 suns) PV concentrator system using commercial PV modules</dc:title><dc:creator>SANGANI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:subject>cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>pv</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentrators systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>non-imaging concentrators</dc:subject><dc:subject>low concentration</dc:subject><dc:subject>v-trough</dc:subject><dc:description>V-trough photovoltaic (PV) concentrator systems along with conventional 1-sun PV module is designed and fabricated to assess PV electricity cost ($/W) reduction. V-trough concentrator (2-sun) system is developed for different types of tracking modes: seasonal, one axis north-south and two axes tracking. Three design models based on these tracking modes are used to develop the V-trough for a 2-sun concentration. Commercially available PV modules of different make and types were evaluated for their usability under 2-sun concentration. The V-trough concentrator system with geometric concentration ratio of 2 (2-sun) increases the output power by 44% as compared to PV flat-plate system for passively cooled modules. Design models with lower trough angles gave higher output power because of higher glass transmittivity. PV modules with lower series resistance gave higher gain in output power. The unit cost ($/W) for a V-trough concentrator, based on different design models, is compared with that of a PV flat plate system inclined at latitude angle (Mumbai, phi = 19.12 degrees). (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T01:27:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T01:27:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLAR ENERGY MATERIALS AND SOLAR CELLS, 91(6), 453-459</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-0248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2006.10.012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6593</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6593</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>