<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11596</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of the weld conditions on the forming-limit strains of tailor-welded blanks</dc:title><dc:creator>NARAYANAN, RG</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>formability</dc:subject><dc:subject>welded blank</dc:subject><dc:subject>weld condition</dc:subject><dc:subject>forming-limit curve</dc:subject><dc:description>The main objective of the present work is to study experimentally the influence of just the weld conditions, namely the weld region, weld orientation, and weld location, on the forming-limit strains of steel laser-welded blanks. Transverse and longitudinal weld orientations are considered for this study. The weld location includes both centre and offset weld positions in the transverse weld orientation. To investigate the forming behaviour of tailor-welded blanks, limit dome height (LDH) tests are performed. Forming behaviour is quantified by the forming-limit curve (FLC). The FLCs of welded blanks are compared with that of an unwelded blank. It is found from the analyses that the weld region shows a negligible effect on the FLC when placed at the centre position irrespective of weld orientation. In the case of transverse welded blanks, when placed at offset locations (20 turn and 30 mm. from geometric centre), limit strains are found to decrease when compared with that of the unwelded blank, with the 30 mm offset location showing the minimum FLC. The offset weld locations (20 mm and 30 mm offset) show reduced limit strains when compared with that of the centre weld location depicting the intrinsic effect of the weld location on the FLC. More variation is seen especially in the stretching region of the forming-limit diagram, while less variation is observed in the drawing region. The FLCs of longitudinal- and transverse-welded blanks with a weld at the centre are nearly identical.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERING PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T08:09:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T08:09:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF STRAIN ANALYSIS FOR ENGINEERING DESIGN, 43(4), 217-227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0309-3247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1243/03093247JSA344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11596</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>