<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16815</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:59:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>A new model for bubbling fluidized bed reactors</dc:title><dc:creator>JAIN, MP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYAMOORTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Fluidization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Powder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Compartments</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATALYTIC REACTORS</dc:subject><dc:description>Various mathematical models have been proposed in the past for estimating the conversions of reactant gases in fluidized bed reactors. A new mathematical model is being proposed in this paper that gives relatively better results compared to the prevailing models for bubbling fluidized bed reactors utilizing Geldart B particles. The new model is named as JSR (Jain, Sathiyamoorthy, Rao) model and it is a modified version of bubble assemblage model of Kato and Wen (1969). This paper discusses the development of JSR model and its verification by using data from chemical engineering literature on fluidization and also experimental data from hydrochlorination of silicon in a fluidized bed reactor. The new model is tested for five processes having operating temperatures from 130 degrees C to 450 degrees C, operating velocities from 0.019 m s(-1) to 0.19 m s(-1) and solid particle sizes from 65 to 325 mesh. (C) 2013 The Institution of Chemical Engineers. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST CHEMICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:59:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:59:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING RESEARCH &amp; DESIGN, 92(3)471-480</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8762</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1744-3563</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cherd.2013.09.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16815</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>