<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-589</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>End-to-end QoS over internet</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAPH, GIRISH P</dc:creator><dc:subject>internet</dc:subject><dc:subject>decision making</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality of service</dc:subject><dc:description>The problem of end-to-end quality of service (QoS) over Internet can be split into two parts; The first part is to develop framework for information exchange, signaling, path selection and setup spanning across multiple autonomous systems (ASes). The second part is to find an optimal inter-domain path based on specific QoS requirements and available resources. The traditional QoS mechanisms try to solve the later part under the constraints under existing Internet. We propose a generalized framework that addresses the first and also simplifies the second. This paper discusses modern scenarios that require end-to-end QoS over Internet. It describes the issues involved with QoS mechanisms using existing BGP-based framework then, proposes evolutionary framework to address them. It introduces a new concept of AS Designated QoS Provider Entities (ADEs) to assist each AS in information exchange, decision making, and signaling. ADE architecture makes it independent of underlying network technologies to support mix of diverse QoS technologies or future changes in them. This framework enables network optimization, connection admission control and aggregation. From commercial perspective, it provides business model to achieve collaboration among different network providers to support end-to-end QoS for premium services.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-01-29T12:09:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:19:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-01-29T12:09:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:19:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the First International Symposium on Advanced Networks and Telecommunication Systems, Mumbai, India, 17-18 December 2007, 1-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1859-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ANTS.2007.4620218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/589</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/589</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>