<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6949</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Segmentation and region of interest based image retrieval in low depth of field observations</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJASHEKHARA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHURI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>contrast</dc:subject><dc:subject>em algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>low depth of field</dc:subject><dc:subject>roi</dc:subject><dc:subject>color histogram</dc:subject><dc:subject>precision</dc:subject><dc:subject>recall</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper we address the problem of extracting the focused region and its use in retrieving similar images from a low depth of field image database. We compute the histogram of the local contrast at each pixel and model it as a mixture of two exponential distributions - one for the focused and the other for the defocused region. Unlike the mixture of Gaussian distributions, a mixture of exponential distributions overlaps with same monotonicity over the entire range in [0, infinity) and it is difficult to separate into components. We estimate the parameters of these distributions using the EM algorithm. This is followed by a hypothesis testing which segments the focused region in the low depth of field image. A content-based retrieval scheme is now confined to the detected region for a proper retrieval. Experimental results for both segmentation and image retrieval using a database consisting of 4986 images are presented to show the efficacy of the suggested scheme. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T15:44:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T15:44:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IMAGE AND VISION COMPUTING, 25(11), 1709-1724</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0262-8856</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.imavis.2006.12.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6949</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6949</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>