<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1301</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>MIRROR: a state-conscious concurrency control protocol for replicated real-time databases</dc:title><dc:creator>XIONG, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARITSA, JR</dc:creator><dc:creator>STANKOVIC, JA</dc:creator><dc:subject>priority inheritance</dc:subject><dc:subject>synchronization</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>concurrency control</dc:subject><dc:subject>data replication</dc:subject><dc:subject>real-time transaction processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-phase commit</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-phase locking (2pl)</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimistic concurrency control (occ)</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimistic two-phase locking (o2pl)</dc:subject><dc:description>Data replication can help database systems meet the stringent temporal constraints of current real-time applications, especially Web-based directory and electronic commerce services. A prerequisite for realizing the benefits of replication, however, is the development of high-performance concurrency control mechanisms. In this paper, we present managing isolation in replicated real-time object repositories (MIRROR), a concurrency control protocol specifically designed for firm-deadline applications operating on replicated real-time databases. MIRROR augments the classical O2PL concurrency control protocol with a novel state-based real-time conflict resolution mechanism. In this scheme, the choice of conflict resolution method is a dynamic function of the states of the distributed transactions involved in the conflict. A feature of the design is that acquiring the state knowledge does not require inter-site communication or synchronization, nor does it require modifications to the two-phase commit protocol. Using a detailed simulation model, we compare MIRROR's performance against the real-time versions of a representative set of classical replica concurrency control protocols for a range of transaction workloads and system configurations. Our performance studies show that (a) the relative performance characteristics of these protocols in the real-time environment can be significantly different from their performance in a traditional (non-real-time) database system, (b) MIRROR provides the best performance in both fully and partially replicated environments for real-time applications with low to moderate update frequencies, and (c) MIRROR's simple to implement conflict resolution mechanism works almost as well as more sophisticated strategies. (C) 2002 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T19:38:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T19:38:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INFORMATION SYSTEMS,27(4)277-297</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-4379</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0306-4379(01)00053-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1301</dc:identifier><dc:source>5th IEEE Real-Time Technology and Application Symposium (RTAS 99),VANCOUVER, CANADA,JUN 02-04, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>