<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14396</identifier><datestamp>2012-09-12T11:31:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Storage allocation and release rules for multi-reservoir system</dc:title><dc:creator>Devamane, M.G.</dc:creator><dc:creator>Jothiprakash, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>Mohan, S.</dc:creator><dc:subject>Multi-pur pose Multi-reser voir System</dc:subject><dc:subject>Storage allocation and release rules</dc:subject><dc:subject>Non-linear programming Model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Regression Models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Krishna River Basin</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study an attempt is made to derive storage allocation release rules for multi-pur pose multi-r eservoir system by using the results obta ined from a non-linear programming model. From the optimiza tion results, the r elea se pattern was observed from each reservoir corresponding to their storage and inflow in each month. These optimal releases and storages were included in the derivation of release rules. The storage allocation rules and release rules are derived by regressing the storages and releases, and monthly regression equations are fitted for each reservoir. It is found that the over-flow or spill is not useful in the derivation of release rules. The derived rule curves are tested with a detailed simulation model, and the performances of these rules for five years are compared with the direct results of detailed optimization model. The comparison indicate that the simple regression equation developed in the present study could be useful in updating reservoir operation plan even for large and complex systems while being found to be simple and easy for practical implementation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Indian Association of Hydrologists</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-09-12T10:59:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-09-12T10:59:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Hydrology Journal, 32(2&amp;3) 208-220</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-569X;0975-6914</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14396</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>