<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17187</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:25:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Compositional influence on the electrical performance of zinc indium tin oxide transparent thin-film transistors</dc:title><dc:creator>MARSAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CARRERAS, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUIGDOLLERS, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>VOZ, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>GALINDO, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALCUBILLA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERTOMEU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANTONY, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Zinc-indium-tin-oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thin-film transistor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Density-of-states</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETRON COSPUTTERING SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNO</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, zinc indium tin oxide layers with different compositions are used as the active layer of thin film transistors. This multicomponent transparent conductive oxide is gaining great interest due to its reduced content of the scarce indium element. Experimental data indicate that the incorporation of zinc promotes the creation of oxygen vacancies, which results in a higher free carrier density. In thin-film transistors this effect leads to a higher off current and threshold voltage values. The field-effect mobility is also strongly degraded, probably due to coulomb scattering by ionized defects. A post deposition annealing in air reduces the density of oxygen vacancies and improves the field-effect mobility by orders of magnitude. Finally, the electrical characteristics of the fabricated thin-film transistors have been analyzed to estimate the density of states in the gap of the active layers. These measurements reveal a clear peak located at 0.3 eV from the conduction band edge that could be attributed to oxygen vacancies. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:25:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:25:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS, 555107-111</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2013.08.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17187</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>