<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-440</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>A simple maximum power point tracker for grid connected variable speed wind energy conversion system with reduced switch count power converters</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJU, AB</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>energy conversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>permanent magnets</dc:subject><dc:subject>velocity measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>wind power</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a simple control strategy for an optimal extraction of output power from grid connected variable speed wind energy conversion system (VSWECS) with reduced switch count power converters is presented. In order to improve the overall efficiency and to reduce the cost, B-4 PWM converters are used. The system consists of a variable speed wind turbine coupled to a permanent magnet synchronous generator (PMSG) through a gear box, two PWM B4-power converters. Output power from PMSG is first converted into DC and then it is fed to the grid. Both the power conversions are performed at unity power factor and the DC link voltage is maintained constant. The MPPT extracts optimum power from the wind turbine from cut-in to rated wind velocity by sensing only the turbine output power. The complete system has been simulated for various wind velocities. The control algorithm is implemented on TMS320F243 DSP and the simulated results are validated by experimental results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-22T05:42:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T18:43:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-22T05:42:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T18:43:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE 34th Annual Power Electronics Specialist Conference (V 2), Acapulco, Mexico,15-19 June 2003, 748-753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/440</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/440</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>