<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16392</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:44:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis, X-ray structure, spectral and electrochemical properties of a beta-meso covalently linked BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex</dc:title><dc:creator>MADHU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>EFFICIENT ENERGY-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>BODIPY DYES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOPHYSICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL COORDINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYADS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLET</dc:subject><dc:subject>RUTHENIUM(II)</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLIGOMERS</dc:subject><dc:description>We synthesized the BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex in decent yield by reacting beta-dipyrromethanyl substituted BODIPY with [{(eta 6-C10H14)RuCl(mu-Cl)}(2)] under simple reaction conditions. The BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex was characterized by 1D, 2D, C-13, B-11, F-19 NMR, HR-MS, UV-vis, fluorescence and electrochemical techniques. The BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex was further characterized by X-ray structure analysis, which showed that the Ru(II)-dipyrrin complex is in perpendicular orientation to the BODIPY plane in the BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex. The ruthenium metal ion in the BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex is bonded to dipyrrin nitrogens, one chloro group and arene ring (arene = C10H14) in an eta(6) manner resulting in a hexa coordination geometry around the Ru(II) ion. The absorption and steady-state fluorescence spectra of the BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex showed a broad and hypsochromically shifted absorption and emission bands compared to that of beta-dipyrromethanyl substituted BODIPY. The electrochemical studies indicated that the BODIPYRu(II) dipyrrin complex was easy to reduce compared to beta-dipyrromethanyl substituted BODIPY supporting the electron deficient nature of the BODIPY-Ru(II) dipyrrin complex.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:44:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:44:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NEW JOURNAL OF CHEMISTRY, 38(11)5551-5558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1144-0546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1369-9261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4nj01114g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16392</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>