<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15274</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T17:00:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Anomalous magnetoresistance and magnetocaloric properties of NdRu2Ge2</dc:title><dc:creator>MAJI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>POSITIVE GIANT MAGNETORESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERMETALLIC COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RARE-EARTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>RMN2GE2 COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERLATTICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METALS</dc:subject><dc:description>It is found that the polycrystalline NdRu2Ge2 undergoes two successive magnetic transitions at T-t = 10K and T-N = 19 K. Evidence of metamagnetic transition is detected in the magnetization isotherm data in the antiferromagnetic regime. Temperature dependence of magnetoresistance (MR) shows that the relative magnitudes of MR at T-N and T-t change considerably as the field is increased from 10 kOe to 30 kOe. Moreover, the MR is found to be positive below 9K for 30 kOe field although the material is ferromagnetic at these temperatures. The highest value of negative MR near T-N is about 42% in a field of 30 kOe, while the positive MR is about 35% at 3K in a field of 50 kOe. Like MR, the magnetocaloric effect (MCE) at T-N and T-t also shows anomalous behavior. The relative magnitudes of MCE at these temperatures are found to change with increase in field. It appears that the high field (&gt; 10 kOe) magnetic state below T-N is complex, giving rise to some antiferromagnetic-like fluctuations, affecting the MR and MCE behavior. (C) 2013 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4791674]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:00:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:00:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 102(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4791674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15274</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>