<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1567</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrochemical treatment of pentachlorophenol in water and pulp bleaching effluent</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, UPENDRA D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, SUMATHI</dc:creator><dc:subject>bleaching</dc:subject><dc:subject>coagulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>effluents</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrochemistry</dc:subject><dc:description>Adsorbable organic halides (AOX) compounds produced during bleaching of pulp are recalcitrant and known to have eco-toxic effect. We have studied the removal of pentachlorophenol (PCP) as a model AOX compound in water as well as in pulp bleaching effluent of a bamboo based mill by electrochemical treatment in batch mode. It was found that 10 mg L−1 of PCP in water was removed almost completely in &lt;10 min at a current density of 6 mA cm−2 in the presence of 1000 mg L−1 NaCl serving as an electrolyte and source of chloride ions. The initial rate of PCP removal was found to decrease at alkaline pH (9.3) as compared to that at acidic pH (5.5). PCP removal in neutralized raw pulp bleach effluent (containing not, vert, similar1830 mg L−1 of chloride) was very slow and incomplete even after 2 h of electrochemical treatment at a current density of 15 mA cm−2. Various pretreatments of raw bleach effluent such as, alkaline sulfide using sodium sulfide, alkaline reduction using ferrous sulfate and coagulation using potash alum were evaluated. Electrochemical treatment of potash alum pretreated effluent (spiked with PCP) could achieve &gt;90% removal of initial colour, COD and PCP in &lt;1 h. The treatment scheme presented here may be a promising technology for removal of AOX, COD and colour from pulp bleaching effluent. The estimated cost of combined treatment (potash alum coagulation + electrochemical) is US$ 0.7–0.9 per cubic meter of the raw pulp bleach effluent.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-22T07:10:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:04:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-22T07:10:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:04:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Separation and Purification Technology 61(2), 115-122</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1383-5866</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.seppur.2007.10.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1567</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1567</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>