<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12569</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Practical methods of computer-aided flat pattern development for sheet metal components</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, KSRK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SELVARAJ, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>parts</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper provides step-by-step illustrations of the practical methods of computer-aided flat pattern development (CAFPAD) for bend formable sheet metal component (SMC) manufacture. Based on these methods, software systems are exclusively designed and developed for fully automated loft generation. The shape and complexity of the SMC geometry influence the choice among these methods comprising of contour augmentation, unfold, cross-section development as well as normal cross-section development techniques. Computer-integrated manufacturing activity for production of over 1000 aircraft SMCs that followed is utilized for constant improvization through continuous testing and validation. Efficient exploitation of special features such as symmetry and multiple bends have become an integral part of the methods included herein, which paved way for the creation of systems extending their scope beyond bend-formable SMCs. An assessment and the suitability of these practical methods vis-a-vis present-day SMC CAD/CAM solutions is also included.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T03:37:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T03:37:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION RESEARCH, 42(15), 3011-3039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7543</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00207540410001691893</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12569</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12569</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>