<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9554</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermotropic liquid-crystalline polyesters containing biphenyl mesogens in the main chain: The effect of connectivity</dc:title><dc:creator>RANGANATHAN, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMESH, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>para,para'-bibenzoic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesophase properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic polyesters</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexible spacers</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>4,4'-dihydroxybiphenyl</dc:subject><dc:subject>homopolyesters</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquid-crystalline polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>biphenyl mesogens</dc:subject><dc:subject>ab approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>odd-even effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>effect of connectivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyesters</dc:subject><dc:subject>structure-property relations</dc:subject><dc:description>A homologous series of main-chain thermotropic liquid-crystalline polyesters containing-rigid biphenyl mesogen and flexible methylene spacers were synthesized with the AB-type self-polycondensation approach. The polyesters were characterized with H-1 NMR, gel permeation chromatography, thermogravimetric analysis, differential scanning calorimetry, polarized light optical microscopy, and X-ray diffraction. These polyesters, containing trimethylene spacers on the acid side and various spacers on the alcohol side of the biphenyl mesogen, showed an odd- even effect in the transition temperatures and mesophase type. The even members showed higher transition temperatures than the odd ones. A normal smectic mesophase was observed for the even members, whereas the odd-membered counterparts exhibited a tilted smectic mesophase. To study the effect of connectivity, the mesophase characteristics of these polyesters were compared with those of the isomeric AB-type polyesters without any methylene spacer on the acid side of the biphenyl moiety. The mesophase characteristics were insensitive to whether the mesogen was connected to a carboxyl unit or a methylene unit. (C) 2004 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T16:27:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T16:27:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF POLYMER SCIENCE PART A-POLYMER CHEMISTRY, 42(11), 2734-2746</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0887-624X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pola.20109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9554</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>