<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16399</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:48:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of wall conduction and rarefaction on shock propagation in a micro-channel</dc:title><dc:creator>WATVISAVE, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANDARKAR, UV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANIK, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Micro shock channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Direct Simulation Monte Carlo</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wall accommodation</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE PROPAGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS-FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPUTATIONS</dc:subject><dc:description>A Direct Simulation Monte Carlo code is coupled with a continuum unsteady conduction finite volume code to study the effects of wall conduction on shock propagation in a micro-channel. In addition, the effects of rarefaction and wall accommodation are also investigated. Wall accommodation is seen to influence the shock attenuation more significantly than wall conduction. The results indicate that both the shock front Mach number and shock strength are comparatively higher in case of adiabatic wall condition as there is no loss of energy from the shocked region. At higher rarefaction, the effect of wall accommodation as well as that of wall conduction are seen to become more noticeable. The simulation results show that it is not necessary to exactly model the wall conduction heat transfer for studying shock attenuation, and the two limiting situations of isothermal and adiabatic approximations are satisfactory as the thermal wall boundary conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:48:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:48:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SHOCK WAVES, 24(3)295-306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0938-1287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1432-2153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00193-013-0477-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16399</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>