<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7566</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>ALL-TRANS-N-RETINYLIDENETRYPTAMINE SCHIFF-BASE IN SURFACTANT SOLUBILIZED WATER POOLS IN HEPTANE - A FLUORESCENCE STUDY</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJUMDAR, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>neutron-diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>reverse micelles</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacteriorhodopsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>chromophore</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>aot</dc:subject><dc:subject>substitutions</dc:subject><dc:subject>rhodopsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequence</dc:subject><dc:subject>location</dc:subject><dc:subject>retinal schiff base</dc:subject><dc:subject>reverse micelle</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacteriorhodopsin</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescence</dc:subject><dc:description>All-trans-N-retinylidenetryptamine Schiff base was incorporated into aerosol-OT (AOT, sodium bis(2-ethylhexyl) sulphosuccinate)/heptane reverse micelles. This micellar system was used as a model to study the retinal-tryptophan interactions in retinal proteins. The retinylidene Schiff base remains stable in the presence of reverse micelle-solubilized water pools. Partition coefficient and microviscosity measurements show that the Schiff base is located in the micellar interphase. The results are discussed in terms of the interaction between the retinylidene chromophore and the active site environment of rhodopsin and bacteriorhodopsin. In the present model, the quencher and emitting units are covalently attached, and are separated by two carbon spacer units. The fluorescence emission data obtained for the micelle-intercalated Schiff base chromophore are compared with the fluorescence of the native protein and intermediates in the photochemical cycle of bacteriorhodopsin. A comparison of the data obtained for tryptamine and the Schiff base with the results available for bacteriorhodopsin and bacterioopsin reveals that there is a large degree of quenching on intercalation of the retinylidene chromophore in the vicinity of the fluorophore. Evidence provided by this model suggests that energy transfer to retinal can occur from tryptophan residues located in the retinal pocket in the native protein. Thus the retinylidene unit can act as a quencher of the energy of tryptophan, the nature and extent of which may depend on the conformation and relative orientation of the protein-bound fluorophore.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T03:22:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T03:22:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHOTOCHEMISTRY AND PHOTOBIOLOGY B-BIOLOGY, 30(40604), 105-113</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1011-1344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/1011-1344(95)07136-P</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7566</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7566</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>