<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18336</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:10:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic analyses and field observations on piles in Kolkata city</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>LATERALLY LOADED PILES</dc:subject><dc:subject>P-Y CURVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AXIAL LOAD</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIQUEFYING SOIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROUP RESPONSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FOUNDATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAND</dc:subject><dc:subject>EARTHQUAKE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SETTLEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLAC3D</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPWAP</dc:subject><dc:subject>PDA</dc:subject><dc:subject>displacement</dc:subject><dc:subject>pile capacity</dc:subject><dc:subject>High Strain Dynamic Testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>pile impedance</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present case study, High Strain Dynamic Testing of piles is conducted at 3 different locations of Kolkata city of India. The raw field data acquired is analyzed using Pile Driving Analyzer (PDA) and CAPWAP (Case Pile Wave Analysis Programme) computer software and load settlement curves along with variation of force and velocity with time is obtained. A finite difference based numerical software FLAC3D has been used for simulating the field conditions by simulating similar soil-pile models for each case. The net pile displacement and ultimate pile capacity determined from the field tests and estimated by using numerical analyses are compared. It is seen that the ultimate capacity of the pile computed using FLAC3D differs from the field test results by around 9%, thereby indicating the efficiency of FLAC3D as reliable numerical software for analyzing pile foundations subjected to impact loading. Moreover, various parameters like top layers of cohesive soil varying from soft to stiff consistency, pile length, pile diameter, pile impedance and critical height of fall of the hammer have been found to influence both pile displacement and net pile capacity substantially. It may, therefore, be suggested to include the test in relevant IS code of practice.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TECHNO-PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:10:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:10:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOMECHANICS AND ENGINEERING, 8(3)415-440</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2005-307X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.12989/gae.2015.8.3.415</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18336</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>