<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1618</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stability of waterfront retaining wall subjected to pseudo-dynamic earthquake forces and tsunami</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMAD, SYED MOHD</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, DEEPANKAR</dc:creator><dc:subject>tsunami</dc:subject><dc:subject>architectural design</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>retaining walls</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismology</dc:subject><dc:description>The paper pertains to a study in which the waterfront retaining wall has been analyzed
for its stability when it is exposed to the forces jointly coming from an earthquake and
tsunami. Closed form solutions following the simple limit equilibrium principles have
been proposed. For the calculation of the seismic passive earth pressure and the wall
inertia force, pseudo-dynamic approach has been considered, while the hydrodynamic
and the tsunami wave pressures have been calculated using different approximating
solutions available in literature. The results presented in the sliding and overturning modes of failure of the wall show that the stability of the wall gets seriously challenged when it gets jointly exposed to the effects of the tsunami and earthquake. About 92% decrease is observed in the value of the factor of safety in sliding mode of failure of the wall as the ratio of tsunami wave height to the upstream still water height increases from 0 to 1.5. Also, the critical mode of failure of the wall has been found to be that of the overturning. Effect of different parameters involved in the analysis has also been studied and it has been observed that quite a few of them like kh, kv, φ, δ, ru have a
significant effect on the stability of the wall. Comparison with a previously existing
methodology using pseudo-static approach suggests that the present pseudo-dynamic
approach is more realistic and comparatively less conservative and hence can be used as
a handy simple economic method for the design of the waterfront retaining walls exposed
to the combined effects of earthquake and tsunami.</dc:description><dc:publisher>World Scientific</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-08-18T05:13:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:15:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-08-18T05:13:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:15:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Earthquake and Tsunami 2(2), 107-131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1793-4311</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1618</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>