<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3152</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>The semiquinone-ruthenium combination as a remarkably invariant feature in the redox and substitution series [ru(q)(n)(acac)(3-n)](m), n=1-3; m = (-2),-1, 0,+1, (+2); q=4,6-di-tert-butyl-n-phenyl-o-iminobenzoquinone</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MONDAL, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>FIEDLER, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZALIS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>URBANOS, FA</dc:creator><dc:creator>JIMENEZ-APARICIO, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAIM, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>transition-metal-complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>density-functional theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>o-iminobenzosemiquinonato complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron-paramagnetic-resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>bridged diruthenium complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed-valence complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>quinone-related ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>non-innocent ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>charge-distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>excitation-energies</dc:subject><dc:description>Three new compounds, [Ru(Q(center dot-))(acac)(2)] = 1, [Ru(Q(center dot-))(2)(acac)] = 2, and [Ru(Q(center dot-))(3)] = 3, were obtained and characterized as Ru(III) complexes with 4,6-di-terbul-N-phenyl-o-iminobenzosemiquinone (Q(center dot-)) ligands All three systems show multiple electron transfer behavior, which was analyzed using electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) and UV-vis-near-infrared (NIR) spectroelectrochemistry. (1)H NMR spectroscopy and a crystal structure analysis suggest antiferromagnetically spin-spin coupled Ru(III) and Q(center dot-) in 1, similar to that in the related compound 4 with unsubstituted o-iminobenzosemiquinone However, in contrast to 4(n) (Remenyi, C.; Kaupp, M. J. Am. Chem Soc. 2005, 127,11399), the system 1(m) exhibits unambiguously metal-centered electron transfer, producing ions [Ru(IV)(Q(center dot-))(acac)(2)](+) = 1(+) and [Ru(II)(Q(center dot-))(acac)(2)](-) = 1(-), both with EPR-evidenced ligand-based spin, as also supported by DFT calculations Compared with the related redox system [Ru(Q)(bpy)(2)](k) (5(k)) (k = 0-3), the spectroelectrochemical similarity suggests corresponding electronic structures except for the 1(+)/5(3+) pair [Ru(IV)(Q(center dot-))(acac)(2)](+) (1(+)) versus [Ru(III)(Q(0))(bpy)(2)](3+) (5(3+))). Compound 2, a three-spin system [Ru(III)(Q(center dot-))(2)(acac)] obtained in the all-cis configuration, possesses a complicated magnetic behavior including strong intramolecular antiferro-magnetic coupling (J(Ru-Q), on the order of -10(3) cm(-1) and J(Q-Q), - 10(2) cm(-1)) and weak intermolecular antiferromagnetic and ferromagnetic interactions. Strong intramolecular coupling leads to one unpaired electron at low temperatures, as also supported by the radical-type EPR signal of the solid and of solutions, which diminishes at higher temperatures. The up-down-up spin arrangement for the ground state of {(Q(center dot-))-Ru(III)-(Q(center dot-))} (S = 1/2) is confirmed by DFT calculations for 2 Oxidation to 2(+) leaves the UV-vis-NIR spectrum almost unchanged, whereas reduction to 2(-) and 2(2-) produces low-energy absorptions. The ligand-centered spin for 2(2-) = [Ru(II)(Q(center dot-))(Q(2-))(acac)](2-) suggests the [Ru(II)(Q(center dot-))(2)(acac)](-) formulation for 2(-). Compound 3, obtained as a structurally characterized mer isomer, has a predominantly ligand-centered highest occupied molecular orbital (HOMO), as evident from the EPR signal of the intermediate 3(+) and as supported by DFT calculations. In contrast, electron addition proceeds to yield a metal/ligand mixed spin intermediate 3(-) according to EPR, in agreement with ca. 25% calculated metal character of the lowest unoccupied molecular orbital (LUMO). The near-infrared absorption of 3 at 1280 nm corresponds to the HOMO-LUMO transition (ligand-to-meta/ligand-to-ligand charge transfer). Oxidation to 3(+) produces a weak broad band at about 2500 nm, while the reduction to 3(-) gives rise to an intense absorption feature at 816 nm. The valence state alternatives are being iscussed for all spectroelectrochemically accessible species, and the individual results are compared across this unique substitution and redox series involving a highly noninnocent ligand/metal combination All established oxidation state formulations involve the iminosemiquinone-ruthenium entity, illustrating the remarkable stability of that arrangement, which corroborates the use of this combination in water oxidation catalysis</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-15T08:40:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-15T08:40:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY,48(24)11853-11864</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic901900g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13960</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3152</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>