<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3945</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microtubule sensors and sensor array based on polyaniline synthesized in the presence of poly(styrene sulfonate)</dc:title><dc:creator>KANUNGO, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CONTRACTOR, AQ</dc:creator><dc:subject>conducting polyaniline</dc:subject><dc:subject>acid)</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>aniline</dc:subject><dc:description>Microtubule sensors for glucose, urea, and triglyceride were fabricated based on poly(styrene sulfonate)-polyaniline (PSS-PANI) composites synthesized within the pores of track-etched polycarbonate membranes. The synthesis of a sufficiently thick and conducting PSS-PANI film at pH 5 provided the advantage of immobilizing enzymes during polymerization. This resulted in the improvement of sensor response for urea and triglyceride by a factor of similar to10(2) with a significant increase in the linear region of response compared to polyaniline-based sensors, where the enzymes were immobilized by physical adsorption after the polymerization. The sensors based on urea and triglyceride were found to have a higher linear range of response, better sensitivity, improved multiple use capability, and faster response time compared to the potentiometric and amperometric sensors based on polyaniline. A microtubule sensor array for glucose, urea, and triglyceride based on PSS-PANI was fabricated by immobilization of three different sets of enzymes on three closely spaced devices and its response was found to be free from cross-interference when a sample containing a mixture of the above analytes was analyzed in a single measurement.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T11:47:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T11:47:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANALYTICAL CHEMISTRY, 75(21), 5673-5679</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-2700</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ac034537h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3945</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3945</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>