<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11039</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Model based energy benchmarking for glass furnace</dc:title><dc:creator>SARDESHPANDE, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAITONDE, UN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>combustion</dc:subject><dc:subject>industry</dc:subject><dc:subject>benchmarking</dc:subject><dc:subject>glass furnace</dc:subject><dc:subject>specific energy consumption (sec)</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy efficiency</dc:subject><dc:description>Enemy benchmarking of processes is important for setting energy efficiency targets and planning energy management strategies. Most approaches used for energy benchmarking are based on statistical methods by comparing with a sample of existing plants. This paper presents a model based approach for benchmarking of energy intensive industrial processes and illustrates this approach for industrial glass furnaces. A simulation model for a glass furnace is developed using mass and energy balances, and heat loss equations for the different zones and empirical equations based on operating practices. The model is checked with field data from end fired industrial glass furnaces in India. The simulation model enables calculation of the energy performance of a given furnace design. The model results show the potential for improvement and the impact of different operating and design preferences on specific energy consumption. A case study for a 100 TPD end fired furnace is presented. An achievable minimum energy consumption of about 3830 kJ/kg is estimated for this furnace. The useful heat carried by glass is about 53% of the heat supplied by the fuel. Actual furnaces operating at these production scales have a potential for reduction in energy consumption of about 20-25%. (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T13:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T13:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY CONVERSION AND MANAGEMENT, 48(10), 2718-2738</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-8904</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enconman.2007.04.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11039</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>