<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14187</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:31:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermally unstable intelligent polymer textile biosensors</dc:title><dc:creator>KARAMCHANDANI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUSTAFA, HD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>CONDUCTING POLYANILINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polymer sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interchange phenomenon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intelligent textiles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transesterification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Partially oriented yarns (POY)</dc:subject><dc:description>A radical, first of its kind, biosensor fabricated from unsaturated polymer resin textile, establishes a dynamic link connecting human thermodynamics to electrical ambiance. The fabrication process involves the esterification of dimethyl terephthalate (DMT) and ethylene glycol (EG). This polymerization is articulately arrested using an innovatively formulated retardant, yielding a permanent thermally unstable textile based sensor. An established non-trivial energy interchange phenomenon is founded, presenting an inimitable calibration mechanism of the developed sensors and charting a novel relationship of exuberated kinematical energy to medicinal prognosis. The calibration mechanism is verified from a health care perspective wherein the sensor is regulated against recordings obtained from volume changes in the radial artery. Quantitative and qualitative comparison is performed with existing foam and metallic sensors. The proposed sensor not only outperforms the existing sensors in durability and stability, but also obtains an impressive accuracy of 87%. The novelty of the proposed invention lies in the ability of the biosensors to be fabricated as textile threads, which can be easily sewn and dyed, hence enabling amalgamation into the daily apparel. The capturing of physiological signal variations, devoid of any metallic components presents a singular facet of research and amalgamates various interdisciplinary fields, while providing a robust architecture with minimal tradeoffs. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:31:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:31:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSORS AND ACTUATORS B-CHEMICAL,156(2)765-772</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-4005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2011.02.036</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14187</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>