<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8441</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance analysis of maximum-likelihood multiuser detection in space-time-coded CDMA with imperfect channel estimation</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, GVV</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOCKALINGAM, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>wireless communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>transmitter</dc:subject><dc:subject>antennas</dc:subject><dc:subject>code division multiple access (cdma)</dc:subject><dc:subject>imperfect channel estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>maximum-likelihood (ml) multiuser detection</dc:subject><dc:subject>space-time codes</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, the performance of maximum-likelihood multitiser detection in. space-time-coded code-division multiple-access (CDMA) systems with imperfect channel estimation is analyzed. A K-user synchronous CDMA system that employs orthogonal space-time block codes with M transmit antennas and N receive antennas is considered. A least-squares estimate of the channel matrix is obtained by sending a sequence of pilot bits from each user. The channel matrix is perturbed by an error matrix that depends on the thermal noise and the correlation between the signature waveforms of different users. Because of the linearity of the channel estimation technique, the characteristic function of the decision variable is used to obtain an exact expression for the pairwise error probability, and by using it, an upper bound on the bit error rate (BER) is obtained. The analytical BER bounds are compared with the BER obtained through simulations. The BER bounds are shown to be increasingly tight for large SNR values. It is shown that the degradation in BER performance due to imperfect channel estimation can be compensated by using a larger number of transmit/receive antennas.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T13:12:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T13:12:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON VEHICULAR TECHNOLOGY, 55(6), 1824-1837</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9545</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TVT.2006.878728</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8441</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>