<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15313</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T17:20:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>High Magnetic Exchange Coupling Constants: A Density Functional Theory Based Study of Substituted Schlenk Diradicals</dc:title><dc:creator>LATIF, IA</dc:creator><dc:creator>HANSDA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>INTRAMOLECULAR FERROMAGNETIC INTERACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL DIMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRON-SPIN-RESONANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AB-INITIO CALCULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOW-LYING TRIPLET</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROUND-STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>M-PHENYLENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>M-XYLYLENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONJUGATED DIRADICALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLET-STATES</dc:subject><dc:description>The Schlenk diradical has been known since 1915. After a detailed experimental work by Rajca, its magnetic nature has remained more or less unexplored. We have investigated by quantum chemical calculations the nature of magnetic coupling in 11 substituted Schlenk diradicals. Substitution has been considered at the fifth carbon atom of the meta-phenylene moiety. The UB3LYP method has been used to study 12 diradicals including the original one. The 6-311G(d,p) basis set has been employed for optimization of molecular geometry in both singlet and triplet states for each species. The singlet optimization has led to the optimization of the broken-symmetry structure for 10 species including the unsubstituted one This development makes it possible to carry out further broken symmetry calculations in two ways. The triplet calculation has been done using 6-311++G(d,p) basis set and the optimized triplet geometry in both procedures. The broken symmetry calculations have used the optimized geometries of either the triplet states or the broken symmetry solutions. The first method leads to the prediction of electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) compatible magnetic exchange coupling constant (J) in the range 517-617 cm(-1). A direct optimization of the broken symmetry geometry gives rise to a lower estimate of J, in the range of 411-525 cm(-1) and compatible with macroscopic Curie studies. The calculated J for the unsubstituted Schlenk diradical is 512 cm(-1) that can be compared with 455 cm(-1) estimated by Rajca. In both cases, introduction of groups with +M and +I effects (Ingold's notation) decreases the J value from that for the unsubstituted Schlenk diradical while -I and -M groups at the same position increases J. These trends have been explained in terms of Hammett constants, atomic spin densities, and dihedral angles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:20:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T17:20:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 116(33)8599-8607</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp3033879</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15313</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>