<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14405</identifier><datestamp>2012-09-12T11:04:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assessing the zone of influence of percolation ponds using hydrological studies</dc:title><dc:creator>Jothiprakash, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>Mohan, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>Elango, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>percolation ponds</dc:subject><dc:subject>zone of influence</dc:subject><dc:subject>groundwater recharge</dc:subject><dc:description>In India, percolation ponds have been known to have the potential to serve as one of the important types of artificial recharging structures. In early 1980 to 1990’s Central as well as State Governments have implemented in a large scale constructing of percolation ponds, but later on the programs were gradually dropped. A systematic study in order to asses the extent and intensity of the influence of the percolation pond both spatially and temporally on the wells in the neighbourhood has been reported herein. Two percolation ponds in Tamil Nadu, India has been observed for three years to assess their potential zone of influence. Five different approaches were adopted to demarcate the extent of the zone of influence based on water level and electrical conductivity fluctuation in the wells.  The intensity of zone of influence was categorized as ‘strong’, ‘moderate’, ‘weak’ and ‘negligible’. In one of the cases, the zone of influence was noted to be polygonal with about 200 m width near the pond to about 400 m width at a distance of about 840 m.  In another case it is only half of the above values inspite its capacity being twice.  The wells outside this zone were geo-hydrologically unconnected with the percolation pond.  In one of the pond, it was found that the percolation pond recharges upstream side also. From the study it is found that the effectiveness of a percolation pond depends upon the sitting and active usage of recharged water.  This study reveals that the Governments can rethink of introducing the scheme of percolation pond with proper emphasis on sitting and usage.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Association of Hydrologists of India</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-09-12T11:04:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-09-12T11:04:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Applied Hydrology, XXII(2&amp;3) 51-67</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-670X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14405</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>