<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16360</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:28:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Internal quantum efficiency analysis of plasmonic textured silicon solar cells: surface plasmon resonance and off-resonance effects</dc:title><dc:creator>THOUTI, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARDANA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOMARALA, VK</dc:creator><dc:subject>plasmonics</dc:subject><dc:subject>textured silicon solar cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>internal quantum efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>minority carrier diffusion length</dc:subject><dc:description>Silver nanoparticles (Ag NPs) of various sizes and concentration were integrated on textured silicon solar cells for further confinement of incident light, generated photocurrent modifications were investigated using spectrally resolved short-circuit current measurements. Internal quantum efficiency (IQE) spectra were used for quantifying the effective minority carrier diffusion lengths (Le(ff)) of plasmonic cells in the long wavelength region (850 &lt; lambda &lt; 1020 nm). The L-eff of an optimized plasmonic solar cell enhanced to 431 mu m compared to 338 mu m of the bare cell, which is due to interacting Ag NPs' scattered fields, leading to enhanced light absorption in the plasmonic cell. Despite the enhanced L-eff values, the overall generated photocurrent reduced with Ag NPs which is due to the significant losses near the surface plasmon resonant region. Reduced IQE of plasmonic cells near and below the surface plasmon resonant region is due to size-dependent parasitic absorption and enhanced back scattering of Ag NPs, and a modified surface recombination process due to Ag NPs' strong near-fields.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:28:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:28:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS D-APPLIED PHYSICS, 47(42)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3727</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-6463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0022-3727/47/42/425101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16360</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>