<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12606</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of tectonics in relation to the seismic activity of the Dalvat area, Nasik District, Maharashtra, India using remote sensing and GIS techniques</dc:title><dc:creator>SARUP, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUTHUKUMARAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHUR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PESHWA, V</dc:creator><dc:description>Well-documented geological data ( from both field and satellite) in the Deccan Volcanic Provinces (DVP) in and around the Dalvat region, Nasik District, India has been analysed by Geographic Information System (GIS) techniques and reported in this paper so as to relate the geology and structures with recent seismicity. It has been the belief among earth scientists that the Deccan Traps in Maharashtra, India is tectonically stable as the region attained solidity long ago. However, recent activity in the study area altered this concept and it is now accepted that seismic activity is still continuing on a mild scale. As such, the need has arisen to take into consideration historical as well as recent geological data to study in detail the tectonic setup in the Deccan Traps. Using the well-known relationship between the shear zone, lineaments, and geomorphology, and incorporating these with tectonic events, an attempt has been made to explore the geology and structures in and around the Dalvat region. Field observations and signatures on remote sensing data show that there is evidence of fault traces in the form of shear zones and slickensides in the Deccan Traps near the Kosurde, Dhanoli, Chikhli, and Manchandar villages of the Nasik District. The study has further been incorporated with seismic density data. Magnitudes of 3.9 were recorded as the maximum micro-epicentres, and they fell on the shear fractures detected in the area of study. In order to identify seismically vulnerable areas, seismic hazard zonation (SHZ) mapping has been carried out. Different data layers, including structural, lithological, geomorphological, drainage, and soil have been visually interpreted, scanned, and rectified. A rose diagram of the lineaments shows trends in the NNE-SSW to NS falling on major seismic zones of the study area, showing weaker zones beneath the surface. Raster images were digitized for conversion to a vector coverage using ERDAS 8.6. and ArcGIS 8.3. The ordinal scale (qualitative) relative weighting rating technique was used to give a seismic hazard index (SHI) value to delineate various seismic hazard zones; namely very low, low, moderate, high, and very high.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T05:56:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T05:56:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF REMOTE SENSING, 27(12), 2371-2387</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0143-1161</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01431160500497846</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12606</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>