<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4627</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ruthenium red-induced bundling of bacterial cell division protein, FtsZ</dc:title><dc:creator>SANTRA, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEURIA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>escherichia-coli ftsz</dc:subject><dc:subject>gtp hydrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>smooth-muscle</dc:subject><dc:subject>z-ring</dc:subject><dc:subject>tubulin</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding</dc:subject><dc:subject>zipa</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>inhibition</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymers</dc:subject><dc:description>The assembly of FtsZ plays a major role in bacterial cell division, and it is thought that the assembly dynamics of FtsZ is a finely regulated process. Here, we show that ruthenium red is able to modulate FtsZ assembly in vitro. In contrast to the inhibitory effects of ruthenium red on microtubule polymerization, we found that a substoichiometric concentration of ruthenium red strongly increased the light-scattering signal of FtsZ assembly. Further, sedimentable polymer mass was increased by 1.5- and 2-fold in the presence of 2 and 10 muM ruthenium red, respectively. In addition, ruthenium red strongly reduced the GTPase activity and prevented dilution-induced disassembly of FtsZ polymers. Electron microscopic analysis showed that 4 - 10 muM of ruthenium red produced thick bundles of FtsZ polymers. The significant increase in the light-scattering signal and pelletable polymer mass in the presence of ruthenium red seemed to be due to the bundling of FtsZ protofilaments into larger polymers rather than the actual increase in the level of polymeric FtsZ. Furthermore, ruthenium red was found to copolymerize with FtsZ, and the copolymerization of substoichiometric amounts of ruthenium red with FtsZ polymers promoted cooperative assembly of FtsZ that produced large bundles. Calcium inhibited the binding of ruthenium red to FtsZ. However, a concentration of calcium 1000-fold higher than that of ruthenium red was required to produce similar effects on FtsZ assembly. Ruthenium red strongly modulated FtsZ polymerization, suggesting the presence of an important regulatory site on FtsZ and suggesting that a natural ligand, which mimics the action of ruthenium red, may regulate the assembly of FtsZ in bacteria.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T05:32:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T05:32:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY, 279(25), 25959-25965</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M312473200</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4627</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4627</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>