<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2455</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization and modeling of flexible photovoltaic modules for portable power applications</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>pv module</dc:subject><dc:subject>contoured photovoltaic</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexible photovoltaic</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid amorphous silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>fill factor</dc:subject><dc:description>From the stand point of sustainable development as well as energy security, there is a need to generate power in an environmentally friendly manner using renewable energy sources. However, practical problems occur when considering portable installations in urban as well as rural settings. A specific example may be where due to logistical reasons, only very lightweight photovoltaic modules can be installed. Apart from weight, architectural constraints may also require the module layout to be contoured. The performance of Flexible PV (FPV) modules with moderate Watt-peak/kg values (8-16) and exposed to sustained insolation conditions (maximum of 910 Watt/m(2)) has been investigated in the present work. A polynomial model for predicting the FPV module performance parameters has been developed. Specifically, the effect of solar irradiance (G) and module temperature (7) on Fill Factor (FF), Open Circuit Voltage (V(OC)) and Short Circuit Current (I(SC)) is determined. Three different FPV technologies have been considered, namely mono-crystalline silicon, poly-crystalline silicon, and amorphous silicon. A consistent improvement in performance prediction as compared to previous PV models has been reported. Contoured FPV (C-FPV) modules for special applications have also been studies. The analysis of C-FPV modules and the modeling of power output under different environmental conditions (insolation, temperature) and contour angle will help in extracting maximum power output.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T18:38:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T18:38:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2009 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SUSTAINABLE POWER GENERATION AND SUPPLY, VOLS 1-4,1225-1231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-4934-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15790</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2455</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Sustainable Power Generation and Supply,Nanjing, PEOPLES R CHINA,APR 06-07, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>