<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5238</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>RISK-FACTORS EVALUATION IN SOME CARDIOVASCULAR-DISEASES</dc:title><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>AJMANI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALE, PA</dc:creator><dc:subject>hemorheological changes</dc:subject><dc:subject>hemorheology</dc:subject><dc:subject>whole blood viscosity</dc:subject><dc:description>Cardiovascular risk factors are associated with limitations of blood fluidity. Rheological behaviour of blood in transient flow may result from the internal organization, which in turn depends upon many parameters, which may be considered as possible elements of a profiling algorithm for diagnostic and prognostic values in various pathophysiological states. This study was designed to investigate haemorheological parameters in patients being treated for hypertension, coronary heart disease and myocardial infarct. On the basis of plasma viscosity, whole blood viscosity, haematocrit, red cell aggregation and red cell deformation, the risk was evaluated. In cases of hypertension there was a significant rise in plasma viscosity, whole blood viscosity, red cell aggregation and a fall in red cell deformability. In cases of coronary disease, plasma viscosity and red cell aggregation was increased, while in patients with myocardial infarcts, where the degree of severity is greater it was found that there was a significant rise in both plasma and whole blood viscosity. Haematocrit values were unaffected in all three groups.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BUTTERWORTH-HEINEMANN LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T09:00:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T09:00:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING, 13(5), 441-443</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0141-5425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0141-5425(91)90029-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5238</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5238</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>