<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-672</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Review on subsurface colloids and colloid-associated contaminant transport in saturated porous media</dc:title><dc:creator>SEN, TUSHAR KANTI</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHILAR, KC</dc:creator><dc:subject>contamination</dc:subject><dc:subject>groundwater</dc:subject><dc:subject>interfaces (materials)</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle size analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>In this review article, the authors present up-to-date developments on experimental, modeling and field studies on the role of subsurface colloidal fines on contaminant transport in saturated porous media. It is a complex phenomenon in porous media involving several basic processes such as colloidal fines release, dispersion stabilization, migration and fines entrapment/plugging at the pore constrictions and adsorption at solid/liquid interface. The effects of these basic processes on the contaminant transport have been compiled. Here the authors first present the compilation on in situ colloidal fines sources, release, stabilization of colloidal dispersion and migration which are a function of physical and chemical conditions of subsurface environment and finally their role in inorganic and organic contaminants transport in porous media. The important aspects of this article are as follows: (i) it gives not only complete compilation on colloidal fines-facilitated contaminant transport but also reviews the new role of colloidal fines in contaminant retardation due to plugging of pore constrictions. This plugging phenomenon also depends on various factors such as concentration of colloidal fines, superficial velocity and bead-to-particle size ratio. This plugging-based contaminant transport can be used to develop containment technique in soil and groundwater remediation. (ii) It also presents the importance of critical salt concentration (CSC), critical ionic strength for mixed salt, critical shear stressor critical particle concentration (CPC) on in situ colloidal fines release and migration and consequently their role on contaminant transport in porous media. (iii) It also reviews another class of colloidal fines called biocolloids and their transport in porous media. Finally, the authors highlight the future research based on their critical review on colloid-associated contaminant transport in saturated porous media.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:05:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:06:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:05:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:06:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Advances in Colloid and Interface Science 119(2-3), 71-96</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0001-8686</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cis.2005.09.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/672</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/672</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>