<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15268</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:57:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of substrate and IPTG concentrations on the burden to growth of Escherichia coli on glycerol due to the expression of Lac proteins</dc:title><dc:creator>MALAKAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Cost due to protein expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>Burden on growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>Early exponential phase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Late exponential phase</dc:subject><dc:subject>Glycerol</dc:subject><dc:subject>Escherichia coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>IPTG</dc:subject><dc:subject>COST</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSCRIPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPERON</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PPGPP</dc:subject><dc:description>Expression of proteins unneeded for growth diverts cellular resources from making necessary protein and leads to a reduction in the growth rate of an organism. This reduction in growth rate is termed as cost. Cost plays an important role in determining the selected expression of a protein in a particular environment. Characterization of cost is important in biotechnology industries where microorganisms are used to produce foreign proteins. We have used the lactose system in Escherichia coli to quantify the cost of growth on glycerol in the presence of isopropyl-beta-d-thiogalactopyranoside (IPTG), an inducer of the lactose system. The effect of the concentration of the carbon source, glycerol, and the inducer of Lac enzymes, IPTG, is studied. The results show that the cost is dependent on the glycerol concentration with a decreasing trend with increasing concentration of glycerol. Also as expected, the cost increases and saturates at a higher concentration of IPTG. The studies also demonstrate that the cost is higher in early exponential phase relative to late exponential phase during the growth as has been reported in the literature. Hill equation fit yielded a typical Monod-type expression for growth on glycerol with and without IPTG. An apparent half-saturation constant was defined which was used to characterize the burden on growth due to protein expression.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED MICROBIOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 93(6)2543-2549</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00253-011-3642-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15268</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>