<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9096</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electronic structure and magnetism in doped semiconducting half-Heusler compounds</dc:title><dc:creator>NANDA, BRK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASGUPTA, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>ferromagnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>exchange</dc:subject><dc:subject>sr2femoo6</dc:subject><dc:subject>explicit</dc:subject><dc:subject>density</dc:subject><dc:subject>phases</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:description>We have studied in detail the electronic structure and magnetism in M (Mn and Cr)-doped semiconducting half-Heusler compounds FeVSb, CoTiSb and NiTiSn (XY(x)M(1-x)Z) in a wide concentration range using the local-spin density functional method in the framework of the tight-binding linearized muffin tin orbital method (TB-LMTO) and supercell approach. Our calculations indicate that some of these compounds are not only ferromagnetic but also half-metallic and may be useful for spintronics applications. The electronic structure of the doped systems is analysed with the aid of a simple model where we have considered the interaction between the dopant transition metal (M) and the valence band X-Z hybrid. We have shown that the strong X-d-M-d interaction places the M-d states close to the Fermi level with the M-t(2g) states lying higher in energy in comparison to the M-e(g) states. Depending on the number of available d electrons, ferromagnetism is realized provided that the d manifold is partially occupied. The tendencies toward ferromagnetic (FM) or antiferromagnetic (AFM) behaviour are discussed within Anderson-Hasegawa models of super-exchange and double-exchange. In our calculations for Mn-doped NiTiSn, the strong preference for FM over AFM ordering suggests a possible high Curie temperature for these systems.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 17(33), 5037-5048</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/17/33/008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9096</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9096</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>