<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9592</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of supersaturation and nucleation in a moving solution droplet with flowing supercritical carbon dioxide</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>DALVI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>antisolvent process</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>mass-transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>precipitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>solvent</dc:subject><dc:subject>supersaturation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nucleation</dc:subject><dc:subject>critical nucleus</dc:subject><dc:subject>partial molar volume fraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid solubility</dc:subject><dc:subject>co2 dissolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>supercritical antisolvent (sas)</dc:subject><dc:description>A supercritical antisolvent (SAS) process is employed for production of solid nanoparticles from atomized droplets of dilute solution in a flowing supercritical carbon dioxide (SC CO2) stream by attaining extremely high, very rapid, and uniform supersaturation. This is facilitated by a two-way mass transfer Of CO2 and solvent, to and from the droplet respectively, rendering rapid reduction in equilibrium solubility of the solid solute in the ternary solution. The present work analyses the degree of supersaturation and nucleation kinetics in a single droplet of cholesterol solution in acetone during its flight in a flowing SC CO2 stream. Both temperature and composition are assumed to be uniform within the droplet, and their variations with time are calculated by balancing the heat and mass transfer fluxes to and from the droplet. The equilibrium solubility of cholesterol with CO2 dissolution has been predicted as being directly proportional to the Partial Molar Volume Fraction (PMVF) of acetone in the binary (CO2-acetone) system. The degree of supersaturation has been simulated up to the time required to attain almost zero cholesterol solubility in the droplet for evaluating the rate of nucleation and the size of the stable critical nuclei formed. The effects of process parameters have been analysed in the pressure range of 7.1-35.0 MPa, temperature range of 313-333 K, SC CO2 flow rate of 0.1136-1.136 mol s(-1), the ratio of the volumetric flow rates of CO2-to-solution in the range of 100-1000, and the initial mole fraction of cholesterol in acetone solution in the range of 0.0025-0.010. The results confirm an extremely high and rapid increase in degree of supersaturation, very high nucleation rates and stable critical nucleus diameter of the order of a nanometre. (c) 2005 Society of Chemical Industry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T18:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T18:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 80(4), 445-454</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-2575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jctb.1223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9592</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>