<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11280</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic response of an asymmetric base isolated structure</dc:title><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>support</dc:subject><dc:description>The response of a one-storey model of a torsionally coupled (asymmetric) building with sliding support to two component random ground motions is obtained. The base of the system consists of sliding blocks resting on sliding foundation raft. The rigid-friction force-deformation behaviour of the sliding blocks is modelled as elasto-plastic with very high initial stiffness. The response of the system is analyzed under different parametric variations to investigate the effectiveness of the sliding support. The parameter includes: eccentricity of superstructure, uncoupled torsional to lateral frequency ratio, mass ratio and coefficient of friction of sliding support. The effectiveness is studied by obtaining the response with and without consideration of interaction between the two lateral frictional resistances of the sliding support on the criterion of sliding. It was shown that the effect of bi-direction interaction is significant and should be included for the effective design of a torsionally coupled system with sliding support. Copyright (C) 1996 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T10:43:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T10:43:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTERS &amp; STRUCTURES, 60(2), 261-267</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0045-7949</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0045-7949(95)00369-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11280</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11280</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>