<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3158</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Recent advances in processing and characterization of periodic mesoporous mcm-41 silicate molecular sieves</dc:title><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATIA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SONWANE, CG</dc:creator><dc:subject>x-ray-diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>pore-size distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>highly ordered mcm-41</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquid-crystalline phases</dc:subject><dc:subject>anion-exchange properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrothermal stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>capillary condensation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrogen adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>water-vapor</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural-properties</dc:subject><dc:description>The discovery of periodic mesoporous MCM-41 and related molecular sieves has attracted significant attention from a fundamental as well as applied perspective. They possess well-defined cylindrical/hexagonal mesopores with a simple geometry, tailored pore size, and reproducible surface properties. Hence, there is an ever-growing scientific interest in the challenges posed by their processing and characterization and by the refinement of various sorption models. Further, MCM-41-based materials are currently under intense investigation with respect to their utility as adsorbents, catalysts, supports, ion-exchangers, and molecular hosts. In this article, we provide a critical review of the developments in these areas with particular emphasis on adsorption characteristics, progress in controlling the pore sizes, and a comparison of pore size distributions using traditional and newer models. The model proposed by the authors for adsorption isotherms and criticalities in capillary condensation and hysteresis is found to explain unusual adsorption behavior in these materials while providing a convenient characterization tool.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-15T09:13:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-15T09:13:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH,40(15)3237-3261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie0010666</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13966</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3158</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>