<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6281</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Towards an integrated agenda for adaptation research: theory, practice and policy</dc:title><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOWNING, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEARY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>WILBANKS, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>climate</dc:subject><dc:description>Adaptation to the adverse impacts of climate change has been recognized as a priority area for national and international policy. The findings of the Fourth Assessment Report of the IPCC have reemphasized the urgency of action and the scale of response needed to cope with climate change outcomes. The scientific community has an important role to play in advancing the information and knowledge base that would help in identifying, developing and implementing effective responses to enhance adaptive capacity and reduce vulnerability. This paper examines the way in which science and research could advance the adaptation agenda. To do so, we pose a number of questions aimed at identifying the knowledge gaps and research needs. We argue that in order to address these science and research needs, an integrated approach is necessary, one that combines new knowledge with new approaches for knowledge generation, and where research and practice co-evolve; and that such a learning-by-doing approach is essential to rapidly scale up and implement concrete adaptation actions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T15:59:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T15:59:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT OPINION IN ENVIRONMENTAL SUSTAINABILITY, 1(2), 219-225</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1877-3435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cosust.2009.10.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6281</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>