<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3069</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>A review of structure and tectonics of kutch basin, western india, with special reference to earthquakes</dc:title><dc:creator>BISWAS, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>2001 bhuj earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>rift basins</dc:subject><dc:subject>geodynamics</dc:subject><dc:description>The Kutch basin is a western margin pericratonic rift basin of India. Nagar Parkar uplift in the north and Kathiawar uplift (Saurashtra horst) in the south respectively along Nagar Parkar and North Kathiawar faults delimit the E-W rift. The Kutch rift was initiated during the Late Triassic break up of the Gondwanaland by the reactivation of primordial faults in the Precambrian Delhi fold belt. The rifting was aborted during Late Cretaceous pre-collision stage of the Indian plate. During post-collision compressive regime of the Indian plate, the Kutch rift basin became a shear zone with strike-slip movements along sub-parallel rift faults. The Kutch Mainland Fault along the rift axis became the active principal fault. Presently, this right lateral strike-slip fault is overstepped by the South Wagad Fault in the eastern part of the basin. The overstep zone between the two wrench faults is a convergent transfer zone undergoing transpressional stress in the strained eastern part of the basin. The epicenters of two big earthquakes as well as the aftershock hypocenters of Bhuj earthquake are located within this zone. The study of the intrusive rocks, rift geometry and seismic tomography indicates presence of a large ultramafic body in the lower crust. An overview of the structural and tectonic evolution of the basin is discussed in the context of earthquakes. Based on structural and detailed depth-wise analysis of aftershock data, a conceptual domino-listric model of Kutch rift is presented here. On the basis of this model, an attempt is made here to explain the dynamics of the earthquake generation in the Kutch basin.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CURRENT SCIENCE ASSN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T21:57:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T21:57:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE,88(10)1592-1600</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13860</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3069</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>