<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8550</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison between implicit and hybrid solvation methods for the determination of pK (a) of mono-protonated form of 13(2)-(demethoxycarbonyl) pheophytin a in methanol</dc:title><dc:creator>MEHTA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>dimethyl-sulfoxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>current losses</dc:subject><dc:subject>pk(a) values</dc:subject><dc:subject>bipolar cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>computation</dc:subject><dc:subject>acetonitrile</dc:subject><dc:subject>cations</dc:subject><dc:subject>regime</dc:subject><dc:subject>anions</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>dielectric polarizable continuum model</dc:subject><dc:subject>cluster-continuum model</dc:subject><dc:subject>pk(a)</dc:subject><dc:description>Both implicit solvation method (dielectric polarizable continuum model, DPCM) and hybrid solvation method (cluster-continuum model) were adopted to calculate the pK (a) of mono-protonated form of 13(2)-(demethoxycarbonyl) pheophytin a (Pheo) in methanol. In the cluster-continuum model calculations, we considered only 1 solvent molecule attached explicitly and others treated implicitly whereas in the DPCM calculations all the solvent molecules were treated implicitly. DPCM calculations were carried out on Pheo, PheoH(+), Pheo-CH(3)OH and PheoH(+)-CH(3)OH in methanol solution. The aim of these calculations was to determine the free energy changes involved in the deprotonation of PheoH(+) (Delta G (sol)) and finally to obtain the corresponding pK (a) value. DPCM calculations were carried out employing the restricted open-shell density functional treatment (ROB3LYP) using the 6-31G(d) basis set to determine the free energy of solvation of bare Pheo and PheoH(+) and of the clusters, Pheo-CH(3)OH and PheoH(+)-CH(3)OH in methanol. In-vacuo geometries of all the species were obtained by performing optimizations at ROB3LYP level using the 6-31G(d) basis. Electronic energies of all the species were then obtained by carrying out single point DFT calculations using 6-311+G(2d, 2p) basis set on the respective optimized geometries. Differences in thermal energy and molecular entropy were calculated by carrying out frequency calculations at ROB3LYP/STO-3G level on the optimized geometries of the truncated models. The optimized geometries of the clusters display intermolecular hydrogen bonding interactions. The pK (a) values of PheoH(+) calculated by DFT-DPCM and cluster-continuum methods are 6 center dot 12 and 4 center dot 70 respectively while the observed value is 4 center dot 14. The hydrogen bonding interaction between the solute and the solvent can be attributed for the good performance of the cluster-continuum model over pure continuum model.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T21:31:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T21:31:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL SCIENCES, 121(5), 881-886</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4134</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12039-009-0104-x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8550</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>