<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2442</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-11T04:34:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Speech recognition based computer keyboard replacement for the quadriplegics, paraplegics, paralytics and amputees</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRAMOULI, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>speech recognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>bio-medicine and information technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>occupational therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>cognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>intelligent systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>assistive technologies for handicapped</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes the design and development of a speech recognition system which can be used to interact with a home computer and to control domestic appliances at the command of a word (speech). It can also be used to control special appliances like an electric wheel chair. This rehabilitative (or assistive) system is developed primarily for individuals who are physically handicapped due to Quadriplegia, Paraplegia, Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, paralysis, congenital defect(s) or accident, leading to de-generated growth of or amputated limbs. The possibility of browsing the web by linking keyboard and mouse emulation with discretely spoken word recognition is the main motivating factor to develop this assistive system. All the details of the developed system are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T17:39:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T17:39:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MEMEA: 2009 IEEE INTERNATIONAL WORKSHOP ON MEDICAL MEASUREMENTS AND APPLICATIONS,241-245</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-3598-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15779</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2442</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Workshop on Medical Measurements and Applications,Cetraro, ITALY,MAY 29-30, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>