<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1621</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental and numerical investigations of flame pattern formations in a radial microchannel</dc:title><dc:creator>FAN, AIWU</dc:creator><dc:creator>MINAEV, SERGEY</dc:creator><dc:creator>SERESHCHENKO, EVGENIY</dc:creator><dc:creator>FURSENKO, ROMAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUDARSHAN KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIU, WEI</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARUTA, KAORU</dc:creator><dc:subject>flammability</dc:subject><dc:subject>methane</dc:subject><dc:subject>microchannels</dc:subject><dc:subject>model structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>arrhenius reaction</dc:subject><dc:description>Flame pattern formations in a heated radial microchannel with a gap width of 1.75 mm were investigated experimentally and numerically. A premixed methane–air mixture was introduced at the center of microchannel formed by two parallel quartz discs which were heated with an external porous burner to create a positive temperature gradient condition in the direction of flow. In addition to conventional stable flames, some non-stationary flame patterns termed single- and double-pelton-like flames and the traveling flame were also observed. The double- and single-pelton-like flames occurred at a random possibility under certain conditions, which rotated around the center of the radial microchannel at a frequency of ~25–55 Hz. Regime diagram of all those flame patterns was drawn based on the experimental findings in the mixture equivalence ratio range of 0.65–1.30 and inlet mixture velocity range of 1.5–5.0 m/s. Meanwhile, the experimental results also qualitatively verify our previous theoretical prediction that is the S-shaped dependency of flame radial location on inlet velocity for stoichiometric mixture. Finally, numerical simulations using a global one-step Arrhenius reaction model successfully captured some rotating flame structures that may be associated with single- and double-pelton-like flames observed in the experiments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-12T08:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:17:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-12T08:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:17:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Combustion Institute 32(2), 3059-3066</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1540-7489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.proci.2008.06.092</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1621</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1621</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>