<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15164</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:33:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Diffuse phase transition and electrical properties of lead-free piezoelectric (LixNa1-x)NbO3 (0.04 &lt;= x &lt;= 0.20) ceramics near morphotropic phase boundary</dc:title><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAKASH, O</dc:creator><dc:subject>LITHIUM-NIOBATE CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPEDANCE SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NA1-XLIXNBO3 CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLID-SOLUTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWDERS</dc:subject><dc:description>Temperature-dependent dielectric permittivity of lead-free (LixNa1-x)NbO3 for nominal x = 0.04-0.20, prepared by solid state reaction followed by sintering, was studied to resolve often debated issue pertaining to exactness of morphotropic phase boundary (MPB) location besides structural aspects and phase stability in the system near MPB. Interestingly, a diffuse phase transition has been observed in the dielectric permittivity peak arising from the disorder induced in A-site and structural frustration in the perovskite cell due to Li substitution. A partial phase diagram has been proposed based on temperature-dependent dielectric permittivity studies. The room temperature piezoelectric and ferroelectric properties were investigated and the ceramics with x = 0.12 showed relatively good electrical properties (d(33) = 28 pC/N, k(p) = 13.8%, Q(m) = 440, P-r = 12.5 mu C/cm(2), E-c = 43.2 kV/cm, and T-m = 340 degrees C). These parameter values make this material suitable for piezoelectric resonator and filter applications. Moreover, a high dielectric permittivity (epsilon'(r) = 2703) with broad diffuse peak near transition temperature, and low dielectric loss (&lt;4%) over a wide temperature range (50-250 degrees C) found in this material may also have a potential application in high-temperature multilayer capacitors in automotive and aerospace related industries. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:33:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:33:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 114(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4817815</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15164</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>