<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2502</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Classification of polarimetric synthetic aperture radar images from SIR-C and ALOS PALSAR</dc:title><dc:creator>TURKAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, YS</dc:creator><dc:subject>decomposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>radar polarimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthetic aperture radar</dc:subject><dc:subject>speckle</dc:subject><dc:subject>target decomposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>terrain classification</dc:subject><dc:description>SIR-C quad-pol MLC data and ALOS PALSAR quad-pol and dual pol SLC data over Indian sites have been processed using PoISARpro software for classification of various land features. The land features include ocean, clear water, settlements, agriculture fields, arid lands, grown and young forest, hilly terrain, mangrove forest, etc. The test sites used are SIR-C L-band and C-band Kolkata city and its surroundings, ALOS PALSAR data over West Bengal, Haryana, Rajasthan, Uttar Pradesh, and Mumbai. For Kolkata city we observed that classification results for L- and C-bands are slightly different. For Mumbai dual pol data classification accuracy is poor due to overlap of backscattering values for bare ground and mangrove vegetation with ocean backscattering values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T22:15:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T22:15:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON RECENT ADVANCES IN MICROWAVE THEORY AND APPLICATIONS, PROCEEDINGS,438-440</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2690-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15832</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2502</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Recent Advances in Microwave Theory and Applications,Jaipur, INDIA,NOV 21-24, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>