<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14666</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:19:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Estimation of seismic ground motions using deterministic approach for major cities of Gujarat</dc:title><dc:creator>SHUKLA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>7.7 BHUJ EARTHQUAKE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PENINSULAR INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>HAZARD ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBABILISTIC ASSESSMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>HISTORICAL SEISMICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NORTHWESTERN INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOURCE PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>KUTCH</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGION</dc:subject><dc:description>A deterministic seismic hazard analysis has been carried out for various sites of the major cities (Ahmedabad, Surat, Bhuj, Jamnagar and Junagadh) of the Gujarat region in India to compute the seismic hazard exceeding a certain level in terms of peak ground acceleration (PGA) and to estimate maximum possible PGA at each site at bed rock level. The seismic sources in Gujarat are very uncertain and recurrence intervals of regional large earthquakes are not well defined. Because the instrumental records of India specifically in the Gujarat region are far from being satisfactory for modeling the seismic hazard using the probabilistic approach, an attempt has been made in this study to accomplish it through the deterministic approach. In this regard, all small and large faults of the Gujarat region were evaluated to obtain major fault systems. The empirical relations suggested by earlier researchers for the estimation of maximum magnitude of earthquake motion with various properties of faults like length, surface area, slip rate, etc. have been applied to those faults to obtain the maximum earthquake magnitude. For the analysis, seven different ground motion attenuation relations (GMARs) of strong ground motion have been utilized to calculate the maximum horizontal ground accelerations for each major city of Gujarat. Epistemic uncertainties in the hazard computations are accounted for within a logic-tree framework by considering the controlling parameters like b-value, maximum magnitude and ground motion attenuation relations (GMARs). The corresponding deterministic spectra have been prepared for each major city for the 50th and 84th percentiles of ground motion occurrence. These deterministic spectra are further compared with the specified spectra of Indian design code IS:1893-Part I (2002) to validate them for further practical use. Close examination of the developed spectra reveals that the expected ground motion values become high for the Kachchh region i.e. Bhuj city and moderate in the Mainland Gujarat, i.e. cities of Surat and Ahmedabad. The seismic ground motion level in the Saurashtra is moderate but marginally differs from that as presently specified in IS:1893-Part I (2002). Based on the present study, the recommended PGA values for the cities studied are 0.13 g, 0.15 g, 0.64 g, 0.14 g and 0.2 g for Ahmedabad city, Surat City, Bhuj City, Jamnagar City and Junagadh city, respectively. The prepared spectra can be further used for seismic resistant design of structures within the above major city boundaries of Gujarat to quantify seismic loading on structures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>COPERNICUS GESELLSCHAFT MBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:19:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:19:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURAL HAZARDS AND EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCES, 12(6)2019-2037</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/nhess-12-2019-2012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14666</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>