<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15107</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:30:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Distributed Power Allocation for Secondary Users in a Cognitive Radio Scenario</dc:title><dc:creator>NADKAR, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>THUMAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEJ, GPS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>Cognitive radio</dc:subject><dc:subject>overlay spectrum sharing</dc:subject><dc:subject>power allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>interference</dc:subject><dc:subject>game theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTROL GAME</dc:subject><dc:subject>WIRELESS DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:description>The major contribution of this paper is distributed power allocation for a multi-user multi-channel Cognitive Radio (CR) network which deploys overlay spectrum sharing by the Primary Users (PUs) and Secondary Users (SUs), and Frequency Division Multiplexing Access (FDMA) for the SUs. The transmit power of each SU is constrained by an individual node power budget, the interference threshold on the PU band, as well as the interference caused to the neighboring SUs. Motivated by the non-convex structure of the problem and the need to execute the power allocation distributedly, the problem is cast within a game theoretic frame-work. Pay-off functions for the SUs are formulated to suit the system model, and the Nash Equilibrium for the game is analyzed. Simulation results are provided to validate the mathematical concepts and to evaluate the performance of the proposed distributed power control algorithm in comparison with other relevant schemes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:30:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:30:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS, 11(4)1576-1586</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TWC.2012.020712.111502</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15107</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>