<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14567</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:27:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Affinity-aware modeling of CPU usage with communicating virtual machines</dc:title><dc:creator>SUDEVALAYAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Platform virtualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Network-affinity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Resource provisioning</dc:subject><dc:description>Use of virtualization in Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) environments provides benefits to both users and providers: users can make use of resources following a pay-per-use model and negotiate performance guarantees, whereas providers can provide quick, scalable and hardware-fault tolerant service and also utilize resources efficiently and economically. With increased acceptance of virtualization-based systems, an important issue is that of virtual machine migration-enabled consolidation and dynamic resource provisioning. Effective resource provisioning can result in higher gains for users and providers alike. Most hosted applications (for example, web services) are multi-tiered and can benefit from their various tiers being hosted on different virtual machines. These mutually communicating virtual machines may get colocated on the same physical machine or placed on different machines, as part of consolidation and flexible provisioning strategies. In this work, we argue the need for network affinity-awareness in resource provisioning for virtual machines. First, we empirically quantify the change in CPU resource usage due to colocation or dispersion of communicating virtual machines for both Xen and KVM virtualization technologies. Next, we build models based on these empirical measurement to predict the change in CPU utilization when transitioning between colocated and dispersed placements. Due to the modeling process being independent of virtualization technology and specific applications, the resultant model is generic and application-agnostic. Via extensive experimentation, we evaluate the applicability of our models for synthetic and benchmark application workloads. We find that the models have high prediction accuracy maximum prediction error within 2% absolute CPU usage. (C) 2013 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:27:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:27:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SYSTEMS AND SOFTWARE, 86(10)2627-2638</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0164-1212</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-1228</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jss.2013.04.085</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14567</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>