<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1415</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydrodynamics and liquid phase residence time distribution in Mesh microreactor</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GORASIA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RANADE, VV</dc:creator><dc:subject>mass-transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>trickle flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>columns</dc:subject><dc:subject>microreactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>residence time distribution</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>hysteresis</dc:subject><dc:subject>image analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper is focused on the experimental analysis of residence time distribution and phase hold-up in a mesh microreactor. A microreactor, where a finely weaved mesh is sandwiched between two flat plates with specific inlets for gas and liquid, is proposed. The microvolumes formed upon sandwiching the mesh are totally connected and thus it yields a view of several interconnected microvolumes. This system is easy to build and does not need precision micromachining. A high-speed photographic analysis yielded the phase distribution for different mesh types over a wide range of operating gas and liquid flow rates. The RTD was studied by measuring the liquid phase conductivity at the outlet of the reactor. Channeling prevailed for mesh with smaller open area. The ADEM was used for fitting the tracer curves with tailing ends. The RTD and the image analysis for all the mesh types showed hysteresis when the gas flow rate was maintained constant and the liquid flow rate was gradually increased and then decreased. (c) 2007 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:48:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:48:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING SCIENCE,62(24)7484-7493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2007.08.063</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14703</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1415</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th International Conference on Gas-Liquid and Gas-Liquid-Solid Reactor Engineering,New Delhi, INDIA,DEC 16-19, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>