<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7168</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of saturated, omega-3 and omega-6 polyunsaturated fatty acids on myocardial infarction</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGESWARI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENON, VP</dc:creator><dc:subject>non-arteriosclerotic rats</dc:subject><dc:subject>fish-oil</dc:subject><dc:subject>cholesterol</dc:subject><dc:subject>isoproterenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>atherosclerosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>lysophosphatidylcholine</dc:subject><dc:subject>supplementation</dc:subject><dc:subject>propranolol</dc:subject><dc:subject>disease</dc:subject><dc:subject>rabbits</dc:subject><dc:subject>myocardial infarction</dc:subject><dc:subject>atherosclerosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>fatty acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>malondialdehyde</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydroperoxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>catalase</dc:subject><dc:subject>superoxide dismutase</dc:subject><dc:description>Dietary fatty acids have cholesterol lowering, antiatherogenic, and antiarrhythmic properties that decrease the risk of myocardial infarction (MI). This study was designed to study the effects of various oils rich in either polyunsaturated (omega-3 or omega-6)fatty acids (PUFA) or saturated fatty acids (SFA) on the severity of experimentally induced MI. Male albino Sprague-Dawley rats (100-150 g; n = 20) were fed diets enriched with fish oil (omega-3 PUFA), peanut ail (omega-6 PUFA), or coconut ail (SFA) far 60 days. Experimental MI was induced with isoproterenol. Mortality razes; serum enzymes aspartate amino transferase; alanine amino transferase; creatine phosphokinase (CPK); lipid profiles in serum myocardium, and aorta; peroxide levels in heart and aorta; activities of catalase and superoxide dismutase; and levels of glutathione were measured. The results demonstrated that mortality rate, CPK levels, myocardial lipid peroxides, and glutathione levels were decreased n the omega-3 PUFA treated group. Maximum increase in parameters indicative of myocardial damage was seen in the coconut oil group. These findings suggest that dietary omega-3 PUFA offers maximum protection in experimentally induced MI in comparison to omega-6 PUFA and SFA enriched diets. SFA was found to have the feast protective effect. (J. Nutr. Biochem. 10:338-344; 1999) (C) Elsevier Science Inc. 1999. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T08:16:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T08:16:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NUTRITIONAL BIOCHEMISTRY, 10(6), 338-344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0955-2863</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0955-2863(99)00007-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7168</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7168</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>