<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14432</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T12:41:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Removal of Chemical Oxygen Demand and Color from Simulated Textile Wastewater Using a Combination of Chemical/Physicochemical Processes</dc:title><dc:creator>YADAV, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>ACTIVATED CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>COAGULATION PROCESSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNESIUM-CHLORIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FENTON PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOCCULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHITOSAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>AZO</dc:subject><dc:description>The treatment of simulated textile wastewater [chemical oxygen demand (COD) = 3360 mg/L] was performed using three chemical/physicochemical processes, viz., coagulation, Fenton oxidation, and adsorption. Coagulation of the wastewater was performed in a jar test apparatus using inorganic and organic coagulants. The best color removal (similar to 96%) was obtained with FeSO4 while FeCl3 and MgCl2 caused similar to 75% and similar to 53% color removal, respectively. The optimum dose for iron-based coagulants was 3 g/L, whereas it was 6 g/L for MgCl2. FeSO4-treated wastewater showed the best results with regard to the settling of flocs. Chitosan was effective for the decolorization of wastewater at low dose (=10 mg/L) and acidic pH (similar to 3.0) showing similar to 20% and 30% COD and color reductions, respectively. For coagulation with FeSO4 followed by adsorption, overall COD and color removal of 85% and 99%, respectively, could be achieved. The raw wastewater treated by Fenton's process (H2O2 dose = 10.5 g/L and H2O2/Fe2+ molar ratio = 20) exhibited COD and color removal of similar to 80% and 99%, respectively. Using Fenton oxidation as a post-treatment step after coagulation with FeSO4, the COD removal was enhanced to similar to 83%, although the color removal remained unaffected. The sequential treatment also increased the BOD5 (biochemical oxygen demand) to COD ratio of the treated wastewater to 0.51.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:41:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:41:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 52(30)10063-10071</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie400855b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14432</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>