<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14746</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:28:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Superposition of Quantum Confinement Energy (SQCE) model for estimating shell thickness in core-shell quantum dots: Validation and comparison</dc:title><dc:creator>SARAN, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Quantum confinement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Core-shell quantum dot</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microemulsion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shell thickness</dc:subject><dc:subject>CdSe-CdS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CdSe-ZnS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluorescence quantum yield</dc:subject><dc:subject>CADMIUM SELENIDE NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SMALL-ANGLE SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIGHT-EMITTING-DIODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTOR NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORE/SHELL NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CDTE NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CDSE NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNS SHELL</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROEMULSION</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel theoretical model based on superposition of core and shell band-gaps, termed as SQCE model, is developed and reported here, which enables one to estimate the shell thickness in a core-shell quantum dot (QD), which is critically important in deciding its optical and electronic properties. We apply the model to two experimental core-shell QD systems, CdSe-CdS and CdSe-ZnS, which we synthesize by microemulsion method. We synthesize and study two series of samples, R and S to study the optical properties. The core size is varied in the R-series (by varying water-to-surfactant ratio, R) whereas the shell thickness is varied in the S-series (by varying the shell-to-core precursor molar ratio, 5). The core and core-shell QDs from R-series and S-series are characterized for particle size, shape and crystallographic information. The shell thickness for all core-shell QD samples is estimated by SQCE model, and experimentally measured with TEM and SAXS. A close match is observed between experimental values and model predictions, thus validating the model. Further, the optimum shell thickness (corresponding to maximum quantum yield) values for CdS and ZnS over a 4.26 nm CdSe core have been estimated as 0.585 nm and 0.689 nm, respectively, from the SQCE model. The SQCE model developed in this work is applicable to other core-shell quantum dots also, such as CdTe-CdS, CdTe-CdSe and CdS-ZnS, and will serve as a useful complement to experimental measurement. (C) 2012 Published by Elsevier</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:28:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:28:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COLLOID AND INTERFACE SCIENCE, 37821-29</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2012.03.056</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14746</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>