<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1293</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Post deposition annealing temperature effect on silicon quantum dots embedded in silicon nitride dielectric multilayer prepared by hot-wire chemical vapor deposition</dc:title><dc:creator>PANCHAL, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:subject>si nano-crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>amorphous-silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar-cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanostructures</dc:subject><dc:subject>si3n4</dc:subject><dc:subject>si-qd/sin(x) multilayer</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:description>The preparations of the 20-period of a Si quantum dot (QD)/SiN(x) multilayer in a hot-wire chemical vapor deposition (HWCVD) chamber is presented in this paper. The changes in the proper-ties of Si-QDs after the post deposition annealing treatment are studied in detail. Alternate a-Si:H and SiN(x) layers are grown in a single SiN(x) deposition chamber by cracking SiH(4), and SiH(4) + NH(3), respectively at 250 degrees C. The as-deposited samples are annealed in the temperature range of 800 degrees C to 950 degrees C to grow Si-QDs. All the samples are characterized by confocal micro Raman, transmission electron microscope (TEM), and photoluminescence (PL) to study the changes in the film structures after the annealing treatment. The micro Raman analysis of the samples shows the frequency line shifting from 482 cm(-1) to 500 cm(-1) indicating the Si transition from an amorphous to a crystalline phase. The TEM micrograph inspection indicates the formation of Si-QDs of size 3 to 5 nm and a density of 5 x 10(12)/cm(2). The high resolution TEM micrographs show an agglomeration of Si-QDs with an increase in the annealing temperature. The PL spectra show a peak shifting from 459 nm to 532 nm with increasing the annealing temperature of the film. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T15:31:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T15:31:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS,517(12)3488-3491</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2009.01.080</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14686</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1293</dc:identifier><dc:source>5th International Conference on Hot-Wire CVD (Cat-CVD) Process,Cambridge, MA,AUG 20-24, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>