<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2815</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Application of Barkhausen Noise measurements for the evaluation of surface integrity of components</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHUGAUNKAR, GV</dc:creator><dc:creator>FIX, R</dc:creator><dc:description>Surface microstructure and residual stress pattern can have important consequences on the performance of components subjected to fatigue loading and to corrosive environments. Barkhausen Noise (BN) measurements can be used as an effective tool to monitor the near surface residual stresses in ferromagnetic materials and to detect microstructural inhomogeneities produced during processing or service exposure of components. The BN measurements consist of monitoring electrical pulses induced in the magnetizing coil of a probe as a result of the magnetic domain wall movements produced in the material under inspection. The intensity of BN signals depends on the stress levels and microstructure of the material. Successful application of the method requires stress response calibration curves determined on a material having chemical composition, processing history and microstructure identical to that of the component surface. The paper gives case studies of the application of BN measurements for the evaluation of surface integrity of components such as gears and welded joints involving residual stress and microstructural variations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A A BALKEMA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T13:50:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T13:50:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRENDS IN NDE SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY - PROCEEDINGS OF THE 14TH WORLD CONFERENCE ON NDT (14TH WCNDT), VOLS 1-5,1647-1651</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-5410-740-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16315</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2815</dc:identifier><dc:source>14th World Conference on NDT - Trends in NDE Science and Technology (14th WCNDT),NEW DELHI, INDIA,DEC 08-13, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>