<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10425</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>A HIGHER-ORDER ELEMENT FOR FINITE-ELEMENT ANALYSIS OF STIFFENED PANELS SUBJECTED TO INPLANE LOADING AND A STUDY ON EFFICIENT ARRANGEMENT OF DOUBLY BONDED STRIP CRACK STIFFENERS</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SETHURAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>stress intensity factors</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:description>An element with a quadratic variation of shear stress field is proposed for the analysis of crack-stiffened panels where the stiffeners (or patches) are attached on both sides of the panel. In formulating the element stiffness matrix the energies due to in-plane deformation of the stiffener and plate and shear deformation of the adhesive, stiffener and the panel have been taken into account. The effectiveness of the element is illustrated by considering a centre crack subjected to a mode I or mode II loading. Shear stresses developed in the adhesive are compared with analytical solutions and are found to be quite accurate in spite of the coarse discretization used. Then the element is employed to examine an inclined edge crack subjected to three different mixed-mode loadings a uniaxial uniformly distributed load, a point loading and an equibiaxial loading, to determine the most efficient arrangement of the stiffener. When the mode I stress intensity factor (SIF) in the parent sheet dominates, placing the stiffener close to the crack centre and oriented normal to the direction of initial crack extension is most advantageous. When the mode II SIF is comparable with the mode I SIF in the parent sheet, placing the stiffener in a particular orientation slightly away from the crack normal position leads to the minimum mode I SIF.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T06:47:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T06:47:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 41(3), 349-365</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0013-7944(92)90076-Q</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10425</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>