<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7865</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Origin of fluorite mineralisation and hydrothermal alteration at the Chandidongri deposit, Rajnandgaon District, Central India - Evidence from oxygen and hydrogen isotopes</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANGKAKOTI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDALAI, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GRAY, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHMAD, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PERASUD, ER</dc:creator><dc:subject>madhya-pradesh</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorite mineralisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrothermal alteration</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxygen and hydrogen isotopes</dc:subject><dc:subject>central india</dc:subject><dc:description>Economic mineralization relatable to the early-Proterozoic Dongargarh granite that forms part of a large volcano-plutonic complex of Central India includes the Chandidongri fluorite deposit located on the granite, a few small deposits of uranium in sheared rhyolites and basic rocks in close proximity to the granite, and minor Cu +/- Pb mineralisation within sheared rhyolites. In the fault-controlled fluorite deposit at Chandidongri, the delta 18O values of fluorite-bearing quartz range from 11.4 to 13.8 per mil, whereas delta O-18 values of quartz from intensely altered granites range from 13.0 to 14.4 per mil. The delta D values of fluid inclusion waters extracted from vein-quartz, fluorite and quartz from altered granites range from -32 to -52, -38 to -40 and -48 to -60 per mil respectively. The delta 18O values and measured delta D values indicate a dominantly meteoric source for the fluorite and alteration fluids that may have undergone slight mixing with magmatic water.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GEOLOGICAL SOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-30T05:48:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-30T05:48:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 67(1), 33-40</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7865</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7865</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>