<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14901</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:26:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurement of surface temperature and emissivity of different materials by two-colour pyrometry</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJ, VC</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-RESISTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FURNACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGE</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental investigation is performed to substantiate the capability of a charge coupled device camera to measure local temperature and emissivity of different materials heated to temperatures above 500 degrees C by two-colour pyrometric technique using colorimetric method. Materials investigated are Inconel 718 with pyromark (high temperature paint), Inconel 718, stainless steel SS 304 and SS 316. Centerline temperature and emissivity distribution is obtained for target plates maintained at constant temperature by AC heating while complete temperature and emissivity distribution is provided for plates heated by flame impingement. The obtained results are compared with a calibrated infrared camera and thermocouples and the temperature distribution is found to be in close agreement. These results pertain to partially oxidized metal alloys covered in this study. Deviation in the measurement of emissivity can be attributed to its dependence on wavelength range, oxidation, and sensitivity of the image detector. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:26:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:26:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS, 84(12)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0034-6748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4847115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14901</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>