<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1568</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biosorption of aqueous chromium(VI) by tamarindus indica seeds</dc:title><dc:creator>AGARWAL, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHUPTAWAT, HITENDRA KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, SANJEEV</dc:creator><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>chromium</dc:subject><dc:subject>tamarind seed</dc:subject><dc:subject>desorption</dc:subject><dc:description>The effectiveness of low cost agro-based materials namely, Tamarindus indica seed (TS), crushed coconut shell (CS), almond shell (AS), ground nut shell (GS) and walnut shell (WS) were evaluated for Cr(VI) removal. Batch test indicated that hexavalent chromium sorption capacity (qe) followed the sequence qe(TS) &gt; qe(WS) &gt; qe(AS) &gt; qe(GS) &gt; qe(CS). Due to high sorptive capacity, tamarind seed was selected for detailed sorption studies. Sorption kinetic data followed first order reversible kinetic fit model for all the sorbents. The equilibrium conditions were achieved within 150 min under the mixing conditions employed. Sorption equilibria exhibited better fit to Freundlich isotherms (R &gt; 0.92) than Langmuir isotherm (R ≈ 0.87). Hexavalent chromium sorption by TS decreased with increase in pH, and slightly reduced with increase in ionic strength. Cr(VI) removal by TS seems to be mainly by chemisorption. Desorption of Cr(VI) from Cr(VI) laden TS was quite less by distilled water and HCl. Whereas with NaOH, maximum desorption achieved was about 15.3%. When TS was used in downflow column mode, Cr(VI) removal was quite good but head loss increased as the run progressed and was stopped after 200 h.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-22T07:23:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:05:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-22T07:23:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:05:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Bioresource Technology 97(7), 949-956</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-8524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.biortech.2005.04.030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1568</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1568</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>