<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3820</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enantio- and Diastereoselectivities in Chiral Sulfur Ylide Promoted Asymmetric Aziridination Reactions</dc:title><dc:creator>JANARDANAN, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:subject>highly stereoselective-synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>polarizable continuum model</dc:subject><dc:subject>corey-chaykovsky reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>ring-opening reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>aza-darzens reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>enantioselective synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>dimethyloxosulfonium methylide</dc:subject><dc:subject>mediated aziridination</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermodynamic control</dc:subject><dc:subject>efficient preparation</dc:subject><dc:description>Density functional theory investigation on the factors controlling enantio- and diastereoselection in asymmetric aziridination reaction by the addition of chiral bicyclic sulfur ylides to substituted aldimines is presented. Hi-fi levels of enantioselection are predicted toward the formation of (2S,3S)-cis and (2R,3S)-trans aziridines by the addition of stabilized ylide (R = COMe) respectively to SO(2)Me and CO(2)Me protected aldimines. Similarly, high %ee is predicted for the formation of (2S,3R)-cis aziridines from semistabilized (R = Ph) ylide. Moderate to high levels of diastereoselectivity is noticed as well. The present study highlights that a correct prediction oil extent of enantioselection requires the knowledge of the activation barriers for elementary steps beyond the initial addition step. In the case of stabilized ylides the ring-closure (or elimination Of Sulfur compound) is found to be crucial in controlling enantio- and diastereoselection. A cumulative effect of electronic as well as other weak interactions is identified as factors contributing to the relative energies of transition states leading to enantio- and diastereomeric products for the stabilized ylide addition to aldimines. On the contrary, steric control appears quite dominant With semistabilized ylide addition. With the smallest substituent on ylide (R = Me), high enantioselectivity is predicted for the formation of (2R,3R)-trans aziridines although the %de in this case is found to be very low.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T01:13:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T01:13:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 73(21), 8163-8174</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo800652c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3820</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3820</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>