<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2485</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>High frequency AC-DC converter for high current applications</dc:title><dc:creator>BHIDE, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>transformer</dc:subject><dc:description>High amount of direct current is essential in many industrial processes. Conventional methods for obtaining high amount of direct current involve parallel operation of converters with interphase or five-legged rectifier transformer. The interphase transformer (IPT) and/or rectifier transformer employed in the system increase overall size of the system and also provide limited control over the operation. This paper presents simpler topology of high frequency AC-DC converter specially for low-voltage high-current industrial applications. In the proposed topology, rectifier module and low frequency L-C filter in the primary stage (required for conventional high frequency converters) are eliminated. The topology provides better control over the operation and helps in reducing size of the overall rectifier system. The topology is simulated for a practical application of 12 V, 5000 A rectifier system. The three-phase high frequency transformer present in the topology is designed and its estimated size is compared with the existing five-legged rectifier transformer for the conventional system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T20:45:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T20:45:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ICEM: 2008 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ELECTRICAL MACHINES, VOLS 1- 4,1666-1671</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1735-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15817</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2485</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conferece on Electrical Machines,Vilamoura, PORTUGAL,SEP 06-09, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>