<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2158</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Voxel-based representation, display and thickness analysis of intricate shapes</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:description>An efficient voxel representation scheme coupled with algorithms for voxelisation, display and thickness analysis of complex free form shapes is presented. The binary voxel model is stored as a stack of layers represented as bit-arrays. Polygonal solid models are converted into voxel format with a maximum resolution of 1000 (one billion voxels) in less than 2 minutes. Near real-time visualization of the voxel model is achieved by direct point rendering using a look-up table based on a finite set of neighbour voxel configurations. Thickness analysis is performed in terms of cross-sectional visualisation, progressive skin removal and radiography with minimum, maximum and total thickness along an orthographic direction. Testing of the algorithms for intricate shapes like Ganesha idol, pelvis bone and automobile cylinder gave satisfactory results. The voxel framework can be coupled to traditional CAD/CAM systems, providing additional capabilities to product engineers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T10:50:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T10:50:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NINTH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER AIDED DESIGN AND COMPUTER GRAPHICS, PROCEEDINGS,415-420</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-2473-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/CAD-CG.2005.86</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15394</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2158</dc:identifier><dc:source>9th International Conference on Computer Aided Design and Computer Graphics,Hong Kong, PEOPLES R CHINA,DEC 07-10, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>