<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2314</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of polypropylene, polyester and glass fibres on various strengths of ordinary and standard concretes</dc:title><dc:creator>DAVE, UV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>mechanical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>shotcrete</dc:subject><dc:subject>monofilament polypropylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibrilliated polypropylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyester</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkali resistant glass</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibre dosage</dc:subject><dc:subject>workability</dc:subject><dc:subject>compressive strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>split tensile strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>flexure strength</dc:subject><dc:description>This research is attributed to ordinary and standard concretes reinforced with four varieties of fibres. Results of experimental investigations on mechanical properties of M20 and M40 control and fibre reinforced concretes are presented. Comparative performance of 12 mm and 20 mm length monofilament polypropylene fibres, graded fibrillated polypropylene fibres, 12 mm polyester fibres &amp; 12 mm AR glass fibres is evaluated. Fibre content is varied as 0, 0.8 kg &amp; 1.6 kg per m(3) of concrete respectively. Compressive, Split Tensile and flexure Strengths are evaluated at the age of 7, 14 and 28 days. Cubes of 150 x 150 x 150 mm are cast to measure compressive &amp; split tensile strengths and beams of 100 x 100 x 500 mm are prepared to evaluate flexural strength. Broken pieces of flexural specimens are tested in compression and tension, to compare results obtained using 'equivalent cube test' and 'splitting prism test' approach. Workability of concrete is measured which reduces with increase in dosage for all fibres. Failure shapes and unit weight have been recorded. A detailed discussion is carried out by comparing results of three strengths. A significant improvement is obtained in various strengths for different fibre varieties tried. Comparative analysis is carried out on performance of concretes for both grades. An attempt is made to correlate results of compressive and tensile strengths evaluated by above two approaches. Suggestions are included for further improvement in terms of strengths &amp; for proper correlation of tensile and compressive strengths between exact and equivalent tests.</dc:description><dc:publisher>DESTECH PUBLICATIONS, INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T04:15:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T04:15:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE FIRST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON RECENT ADVANCES IN CONCRETE TECHNOLOGY,623-634</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-932078-76-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15906</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2314</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st International Conference on Recent Advances in Concrete Technology,Washington, DC,SEP 19-21, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>