<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17513</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:36:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Laminar flow heat transfer studies in a twisted square duct for constant wall heat flux boundary condition</dc:title><dc:creator>BHADOURIYA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>TUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEADY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PIPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heat transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminar flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>twist ratio</dc:subject><dc:subject>periodic flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>twisted duct</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhancement</dc:subject><dc:description>The problem of fluid flow and heat transfer was studied for flow inside twisted duct of square cross-section. Three-dimensional numerical solutions were obtained for steady fully developed laminar flow and for uniform wall heat flux boundary conditions using commercially available software. Reynolds number range considered was 100-3000. Twist ratio used are 2.5, 5, 10 and 20. Fluids considered are in Prandtl number range of 0.7-20. Product of friction factor and Reynolds number is found to be a function of Reynolds number and maximum values are observed for a twist ratio of 2.5 and Reynolds number of 3000. Maximum Nusselt number is observed for the same values along with Prandtl number of 20. Correlations for friction factor and Nusselt number are developed involving swirl parameter. Local distribution of friction factor ratio and Nusselt number across a cross-section is presented. Based on constant pumping power criteria, enhancement factor is defined to compare twisted ducts with straight ducts. Selection of twisted square duct is presented in terms of enhancement factor. It is found that twisted duct performs well in the laminar region for range of parameters studied. Heat transfer enhancement for Reynolds number of 3000 and Prandtl number of 0.7 for twist ratio of 2.5, 5, 10, and 20 is 20%, 17.8%, 16.1% and 13.7%, respectively. The results are significant because it will contribute to development of energy efficient compact size heat exchangers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:36:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:36:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SADHANA-ACADEMY PROCEEDINGS IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES, 40(2)467-485</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-2499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-7677</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12046-015-0345-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17513</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>