<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17921</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:22:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Conformational Simulation of Sulfamethizole by Molecular Complexation and Insights from Charge Density Analysis: Role of Intramolecular S center dot center dot center dot O Chalcogen Bonding</dc:title><dc:creator>THOMAS, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>VECCHAM, SPKP</dc:creator><dc:creator>FARRUGIA, LJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROW, TNG</dc:creator><dc:subject>RECEPTOR ANTAGONIST C30H30N6O3S</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPERIMENTAL ELECTRON-DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEUTRON-DIFFRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIRSHFELD SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERMOLECULAR INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPRAMOLECULAR CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TAUTOMERIC PREFERENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN-BONDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:description>Intramolecular S center dot center dot center dot O chalcogen bonding and its potential to lock molecular conformation have been examined in the crystal forms of sulfamethizole, a sulfonamide antibiotic. Molecular complexes of sulfamethizole, including salts and cocrystal, have been synthesized, and their crystal structures were analyzed in order to examine the possible conformational preferences of the molecule in various ionic states and supramolecular environments (neutral/cocrystal, anionic salt, and cationic salt forms). The electrostatic potential mapped on Hirshfeld surfaces generated for these crystal forms provides insights into the possible binding modes of the drug in different environments. Further, the observed conformation locking feature has been rationalized in terms of the experimental charge density features of the intramolecular S center dot center dot O chalcogen bonding in sulfamethizole. The study quantitatively illustrates and rationalizes an intriguing case of a local minimum of molecular conformation being exclusively preferred over the global minimum, as it facilitates more efficient intermolecular interactions in a supramolecular environment.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:22:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:22:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CRYSTAL GROWTH &amp; DESIGN, 15(5)2110-2118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1528-7483</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1528-7505</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/cg5016687</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17921</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>