<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15586</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:48:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Free and forced vibration control of piezoelectric FGM plate subjected to electro-mechanical loading</dc:title><dc:creator>JADHAV, PA</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJORIA, KM</dc:creator><dc:subject>ACTIVE CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTUATORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper investigates the free and forced vibration analysis of a newly introduced metal based functionally graded (FG) plate integrated with a piezoelectric actuator and sensor at the top and bottom faces respectively. The material properties of the FG plate are assumed to be graded along the thickness direction according to a simple power law distribution in terms of the volume fraction of the constituents, while the Poisson ratio is assumed to be constant. The plate is simply supported at all edges. The finite element model is based on higher order shear deformation theory (HOST), the von Karman hypothesis and degenerated shell elements. The displacement component of the present model is expanded in Taylor's series in terms of the thickness co-ordinate. The Hamilton principle is used to derive the equation of motion for the piezoelectric functionally graded material (FGM) plate. The free and forced vibration analysis of the simply supported piezoelectric FG plate is carried out to present the effect of the power law index and the piezoelectric layer. The present analysis is carried out on a newly introduced FGM, which is a mixture of aluminum and stainless steel. Stainless steel is a high strength material but it can rust in extreme cases, and aluminum does not rust but it is a low strength material. The FGM exhibits corrosion resistance as well as the high strength property in a single material. This new FGM will definitely help in the construction as well as the metal industry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:48:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:48:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS AND STRUCTURES, 22(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0964-1726/22/6/065021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15586</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>