<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18103</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:55:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Perturbative order analysis of the similarity transformed Hamiltonian in Fock-space coupled cluster theory: difference energy and electric response properties</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAL, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>EXCITED-STATE PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPEN-SHELL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION-ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRIPLE EXCITATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONFIGURATION-INTERACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONIZED STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOUBLES METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>INCLUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>5TH-ORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric response properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fock space</dc:subject><dc:subject>similarity transformed Hamiltonian</dc:subject><dc:subject>perturbative order</dc:subject><dc:description>A perturbative analysis of the ground-state similarity transformed Hamiltonian and its effect on the various Fock-space coupled cluster (FSCC) sectors is presented through calculation of ionisation potential, electron affinity, excitation energies and response properties. Various truncation schemes of the effective Hamiltonian are presented with explicit form of the defining equations. Based on such a truncation, the approximate methods are labelled as FSCC(n), where n represents the correlation energy of the ionised, electron attached or excited states corrected at least up to nth order within coupled cluster singles and doubles scheme (CCSD). A lower scaling CC2 type of approach (abbreviated as FS-CC2) is compared against the group of FSCC(n) methods for energies. Electric response properties have been compared and contrasted for the two lower scaling methods: FSCC(2) and FS-CC2. The various truncated methods are tested for a number of small molecules. The results obtained from a range of truncated methods are compared against full FSCCSD calculations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:55:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:55:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MOLECULAR PHYSICS, 113(13-14SI)2046-2060</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0026-8976</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1362-3028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00268976.2015.1059509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18103</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>