<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16434</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:05:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Near room temperature reduction of graphene oxide Langmuir-Blodgett monolayers by hydrogen plasma</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOTCHA, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUTAR, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAM, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALWAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJOR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>EXFOLIATED GRAPHITE OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>X-RAY-ABSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENT REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMORPHOUS-CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPARENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROUTE</dc:subject><dc:description>Langmuir-Blodgett monolayer sheets of graphene oxide (GO) were transferred onto Si and SiO2/Si, and subjected to hydrogen plasma treatment near room temperature. GO monolayers were morphologically stable at low power (15 W) plasma treatment, for durations up to 2 min and temperatures up to 120 degrees C. GO monolayers reduced under optimized plasma treatment conditions (30 s duration at 50 degrees C) exhibit a sheet thickness of (0.5-0.6) nm, high sp(2)-C content (75%), a low O/C ratio (0.16) and a significant red-shift of Raman G-mode to 1588 cm(-1), indicating efficient de-oxygenation and a substantial decrease of defects. A study of the valence band electronic structure of hydrogen plasma reduced GO monolayers shows an increase of DOS in the vicinity of the Fermi level, due to the increase of C 2p-pi states, and a substantial decrease of work function. These results, along with conductivity measurements and transfer characteristics, reveal the p-type nature of hydrogen plasma reduced GO monolayers, displaying a conductivity of (0.2-31) S cm(-1) and a field effect mobility of (0.1-6) cm(2) V-1 s(-1). Plasma treatment at higher temperatures results in a substantial increase in sp(3)-C/damaged alternant hydrocarbon content and incorporation of defects related to the hydrogenation of the graphitic network, as evidenced by multiple Raman features, including a large red-shift of D-mode to 1331 cm(-1) and a high I(D)/I(G) ratio, and supported by the appearance of mid-gap states in the vicinity of the Fermi level.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:05:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:05:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 16(23)11708-11718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4cp00875h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16434</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>