<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2087</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of partial safety factors for establishing acceptable flaws for brittle piping</dc:title><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RASTOGI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAKHARDANDE, MJ</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper presents a case study on the application of Load and Resistance Factor Design (LRFD) approach to the Section XI Appendix H of ASME Boiler and Pressure Vessel code for flaw evaluation. This study considers a case of brittle piping. The circumferential and longitudinal cracks are considered. Partial safety factors are generated for maximum reliability index of 2.0 in case of circumferential flaws and for two levels of target failure probability (reliability index beta = 2.0, 3.09) in case of longitudinal flaws. The partial safety factors are generated for fracture toughness and applied stress values. The variability in fracture toughness is modeled using Weibull distribution. Coefficient of variation of 10-30% is considered in fracture toughness. The stress is modeled as normal, lognormal and extremal distributions with coefficient of variation of 10-30%. Since the effect of statistical correlation on the load and resistance factors is relatively insignificant for target reliability values of practical interest, the effect of correlated variables may be neglected.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T05:53:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T05:53:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Advanced Reliability Modeling,491-498</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>981-238-871-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/9789812702685_0062</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15621</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2087</dc:identifier><dc:source>Asian International Workshop on Advanced Reliability Modeling,Hiroshima, JAPAN,AUG 26-27, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>