<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14124</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:22:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>The role of niobium carbide in radiation induced segregation behaviour of type 347 austenitic stainless steel</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMEDABADI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAIN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAGWAT, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL POTENTIOKINETIC REACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESS-CORROSION CRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERGRANULAR CORROSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTON IRRADIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>OVERSIZED SOLUTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOY 690</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOOP EPR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUSCEPTIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSITIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITROGEN</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of niobium carbide precipitates on radiation induced segregation (RIS) behaviour in type 347 stainless steel was investigated. The material in the as-received condition was irradiated using double-loop 4.8 MeV protons at 300 degrees C for 0.43 dpa (displacement per atom). The RIS in the proton irradiated specimen was characterized using double-loop electrochemical potentiokinetic reactivation (DL-EPR) test followed by atomic force microscopic examination. The nature of variation of DL-EPR values with the depth matched with the variation of the calculated irradiation damage (dpa) with the depth. The attack on grain boundaries during EPR tests was negligible indicating absence of chromium depletion zones. The interface between niobium carbide and the matrix acts as a sink for point defects generated during irradiation and this had reduced point defect flux toward grain boundaries. The attack was noticed at a few large cluster of niobium carbide after the DL-EPR test at the depth of maximum attack for the irradiated specimen. Pit-like features were not observed within the matrix indicating the absence of chromium depletion regions within the matrix. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:22:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:22:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MATERIALS,415(1)123-131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2011.05.051</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14124</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>