<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14555</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:21:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of Assumed-Transition-Point Criterion in Context of Reynolds-Averaged Simulations Around Lighter-Than-Air Vehicles</dc:title><dc:creator>SUMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAKSHMIPATHY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANT, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>SHAPE OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIRSHIP BODIES</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, the performance of the assumed-transition-point criterion, in conjunction with Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes simulations is evaluated over the hull of a lighter-than-air vehicle. The evaluation is performed by comparing the Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes computations of drag, lift, and moment coefficients against those measured in experiments where 1) transition is forced to occur (forced-transition case) and 2) transition is allowed to occur naturally (free-transition case). It was found that by using the assumed-transition-point criterion Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes computations satisfactorily recover the drag coefficient both at zero angle of attack and nonzero angles of attack up to five degrees when compared against the forced-transition case. However, irrespective of the location of the assumed transition point, Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes fails to recover the experimentally observed values of the force and moment coefficients for the free-transition case. At this point, it is not clear if this failure is attributable to the assumed-transition-point criterion or to the Reynolds-averaged Navier Stokes framework itself. A similar systematic evaluation with more scale resolving computational fluid dynamics methods (large eddy simulation or bridging methods) may be helpful in ascertaining the reason of this failure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUTICS  ASTRONAUTICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:21:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:21:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF AIRCRAFT, 50(2)450-456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/1.C031880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14555</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>