<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9014</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ore group classification - A case study from Ingaldhal sulphide deposit, Karnataka Craton, India</dc:title><dc:creator>ANTONY, JP</dc:creator><dc:subject>chitradurga greenstone-belt</dc:subject><dc:subject>acid volcanic-rocks</dc:subject><dc:subject>sulfide deposits</dc:subject><dc:subject>southern india</dc:subject><dc:subject>evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>ages</dc:subject><dc:subject>ore groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>ingaldhal sulphide deposit</dc:subject><dc:subject>copper rich groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>zinc rich groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>karnataka craton</dc:subject><dc:description>All varieties of base metal sulphide deposits may be classified using base metal ratios viz. Copper Ratio (CR=100Cu/(Cu+Zn)), Zinc Ratio (ZR=100Zn/(Zn+Pb)) and Lead Ratio (PR=100Pb/(Pb+Cu)). Based on this ore group classification an attempt has been made to identify ore groups present in the late Archaean volcanic associated Ingaldhal Sulphide Deposit (ISD) of Karnataka Craton. Using base metal ratios (CR, ZR and PR) five distinct fields are suggested: Cu, Cu-Zn, Cu-Zn-Pb, Zn-Cu and Zn-Cu-Pb/Zn-Pb-Cu with their associated geological and geochemical characteristics. A transitional change in the ore groups is observed from the North Block (Cu rich groups; CR&gt;50) to South Block (Zn and Pb dominated groups; CR&lt;50) and the Main Block is represented by all the five ore groups. This classification may be useful as a pointer in the exploration of polymetallic base metal deposits. Copper rich groups (Cu, Cu-Zn and Cu-Zn-Pb) exhibit high concentration of Bi and Co, and low CaO and Cd whereas the Zn rich groups (Zn-Cu and Zn-Cu-Pb/Zn-Pb-Cu) show high CaO and Cd, and low Bi and Co. The CR of most of the ore groups exhibit a sympathetic relation with Co and Ag. A preliminary attempt has been made for better understanding of ore group genesis of ISD by integrating ore group characteristics with deduced geothermometry.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INT ASSOC GONDWANA RESEARCH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T11:44:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T11:44:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GONDWANA RESEARCH, 2(1), 67-77</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1342-937X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1342-937X(05)70127-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9014</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>