<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10042</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fabrication of Mineralized Polymeric Nanofibrous Composites for Bone Graft Materials</dc:title><dc:creator>NGIAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIAO, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHENG, ZY</dc:creator><dc:creator>YANG, FY</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUBLER, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAN, CK</dc:creator><dc:subject>osteoblast-like cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanophase ceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>extracellular-matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>tissue regeneration</dc:subject><dc:subject>chitosan scaffolds</dc:subject><dc:subject>osteogenic cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>collagen matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydroxyapatite</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:description>Poly-L-lactic acid (PLLA) and PLLA/collagen (50% PLLA+50% collagen; PLLA/Col) nanofibers were fabricated using electrospinning. Mineralization of these nanofibers was processed using a modified alternating soaking method. The structural properties and morphologies of mineralized PLLA and PLLA/Col nanofibers were investigated using X-ray diffraction (XRD), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and contact angle measurements. Human bone-derived osteoblasts were cultured on the materials for up to 1 week to assess the biological properties of the nanofibrous composites. Cell attachment on these nanocomposites was also tested within 1 h of culture at room temperature. The mechanical properties of the cell-nanocomposite constructs were determined using tensile testing. From our results, the bone-like nano-hydroxyapatite (n-HA) was successfully deposited on the PLLA and PLLA/Col nanofibers. We observed that the formation of n-HA on PLLA/Col nanofibers was faster and significantly more uniform than on pure PLLA nanofibers. The n-HA significantly improved the hydrophilicity of PLLA/Col nanofibers. From the results of cell attachment studies, n-HA deposition enhanced the cell capture efficacy at the 20-minute time point for PLLA nanofibers. The E-modulus values for PLLA+n-HA with cells (day 1 and day 4) were significantly higher than for PLLA+n-HA without cells. Based on these observations, we have demonstrated that n-HA deposition on nanofibers is a promising strategy for early cell capture.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MARY ANN LIEBERT INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T14:10:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T14:10:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TISSUE ENGINEERING PART A, 15(3), 535-546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1937-3341</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1089/ten.tea.2008.0011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10042</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10042</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>