<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-227</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Device degradation of n-channel poly-Si TFTs due to high-field, hot-carrier and radiation stressing</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAMESRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAL, RAKESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>AKUMAR, KP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIN, KO</dc:creator><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric variables measurement</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionizing radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>hot carriers</dc:subject><dc:subject>low temperature effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>current voltage characteristics</dc:subject><dc:description>There has been increasing interest in polysilicon thin film transistors (TFTs) for high-performance applications, particularly in high-resolution displays. For these applications, the primary requirement is that the TFTs have a low threshold voltage, low and stable leakage current and reasonably high carrier mobility. The poly-Si TFTs typically have sufficiently large mobilities to be used for high-drive and moderately high-frequency applications. However, since low temperatures are used in poly-Si TFT fabrication, both semiconducting and insulating layers are of poorer quality than those used in crystalline-Si technology. Consequently, long term TFT stability is an important issue. A considerable amount of research has focused on the stability of poly-Si TFTs. The instabilities are basically associated with hot carrier injection and degradation, negative gate bias instability and gate-induced carrier injection and trapping (Young, 1996). This leads to degradation of several device parameters such as threshold voltage, mobility, transconductance, and subthreshold slope. The work presented here is a comprehensive study of degradation in low temperature (&amp;les;600°C) poly-Si TFTs due to high-field, hot-carrier and ionizing radiation stressing. This unified approach makes it possible to identify the key reasons for degradation. Furthermore, a systematic study of the dependence on device geometry, as reported here, also helps understanding of the degradation mechanisms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-08T08:39:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T11:36:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-08T08:39:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T11:36:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 8th International Symposium on the Physical and Failure Analysis of Integrated Circuits, Singapore, 9-13 July 2001, 258-262</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-6675-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/IPFA.2001.941498</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/227</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>