<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16868</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:25:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Benchmarking energy consumption for dump trucks in mines</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, LK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Benchmarking</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy consumption</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dump truck</dc:subject><dc:subject>Opencast mine</dc:subject><dc:subject>Specific fuel consumption</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optimisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>DATA ENVELOPMENT ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:description>Dump trucks are used for transportation in opencast mines and consume about 32% of the total energy use in mines. This paper presents a generic model to benchmark energy consumption for dump trucks in mines. The modelling framework estimates minimum specific fuel consumption (SFC) of dump trucks using mine equipment, engine characteristics and vehicle dynamics. The model investigates the variation of SFC with operating input parameters like payload, material handling rate, vehicle speed, distance, mine gradient, etc. The applicability of the proposed model is illustrated through a case study of multiple dump trucks in a down gradient opencast limestone mine in India. The minimum SFC of 89 g/t is estimated for a mine transport system with three excavators and two crushers. The case study shows a potential fuel saving of 17%. The modelling framework developed can be used to set rational targets for energy consumption for dump trucks in mines. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:25:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:25:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED ENERGY, 1131382-1396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-2619</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-9118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apenergy.2013.08.058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16868</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>