<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15257</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:52:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental investigation of heat transfer in gas-solid packed fluidized bed</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYAMOORTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>VINJAMUR, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Packed fluidization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiphase system</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heat transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Effective thermal conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lithium titanate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFECTIVE THERMAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>LITHIUM-TITANATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COARSE PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:description>Packed fluidization is a novel technique, in which small particles are allowed to fluidize in the interstices of relatively large and stationary packing to enhance heat transfer rates of a unary packed bed of same size pebbles. In the present study, heat transfer in unary packed bed and binary packed fluidized bed were investigated and compared in terms of the effective thermal conductivity. In the experimental works, large pebbles (size: 3-10 mm) of two different materials viz, lithium titanate and alumina and small particles (size: 231-780 mu m), also of two different materials viz., lithium titanate and silica were used. It was found that the heat transfer in unary packed bed is enhanced due to the packed fluidization and in terms of the effective thermal conductivity; the enhancement was up to 260%. It was found that the volume fraction of small particles, operating gas velocity, particle to pebble size ratio and the type of materials have a significant effect in enhancing the effective thermal conductivity and heat transfer rates. It was also found that 60% (v/v) of small particles in the interstitial voids of packing pebbles can give much improved effective thermal conductivity keeping all other operating parameters same. Possible mechanism for heat transfer enhancement due to packed fluidization has been proposed. Based on the results for different particle and pebble sizes, materials and process variables viz, particles to pebble size ratios, operating gas velocity ratios, volume fraction of small particles in the interstices and bed wall temperatures, we could arrive at optimum conditions for determining effective thermal conductivity and a correlation to estimate the same. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:52:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:52:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POWDER TECHNOLOGY, 246252-268</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2013.04.054</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15257</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>