<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15242</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:44:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experiments and Kinetic Modeling for CO2 Gasification of Indian Coal Chars in the Context of Underground Coal Gasification</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAPATI, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAGGUPATI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGHALAYAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAPRU, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANESH, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>RANDOM PORE MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUID-SOLID REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON-DIOXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>REACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEAM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:description>Gasification of four Indian coals is carried out in a CO2 atmosphere, using a thermogravimetric analyzer (TGA) to determine the intrinsic kinetics over a temperature range of 800-1050 degrees C with different partial pressures of CO2. The applicability of three models, viz., the volumetric reaction model, the shrinking core model and the random pore model, is evaluated. Of these three models, the random pore model is found to be the most suitable for all the coals considered in the current study. The dependence of the reaction rate on the gas-phase partial pressures is explained by the Langmuir-Hinshelwood model, and the parameters for the inhibition due to CO and CO2 are determined by performing experiments at different partial pressures. In underground coal gasification, the reaction takes place on reasonably large sized coal particles, wherein diffusion effects are significant A one-dimensional reaction diffusion model is therefore developed in order to determine the diffusional resistance in the coal particle, and values of diffusivity are estimated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:44:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:44:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 51(46)15041-15052</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie3022434</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15242</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>