<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15030</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:50:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Mn substitution on the magnetic and magneto-transport properties of Fe3-xMnxSi (0 &lt;= x &lt;= 1.25) alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>PAL, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL SOLUTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEUSLER ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SITE PREFERENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-RESISTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYPERFINE FIELDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAND-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FE3SI</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOMENTS</dc:subject><dc:description>Effect of partial Mn substitution for Fe in Fe3Si on the structural, magnetic, transport, and magnetotransport properties has been studied. Mn substitution is found to induce a re-entrant antiferromagnetic phase at low temperatures. The increase in the antiferromagnetic exchange causes a gradual decrease in the Curie temperature and the saturation magnetization. Temperature dependence of the electrical resistivity data shows that the high temperature resistivity is dominated by electron-phonon scattering, while below the re-entry temperature (T-R), electron-magnon scattering is dominant. These results are in agreement with the reported spin polarization studies and indicate that the reentrant behavior is detrimental to half metallicity. Application of a field causes negative magnetoresistance (MR) above TR. However, at 5K, the magnetoresistance is found to be positive, with the magnitude increasing with x. For x&gt;0.8, field induced irreversibility has been found in MR vs. field isotherms at 5 K, which indicates that the re-entrant phase has competing magnetic interactions. Canted magnetic structure known to exist in this system is assumed to be responsible for this anomalous behaviour. (C) 2013 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4794126]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:50:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:50:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 113(9)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4794126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15030</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>