<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14940</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:55:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Al dopants on the structural, optical and gas sensing properties of spray-deposited ZnO thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAJAPATI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHAY, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemisorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOPED ZNO</dc:subject><dc:subject>PYROLYSIS TECHNIQUE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACETONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTORESPONSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFECTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LPG</dc:subject><dc:description>Undoped and Al-doped ZnO thin films were deposited on glass substrates by the spray pyrolysis method. The structural, morphological and optical properties of these films were investigated by X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), atomic force microscopy (AFM), UV-Vis spectroscopy, photoluminescence (PL) and photoconductivity (PC) measurements, respectively. XRD analyses confirm that the films are polycrystalline zinc oxide with the hexagonal wurtzite structure, and the crystallite size has been found to be in the range 20-40 nm. SEM and AFM analyses reveal that the films have continuous surface without visible holes or faulty zones, and the surface roughness decreases on Al doping. The Al-doped films have been found to be highly transparent (&gt;85%) and show normal dispersion behavior in the wavelength range 450-700 nm. The doped films show only ultraviolet emission and are found to be highly photosensitive. Among all the films examined, at 300 C the 1.0 at% Al-doped film shows the selective high response (98.2%) to 100 ppm acetone concentration over to methanol, ethanol, propan-2-ol, formaldehyde and hydrogen. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:55:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:55:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS CHEMISTRY AND PHYSICS, 142(1)276-285</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2013.07.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14940</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>