<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12653</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tuned mass dampers for torsionally coupled systems</dc:title><dc:creator>PANSARE, AP</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>optimum absorber parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>design formulas</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration control</dc:subject><dc:subject>wind excitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>harmonic</dc:subject><dc:subject>tmds</dc:subject><dc:subject>torsional coupling</dc:subject><dc:subject>robustness</dc:subject><dc:subject>accidental eccentricity</dc:subject><dc:description>The steady state response of a torsionally coupled system with tuned mass dampers (TMDs) to external wind-induced harmonic excitation is presented. The torsionally coupled system is considered as one-way eccentric system. The eccentricity considered in the system is accidental eccentricity only. The performance of single tuned mass damper (TMD) optimally designed without considering the torsion is investigated for the torsionally coupled system and found that the effectiveness of a single TMD is significantly reduced due to torsion in the system. However, the design of TMD system without considering the torsion is only justified for torsionally stiff systems. Further, the optimum parameters of a single TMD considering the accidental eccentricity are obtained using numerical searching technique for different values of uncoupled torsional to lateral frequency ratio and aspect ratio of the system. The optimally designed single TMD system is found to be less effective for torsionally coupled system in comparison to uncoupled system. This is due to the fact that a torsionally coupled system has two natural frequencies of vibration, as a result, at least two TMDs are required which can control both lateral and torsional response of the system. The optimum damper parameters of different alternate arrangements such as (i) two identical TMDs placed at opposite corners, (ii) two independent TMDs and (iii) four TMDs are evaluated for minimum response of the system. The comparative performance of the above TMDs arrangements is also studied for both torsionally coupled and uncoupled systems. It is found that four TMDs arrangement is quite effective solution for vibration control of torsionally coupled system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TECHNO-PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T08:39:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T08:39:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WIND AND STRUCTURES, 6(1), 23-40</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1226-6116</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12653</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12653</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>