<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17553</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:56:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermal-hydraulic characteristics and performance of 3D wavy channel based printed circuit heat exchanger</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, HH</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANEESH, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHURI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>PCHE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computational fluid dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Printed circuit heat exchanger</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thermal-hydraulic performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wavy channel</dc:subject><dc:description>CFD study is done here to propose an efficient PCHE (Printed Circuit Heat Exchanger) model; used as a recuperator in International Thermonuclear Experimental Reactor (ITER). 3D steady state conjugate heat-transfer numerical simulations are done; considering the variation of thermo-physical properties as a function of temperature. Helium is used as a working fluid and alloy 617 as solid substrate. The study is done for various angle of bend (theta = 0 degrees (straight), 5 degrees, 10 degrees and 15 degrees) and Reynolds number (Re = 350, 700, 1400 and 2100). Various types of flow patterns, within one wavy-section, are presented to analyze thermal-hydraulic characteristics. Thermal hydraulic performance parameters are presented for the various wavy-sections as well as within a section; and for the complete PCHE model. Heat transfer enhancement as compared to pressure penalty is higher for the wavy channel; and increases with increasing Re and theta. Wavy as compared to plane channel based PCHE is demonstrated here to give better thermal-hydraulic performance. A detailed characteristics as well as performance-parameters for thermal hydraulics in a 3D wavy channel based PCHE model not found in the literature is presented here. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:56:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:56:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED THERMAL ENGINEERING, 87,519-528</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1359-4311</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.applthermaleng.2015.04.077</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17553</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>