<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7337</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental investigation on ductile stable crack growth emanating from wire-cut notch in AISI 4340 steel</dc:title><dc:creator>MOURAD, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALGHAFRI, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ABU ZEID, OA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>fracture-behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>brittle-fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>criterion</dc:subject><dc:subject>initiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>cleavage</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental investigation on the stable crack growth (SCG) behaviour in AISI4340 using CT type specimen with a sharp slit (0.05 mm) under mode I and mixed modes (I and II) loading is presented. The slit was made in the specimen through wire cutting technique. Different combinations of loading angle 0 and ratio of original crack length to specimen width alpha(0)/M are examined. Data concerned with direction of initial crack extension, load-load line displacement (L-LLD) diagrams, initiation and maximum loads, range of stable crack growth, crack tip blunting, crack front geometry, fracture surfaces and their scanning electron micrographs are obtained. A noticeable blunting effect is observed prior to crack initiation. Although the crack initiates from a straight front, a considerable front tunnelling effect occurs as the crack extends. Under mixed mode, the crack extension takes place initially almost along a straight path, inclined with the main crack. The loading angle and initial crack length affect the initiation (P) and maximum (Pmax) loads significantly, but the ratio between P-max and Pi remains almost constant. The direction of initial stable crack extension due to mixed mode loading is determined throughout an elastic finite element analysis. There is a good agreement between the experimental and predicted results. (C) 2004</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T22:00:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T22:00:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 235(6), 637-647</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2004.10.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7337</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7337</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>