<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16148</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T06:09:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Curcuminoids-loaded liposomes in combination with arteether protects against Plasmodium berghei infection in mice</dc:title><dc:creator>ADITYA, NP</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHIMOTE, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUNALAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATANKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADHUSUDHAN, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>Malaria</dc:subject><dc:subject>Curcuminoids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Liposomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Combination therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Parasitemia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VIVO</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIPID NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MURINE MALARIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHARMACOKINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANGIOGENESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOTHERAPY</dc:subject><dc:description>Curcuminoids are poorly water-soluble compounds with promising antimalarial activity. To overcome some of the drawbacks of curcuminoids, we explored the potential of liposomes for the intravenous delivery of curcuminoids in a model of mouse malaria. The curcuminoids-loaded liposomes were formulated from phosphatidylcholine (soy PC) by the thin-film hydration method. Antimalarial activity of curcuminoids-loaded liposomes alone and in combination with alpha/beta arteether when administered intravenously, was evaluated in Plasmodium berghei infected mice. Animals treated with curcuminoids-loaded liposomes showed lower parasitemia and higher survival when compared to control group (no treatment). Importantly, the combination therapy of curcuminoids-loaded liposomes (40 mg/kg body wt) along with alpha/beta arteether (30 mg/kg body wt) was able to not only cure infected mice but also prevented recrudescence. These data suggest that curcuminoids-loaded liposomes may show promise as a formulation for anti-malarial therapy. (C) 2012 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T06:09:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T06:09:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTAL PARASITOLOGY, 131(3)292-299</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.exppara.2012.04.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16148</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>