<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15925</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:16:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pseudo-Static and Pseudo-Dynamic Stability Analysis of Tailings Dam Under Seismic Conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Tailings earthen dam</dc:subject><dc:subject>Slope stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seismic load</dc:subject><dc:subject>Amplification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seepage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Safety factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATERFRONT RETAINING WALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EARTHQUAKE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper the seismic slope stability analyses are performed for a typical section of 44 m high water retention type tailings earthen dam located in the eastern part of India, using both the conventional pseudo-static and recent pseudo-dynamic methods. The tailings earthen dam is analyzed for different upstream conditions of reservoir like filled up with compacted and non-compacted dumped waste materials with different water levels of the pond tailings portion. Phreatic surface is generated using seepage analysis in geotechnical software SEEP/W and that same is used in the pseudo-static and pseudo-dynamic analyses to make the approach more realistic. The minimum values of factor of safety using pseudo-static and pseudo-dynamic method are obtained as 1.18 and 1.09 respectively for the chosen seismic zone in India. These values of factor of safety show clearly the demerits of conventional pseudo-static analysis compared to recent pseudo-dynamic analysis, where in addition to the seismic accelerations, duration, frequency of earthquake, body waves traveling during earthquake and amplification effects are considered.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ACAD SCIENCES INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:16:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:16:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE NATIONAL ACADEMY OF SCIENCES INDIA SECTION A-PHYSICAL SCIENCES, 83(1)63-71</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40010-013-0069-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15925</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>