<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1289</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of A-site ionic size variation on the magnetic and transport properties of (PrxSm1-x)(2/3)Sr1/3MnO3 (0 &lt;= x &lt;= 1)</dc:title><dc:creator>ASTHANA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHO, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>resistivity</dc:subject><dc:description>The effects of average A-site ionic size on magnetic and transport properties have been studied in (PrxSm1-x)(2/3)Sr1/3MnO3 (0 &lt;= x &lt;= 1) manganites with fixed carrier concentration. An effect of average Asite ionic radius (&lt; rA &gt;) with the Pr substitution has been clearly observed in the continuous changes of ferromagnetic transition temperature and metal-insulator transition temperature. The change of the resistivity with the x was explained by a variation in the hopping integral between Mn3+ and Mn4+, which is dependent on the Mn-O-Mn bond angle affected by the average A-site ionic size. Remarkably, the Smdoped manganites showed an antiferromagnetic transition by the rare-earth moments below 50 K as well as the ferromagnetic transition by Mn moments at a higher temperature. A phase diagram of (PrxSm1-x)(2/3)Sr1/3MnO3 (0 &lt;= x &lt;= 1) was successfully constructed on the basis of magnetic and transport studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T15:27:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T15:27:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICA STATUS SOLIDI B-BASIC SOLID STATE PHYSICS,244(12)4542-4545</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0370-1972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pssb.200777399</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14685</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1289</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Symposium on Advanced Magnetic Materials and Applications,Cheju Isl, SOUTH KOREA,MAY 28-JUN 01, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>