<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17485</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:22:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Deformation Twinning in Zirconium: Direct Experimental Observations and Polycrystal Plasticity Predictions</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHESH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANT, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAIBABA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHANNEL-DIE COMPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BACKSCATTERED DIFFRACTION DATA</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLANE-STRAIN COMPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEXTURE DEVELOPMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLOGRAPHIC TEXTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HARDENING RESPONSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSTITUTIVE LAW</dc:subject><dc:description>Deformation twinning was directly observed in three commercial zirconium alloy samples during split channel die plane-strain compression. One pair of samples had similar starting texture but different grain size distributions, while another pair had similar grain size distribution but different starting textures. Extension twinning was found to be more sensitive to the starting texture than to the grain size distribution. Also, regions of intense deformation near grain boundaries were observed. A hierarchical binary tree-based polycrystal plasticity model, implementing the Chin-Hosford-Mendorf twinning criterion, captured the experimentally observed twinning grains' lattice orientation distribution, and the twin volume fraction evolution, provided the critical resolved shear stress for extension twinning, was assumed much larger than any of the values reported in the literature, based on the viscoplastic self-consistent model. A comparison of the models suggests that obtained using the present model and the viscoplastic self-consistent models physically correspond to the critical stress required for twin nucleation, and twin growth, respectively. (C) The Minerals, Metals &amp; Materials Society and ASM International 2015</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:22:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:22:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 46A(11)5058-5071</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1543-1940</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-015-3085-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17485</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>