<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18000</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:02:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>2,6-Dimethylphenol derived H-phosphonate and alpha-hydroxyphosphonate: facile synthesis, crystal chemistry, supramolecular association and metal complexation</dc:title><dc:creator>HOSSAIN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>HYDROXY PHOSPHONATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNACTIVATED KETONES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTON CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMIDO COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENANTIOSELECTIVE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COORDINATION POLYMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENT SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATALYTIC-ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORGANIC FRAMEWORK</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACIDIC CONDITIONS</dc:subject><dc:description>Facile synthesis of a H-phosphonate [(ArO)P(O)H(OH)] (2) and an alpha-hydroxyarylphosphonate [(ArO)P(O)(OH)(CMe2OH)] (3) has been achieved through the hydrolysis of [(ArO)PCl2] (1) with toluene and acetone as the solvent, respectively. The dichloride (1) itself was synthesized from the reaction of ArOH (Ar = 2,6-Me2C6H3O) with phosphorous trichloride. The unstable H-phosphonate (2) and the three different crystalline modifications of the alpha-hydroxyarylphosphonate (3) (viz., ansolvate, solvate and hydrate) have been crystallized under different crystallization conditions and their molecular structures have been determined by single crystal X-ray diffraction studies. These four crystalline forms exhibit either two-dimensional sheet-like polymeric structures or tubular structures with water channels, assisted by supramolecular interactions such as H-bonding, CH-pi, etc. Crystallisation of the alpha-hydroxyarylphosphonate (3) from a warm dimethylformamide solution leads to the ready decomposition of the solvent to the dimethylammonium cation, giving the salt of 3, [Me2NH2][(ArO)(CMe2OH)POO] (6). The reactivity of the alpha-hydroxyarylphosphonate 3 with metal acetates has been investigated and its copper and zinc complexes [M(HL)(2)(2,2'-bpy)(H2O)](H2O) (M = Cu (7); Zn (8) (HL = [(ArO) P(O)(O)(CMe2OH)](-)) have been isolated and structurally characterized. Mononuclear 7 and 8 form linear polymeric chains assisted by intermolecular H-bonding interactions involving a large number of proton donor and acceptor sites present in these complexes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:02:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:02:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CRYSTENGCOMM, 17(23)4355-4366</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1466-8033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5ce00675a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18000</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>