<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-646</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic analysis and linear control strategies for proton exchange membrane fuel cell using a distributed parameter model</dc:title><dc:creator>METHEKAR, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDI, RD</dc:creator><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>linear control systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>ion exchange membranes</dc:subject><dc:description>To satisfy high power density demand in proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs), a robust control strategy is essential. A linear ratio control strategy is examined in this work. The manipulated variables are selected using steady-state relative gain array (RGA) analysis to be the inlet molar flow rates of hydrogen and coolant, and the controlled variables are average power density and average solid temperature, respectively. By selecting proper manipulated variables, the PEMFC does not exhibit sign change in gain and hence can be controlled by using a linear controller. Transfer function models obtained from step tests on the distributed parameter PEMFC model are used to design controllers for the multiple input–multiple output (MIMO) system. In addition, a ratio control strategy is proposed and evaluated, where the inlet molar flow rate of oxygen is used as a dependent manipulated variable and changed in a constant ratio with respect to the inlet molar flow rate of hydrogen. Simulation results show that the ratio control strategy provides a faster response than a MIMO control strategy. This ratio control strategy is able to circumvent the problem of oxygen starvation, and the increase in average solid temperature is small as compared to the MIMO control strategy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-16T04:41:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:53:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-16T04:41:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:53:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Power Sources 165(1), 152-170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0378-7753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2006.11.047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/646</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/646</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>