<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5927</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interfacial properties as biophysical markers of cervical cancer</dc:title><dc:creator>PREETHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HUILGOL, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>membrane-fluidity</dc:subject><dc:subject>lung-cancer</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>tensiometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>metastasis</dc:subject><dc:subject>monolayers</dc:subject><dc:subject>medicine</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>tissue monolayer</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface pressure-area isotherm</dc:subject><dc:subject>hysteresis</dc:subject><dc:subject>cervical cancer</dc:subject><dc:subject>minimum surface tension</dc:subject><dc:description>Monolayers at air-liquid interfaces offer a convenient model for understanding the behavior of many natural systems like biological membranes. Langmuir monolayers were used to characterize the interfacial properties of tissue homogenates, organic phases and aqueous phases of tissue biopsy samples from 30 patients of cervical cancer and 15 normals. Our results reveal that the tensiometric parameters can differentiate between cancer and normal tissues obtained from human cervix and were statistically significant using t test (P &lt; 0.05). The minimum surface tension of the cancer tissue monolayer was 52.9 +/- 4.4 mN/m, 1.4-folds greater than the normal cervical tissue homogenate value of 38.5 +/- 2.6 mN/m. The normal tissue homogenate isotherm had a hysteresis area of 90.3 mu J, which was approximately 6.2 times greater than that of the cervical cancer tissue monolayer. The total lipid and phospholipid contents of the cancerous cervical tissue were roughly double that of the normal cervical tissue and the surface activity was also in line with this observation. The difference in hysteresis of the cancerous and normal tissues indicates a decreased stability of the cancerous tissue film as compared to normal. The difference in surface activity denotes alterations in the molecular packing of the tissues in the cancerous state, which may have implications in terms of drug permeability and responsiveness. Further, differences in surface activity may play a role in altered cell adhesion and metastasis. This study is the first to evaluate surface properties of cancerous tissues and can lead to the development of a biophysical marker of cervical cancer based on inter-facial properties. (c) 2005 Elsevier SAS. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER FRANCE-EDITIONS SCIENTIFIQUES MEDICALES ELSEVIER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T16:51:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T16:51:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOMEDICINE &amp; PHARMACOTHERAPY, 59(9), 491-497</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0753-3322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biopha.2005.02.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5927</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5927</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>