<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2034</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optical analysis of scanning microstereolithography systems - art. no. 61090C</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUBEY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>microstereolithography</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-fabrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>mems</dc:subject><dc:description>Microstereolithography (MSL) is rapidly developing technique for micro-fabrication. Vector-by-vector scanning MSL has a potential to create true 3D micro-devices as compared to mostly planar (2D-21/2D) devices fabricated by conventional MEMS techniques. Previous literature shows two different scanning methods :(1) Galvanomirror scanning, (2) Photoreactor tank scanning. Galvanomirror scanning technique has higher fabrication speed but poor resolution because of defocusing of laser spot on the resin surface. Photo-reactor tank scanning has higher resolution but produces a wavy structures and limited speed of fabrication. This paper proposes and develops an offaxis lens scanning technique for MSL and carries out optical analysis to compare its performance with the existing techniques mentioned above. The comparison clearly demonstrates improved performance with the proposed offaxis lens scanning technique.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T02:37:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T02:37:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Micromachining and Microfabrication Process Technology XI,6109,C1090-C1090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-6151-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.645856</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2034</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Micromachining and Microfabrication Process Technology XI,San Jose, CA,JAN 25, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>