<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14315</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T09:42:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tensile stress induced depolarization in [001]-poled transverse mode Pb(Zn(1)/3Nb(2/3))O(3) -(6-7)%PbTiO(3) single crystals</dc:title><dc:creator>SHUKLA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIM, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper investigates the effects of electrically induced and direct tensile stress on the deformation and dielectric properties of Pb(Zn(1)/3Nb(2/3))O(3)-(6- 7)% PbTiO(3) single crystals of [110](L) x [001](T) cut by using a unimorph sample and a four-point-bend (FPB) sample, respectively. The results show a dip in tip displacement for the unimorph sample at sufficiently high electric field parallel to the poling field direction and a sudden rise in capacitance for the FPB sample at sufficiently high tensile stress in the [110] crystal direction, respectively. These phenomena are attributed to the tensile stress induced rhombohedral-to-orthorhombic phase transition and associated depolarization events in the crystal. For the said crystal cut, the obtained tensile depoling stress is in the range of 15-20 MPa. The present work furthermore shows that the occurrence of tensile stress-induced depolarization is possible even when the direction of the applied electric field is parallel to the poling field direction, as in the unimorph sample examined. (C) 2011 American Institute of Physics. [doi:10.1063/1.3552587]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:42:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:42:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS,109(7)-</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3552587</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14315</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>