<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11588</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of accuracy of high-aspect-ratio holes generated using micro-electric discharge machining drilling</dc:title><dc:creator>PURANIK, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>edm process</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>micromachining</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-edm drilling</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-holes</dc:subject><dc:subject>oversize</dc:subject><dc:subject>analysis of means (aom)</dc:subject><dc:subject>analysis of variance (anova)</dc:subject><dc:subject>taguchi methods</dc:subject><dc:description>Micro-electric discharge machining (micro-EDM) has evolved as one of the prominent processes to generate high-aspect-ratio and accurate micro-structures in many industrial applications. This paper presents an extensive experimental analysis of the micro-EDM process to explore the relationship between accuracy as a function of depth of micro-holes drilled using micro-EDM drilling. It is shown that a depth of 5.0 mm can be achieved by a 200 mu m diameter tool electrode while controlling the regular process parameters, but beyond this length, the process is governed by a number of derived phenomena such as secondary sparking, debris accumulation, etc. instead of the regular processing parameters. The optimum depth of the hole that could be achieved with a good accuracy i.e. a minimum oversize lies between 2.5 and 5.0 mm, the largest depth that could be achieved was 8.33 mm. The highest aspect ratio achieved in this experiment was 15.63.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERING PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T07:43:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T07:43:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART B-JOURNAL OF ENGINEERING MANUFACTURE, 222(11), 1453-1464</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0954-4054</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1243/09544054JEM1186</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11588</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11588</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>