<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17281</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:12:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mercuration of apo-alpha-lactalbumin: binding of Hg2+ followed by protein-mediated nanoparticle formation</dc:title><dc:creator>THAWARI, AG</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEMGIRE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GOLD NANOCLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILVER</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:description>Nanoparticles and nanocrystals of mercury are formed when Hg2+ salt reacts with apo-alpha-lactalbumin (apoa-alpha-LA). Reduction followed by nanoparticle formation is further augmented by the protein, as it also acts as a coating agent. The initial interaction of Hg2+ with apo-alpha-LA was demonstrated by changes observed in absorption, emission, and CD spectroscopy, where the latter technique also detected structural changes in the protein. Such structural changes are expected when Hg2+ binds to the protein, and therefore, the binding was determined by isothermal titration calorimetry (ITC). The binding was further proven by MALDI, which showed mercurated species of protein with a Gaussian distribution exhibiting a weighted average of 6 and 9 Hg2+ ions bound to protein when apo-alpha-LA was treated with 10 and 100 equivalents, respectively. The molecular dynamics studies revealed the binding of Hg2+ ions followed by the structural changes that occurred in the protein. The reaction between Hg2+ and apo-alpha-LA yields noncrystalline nanoparticles at lower molar ratios of Hg2+ and crystalline ones at higher molar ratios. The existence of both of these nanoparticles was proven by extensive TEM studies, and the mercury nanocrystals were further studied using fluorescence microscopy. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy demonstrated that the protein has the ability to convert Hg2+ to Hg-0, and the resultant Hg-0 cluster is known to be less harmful than Hg2+ to the organism. All of these studies support the use of apo-alpha-LA in the form of nanoparticles and nanocrystals to detoxify Hg2+.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:12:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:12:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 4(96)53429-53436</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4ra07156e</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17281</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>