<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5335</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of dynamic strain ageing on the tensile properties of a modified 9Cr-1Mo steel</dc:title><dc:creator>KISHORE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>serrated flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:description>Tensile testing of a modified 9Cr-.1Mo steel in two microstructural conditions (710T - normalized at 1100 degrees C, tempered at 710 degrees C, and 550T - normalized at 1100 degrees C tempered at 550 degrees C) in the temperature range 25-450 degrees C, under strain rates of 2.3 x 10(-5)-2.3 x 10(-3) s(-1) exhibited serrated flow curves, with serrations appearing almost at the onset of deformation and disappearing before ultimate strengths were attained. The serrated flow curves (characteristics of dynamic strain ageing) were accompanied by increased ultimate strengths, loss of ductility and negative strain-rate sensitivity, relative to the ambient temperature properties. However, the increase in ultimate strength and the reduction in ductility were much larger for 710T specimens, as compared to 550T ones. In the dynamic strain ageing regime, the work-hardenability of 710T specimens increased rapidly while that of 550T specimens remained practically unaffected. Based on the microstructural consideration and the observed activation energy of 45 kJ mol(-1), it is proposed that serrations are initiated by a nitrogen atmosphere formation on the waiting dislocations by a pipe diffusion mechanism, and they disappear by diffusion to the precipitate sinks during deformation. Because the fine alloy carbide precipitates in 550T specimens are more effective sinks than those of 710T ones, they can cause much faster depletion of the atmosphere, resulting in a much smaller effect of dynamic strain ageing on the tensile properties of 550T specimens.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CHAPMAN HALL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T14:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T14:56:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE, 32(2), 437-442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-2461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1018569803900</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5335</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5335</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>