<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11546</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>BLOOD-VISCOSITY PARAMETER CORRELATION WITH TYPES OF LEUKEMIA</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>ADVANI, SH</dc:creator><dc:creator>HEGDE, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, S</dc:creator><dc:description>We investigated the hemorheological, hematological and biochemical parameters in 30 cases of acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL), 21 cases of acute myelogenous leukemia (AML) and 30 cases of chronic myelogenous leukemia (CML). The parameters studied include whole blood viscosity, plasma viscosity, erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), red cell filterability, hematocrit, platelet count and aggregation, fibrinogen, hemoglobin, leucocyte count, bleeding time and lactate dehydrogenase activity (LDH). In the cases of ALL we observed significant decrease in whole blood viscosity, hemoglobin, hematocrit and platelet count but an increase in plasma viscosity, fibrinogen, bleeding time and LDH activity. In the cases of AML, we observed increase in whole blood viscosity, plasma viscosity, ESR, fibrinogen, leucocyte count, bleeding time and LDH activity but decrease in the hemoglobin, hematocrit and platelet count. In the cases of CML, we observed an increase of whole blood viscosity, plasma viscosity, ESR, fibrinogen elevation but decreases in bleeding time. In all cases, red cell filterability was unaffected.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PHYSIOL CHEM PHYSICS MED NMR</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T05:07:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T05:07:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY AND PHYSICS AND MEDICAL NMR, 24(2), 159-164</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0748-6642</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11546</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>