<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18097</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:52:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Disaster Vulnerability Mapping for a Densely Populated Coastal Urban Area: An Application to Mumbai, India</dc:title><dc:creator>SHERLY, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARMAKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARTHASARATHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAN, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAU, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>DATA ENVELOPMENT ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOCIAL VULNERABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NATURAL DISASTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOCIOECONOMIC VULNERABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENVIRONMENTAL HAZARDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADAPTIVE CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IDENTIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDICATORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADAPTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>coastal urban areas</dc:subject><dc:subject>critical facilities vulnerability</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEA</dc:subject><dc:subject>disaster management</dc:subject><dc:subject>infrastructure vulnerability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mumbai</dc:subject><dc:subject>PCA</dc:subject><dc:subject>socioeconomic vulnerability</dc:subject><dc:subject>(DEA)</dc:subject><dc:subject>?????(PCA)</dc:subject><dc:subject>areas urbanas costeras</dc:subject><dc:subject>vulnerabilidad de las instalaciones criticas</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEA</dc:subject><dc:subject>manejo de desastres</dc:subject><dc:subject>vulnerabilidad de la infraestructura</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bombay</dc:subject><dc:subject>PCA</dc:subject><dc:subject>vulnerabilidad socioeconomica</dc:subject><dc:description>Coastal urban cities frequently face multiple hazards, including potentially disastrous extreme events. To combat this, vulnerability assessment is essential to developing an effective mitigation strategy. This study proposes a framework to assess the vulnerability of any densely populated urban area to disasters by considering both the population and the assets that are at risk. A set of indicators is also proposed to assess the vulnerability of social and socioeconomic systems, infrastructure, critical facilities, and adaptive capacity. The components of vulnerability were evaluated individually, using an accessible open source geographic information system at a fine 1-km grid scale, providing an insight into the spatial variability of the vulnerability. The optimal weight for individual indicators was assigned using data envelopment analysis to minimize subjective judgment and establish confidence in the results obtained. To decorrelate and reduce the dimensionality of the multivariate data, principal component analysis was performed. The proposed methodology was demonstrated on the twenty-four wards of Mumbai under the jurisdiction of the Municipal Corporation of Greater Mumbai and showed the mideastern part of Mumbai as the most vulnerablemainly due to the increase in population and the marginal workers' ratio. A reduction in social vulnerability has been observed, however, across the city through improvement in the literacy rate and the main workers' ratio. ????????????,???????????????????????,?????????????????????????????????????????,???????????????????????????????????????,??????????????????????????????????????????,????????????????????????????,????????????????????????,???????????,????????,???????????????????????????,???????????????????,????????????????????????????,???????????????????????????????????????????,??????????????????,?????????? Las ciudades costeras a menudo enfrentan multiples riesgos, incluso eventos extremos potencialmente desastrosos. Para contrarrestar esto, es esencial la evaluacion de vulnerabilidad, a partir de lo cual desarrollar una estrategia efectiva de atenuacion. Este estudio propone un marco para evaluar la vulnerabilidad al desastre de cualquier area urbana densamente poblada, tomando en cuenta tanto la poblacion como los bienes que estan en riesgo. Se propone tambien un conjunto de indicadores para evaluar la vulnerabilidad de los sistemas sociales y socioeconomicos, la infraestructura, las instalaciones criticas y la capacidad de adaptacion. Los componentes de vulnerabilidad fueron evaluados individualmente utilizando un sistema de informacion geografica con fuente de acceso abierto, en reticula de escala fina de 1-km, que proporciona una vision valida del caracter variable de la vulnerabilidad en terminos espaciales. El peso optimo de los indicadores individuales se asigno usando el analisis de envolvimiento de datos para minimizar el juicio subjetivo y crear confianza sobre los resultados obtenidos. Se ejecuto un analisis de componentes principales para decorrelacionar y reducir la dimensionalidad de los datos multivariados. La metodologia propuesta fue demostrada en veinticuatro distritos de Bombay, bajo jurisdiccion de la Corporacion Municipal del Gran Bombay, mostrando la parte medio-oriental de la ciudad como la mas vulnerableprincipalmente debido al incremento de la poblacion y a la proporcion de trabajadores ocasionales. Sin embargo, se ha observado una reduccion de la vulnerabilidad social a traves de la ciudad, gracias a mejoramiento de la tasa de alfabetismo y de la proporcion de trabajadores mas estables.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROUTLEDGE JOURNALS, TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:52:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:52:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANNALS OF THE ASSOCIATION OF AMERICAN GEOGRAPHERS, 105(6)1198-1220</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0004-5608</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1467-8306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00045608.2015.1072792</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18097</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>