<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18244</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:12:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Part I: Physical Insights Into the Two-Stage Breakdown Characteristics of STI-Type Drain-Extended pMOS Device</dc:title><dc:creator>TAILOR, KH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHRIVASTAVA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOSSNER, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Avalanche breakdown</dc:subject><dc:subject>drain-extended MOSFET (DeMOS)</dc:subject><dc:subject>input-output (I/O)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kirk effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>parasitic bipolar triggering</dc:subject><dc:subject>safe operating area (SOA)</dc:subject><dc:subject>shallow-trench isolation (STI)</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-stage breakdown</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we study breakdown characteristics in shallow-trench isolation (STI)-type drain-extended MOSFETs (DeMOS) fabricated using a low-power 65-nm triple-well CMOS process with a thin gate oxide. Experimental data of p-type STI-DeMOS device showed distinct two-stage behavior in breakdown characteristics in both OFF-and ON-states, unlike the n-type device, causing a reduction in the breakdown voltage and safe operating area. The first-stage breakdown occurs due to punchthrough in the vertical structure formed by p-well, deep n-well, and p-substrate, whereas the second-stage breakdown occurs due to avalanche breakdown of lateral n-well/p-well junction. The breakdown characteristics are also compared with the STI-DeNMOS device structure. Using the experimental results and advanced TCAD simulations, a complete understanding of breakdown mechanisms is provided in this paper for STI-DeMOS devices in advanced CMOS processes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:12:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:12:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ELECTRON DEVICES, 62(12)4097-4104</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9383</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9646</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TED.2015.2481899</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18244</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>