<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11046</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling of vibration of beam in presence of inclined edge or internal crack for its possible detection based on frequency measurements</dc:title><dc:creator>NANDWANA, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>natural frequencies</dc:subject><dc:subject>damage detection</dc:subject><dc:subject>cantilever beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>identification</dc:subject><dc:subject>location</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration modelling of cracked beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration based detection of crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>ndt of crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>inclined edge crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>internal crack</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper modelling of transverse vibration of a slender beam in the presence of an inclined edge, or internal normal, crack using a rotational spring has been done to enable a possible detection of location of the crack based on the measurement of natural frequencies. The characteristic equation obtained from the vibration analysis of the beam is manipulated to give a relationship between the stiffness of the spring and the location of the crack. Plots of spring stiffness vs crack locations are obtained for the three lowest transverse modes using this relationship. Their common intersection point gives the crack location and the corresponding stiffness. Through a large number of numerical examples it has been shown that in the case of an inclined edge crack the modelling through the rotational spring is feasible for at least small crack angles and the error in the prediction of crack location is less than 4.5%. In the case of the internal crack the performance is satisfactory provided the crack size is more than 20% of the section depth. (C) 1997 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T14:20:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T14:20:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 58(3), 193-205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0013-7944(97)00078-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11046</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>