<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5260</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flanking microstructures</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOYI, HA</dc:creator><dc:subject>simple shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformable inclusions</dc:subject><dc:subject>himalayan orogen</dc:subject><dc:subject>analog models</dc:subject><dc:subject>folds</dc:subject><dc:subject>faults</dc:subject><dc:subject>sense</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonsense</dc:subject><dc:subject>flanking microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>flanking structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>ductile shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>higher himalayan crystallines</dc:subject><dc:description>Ductile sheared rocks of the Higher Himalayan Crystalline unit (HHC) in micro-scale reveal flanking microstructures defined by nucleated minerals (the cross-cutting elements, CEs), and deflected cleavages and grain margins (the host Fabric elements, HEs) of other minerals. Depending on different or the same senses of drag across the cross-cutting elements, the flanking microstructures are grouped into Type 1 or Type 2 varieties, respectively. Cross-cutting elements of Type 2 flanking microstructures connote post-tectonic directional growth. The cross-cutting elements of the Type I flanking microstructures consistently demonstrate top-to-SW non-coaxial shearing in the Higher Himalayan Crystalline unit. Here the external host fabric elements bounding the cross-cutting elements act as the C-planes. These cross-cutting element minerals are usually parallelogram-shaped, underwent crystal-plastic deformation and their nucleations are pre- or syntectonic. The facts that the host fabric elements are dragged even in absence of rheological softening at the boundaries of the cross-cutting elements, and that the cross-cutting elements are non-rigid, indicate strong bonds between the host fabric elements and the cross-cutting elements. Salient morphological variations in the flanking microstructures are: (1) variable intensity and senses of drag along the single and the opposite crosscutting element margins; (2) host fabric elements defined only at one side of the cross-cutting elements; and (3) presence of a thin hazy zone at the HE-CE contacts. The observed cross-cutting element minerals are either of nearly the same or of greater competency than the mineral grains which host them.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CAMBRIDGE UNIV PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T10:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T10:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOLOGICAL MAGAZINE, 146(4), 517-526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7568</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1017/S0016756809005986</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5260</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5260</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>