<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14540</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:13:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling of Gas Metal Arc Welding Process Using an Analytically Determined Volumetric Heat Source</dc:title><dc:creator>SYED, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PITTNER, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RETHMEIER, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>gas metal arc welding</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat conduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>volumetric heat source</dc:subject><dc:subject>experimental validation</dc:subject><dc:subject>PULSE PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUID-FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:description>High peak temperature and continuous deposition of electrode droplets in the weld puddle inhibit real-time monitoring of thermal cycles and bead dimensions in gas metal arc welding. A three-dimensional numerical heat transfer model is presented here to compute temperature field and bead dimensions considering a volumetric heat source to account for the transfer of arc energy into the weld pool. The heat source dimensions are analytically estimated as function of welding conditions and original joint geometry. The deposition of electrode material is modeled using deactivation and activation of discrete elements in a presumed V-groove joint geometry. The computed values of bead dimensions and thermal cycles are validated with the corresponding measured results. A comparison of the analytically estimated heat source dimensions and the corresponding numerically computed bead dimensions indicate that the former could rightly serve as the basis for conduction heat transfer based models of gas metal arc welding process.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IRON STEEL INST JAPAN KEIDANREN KAIKAN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:13:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:13:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ISIJ INTERNATIONAL, 53(4)698-703</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2355/isijinternational.53.698</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14540</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>