<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11034</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>MIXED CONVECTION HEAT-TRANSFER FROM THE BOTTOM TIP OF A CYLINDER SPINNING ABOUT A VERTICAL AXIS IN A SATURATED POROUS-MEDIUM</dc:title><dc:creator>KAMATH, RV</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARATHE, AG</dc:creator><dc:subject>natural-convection</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work is a numerical study of heat transfer characteristics from the bottom tip of a cylinder spinning about a vertical axis in an infinitely saturated porous medium. The problem is axisymmetic. The non-dimensionalized governing equations are solved using the SIMPLER algorithm on a staggered grid. The influence of rotational Reynolds numbers and Darcy numbers on the heat transfer for a Grashof number of 10(4) and Prandtl number of 7.0 is studied. It is found that for very high Darcy numbers, over a wide range of rotational Reynolds numbers, the heat transfer takes place mainly due to conduction. The convective heat transfer takes place for lower Darcy numbers and for higher rotational Reynolds numbers. Moreover, there is a rapid increase in the overall Nusselt number below a certain Darcy number with increase in the rotational Reynolds numbers. The effect of the Darcy number and the rotational Reynolds number on the heat transfer and fluid flow in the porous medium is depicted in the form of streamline and isotherm plots. The variation of the overall Nusselt number with respect to the Darcy number for various rotational Reynolds numbers is plotted. The variation of the local Nusselt number with respect to the radial coordinate at the heated tip of the vertical cylinder is plotted for various Darcy and rotational Reynolds numbers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T13:34:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T13:34:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 35(4), 823-832</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0017-9310(92)90250-V</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11034</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11034</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>