<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9565</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Unified conceptual approach to targeting and design of water and hydrogen networks</dc:title><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHENOY, UV</dc:creator><dc:subject>mass-exchange networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-process plants</dc:subject><dc:subject>pinch analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>supply chains</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow-rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>minimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>process systems engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>network design and optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>mass transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>pinch analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>water minimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen management</dc:subject><dc:description>An algorithm is proposed to target the minimum freshwater for fixed flow rate (FF) problems in single-contaminant water networks. The approach is based on an extension of the limiting composite curve concept proposed earlier for fixed contaminant-load (FC) problems. The targeting method is elegant, noniterative, and can be applied to FF problems involving regeneration to minimize waste discharge. To design networks that achieve the minimum freshwater targets set for FF problems, an algorithm is presented based on the principle of nearest neighbors. The principle simply states that the sources to be chosen to satisfy a particular water demand must be the nearest available neighbors in terms of contaminant concentration. A significant advantage of the approach is that the same targeting concepts can be profitably used to determine the minimum makeup utility in hydrogen networks. Furthermore, hydrogen networks may be designed by the unified conceptual approach using the nearest neighbors algorithm. The hydrogen networks may then be evolved to account for the pressure constraints imposed by compressors or improved by regeneration through purification processes such as pressure-swing adsorption. (c) 2005 American Institute of Chemical Engineers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:04:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:04:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AICHE JOURNAL, 52(3), 1071-1082</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0001-1541</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/aic.10724</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9565</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9565</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>