<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12478</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Casting product-process-producer compatibility evaluation and improvement</dc:title><dc:creator>AKARTE, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>analytic hierarchy process</dc:subject><dc:subject>process selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>decision</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>casting</dc:subject><dc:subject>design for manufacture</dc:subject><dc:subject>foundry</dc:subject><dc:subject>process selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>supplier selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>analytic hierarchy process</dc:subject><dc:description>The manufacturability of a cast product depends on process capabilities, which in turn depend on the facilities of the producer ( foundry). Selecting the right combination of the product, process, and producer to simultaneously optimize functionality and manufacturability considerations is a challenging task. This paper presents a multi-criteria methodology that integrates the hitherto separate problems of process and producer selection, by introducing the concept of an ideal foundry. A set of 25 common criteria ( 11 objective and 14 subjective type) grouped under six headings ( geometry, quality, production, delivery, facility, and other), have been identified to evaluate the process and the producer. Objective criteria are assessed using a fuzzy logic approach, whereas a rating method has been employed to accommodate subjective criteria. An analytical hierarchy process has been used to obtain the relative importance of the evaluation criteria. The methodology is also useful for benchmarking of foundries, and feedback for improving product-process compatibility. This is illustrated with an industrial example of a steel impeller casting.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T22:04:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T22:04:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION RESEARCH, 45(21), 4917-4936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7543</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00207540600887661</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12478</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12478</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>