<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7081</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-20T11:41:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>THE MORPHOLOGY AND AGING BEHAVIOR OF DELTA-FERRITE IN A MODIFIED 9CR-1MO STEEL</dc:title><dc:creator>KISHORE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:description>Dual phase (martensite + delta-ferrite) microstructures were developed in a modified 9Cr-1Mo steel, by austenitising at 1523-1623 K, followed by water-quenching. These duplex structures were thermally aged at 973 K for ageing periods varying from 30 min to 21 h. Morphological aspects of delta-ferrite phase and its response to age-hardening were studied by optical, scanning electron and transmission electron microscopy, X-ray diffraction, electron probe microanalysis and microhardness testing. It was observed that austenitizing at 1523 K produced fine, acicular delta-ferrite while the delta-ferrite formed by austenitising at higher temperatures (1573-623 K) were massive, irregular-shaped and banded. Moreover the presence of delta-ferrite caused an abnormally strong (110) reflection, observed in X-ray diffraction patterns of martensite plus delta-ferrite structures. This behaviour is thought to be due to development of (110) texture in delta-ferrite phase. Thermal ageing at 973 K caused age-hardening of delta-ferrite with a peak hardness attained after 3.6 ks of ageing. Electron microscopic results suggest that the observed hardening was caused by the formation of Fe2Mo Laves phase.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T02:06:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T02:06:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MATERIALS, 195(1-2), 198-204</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0022-3115(92)90377-W</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7081</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7081</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>