<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10558</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Asymmetric entrainment effect on the local surface temperature of a flat plate heated by an obliquely impinging two-dimensional jet</dc:title><dc:creator>VIPAT, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>FENG, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRADEEP, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>LU, TJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>circular air-jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>asymmetric entrainment</dc:subject><dc:subject>cold jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>heated jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>inclination</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-dimensional jet</dc:subject><dc:description>The flow and temperature fields caused by a two-dimensional heating air jet obliquely impinging on a flat plate are experimentally characterized. Whilst the jet flow is discharged at Re(Dh) = 8.2 X 10(3) based on the hydraulic diameter of the orifice, D(h), and the jet exit-to-plate spacing (separation distance) is fixed at 8D(h). the impingement angle (inclination) is systematically decreased from 90 degrees (normal impinging) to 30, (oblique impinging). A separate experiment is carried out for a two-dimensional cooling jet obliquely impinging on a heated plate (constant heat flux). The results demonstrate that the response of local surface temperature to plate inclination behaves in a completely different manner. For impinging jet cooling, the inclination (from normal impinging position) reduces the local effective temperature values at corresponding points about actual stagnation point, inclusive of it. For impinging jet heating, the inclination causes, conversely, an increase in local surface temperature including the stagnation point temperature. However, the shifting of the actual stagnation point towards the uphill side of the plate is consistently observed for both hot and cold jet cases. This newly found feature for an obliquely impinging jet is attributed to the combined effects of asymmetric entrainment and momentum redistribution (i.e., thickening/thinning of hydraulic boundary layers on each side of the plate with respect to the actual stagnation point). (C) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T15:27:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T15:27:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 52(21-22), 5250-5257</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2009.04.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10558</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>