<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17984</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:54:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Arginine-assisted immobilization of silver nanoparticles on ZnO nanorods: an enhanced and reusable antibacterial substrate without human cell cytotoxicity</dc:title><dc:creator>AGNIHOTRI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJAJ, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>ANTIMICROBIAL ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>AG</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICACY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:description>Silver-based hybrid nanomaterials are gaining interest as potential alternatives for conventional antimicrobial agents. Herein, we present a simple, facile and eco-friendly approach for the deposition of silver nanoparticles (AgNPs) on ZnO nanorods, which act as a nanoreactor for in situ synthesis and as an immobilizing template in the presence of arginine. The presence of arginine enhanced the stability of ZnO deposition on the glass substrate by hindering the dissolution of zinc under alkaline conditions. Various Ag/ZnO hybrid nanorod (HNR) samples were screened to obtain a high amount of silver immobilization on the ZnO substrate. Ag/ZnO HNRs displayed potent antibacterial ability and could achieve 100% kill for both Escherichia coli and Bacillus subtilis strains under various test conditions. The hybrid material mediated its dual mode of antibacterial action through direct contact-killing and release of silver ions/nanoparticles and showed superior bactericidal performance compared to pure ZnO nanorods and colloidal AgNPs. No significant decline in antibacterial efficacy was observed even after the same substrate was repeatedly reused multiple times. Interestingly, the amount of Ag and Zn release was much below their maximal limit in drinking water, thus preventing potential health hazards. Immobilized AgNPs showed no cytotoxic effects on the human hepatocarcinoma cell line (HepG2). Moreover, treating cells with the antibacterial substrate for 24 hours did not lead to significant generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS). The good biocompatibility and bactericidal efficacy would thus make it feasible to utilize this immobilization strategy for preparing new-generation antibacterial coatings.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:54:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:54:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOSCALE, 7(16)7415-7429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2040-3364</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2040-3372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4nr06913g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17984</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>