<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6584</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Estimation of monthly averaged direct normal solar radiation using elevation angle for any location</dc:title><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANGANI, CS</dc:creator><dc:subject>diffuse</dc:subject><dc:subject>insolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar pv/thermal concentrator</dc:subject><dc:subject>direct normal solar radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>monthly averaged daily and hourly global radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>monthly averaged daily and hourly diffuse radiation</dc:subject><dc:description>Light concentrators used in solar photovoltaic and solar thermal applications, and concentrates light by a factor of 10 or more, use only direct normal solar radiation, IN. A new method, called elevation angle constant (EAC) method, is developed to determine the resource potential of IN for different locations. This method is applicable to estimate the IN at any location in the world. The EAC method is based on empirical relations. The method calculates the elevation angle constant (c) for a given location and time. It uses readily available daily global and diffuse global radiation data to estimate the IN. This is different from existing methods which invariably uses hourly global and diffuse radiation. The values of IN are estimated for 12 locations across the world. The values of IN obtained using the EAC method have been compared with values obtained using the model-based approach (Appendix-1). The comparison is also done with the measured values for some stations. Ninety percent of the estimated values of IN using the EAC method for the stations like Angola, Egypt, Kuala Lumpur, Singapore, Brussels, Stuttgart, Ottawa, Birmingham, Los Angeles, Wellington, Perth and New Delhi are within +/- 5% of the values estimated by the model-based approach (Appendix-1). (c) 2007</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T00:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T00:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLAR ENERGY MATERIALS AND SOLAR CELLS, 92(1), 38-44</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-0248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.solmat.2007.08.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6584</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6584</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>