<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14687</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:30:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of carbon encapsulated iron oxide/iron carbide nanocomposite for hyperthermia</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANTRI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>X-Ray diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transmission electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saturation magnetization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hyperthermia</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOMAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ETHANOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIELD</dc:subject><dc:description>Magnetic nanocomposite has been synthesized successfully using biopolymer route which acts as a source of carbon for carbide formation. The present approach based on thermal decomposition represents a considerable advance over previous reports that often use high-energy procedures or costly and hazardous precursors. X-ray diffraction, high-resolution transmission electron microscopy and vibrating sample magnetometer have been used to characterize the composites. Multi phase formation is evident from X-ray diffraction in the as-prepared samples. Phase confirmation was further done from M (magnetization) versus T (temperature) curve indicating presence of different phases of carbide along with iron oxide. TEM study suggests formation of cuboidal shape nanocomposite using two different quenching conditions. Transmission electron microscopy also confirmed the formation of carbon layer in the vicinity of the Fe3O4/Fe3C nanoparticles. The magnetic measurement shows that the composite nanoparticles exhibit a maximum magnetization of 60 emu g(-1) at room temperature. Biocompatibility study with three different cell lines (HeLa, MCF-7 and L929) confirms that these nanocomposites are biocompatible. Temperature versus time measurement in an AC field suggests good heating ability of the samples. These investigations indicate that these nanocomposites may be useful for bioapplications, in particular for hyperthermia. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:30:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:30:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS, 324(23)3975-3980</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmmm.2012.05.059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14687</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>