<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9168</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Phase coexistence, microstructure and magnetism in Ni-Mn-Sb alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, NVR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKARAN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:subject>shape-memory alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>heusler alloy</dc:subject><dc:description>We present here a detailed investigation on the structural and magnetic transformations in the Ni(50)Mn(50-x)Sb(x) Heusler alloys with composition x = 12, 13 and 14. The evolution of martensitic to austenitic transformation has been investigated using temperature dependent x-ray diffraction study. A wide region of phase coexistence is observed across the martensitic transformation. The unit cell volume contracts by 0.82% and 0.74% for x = 12 and 14, respectively, at the martensitic transformation temperature. The martensitic transition temperature decreases with increase in Sb concentration. The magnetic interactions in the martensitic and austenitic phases are found to be ferromagnetic, however, with different strengths, giving rise to two separate magnetic transitions with T(C)(M) &lt; T(C)(A). The magnetization studies reveal the presence of antiferromagnetic-ferromagnetic interactions in the alloys. Exchange bias blocking temperature has been observed around 100 K for the alloy x = 12. Magnetic field induced structural transition has been observed in x = 14 alloy, in which the structural transition temperature shifts by 25 K in a field of 3 T.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T23:03:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T23:03:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS D-APPLIED PHYSICS, 42(6), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3727</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0022-3727/42/6/065002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9168</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9168</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>