<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16556</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:37:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Elucidation of Band Structure of Charge Storage in Conducting Polymers Using a Redox Reaction</dc:title><dc:creator>CONTRACTOR, AQ</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:subject>METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYANILINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILM</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel technique to investigate charge storage characteristics of intrinsically conducting polymer films has been developed. A redox reaction is conducted on a polymer film on a rotating disk electrode under potentiostatic condition so that the rate of charging of the film equals the rate of removal of the charge by the reaction. The voltammogram obtained from the experiment on polyaniline film using Fe2+/Fe3+ in HCl as the redox system shows five distinct linear segments (bands) with discontinuity in the slope at specific transition potentials. These bands are the same as those indicated by electron spin resonance (ESR)/Raman spectroscopy with comparable transition potentials. From the dependence of the slopes of the bands on concentration of ferrous and ferric ions, it was possible to estimate the energies of the charge carriers in different bands. The film behaves as a redox capacitor and does not offer resistance to charge transfer and electronic conduction.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:37:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:37:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANALYTICAL CHEMISTRY, 86(13)6323-6330</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-2700</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-6882</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ac500440d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16556</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>