<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4254</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intensification of instantaneous heterogeneous reaction by simple salts and charged microphase</dc:title><dc:creator>HASNAT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>reversible-reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>micellar catalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>absorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>diffusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>co2</dc:subject><dc:description>The mass-transfer rate for the instantaneous heterogeneous reaction between N,N-diethylaniline (organic phase) and HCl in the aqueous phase was determined in the presence of a number of supporting electrolytes, that is, NaCl, SrCl2, AlCl3, and cetyltrimethyl ammonium bromide surfactant micelle. Both the simple salts and the cationic surfactant enhance the mass transfer of the reactive H+ ion, the effectiveness being in the order of CTAB &gt; AlCl3 &gt; SrCl2 &gt; NaCl. The experimentally observed enhancement factor for the reaction in the presence of the supporting electrolytes ranges from 1.3 to 6. This enhancement is explained on the basis of the "ion-coupling" effect that augments the diffusive fluxes of the more mobile ionic species in a multi-ion system. The film-theory approximation is used to obtain theoretical estimates of the enhancement factor, and these are found to be in reasonably good agreement with the experimentally obtained values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST CHEMICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T11:15:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T11:15:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AICHE JOURNAL, 44(3), 656-666</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0001-1541</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/aic.690440314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4254</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>