<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17305</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:25:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic Calibration and Validation of an Accelerometer Force Balance for Hypersonic Lifting Models</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIVEDI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENEZES, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSEINI, H</dc:creator><dc:description>An accelerometer-based force balance was designed and developed for the measurement of drag, lift, and rolling moment on a blunt-nosed, flapped delta wing in a short-duration hypersonic shock tunnel. Calibration and validation of the balance were carried out by a convolution technique using hammer pulse test and surface pressure measurements. In the hammer pulse test, a known impulse was applied to the model in the appropriate direction using an impulse hammer, and the corresponding output of the balance (acceleration) was recorded. Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) was operated on the output of the balance to generate a system response function, relating the signal output to the corresponding load input. Impulse response functions for three components of the balance, namely, axial, normal, and angular, were obtained for a range of input load. The angular system response function was corresponding to rolling of the model. The impulse response functions thus obtained, through dynamic calibration, were operated on the output (signals) of the balance under hypersonic aerodynamic loading conditions in the tunnel to get the time history of the unknown aerodynamic forces and moments acting on the model. Surface pressure measurements were carried out on the model using high frequency pressure transducers, and forces and moments were deduced thereon. Tests were carried out at model angles of incidence of 0, 5, 10, and 15 degrees. A good agreement was observed among the results of different experimental methods. The balance developed is a comprehensive force/moment measurement device that can be used on complex, lifting, aerodynamic geometries in ground-based hypersonic test facilities.</dc:description><dc:publisher>HINDAWI PUBLISHING CORPORATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:25:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:25:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC WORLD JOURNAL,</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1537-744X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2014/813759</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17305</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>