<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14642</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:07:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Correlation between pellet morphology and glycopeptide antibiotic balhimycin production by Amycolatopsis balhimycina DSM 5908</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, KP</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANGIKAR, PP</dc:creator><dc:creator>JADHAV, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Antibiotic production</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mycelia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Submerged cultivation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Substrate consumption</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYGROSCOPICUS VAR.-GELDANUS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CITRIC-ACID PRODUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGE-ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MYCELIAL MORPHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILAMENTOUS MICROORGANISMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBMERGED CULTIVATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METABOLITE PRODUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BATCH FERMENTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CULTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:description>Actinomycetes, a class of filamentous bacteria, are an important source of several industrially relevant secondary metabolites. Several environmental factors including the media composition affect both biomass growth and product formation. Likewise, several studies have shown that environmental factors cause changes in cellular morphology. However, the relationship between morphology and product formation is not well understood. In this study, we first characterized the effect of varying concentrations of phosphate and ammonia in defined media on pellet morphology for an actinomycete Amycolatopsis balhimycina DSM 5908, which produces balhimycin, a glycopeptide antibiotic. Our results show that higher balhimycin productivity is correlated with the following morphological features: (1) higher pellet fraction in the biomass, (2) small elongated pellets, and (3) shorter filaments in hyphal growth in the periphery of the pellets. The correlation between morphology and product formation was also observed in industrially relevant complex media. Although balhimycin production starts after 72 h with maximum production around 168 h, the morphological changes in pellets are observed as early as 24 h after commencing of the batch. Therefore, morphology may be used as an early predictor of the end-of-batch productivity. We argue that a similar strategy can be developed for other strains where morphological indicators may be used as a batch monitoring tool.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:07:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:07:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF INDUSTRIAL MICROBIOLOGY &amp; BIOTECHNOLOGY, 39(1)27-35</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10295-011-0995-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14642</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>