<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17653</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:47:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Replicating the geographical cloud: Provisioning omnipresence, omniscience and omnipotence</dc:title><dc:creator>MUSTAFA, HD</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAVEJA, BM</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cloud computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Virtualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Abstraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grid computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Symbiosis</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper discusses the current state-of-art and proposes a novel evolution of cloud computing and communications. New attributes, introduced continuously, have additively improved and evolved cloud computing to what it is today. Grid computing, data-centers and High Performance Computing (HPC) are critically reviewed and fall-outs are analyzed to corroborate new solutions. We propound a futuristic paradigm, founded on symbiosis and utility-oriented ideas, and propose a new architecture/framework for systems of the future. The authors have also made an attempt to address the question of what is to transcend cloud computing and current networking paradigms. Several applications are discussed qualitatively and rudimentary approaches are discussed. Principal theoretic feasibility of one of the proposed hypothesis of cloud communications is established. In this proposed scenario we obtain a linear increase in communication capacity, with minimal energy requirement. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:47:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FUTURE GENERATION COMPUTER SYSTEMS-THE INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF GRID COMPUTING AND ESCIENCE, 47,1-15</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-739X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-7115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.future.2014.12.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17653</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>