<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18166</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:29:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Postprocessing for speeding up general quantum search algorithms</dc:title><dc:creator>TULSI, A</dc:creator><dc:description>A general quantum search algorithm aims to evolve a quantum system from a known source state vertical bar s &gt; to an unknown target state vertical bar t &gt;. It uses a diffusion operator D-s that has the source state as one of its eigenstates and I-t, where I-psi denotes the selective phase inversion of the vertical bar psi &gt; state. It evolves vertical bar s &gt; to a particular state vertical bar w &gt;, which we will call the w state, in O(B/alpha) time steps, where alpha is vertical bar &lt; t vertical bar s &gt;vertical bar and B is a characteristic of the diffusion operator. Measuring the w state gives the target state with a success probability of O(1/B-2), and O(B-2) applications of the algorithm can boost it from O(1/B-2) to O(1), making the total time complexity O(B-3/alpha). In the special case of Grover's algorithm, D-s is I-s and B is very close to 1. A more efficient way to boost the success probability is quantum amplitude amplification provided we can efficiently implement I-w. Such an efficient implementation is not known so far. In this paper, we present an efficient algorithm to approximate selective phase inversions of the unknown eigenstates of an operator using a phase estimation algorithm. This algorithm is used to efficiently approximate I-w, which reduces the time complexity of general algorithm to O(B/alpha). Although O(B/alpha) algorithms are known to exist, our algorithm offers physical implementation advantages.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:29:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:29:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW A, 92(2)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1050-2947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1094-1622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevA.92.022353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18166</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>