<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18287</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:46:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular layer deposition of alucone films using trimethylaluminum and hydroquinone</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHULI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>INORGANIC THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ETHYLENE-GLYCOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE-CHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPARENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIETHYLZINC</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERS</dc:subject><dc:description>A hybrid organic-inorganic polymer film grown by molecular layer deposition (MLD) is demonstrated here. Sequential exposures of trimethylaluminum [Al(CH3)(3)] and hydroquinone [C6H4(OH)(2)] are used to deposit the polymeric films, which is a representative of a class of aluminum oxide polymers known as "alucones." In-situ quartz crystal microbalance (QCM) studies are employed to determine the growth characteristics. An average growth rate of 4.1 angstrom per cycle at 150 degrees C is obtained by QCM and subsequently verified with x-ray reflectivity measurements. Surface chemistry during each MLD-half cycle is studied in depth by in-situ Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) vibration spectroscopy. Self limiting nature of the reaction is confirmed from both QCM and FTIR measurements. The conformal nature of the deposit, typical for atomic layer deposition and MLD, is verified with transmission electron microscopy imaging. Secondary ion mass spectroscopy measurements confirm the uniform elemental distribution along the depth of the films. (C) 2014 American Vacuum Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A V S AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:46:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:46:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VACUUM SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY A, 33(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0734-2101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-8559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1116/1.4900934</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18287</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>