<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14246</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T09:00:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Triazole-Linked-Thiophene Conjugate of Calix[4]arene: Its Selective Recognition of Zn(2+) and as Biomimetic Model in Supporting the Events of the Metal Detoxification and Oxidative Stress Involving Metallothionein</dc:title><dc:creator>PATHAK, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MONDAL, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOWER RIM</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTRACELLULAR ZINC</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIVING CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECEPTORS</dc:subject><dc:description>Supramolecular calix[4]arene conjugate (L) has been developed as a sensitive and selective sensor for Zn(2+) in HEPES buffer among the 12 metal ion by using fluorescence, absorption and ESI MS and also by visual fluorescent color. The structural, electronic, and emission properties of the calix[4]arene conjugates L and its zinc complex, [ZnL], have been demonstrated using ab initio density functional theory (DFT) combined with time-dependent density functional theory (TDDFT) calculations. The TDDFT calculations reveal the switch on fluorescence behavior of L is mainly due to the utilization of the lone pair of electrons on imine moiety by the Zn2+. The resultant fluorescent complex, [ZnL], has been used as a secondary sensing chemo-ensemble for the detection of -SH containing molecules by removing Zn(2+) from [ZnL] and forming {Cys/DTT center dot Zn} adducts as equivalent to those present in metallothioneins. The displacement followed by the release of the coordinated zinc from its Cys/DTT complex by heavy metal ion (viz. Cd(2+) and Hg(2+)), as in the metal detoxification process or by ROS (such as H(2)O(2)) as in the oxidative stress, has been well demonstrated using the conjugate L through the fluorescence intensity retrieval wherein the fluorescence intensity is the same as that observed with [ZriL], which in turn mimics the zinc sensing element (MTF) in biology.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:00:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T09:00:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY,76(24)10039-10049</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo201865x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14246</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>