<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1488</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>A quadratic inequality approach for design of robust controller for a parametric uncertain jet engine</dc:title><dc:creator>NATARAJ, PSV</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, SURESH</dc:creator><dc:subject>uncertain systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>control system analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>control equipment</dc:subject><dc:subject>frequency domain analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>The control logic of a modern jet engine is comprised of many control loops and the control system must account for the uncertainties in the model with which it was designed. This paper presents a quadratic inequality based methodology for designing a robust controller of a parametric uncertain jet engine. The inequalities are used for generation of controller bounds to achieve robust stability and tracking specifications prior to loop shaping. The design is done in frequency domain and the evolved robust controller controls the system that does not have a distinct set of poles and zeros but a range over which each of the poles and zeros might lie. The methodology has multifarious advantages as it can be easily implemented, doesnot require template generation and provides the designer a good insight of the QFT bounds at any given design frequency and controller phase. The approach is demonstrated for the design of speed control loop of a parametric uncertain twin spool jet engine.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:07:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:22:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:07:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:22:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE Region 10 Annual International Conference, Proceedings/TENCON (V 1), Bangalore, India, 15-17 October 2003, 289-293</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8162-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/TENCON.2003.1273332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1488</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>