<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4197</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization of periodic motions in aircraft lateral dynamics</dc:title><dc:creator>ANANTHKRISHNAN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUDHAKAR, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>slender delta wings</dc:subject><dc:subject>rock</dc:subject><dc:description>Limit cycles in aicraft lateral dynamics are called wing rock. Wing rock prevention and/or control is an important objective for aircraft that need to fly and maneuver at moderate to high angles of attack, This requires a characterization of wing rock periodic motions, which is our aim. Normal and large-amplitude types of wing rock are distinguished. Onset of normal wing rock occurs at a Hopf bifurcation followed by limit cycle oscillations of gradually growing amplitude. Onset of large-amplitude wing rock is similar, but the limit cycles following the Hopf bifurcation show a jump to a large-amplitude oscillation at a periodic saddle-node bifurcation. Large-amplitude wing rock is shown to be the result of lateral-longitudinal coupling in conjunction with a resonance condition. A continuation algorithm is used to track periodic solutions with varying parameters and to locate bifurcation points. A strategy to avoid large-amplitude wing rock is indicated on the basis of the study.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUT ASTRONAUT</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T08:14:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T08:14:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GUIDANCE CONTROL AND DYNAMICS, 19(3), 680-685</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0731-5090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/3.21674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4197</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>