<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1781</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis of nanocrystalline copper-tungsten alloys by mechanical alloying</dc:title><dc:creator>RAGHU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNDARESAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, TRR</dc:creator><dc:subject>cu</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical alloying</dc:subject><dc:subject>copper-tungsten</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid solubility</dc:subject><dc:description>Copper-tungsten exhibits total absence of solubility in both solid and liquid state. Mechanical alloying (MA) as a solid state, nonequilibrium process can be beneficial to the processing of such an immiscible system with the added features of refinement of structure. A study war undertaken to synthesise various Cu-W alloys and develop an ultrafine microcomposite structure of tungsten in copper matrix by mechanical alloying. Elemental powders of copper and tungsten were milled in high energy ball mills. The milling behaviour was found to depend on the composition milling time and milling atmosphere. The milled powders were characterised for their particle size, microstructure and lattice parameters. Metastable mutual solid solubility in the system was confirmed. Crystallite sizes were found to be in the nanocrystalline regime. The conversion of milling energy effectively to generate deformed surfaces, which in turn led to metastable solid solubility and nanocrystalline structure, was aided by the presence of oxygen in the milling atmosphere, (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T02:30:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T02:30:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING,304,438-441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0921-5093(00)01444-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15023</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1781</dc:identifier><dc:source>10th International Conference on Rapidly Quenched and Metastable Materials (RQ10),BANGALORE, INDIA,AUG 23-27, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>