<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16512</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:25:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis, Spectral Characterization, Structures, and Oxidation State Distributions in [(corrolato)Fe-III(NO)](n) (n=0,+1,-1) Complexes</dc:title><dc:creator>SINHA, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEIBEL, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWALA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARAI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHWEINFURTH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUROHIT, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON NITROSYL PORPHYRINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITRIC-OXIDE REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>O HYDROGEN-BOND</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPIN DELOCALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>C-H</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDUCTIVE NITROSYLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBSTITUTED CORROLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON(III) PORPHYRIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION-ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:description>Two novel trans-A(2)B-corroles and three [(corrolato){FeNO}(6)] complexes have been prepared and characterized by various spectroscopic techniques. In the native state, all these [(corrolato){FeNO}(6)] species are diamagnetic and display "normal" chemical shifts in the H-1 NMR spectra. For two of the structurally characterized [(corrolato){FeNO}(6)] derivatives, the Fe-N-O bond angles are 175.0(4)degrees and 171.70(3)degrees (DFT: 179.94 degrees), respectively, and are designated as linear nitrosyls. The Fe-N (NO) bond distances are 1.656(4) angstrom and 1.650(3) angstrom (DFT: 1.597 angstrom), which point toward a significant Fe-III -&gt; NO back bonding. The NO bond lengths are 1.159(5) angstrom and 1.162(3) angstrom (DFT: 1.162 angstrom) and depict their elongated character. These structural data are typical for low-spin Fe(III). Electrochemical measurements show the presence of a one-electron oxidation and a one-electron reduction process for all the complexes. The one-electron oxidized species of a representative [(corrolato){FeNO}(6)] Complex exhibits ligand to ligand charge transfer (LLCT) transitions (cor(pi) -&gt; cor(pi*)) at 399 and 637 nm, and the one-electron reduced species shows metal to ligand charge transfer (MLCT) transition (Fe(d pi) -&gt; cor(pi*)) in the UV region at 330 nm. The shift of the v(NO) stretching frequency of a representative [(corrolato){FeNO}(6)] complex on one-electron oxidation occurs from 1782 cm(-1) to 182,0 cm(-1), which corresponds to 38 cm(-1), and on one-electron reduction occurs from 1782 cm-1 to 1605 cm(-1), which corresponds to 177 cm(-1). The X-band electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectrum of one-electron oxidation at 295 K in CH2Cl2/0.1 M Bu4NPF6 displays an isotropic signal centered at g = 2.005 with a peak-to-peak separation of about 15 G. The in situ generated one-electron reduced species in CH2Cl2/0.1 M Bu4NPF6 at 295 K shows an isotropic signal centered at g = 2.029. The 99% contribution of corrole to the HOMO of native species indicates that oxidation occurs from the corrole moiety. The results of the electrochemical and spectroelectrochemical measurements and density functional theory calculations clearly display a preference of the {FeNO}(6) unit to get reduced during the reduction step and the corrolato unit to get oxidized during the anodic process. Comparisons are presented with the structural, electrochemical, and spectroelectrochemical data of related compounds reported in the literature, with a particular focus on the interpretation of the EPR spectrum of the one:electron oxidized form.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:25:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:25:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 53(3)1417-1429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-510X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic402304e</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16512</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>