<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3594</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-24T09:09:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>A wave propagation and vibration-based approach for damage identification in structural components</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RICCI, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>MONACO, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>composite structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:description>A damage index (DI) approach for damage detection and localization based on high frequency wave propagation data and low frequency vibration measurements is presented. Improved ultrasonic and vibration test setups, consisting of either distributed high-fidelity piezoelectric sensor arrays or laser vibrometer, data acquisition boards, signal conditioning and dedicated software have been implemented. In the wave propagation measurements, the data consist of broadband signals due to ultrasonic waves propagating in the structure, while in the vibration measurements they are modal response of the structure produced by the actuators. Using the initial measurements performed on an undamaged structure as baseline, damage indices are evaluated from the comparison of the frequency response of the monitored structure with an unknown damage. In case of wave propagation measurements, a damaged/undamaged path mechanism is used to approximately locate the damage using the correlations obtained between the statistical DI (statistic t) values at the sensor locations (control points). For vibration measurements, both piezoelectric patches and the laser vibrometer are used as response sensors in an effort to examine their sensitivity to damage detection. It is found that the laser vibrometer acquisitions produce improved sensitivity and higher accuracy of the DI when compared to piezo-patches as response sensors. In addition, Modal Assurance Criterion (MAC) has been used to compare and quantify the changes in the modal parameters evaluated from the measurements carried out on the healthy and damaged structure. The DI approach is used to identify various types of defects in the form of loose rivet holes, delaminations due to low velocity impact and added mass for changes in the stiffness, in both metallic and composite structural components with relatively complex geometries. It is shown that the procedure is able to identify an emerging and/or growing defect, with some degree of confidence. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SOUND AND VIBRATION, 322(1-2), 167-183</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-460X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jsv.2008.11.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3594</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3594</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>