<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1369</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of swift heavy ion irradiation on band gap of strained AlGaN/GaN Multi Quantum Wells</dc:title><dc:creator>DEVARAJU, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHISH, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATHAK, AP</dc:creator><dc:creator>TUROS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAZZAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRAVE, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAZZOLDI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>ARORA, BM</dc:creator><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantum wells</dc:subject><dc:subject>hrxrd</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoluminescence and irradiation</dc:subject><dc:description>III-Nitrides have attracted much attention due to their versatile and wide range of applications, such as blue/UV light emitting diodes. Strained layer super lattices offer extra degree of freedom to alter the band gap of lattice-mismatched hetero-structures. Swift Heavy Ion (SHI) irradiation is a post growth technique to alter the band gap of semiconductors, spatially. In the present study, strained AlGaN/GaN Multi Quantum wells (MQWs) were grown on sapphire with insertion of AIN and GaN as buffer layers between substrate and epi-layers by MOCVD. These buffer layers are known to improve the structural and optical properties. Such grown AlGaN/GaN MQWs were irradiated with 200 MeV Au ions at a fluence of 5 x 10(11) ions/cm(2). As grown and irradiated samples have been characterized by HRXRD and PL. The analysis of symmetrical and asymmetrical reciprocal space mapping gives information on perpendicular and in-plane strain. Measured values show that lattice mismatch increases upon irradiation. However, increase in the mismatch upon irradiation has affected the band gap of MQWs, which has been confirmed by PL measurements. PL shows that there is an increase of intensity of luminescence of GaN and MQWs by one order of magnitude upon irradiation, which is attributed to SHI induced dynamic annealing processes. (c) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:21:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T16:21:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION B-BEAM INTERACTIONS WITH MATERIALS AND ATOMS,268(19)3001-3004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-583X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nimb.2010.05.027</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14696</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1369</dc:identifier><dc:source>15th International Conference of the Radiation Effects in Insulators,ITALY,AUG 30-SEP 04, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>