<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8128</identifier><datestamp>2013-12-20T07:07:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Stable Online Algorithm for Energy-Efficient Multiuser Scheduling</dc:title><dc:creator>SALODKAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARANDIKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BORKAR, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>fading channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>wireless networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>constraints</dc:subject><dc:subject>allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality</dc:subject><dc:subject>service</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiuser fading channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>constrained markov decision process</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy-efficient scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>learning algorithm</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we consider the problem of energy-efficient uplink scheduling with delay constraint for a multiuser wireless system. We address this problem within the framework of constrained Markov decision processes (CMDPs) wherein one seeks to minimize one cost (average power) subject to a hard constraint on another (average delay). We do not assume the arrival and channel statistics to be known. To handle state-space explosion and informational constraints, we split the problem into individual CMDPs for the users, coupled through their Lagrange multipliers; and a user selection problem at the base station. To address the issue of unknown channel and arrival statistics, we propose a reinforcement learning algorithm. The users use this learning algorithm to determine the rate at which they wish to transmit in a slot and communicate this to the base station. The base station then schedules the user with the highest rate in a slot. We analyze convergence, stability, and optimality properties of the algorithm. We also demonstrate the efficacy of the algorithm through simulations within IEEE 802.16 system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T12:58:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T12:58:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON MOBILE COMPUTING, 9(10), 1391-1406</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1536-1233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TMC.2010.106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8128</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8128</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>