<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9417</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Highly Transparent Thermoplastic Elastomer From Isotactic Polypropylene and Styrene/Ethylene-Butylene/Styrene Triblock Copolymer: Structure-Property Correlations</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMAD, Z</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, KD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAROOP, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRESCHILLA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BISWAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHOWMICK, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>dynamic-mechanical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>density polyethylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrile rubber</dc:subject><dc:subject>blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyisobutylene</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>vulcanization</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>pp</dc:subject><dc:description>Polypropylene (PP) is one of the most useful general purpose plastics. However, the poor transparency and brittleness of PP restricts its applications in the field of medical and personal care where silicone and polyvinyl chloride (PVC) are presently used. This work concentrates on developing highly transparent elastomeric PP blends and also thermoplastic elastomer by blending isotactic polypropylene (I-PP) with styrene/ethylene-butylene/styrene (SEBS) triblock copolymer. PP/SEBS blend derived from high melt flow index (MFI) PP and high MFI SEBS exhibit remarkable transparency (haze value as low as 6%) along with good percentage of elongation and processability. The reduction in difference of refractive index (RI) between PP and SEBS has been observed by blending SEBS with PP. The wide angle X-ray diffraction studies show that there is significant reduction in the percentage crystallinity of PP by the addition of SEBS block copolymer. Temperature-dependent polarized light microscopy studies reveal the reduction in spherulites size by the addition of SEBS block copolymer. Transmission electron micrographs show that the SEBS polymer forms a fine lamellar structure throughout the PP matrix with phase inversion at higher SEBS concentration. Development of phase morphology, crystalline morphology, and crystallinity in different blends has been analyzed and microstructure-haze correlations have been developed. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 50:331-341, 2010. (C) 2009 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T06:51:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T06:51:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE, 50(2), 331-341</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.21540</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9417</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9417</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>