<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-41</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Understanding the relationship between the primary structure of proteins and its propensity to be soluble on overexpression in Escherichia coli</dc:title><dc:creator>IDICULA-THOMAS, SUSAN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAJI, PETETY V</dc:creator><dc:subject>mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>solubility</dc:subject><dc:subject>escherichia coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>correlation theory</dc:subject><dc:description>Solubility of proteins on overexpression in E. coli is a manifestation of the net effect of several sequence-dependent and sequence-independent factors. This study aims to delineate the relationship between the primary structure and solubility on overexpression. The amino acid sequences of proteins reported to be soluble or to form inclusion bodies on overexpression in E. coli under normal growth conditions have been analyzed. The results show a positive correlation between thermostability and solubility of proteins and an inverse correlation between the in vivo half-life of proteins and solubility. The amino acid (Asn, Thr, Tyr) composition and the tripeptide frequency of the protein were also found to influence its solubility on overexpression. The amino acids that were seen to be present in a comparatively higher frequency in inclusion body forming proteins have a higher sheet propensity whereas those that are seen more in soluble proteins have a higher helix propensity; this is indicative of a possible correlation between sheet propensity and inclusion body formation. Thus, the present analysis shows that thermostability, in vivo half-life, Asn, Thr and Tyr content and tripeptide composition of a protein are correlated to the propensity of a protein to be soluble on overexpression in E. coli. The precise mechanism by which these properties affect the solubility status of the overexpressed protein remains to be understood.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press</dc:publisher><dc:date>2007-01-18T10:41:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:21:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007-01-18T10:41:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:21:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Protein Sci., 14:582-592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/41</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/41</dc:identifier><dc:language>en_US</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>