<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4965</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Wave height estimation using disaggregation models</dc:title><dc:creator>DEO, MC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHERIEF, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:description>Wave height data are sometimes available at different space locations in the form of average values over larger time intervals. Difficulties may arise when such data are to be used for applications such as small-term operational forecasting for which information at closer intervals of time would be necessary. This paper presents an effort made to deduce wave heights over smaller time periods from their values sampled over longer durations, with the help of the disaggregation models traditionally used in hydrology. Use has been made of basic, extended as well as condensed disaggregation models. Considering the reliability and accuracy of wave rider buoy data, the same has also been employed along with satellite data for comparison purposes and for conducting some additional investigations. It has been found that statistically advantageous disaggregation models produce more satisfactory estimates of small-interval waves and that the smaller the level difference between high-level, large-interval series and low-level, small-interval ones, the larger the accuracy of resulting estimates.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T15:18:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T15:18:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF WATERWAY PORT COASTAL AND OCEAN ENGINEERING-ASCE, 123(2), 63-67</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0733-950X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)0733-950X(1997)123:2(63)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4965</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4965</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>