<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4379</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-05T09:27:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Large magnetoresistance in (La(1-x)Ca(x)MnO(3))(1-y): ZrO(2) composite</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RUSSEK, SE</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJ, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>colossal magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>percolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:description>Colossal magnetoresistance (CMR) composite materials have been synthesized to explore the possibility of improving magneto-transport and structural properties in CMR systems. In this work we describe (La(1-x)Ca(x)MnO(3))(1-y) (LCMO) (ZrO(2))(y) (xapproximate to0.3 and 0.0less than or equal toyless than or equal to0.40 mole %) composites that have been synthesized using a modified (non Pechini type) sol-gel technique. Magnetoresistivity of the composites was evaluated at 5 T field and in the temperature range 5-300 K. The composites show higher magnitude of MR compared to pure LCMO. The MR rises from a base value 76%, for the case y=0, to a maximum value of 93.8%, obtained at y=0.05. dc susceptibility measurements show a distinct ferromagnetic to paramagnetic transition in all composites. The ferromagnetic transition temperature (T(C)) drops from 225 K in pure LCMO (y=0) to 121 K in y=0.05 and then slowly rises to 157 K as y increases. The plots of zero field cooled susceptibility chi(ZFC) (T) and field cooled susceptibility chi(FC) (T) diverge clearly below T(C), indicating magnetic irreversibility. The composite exhibits a clear metal-insulator transition (T(MI)) at or just above the magnetic transition. The peak resistivity rho(MI) at the metal-insulator transition also exhibits interesting changes. For pure LCMO polycrystals, rho(MI)=102 Omega cm, but it increases to 228 Omega cm for y=0.05 and then gradually decreases to 1.94 Omega cm for ygreater than or equal to0.10. The phase evolution in the LCMO:ZrO(2) composites was studied by x-ray powder diffraction and correlated to the magnetic and electrical properties. (C) 2003</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T08:44:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T08:44:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 93(10), 8301-8303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.1556260</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4379</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4379</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>