<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17301</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:23:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of barrier thickness on structural, optical, and spectral behaviors of vertically strain coupled InAs/GaAs quantum dot infrared photodetectors</dc:title><dc:creator>GHADI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>ADHIKARY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TONGBRAM, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDEL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENDYALA, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAJAPATI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>HIGH-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVELENGTH</dc:subject><dc:description>The optical, electrical, and spectral properties of a strain coupled InAs quantum dot detector with a fixed quaternary capping of InAlGaAs and variable GaAs barrier thickness were investigated along with an equivalent uncoupled structure. Self-assembled quantum dots with a multimodal dot size distribution were achieved owing to vertical strain coupling. Strain and electronic coupling were utilized to improve the optical and electrical performance of the fabricated quantum dot infrared photodetector. The peak spectral response was tuned by varying barrier thickness, and a blue shift (almost 1 mu m) was observed by increasing the capping thickness from sample A (90 angstrom capping) to E (500 angstrom capping). High responsivity and detectivity (similar to 10(10) cm Hz(1/2)W) were observed for all coupled samples as compared to the uncoupled sample. All coupled samples showed high thermal stability in the photoluminescence peak with high-temperature annealing. (C) 2014 American Vacuum Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A V S AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:23:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:23:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VACUUM SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY B, 32(5)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1071-1023</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1116/1.4894461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17301</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>