<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18095</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:51:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Carrier and photon dynamics in a topological insulator Bi2Te3/GaN type II staggered heterostructure</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATURVEDI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUKSEY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSISTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIODES</dc:subject><dc:description>We have demonstrated a type-II band-aligned heterostructure between pulsed laser deposited topological insulator bismuth telluride and metal organic-chemical-vapour deposited GaN on a sapphire substrate. The heterostructure shows a large valence band-offset of 3.27 eV as determined from x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, which is close to the bandgap of GaN (3.4 eV). Further investigation using x-ray diffraction, Raman spectroscopy, and energy-dispersive x-ray spectrum reveals the stoichiometric and material properties of bismuth telluride on GaN. Steady state photon emission from GaN is found to be modulated by the charge transfer process due to diffusion across the junction. The time constant involved with the charge transfer process is found to be 0.6 ns by transient absorption spectroscopy. The heterostructure can be used for designing devices with different functionalities and improving the performance of the existing devices on GaN. (C) 2015 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:51:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:51:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 107(19)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1077-3118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4935554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18095</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>