<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15125</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:14:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Viscous dissipation pattern in incompressible Newtonian simple shear zones: an analytical model</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MULCHRONE, KF</dc:creator><dc:subject>Viscous dissipation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Newtonian fluid</dc:subject><dc:subject>Simple shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poiseuille flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLLISIONAL OROGENS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMAL EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERSIAN-GULF</dc:subject><dc:subject>SALT DIAPIRS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>HISTORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEUKOGRANITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAMORPHISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISCOSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>UPLIFT</dc:subject><dc:description>An analytical model of shear heating in an inclined simple shear zone with Newtonian rheology under a reverse shear sense and an upward resultant pressure gradient is presented. Neglecting a number of secondary factors, the shear heat is expressed as a function of the total slip rates at the boundaries, pressure gradient, dip and thickness of the shear zone, and density, viscosity, and thermal conductivity of the rock. A quartic temperature profile develops with a point of maximum temperature near the bottom part of the shear zone in general. The profile is parabolic if pressure gradient vanishes leading to a Couette flow. The profile attains a bell shape if there is no slip at the boundaries, i.e., a true Pouseille flow. The present model of shear heating is more applicable in subduction channels and some extruding salt diapirs where the rheology is Newtonian viscous and pressure gradient drives extrusion.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:14:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:14:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES, 102(4)1165-1170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00531-013-0879-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15125</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>