<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1430</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of effluent recycling and shock loading on the biodegradation of complex phenolic mixture in hybrid UASB reactors</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, ANUSHUYA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SUDHIR KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:subject>effluent treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical oxygen demand</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical reactors</dc:subject><dc:description>This study describes the feasibility of anaerobic treatment of synthetic coal wastewater using four identical 13.5 L (effective volume) bench scale hybrid up flow anaerobic sludge blanket (HUASB) reactors (R1, R2, R3 and R4) under mesophilic (27 ± 5 °C) conditions. Synthetic coal wastewater with an average chemical oxygen demand (COD) of 2240 mg/L and phenolics concentration of 752 mg/L was used as substrate. Effluent recirculation was employed at four different effluent to feed recirculation ratios (R/F) of 0.5, 1.0, 1.5 and 2.0 for 100 days to study the effect of recirculation on the performance of the reactors. Phenolics and COD removal was found to improve with increase in effluent recirculation. An effluent to feed recycle ratio of 1.0 resulted in maximum removal of phenolics and COD. Phenolics and COD removal improved from 88% and 92% to 95% each, respectively. The concentration of volatile fatty acids in the effluent was lower than the influent when effluent to feed recirculation was employed. Effect of shock loading on the reactors revealed that phenolics shock load up to 2.5 times increase in the normal input phenolics concentration in the form of continuous shock load for 4 days did not affect the reactors performance irreversibly.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-05T04:29:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:44:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-05T04:29:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:44:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Bioresource Technology 99(9), 3745-3753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.biortech.2007.07.014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-8524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1430</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1430</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>