<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2083</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fluid flow and heat transfer analysis of automotive radiator using CFD tools</dc:title><dc:creator>MALAPURE, VP</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>finned surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat exchanger</dc:subject><dc:subject>specific dissipation</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a three-dimensional numerical analysis of flow and heat transfer over plate fins in a compact heat exchanger used as a radiator in the automotive industry. The aim of this study is to predict the heat transfer and pressure drop in the radiator. FLUENT 6.1 is used for simulation. Several cases are simulated in order to investigate the coolant temperature drop, heat transfer coefficient for the coolant and the air side along with the corresponding pressure drop. It is observed that the heat transfer and pressure drop fairly agree with experimental data. It is also found that the fin temperature depends on the frontal air velocity and the coolant side heat transfer coefficient is in good agreement with classical Dittus - Boelter correlation. It is also found that the specific dissipation increases with the coolant and the air flow rates. This work can further be extended to perform optimization study for radiator design.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T05:34:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T05:34:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>HT2005: Proceedings of the ASME Summer Heat Transfer Conference 2005, Vol 3,555-561</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7918-4733-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/HT2005-72247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15617</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2083</dc:identifier><dc:source>ASME Heat Transfer Summer Conference,San Francisco, CA,JUL 15-22, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>