<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3962</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Monomeric, tetrameric, and polymeric copper di-tert-butyl phosphate complexes containing pyridine ancillary ligands</dc:title><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYENDIRAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTHIRAJA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>WALAWALKAR, MG</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALLAH, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>RIVIERE, E</dc:creator><dc:subject>ammonium hexaaquacopper(ii) sulfate</dc:subject><dc:subject>jahn-teller distortion</dc:subject><dc:subject>ray crystal-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>di(tert-butyl)phosphate complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>bridged copper(ii)</dc:subject><dc:subject>precursors</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphonate</dc:subject><dc:subject>cluster</dc:subject><dc:subject>metallasiloxanes</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of di-tert-butyl phosphate (((BuO)-Bu-t)(2)P(O)(OH), dtbp-H) with copper acetate in the presence of pyridine (py) and 2,4,6-trimethylpyridine (collidine) has been investigated. Copper acetate reacts with dtbp-H in a reaction medium containing pyridine, DOC, THF, and CH3OH to yield a one-dimensional polymeric complex [Cu(dtbP)(2)(py)(2)(mu-OH2)](n) (1) as blue hollow crystalline tubes. The copper atoms in 1 are octahedral and are surrounded by two terminal phosphate ligands, two pyridine molecules, and two bridging water molecules. The mu-OH2 ligands that are present along the elongated Jahn-Teller axis are responsible for the formation of the one-dimensional polymeric structure. Recrystallization of 1 in a DMSO/THF/CH3OH mixture results in the reorganization of the polymer and its conversion to a more stable tetranuclear copper cluster [Cu-4(mu(3)-OH)(2)(dtbP)(6)(py)(2)] (2) in about 60% yield. The molecular structure of 2 is made up of a tetranuclear core [Cu-4(mu(3)-OH)(2)] which is surrounded by six bidentate bridging dtbp ligands. While two of the copper atoms are pentacoordinate with a tbp geometry, the other two copper atoms exhibit a pseudooctahedral geometry with five normal Cu-O bonds and an elongated Cu-O linkage. The pentacoordinate copper centers bear an axial. pyridine ligand. The short Cu...Cu nonbonded distances in the tetranuclear core of 2 lead to magnetic ordering at low temperature with an antiferromagnetic coupling at similar to20 K (J(p) = -44 cm(-1), J(c) = -66 cm(-1), g = 2.25, and p = 0.8%). When the reaction between di-tert-butyl phosphate (dtbp-H) and copper acetate was carried out in the presence of collidine, large dark-blue crystals of monomeric copper complex [Cu(dtbP)(2)(collidine)(2)] (3) formed as the only product. A single-crystal X-ray diffraction study of 3 reveals a slightly distorted square-planar geometry around the copper atom. Thermogravimetric analysis of 1-3 revealed a facile decomposition of the coordinated ligands and dtbp to produce a copper phosphate material around 500 degreesC. An independent solid-state thermolysis of all the three complexes in bulk at 500-510 degreesC for 2 days produced copper pyrophosphate Cu2P2O7 along with small quantities of Cu(PO3)(2) as revealed by DR-UV spectroscopic and PXRD studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T13:13:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T13:13:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 43(3), 945-953</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic0349508</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3962</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3962</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>