<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16732</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:17:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling and Analysis of Stator Interturn Fault Location Effects on Induction Machines</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, DC</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, MC</dc:creator><dc:subject>Fault location</dc:subject><dc:subject>stationary reference frame</dc:subject><dc:subject>stator interturn (SIT) faults</dc:subject><dc:subject>transient modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>winding functions (WFs)</dc:subject><dc:subject>TURN SHORT-CIRCUITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIAGNOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WINDINGS</dc:subject><dc:description>Locating the stator interturn (SIT) fault on the motor winding structure adds an important feature in the fault diagnosis. This motivates to study the effects of SIT fault location on the induction machine. In this paper, a simple yet accurate stationary reference frame q - d - 0 model of SIT-faulted induction machine, including the fault location parameter, is developed. The fundamental components of winding functions (WFs) are used to calculate the machine inductances for the proposed model. These inductances in stationary reference frame q - d - 0 variables are rotor-position-independent expressions and functions of fault severity and fault location. The proposed model is as accurate as the multiple-coupled-circuit model for fault location study. It does not require the recalculation of machine inductances in each integration step to solve the model. The experimental validation of the model is presented. The steady-state analysis based on the proposed model indicates that the inclination of the current vector locus and the phase angle of the negative-sequence current phasor are the strong indicators of the SIT fault location.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:17:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:17:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS, 61(9)4552-4564</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0278-0046</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-9948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIE.2013.2288191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16732</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>