<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10219</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Conformational features of a hexapeptide model Ac-TCAAKA-NH2 corresponding to a hydrated a helical segment from glyceraldehyde 3-phosphate dehydrogenase: Implications for the role of turns in helix folding</dc:title><dc:creator>SASIDHAR, YU</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNA, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>immunogenic peptide-fragments</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen-bond interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>diffusion-collision model</dc:subject><dc:subject>proton proton distances</dc:subject><dc:subject>occurring amino-acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>staphylococcal nuclease</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonbonded interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy parameters</dc:subject><dc:subject>water solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>small proteins</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent analysis of alpha helices in protein crystal structures, available in literature, revealed hydrated or helical segments in which, water molecule breaks open helix 5--&gt;1 hydrogen bond by inserting itself hydrogen bonds to both C=O and NH groups of helix hydrogen bond without disrupting the helix hydrogen bond, and hydrogen bonds to either C=O or NH of helix hydrogen bond. These hydrated segments display a variety of turn conformations and an thought to be folding intermediates' trapped during folding-unfolding of alpha helices. A role for reverse turns is implicated ill the folding of alpha helices. We considered a hexapeptide model Ac-(1)TGAAKA(6)-NH2 from glyceraldehyde 3-phosphate dehydrogenase, corresponding to a hydrated helical segment to assess its role in helix folding. The sequence is a site for two 'folding intermediates'. The conformational features of the model peptide have been investigated by H-1 2D NMR techniques and quantum mechanical. perturbative configuration interaction over localized orbitals (PCILO) method. Theoretical modeling largely correlates with experimental observations. Based upon the amide proton temperature coefficients, the observed d alpha n(i, i+1), d alpha n(i, i+2), dnn(i, i+1), d beta n(i, i+1) NOEs and the results from theoretical modeling, we conclude that the residues of the peptide sample alpha helical and neck regions of the Ramachandran phi, psi map with reduced conformational entropy and there is a potential for turn conformations at N and C terminal ends of the peptide. The role of reduced conformational entropy and turn potential in helix formation have been discussed. We conclude that the peptide sequence can serve as a 'folding intermediate' in the helix folding of glyceraldehyde 3-phosphate dehydrogenase.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T04:03:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T04:03:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY &amp; BIOPHYSICS, 37(1), 34-44</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-1208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10219</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>