<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6637</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>GIS-based soil liquefaction susceptibility map of Mumbai city for earthquake events</dc:title><dc:creator>MHASKE, SY</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>gis</dc:subject><dc:subject>gram plus</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquefaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>hazard map</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>set data</dc:subject><dc:description>The problem of liquefaction of soil during seismic event is one of the important topics in the field of Geotechnical Earthquake Engineering. Liquefaction of soil is generally occurs in loose cohesionless saturated soil when pore water pressure increases suddenly due to induced ground motion and shear strength of soil decreases to zero and leading the structure situated above to undergo a large settlement, or failure. The failures took place due to liquefaction induced soil movement spread over few square km area continuously. Hence this is a problem where spatial variation involves and to represent this spatial variation Geographic Information System (GIS) is very useful in decision making about the area subjected to liquefaction. In this paper, GIS software GRAM++ is used to prepare soil liquefaction susceptibility map for entire Mumbai city in India by marking three zones viz, critically liquefiable soil, moderately liquefiable soil and non liquefiable soil. Extensive field borehole test data for groundwater depth, standard penetration test (SPT) blow counts, dry density, wet density and specific gravity, etc. have been collected from different parts of Mumbai. Simplified procedure of Youd et al. (2001) is used for calculation of factor of safety against soil liquefaction potential. Mumbai city and suburban area are formed by reclaiming lands around seven islands since 1865 till current date and still it is progressing in the area such as Navi Mumbai and beyond Borivali to Mira road suburban area. The factors of safety against soil liquefaction were determined for earthquake moment magnitude ranging from M(w) = 5.0 to 7.5. It is found that the areas like Borivali, Malad, Dahisar, Bhandup may prone to liquefaction for earthquake moment magnitude ranging from M(w) = 5.0 to 7.5. The liquefaction susceptibility maps were created by using GRAM++ by showing the areas where the factor of safety against the soil liquefaction is less than one. Proposed liquefaction susceptibility map of Mumbai city can be used by researchers for earthquake hazard analysis, for the preventive measures in disaster management, for urban planning and further development of Mumbai city and suburban area. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T04:21:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T04:21:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED GEOPHYSICS, 70(3), 216-225</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0926-9851</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jappgeo.2010.01.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6637</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6637</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>