<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-609</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-26T06:44:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Understanding electromagnetic radiation due to partial discharges by simulating the motion of a group of charged particles and their interaction</dc:title><dc:creator>BHANGAONKAR, AVINASH S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>uhf antennas</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric fields</dc:subject><dc:subject>electromagnetic waves</dc:subject><dc:subject>insulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>partial discharges</dc:subject><dc:subject>power apparatus</dc:subject><dc:description>Partial discharge (PD) is one of the most critical insulation deterioration processes that can be monitored in any electrical equipment. It is a complex phenomenon that requires understanding the physical, chemical and electrical repercussions for its interpretation. PD generates a plethora of signals in the electrical domain that need to be properly captured and measured for estimating the impact of degradation. However, the correlation of the physics of this process with the manifestation of the measured signals is extremely complex due to the presence of various possible conditions and parameters that affect it. One of the novel methods of measuring this intricate process uses ultrahigh frequency (UHF) antennas which can receive the radiated electromagnetic waves from PD pulses. An attempt is made to simulate the radiation process using first principles of physics, for such discharges. The behaviour of a group of charged particles under the influence of external field is considered from the point of view of their motion and the electromagnetic radiation from them. This paper aims to shed more light on the physical processes which possibly generate the kind of signals that are received by an antenna.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-10T05:28:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:25:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-10T05:28:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:25:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Symposium on Conference Record of Electrical Insulation, Vancouver, USA, 9-12 June 2008, 663-666</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2091-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ELINSL.2008.4570418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/609</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/609</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>