<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12521</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intelligent layout planning for rapid prototyping</dc:title><dc:creator>GOGATE, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDE, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>3-dimensional component layout</dc:subject><dc:subject>stereolithography apparatus</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>orientation</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>rapid prototyping (rp)</dc:subject><dc:subject>3d layout planning</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithms (ga)</dc:subject><dc:description>Significant savings in cost and time can be achieved in rapid prototyping (RP) by manufacturing multiple parts in a single setup to achieve efficient machine volume utilization. This paper reports the design and implementation of a system for the optimal layout planning of 3D parts for a RP process. A genetic algorithm (GA) based search strategy has been used to arrive at a good packing layout for a chosen set of parts and RP process. A two stage approach has been proposed to initially short-list acceptable orientations for each part followed by the search for a layout plan which optimizes in terms of final product quality and build time. The GA uses a hybrid objective function comprising of the weighted measures like part build height, staircase effect, volume and area-of-contact of support structures. In essence it captures the key metrics of efficiency and goodness of packing for RP. The final layout plan is produced in the form of a composite part CAD model which can be directly exported to a RP machine for manufacturing. Design methodology of the system has been presented with some representative case studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T00:45:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T00:45:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PRODUCTION RESEARCH, 46(20), 5607-5631</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7543</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00207540701277002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12521</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12521</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>