<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16895</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:33:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Finite element modeling of orthogonal micromachining of anisotropic pyrolytic carbon via damaged plasticity</dc:title><dc:creator>BAJPAI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Pyrolytic carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>Finite element modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orthogonal microgrooving</dc:subject><dc:subject>Concrete damaged plasticity</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE</dc:subject><dc:description>Engineered features on pyrolytic carbon (PyC) have been demonstrated as an approach to improve the flow hemodynamics of the cardiovascular implants such as bileaflet mechanical heart valve. PyC also finds application in thermonuclear and missile components due to its unique directional thermal properties. However, very little work has been reported on modeling of machining/micromachining of PyC. Note that PyC is a brittle anisotropic material and its machining characteristics differ from plastically deformable isotropic materials. Consequently, this study is aimed at developing a finite element model to understand the mechanics of material removal in the plane of transverse isotropy (horizontally stacked laminae) of PyC. A damaged plasticity model has been used to capture the effect of material degradation under machining. Uniaxial tension/compression tests have been carried out to calibrate the damaged plasticity model. A cohesive element layer has been used between the chip layer and the bulk material to simulate the delamination/peeling effect. The model predicts cutting force and thrust forces at different set of process parameters. The orthogonal cutting model has been validated against the experimental data for different cutting conditions for cutting and thrust forces. In addition, the chip geometry has also been compared. The prediction error in the model lies between 9% and 27%. Parametric studies have also been performed to understand the effect of the machining parameters on the process response. It is found that use of the positive rake angle decreases the cutting forces up to 75%. (C) 2013 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:33:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:33:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PRECISION ENGINEERING-JOURNAL OF THE INTERNATIONAL SOCIETIES FOR PRECISION ENGINEERING AND NANOTECHNOLOGY, 38(2)300-310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0141-6359</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.precisioneng.2013.10.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16895</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>