<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18003</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:04:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>The role of surface oxygenated-species and adsorbed hydrogen in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) mechanism and product selectivity on Pd-based catalysts in acid media</dc:title><dc:creator>RAHUL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEVIVARAPRASAD, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEERGAT, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>CRYSTAL MICROBALANCE ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL-BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYCRYSTALLINE PLATINUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFLUORINATED IONOMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALLADIUM ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEROXIDE GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SORPTION PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE LAYERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUEL-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:description>Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is investigated on bulk PdO-based catalysts (oxides of Pd and Pd3Co) in oxygen-saturated 0.1 M HClO4 to establish the role of surface oxides and adsorbed hydrogen in the activity and product selectivity (H2O/H2O2). The initial voltammetric features suggest that the oxides are inactive toward ORR. The evolution of the ORR voltammograms and potential-dependent H2O2 generation features on the PdO catalyst suggest gradual and parallel in situ reduction of the bulk PdO phase below similar to 0.4 V in the hydrogen underpotential deposition (H-upd) region; the reduction of the bulk PdO catalyst is confirmed from the X-ray photoelectron spectra (XPS) and X-ray diffraction (XRD) patterns. The potential-dependent H2O2 generation features originate due to the presence of surface oxides and adsorbed hydrogen; this is further confirmed using halide ions (Cl- and Br-) and peroxide as the external impurities.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:04:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:04:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 17(23)15146-15155</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5cp00692a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18003</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>