<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16309</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:03:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Multi-parametric approach towards the assessment of radon and thoron progeny exposures</dc:title><dc:creator>MISHRA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAPRA, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAYYA, YS</dc:creator><dc:subject>DEPOSITION VELOCITIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDOOR RADON</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUNG-CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>DAUGHTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DTPS</dc:subject><dc:description>Conventionally, the dosimetry is carried out using radon and thoron gas concentration measurements and doses have been assigned using assumed equilibrium factors for the progeny species, which is inadequate pertaining to the variations in equilibrium factors and possibly due to significant thoron. In fact, since the true exposures depend upon the intricate mechanisms of progeny deposition in the lung, therefore an integrated approach for the assessment of progeny is essential. In this context, the recently developed deposition based progeny concentration measurement techniques (DTPS: Direct Thoron progeny sensors and DRPS: Direct Radon progeny sensors) appear to be best suited for radiological risk assessments both among occupational workers and general study populations. DTPS and DRPS consist of aluminized mylar mounted LR115 type passive detectors, which essentially detects the alpha particles emitted from the deposited progeny atoms on the detector surface. It gives direct measure of progeny activity concentrations in air. DTPS has a lower limit of detection limit of 0.1Bq/m(3) whereas that for DRPS is 1 Bq/m(3), hence are perfectly suitable for indoor environments. These DTPS and DRPS can be capped with 200-mesh type wire-screen to measure the coarse fraction of the progeny concentration and the corresponding coarse fraction deposition velocities as well as the time integrated fine fraction. DTPS and DRPS can also be lodged in an integrated sampler wherein the wire-mesh and filter-paper are arranged in an array in flow-mode, to measure the fine and coarse fraction concentration separately and simultaneously. The details are further discussed in the paper. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:03:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:03:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>REVIEW OF SCIENTIFIC INSTRUMENTS, 85(2)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0034-6748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4865165</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16309</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>