<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3104</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mixing of granular materials: a test-bed dynamical system for pattern formation</dc:title><dc:creator>HILL, KM</dc:creator><dc:creator>GILCHRIST, JF</dc:creator><dc:creator>OTTINO, JM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAKHAR, DV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MCCARTHY, JJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>horizontal rotating cylinder</dc:subject><dc:subject>radial segregation</dc:subject><dc:subject>axial segregation</dc:subject><dc:subject>chaotic advection</dc:subject><dc:subject>size segregation</dc:subject><dc:subject>drum</dc:subject><dc:subject>solids</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>media</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:description>Mixing of granular materials provides fascinating examples of pattern formation and self-organization. More mixing action - for example, increasing the forcing with more vigorous shaking or faster tumbling - does not guarantee a better-mixed final system. This is because granular mixtures of just barely different materials segregate according to density and size; in fact, the very same forcing used to mix may unmix. Self-organization results from two competing effects: chaotic advection or chaotic mixing, as in the case of fluids, and flow-induced segregation, a phenomenon without parallel in fluids. The rich array of behaviors is ideally suited for nonlinear-dynamics-based inspection. Moreover, the interplay with experiments is immediate. In fact, these systems may constitute the simplest example of coexistence between chaos and self-organization that can be studied in the laboratory. We present a concise summary of the necessary theoretical background and central physical ideas accompanied by illustrative experimental results to aid the reader in exploring this fascinating new area.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-14T11:19:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-14T11:19:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF BIFURCATION AND CHAOS,9(8)1467-1484</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0218-1274</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0218127499001036</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13904</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3104</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>