<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6659</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydride blister formation in Zr-2.5wt%Nb pressure tube alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>wt pct nb</dc:subject><dc:subject>zirconium alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>induced embrittlement</dc:subject><dc:subject>zircaloy-4 plate</dc:subject><dc:subject>cracking</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>fabrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen</dc:subject><dc:description>Hydride blisters were grown over a period of 5-91 days under controlled thermal boundary condition using Zr-2.5wt%Nb pressure tube sections, Rectangular plate type specimens were hydrided to hydrogen concentration in the range of 20-250 ppm by weight and homogenized at 400 degreesC, These specimens were held in a specially fabricated jig capable of producing the required thermal gradients. The bulk specimen and the cold spot temperatures were maintained in the range of 270-400 degreesC and 40-100 degreesC respectively. Depending on the thermal gradients employed, two types of blister morphology were identified. The type I blister was single, round and located at the cold spot region whereas the type 11 blister consisted of several small blisters along a ring around the cold spot. Microstructural examination of the blister cross-section revealed three regions; a single-phase region consisting of hydrides, a region consisting of matrix containing both radial and circumferential hydrides, and another region consisting of matrix and circumferential hydrides. An attempt was made to rationalize the observed radial circumferential hydride platelet orientation. Hydride blister growth rates were found to vary strongly with hydrogen concentration and bulk specimen temperature. The observed time for blister growth was found to be in agreement with the Sawatzky's model [31]. (C) 2002</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T06:15:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T06:15:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MATERIALS, 301(40604), 153-164</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0022-3115(02)00708-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6659</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6659</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>