<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1359</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Molecular interactions of cord factor with dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine monolayers: implications for lung surfactant dysfunction in pulmonary tuberculosis</dc:title><dc:creator>CHIMOTE, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>langmuir blodgett films</dc:subject><dc:subject>lipids</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>monolayers</dc:subject><dc:description>Molecular interactions between mycobacterial cell wall lipid, cord factor (CF) and the abundant surfactant lipid, dipalmitoylphosphatidylcholine (DPPC) were investigated using Langmuir monolayers at physiological temperatures (37 °C). Surface topography of the films was visualized by atomic force microscopy (AFM). Thermodynamic behavior of the mixed monolayers was evaluated by investigating the molecular area excess, excess Gibbs free energy of mixing and maximum compressibility modulus (SCMmax). Cord factor formed immiscible and thermodynamically unstable monolayers with DPPC. Monolayer presence of cord factor altered the physical state of DPPC monolayers from liquid condensed to liquid expanded with the lowering of SCMmax from 160 to 40 mN/m, respectively. AFM imaging exhibited smooth homogenous surface topography of DPPC films which in the presence of cord factor was markedly altered with the appearance of aggregates and increased surface roughness. The results highlight the capacity of cord factor to disturb DPPC monolayer organization and structure. Interfacial presence of cord factor results in DPPC monolayer fluidization. Lung surfactant function is attributed to its ability to form well packed low compressibility films. Such molecular interactions suggest a dysfunction of lung surfactant in pulmonary tuberculosis due to surfactant monolayer fluidization.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-14T13:32:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:16:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-14T13:32:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:16:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Colloids and Surfaces B: Biointerfaces 65(1), 120-125</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>09277765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.colsurfb.2008.03.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1359</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1359</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>