<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-205</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:06:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electron microscopy of modified aluminum alkoxide microstructures on freeze-drying</dc:title><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENON, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>freeze-drying</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkoxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>chelate</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>freeze</dc:subject><dc:subject>freeze-fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>sonogel</dc:subject><dc:subject>cryo-sem</dc:subject><dc:subject>lyophilization</dc:subject><dc:description>Direct imaging of microstructures in chelated aluminum alkoxide systems subjected to freeze-drying and freeze-thaw-drying is reported using cryo-scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and SEM techniques, Aluminum sec-butoxide was chelated with a beta-diketoester in different molar ratios. This system was gelled by hydrolysis under intense sonication. The sonogels formed were subjected to cryo-SEM. Samples for cryo-SEM were made by freezing the chelated alkoxide samples in liquid nitrogen and freeze-fracturing them inside the cryo-SEM and monitoring the apparent morphological changes on exposure to the cryo-SEM environment including intentional sample heating, Microstructures of unchelated, 1:1 chelated and 1:2 chelated (alkoxide:chelate) sonogels after freezing, thawing, and drying were also imaged by SEM techniques, Heterogeneity introduced by chelation of alkoxide is proposed as the cause for the formation of flakes in freeze-thaw-dried chelated alkoxide gels, Microstructures of 1:1 chelated freeze dried alkoxide were compared with the freeze-thaw-dried gels, The absence of flakes in the chelated samples when subjected to in situ freeze-drying indicated reversible nature of the gels. (C) 1997 Academic Press.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC JNL-COMP SUBSCRIPTIONS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-16T06:27:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:06:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-16T06:27:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:06:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Letter</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF COLLOID AND INTERFACE SCIENCE,191(2)521-524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9797</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1006/jcis.1997.4946</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13994</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/205</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>