<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-256</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling tidal power plant at Saphale</dc:title><dc:creator>DEOKAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>LINGAYAT, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUKHATME, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>tidal power stations</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrohydrodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>numerical methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>partial differential equations</dc:subject><dc:description>A small scale site is available near Saphale village in Thane district of Maharashtra state. The shorter construction times and local consumption of the power generated makes this site economically attractive for establishment of the first pilot tidal power plant in the country. The use of mathematical modeling in planning and design of tidal power plant is established and accepted practice world over. Predicting the changes in tidal dynamics is a major aspect of tidal power projects. The flat estuary model is used for initial estimation of energy potential in a tidal cycle. The one dimensional model is used during feasibility analysis of the tidal power plant. The fundamental principles used in modeling the dynamical behavior of the various components of the tidal power plant and its application to small scale tidal power generation are discussed in this paper.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-10T06:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:09:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-10T06:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:09:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Tencon'98: Proceedings of the IEEE Region 10 International Conference on Global Connectivity in Energy, Computer, Communication and Control (V 2), New Delhi, India, December 17-19, 1998, 544-547</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-4886-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/TENCON.1998.798281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/256</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>