<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1244</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Photoluminescence studies on RF plasma-polymerized thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>SARAVANAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHAI, CJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHARAMAN, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATACHALAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>AVASTHI, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, F</dc:creator><dc:subject>polyaniline</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>aniline</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyaniline</dc:subject><dc:subject>infrared and raman spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical vapour deposition</dc:subject><dc:description>Conjugated polymers in the form of thin films play an important role in the field of materials science due to their interesting properties. Polymer thin films find extensive applications in the fabrication of devices, such as light emitting devices, rechargeable batteries, super capacitors, and are used as intermetallic dielectrics and EMI shieldings. Polymer thin films prepared by plasma-polymerization are highly cross-linked, pinhole free, and their permittivity lie in the ultra low k-regime. Electronic and photonic applications of plasma-polymerized thin films attracted the attention of various researchers. Modification of polymer thin films by swift heavy ions is well established and ion irradiation of polymers can induce irreversible changes in their structural, electrical, and optical properties. Polyaniline and polyfurfural thin films prepared by RF plasma-polymerization were irradiated with 92 MeV silicon ions for various fluences of 1x10(11) ions cm(-2), 1x10(12) ions cm(-2), and 1x10(13) ions cm(-2). FTIR have been recorded on the pristine and silicon ion irradiated polymer thin films for structural evaluation. Photoluminescence (PL) spectra were recorded for RF plasma-polymerized thin film samples before and after irradiation. In this paper the effect of swift heavy ions on the structural and photoluminescence spectra of plasma-polymerized thin films are investigated. (C) 2005 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T14:14:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T14:14:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SYNTHETIC METALS,155(2)311-315</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0379-6779</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.synthmet.2005.09.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14432</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1244</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th International Topical Conference on Optical Probes of Conjugated Polymers and Biosystems,Bangalore, INDIA,JAN 04-08, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>