<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3717</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>An optimized method for Aspergillus niger spore production on natural carrier substrates</dc:title><dc:creator>BAPAT, PM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANGIKAR, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>solid-state fermentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>waste-water</dc:subject><dc:subject>coniothyrium-minitans</dc:subject><dc:subject>biotransformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sporulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>terpenes</dc:subject><dc:subject>starch</dc:subject><dc:description>Aspergillus niger spores have wide ranging applications in the fermentation industry as well as in wastewater treatment. We present an optimized method for production of A. niger spores on natural substrates such as rice, split pea, and millet. The specific productivity (number of spores per gram of dry substrate) was 31-fold greater and volumetric productivity was 750-fold greater compared to agar slopes. The important process variables were incubation temperature, moisture content, and inoculum quantity. We find that the optimal condition for total spore count is different from the viable spore count for millet. The optimum lies in a narrow region defined by the process parameters. Of the three substrates tested split pea gave the highest specific spore productivity of 3.1 x 10(10) spores per gram of dry substrate. This is the first report of systematic study on the effect of process parameters on spore viability. The method of A. niger spore production on natural substrate appears advantageous as compared to the currently practiced method in terms of scale-up, cost, and ease of operation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T16:16:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T16:16:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOTECHNOLOGY PROGRESS, 19(6), 1683-1688</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>8756-7938</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/bp0341141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3717</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3717</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>