<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17226</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:44:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Phenylene-Diimine-Capped Conjugate of Lower Rim 1,3-Calix[4]Arene As Molecular Receptor for Mg2+ via Arm Conformational Changes Followed by Aggregation and Mimicking the Species by Molecular Mechanics</dc:title><dc:creator>NEHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNESIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOIETY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZN2+</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:description>A phenylene-diimine-capped conjugate of lower rim 1,3-calix[4]arene (L) was synthesized, characterized, and shown to selectively bind to Mg2+ using its capped arms. This results in a selective recognition of Mg2+ through eliciting fluorescence enhancement of similar to 70 fold with a detection limit of 40 +/- 5 ppb. However, in the presence of blood serum, the lowest detection limit is 209 +/- 10 ppb (0.2 mu M). The binding of Mg2+. to L is authenticated by absorption and H-1 NMR data. The Job's plot derived on the basis of the absorption data showed 1:1 stoichiometry between the receptor and Mg2+. The 1:1 species was further confirmed through ESI MS, that is, being supported by the isotope peak pattern authenticating the presence of Mg2+ in the complex. The L binds Mg2+ octahedrally using the tetradentate L2- and two additional acetic acid moieties by bringing conformational changes as studied on the basis of MM computations. The conformational changes that occur in the capped arms upon Mg2+ binding were supported experimentally by NOESY. AFM and SEM studies showed that spherical particles of L are modified into flower and chain type aggregates upon complexation with Mg2+, confirming the supramolecular behavior of the species formed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:44:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:44:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 79(12)5763-5770</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jo500892r</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17226</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>