<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9302</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental investigation on the aerodynamic characteristics of a tandem wing configuration in close ground proximity</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMED, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOHAMA, Y</dc:creator><dc:subject>tunnel</dc:subject><dc:subject>experimental investigation</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>tandem wings</dc:subject><dc:subject>ground effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>lift</dc:subject><dc:subject>drag</dc:subject><dc:description>Influence of ground clearance and angle of attack on the aerodynamic characteristics of a tandem wing configuration with a variable distance between them and held together by two flat end plates, is studied experimentally. A moving belt system was used to simulate the true ground effect. Both the wing sections were having SYM-1B profile, which is known to have excellent aerodynamic characteristics in ground effect. It was found that the ground clearance of the wings and the angles of attack to the wings have a very strong influence on the aerodynamic performance of the tandem wings. A strong interference effect between the wake ol the front wing and the rear wing affects the aerodynamic performance of the tandem wing configuration, especially when the distance between the wings is shorter. The system showed high pitching instability for increased spacing between the tandem wings.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JAPAN SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T08:39:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T08:39:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JSME INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL SERIES B-FLUIDS AND THERMAL ENGINEERING, 42(4), 612-618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1340-8054</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9302</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>