<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2628</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Strength evaluation of fiber reinforced hot mixed open graded asphalt concrete</dc:title><dc:creator>BHOSALE, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>cyclic unconfined compression test</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclic triaxial test</dc:subject><dc:subject>fiber reinforced ac</dc:subject><dc:subject>open graded ac mix</dc:subject><dc:subject>bailey method</dc:subject><dc:subject>resilient modulus</dc:subject><dc:description>Hot mixed asphalt concrete is a composite material of aggregate particles of crushed rock of different sizes, glued together with an asphalt binder, which is much softer than the aggregate. The term open graded is used since the percentage of air voids in it, are more than 20%, which is much higher than that in the normal asphalt concrete mixes. These mixes are used as a crack relief layer for mitigation of reflection cracking on asphalt concrete overlays. Bailey Method for gradation selection (Vavrik et al. 2002) is used for deciding aggregate gradation, because the method advocates a strong aggregate skeleton for rut resistance along with adequate voids in mineral aggregate for good durability. Cylindrical sample of diameter 101.6 mm and height of 203.2 mm (ASTM D 1074 - 1996), is utilized for the testing work. The Unconfined Compression Test (ASTM D 1074 - 1996), Triaxial Compression Test, and Resilient Modulus Test (TRB Special Report 162) are used for the strength evaluation of the open graded asphalt concrete mix. PET Fibers are used as reinforcement in the open graded asphalt concrete mixes. These reinforced samples are also tested for their mechanical properties. The testing is performed at a room temperature of 27 degrees C. The aim of this paper is to present and compare the test results of the unreinforced and fiber reinforced open graded asphalt concrete mixes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MILLPRESS SCIENCE PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T13:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T13:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Geosynthetics, Vols 1-4,801-804</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-5966-044-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2628</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th International Conference on Geosynthetics (8ICG),Yokohama, JAPAN,SEP 18-22, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>