<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17189</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:26:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural and optical properties of ZnO nanorods grown chemically on sputtered GaN buffer layers</dc:title><dc:creator>NANDI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHANTA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJOR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>ZnO</dc:subject><dc:subject>GaN</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanorods</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemical bath deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPITAXIAL-GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEED LAYER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBSTRATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARRAYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HETEROJUNCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOBELTS</dc:subject><dc:description>ZnO nanorods were grown on 200 nm thick sputtered ZnO and GaN buffer layers on quartz substrates by chemical bath deposition. Field emission scanning electron microscopy and X-ray diffraction studies show that the ZnO nanorods on GaN buffer layer possess larger diameter and smaller lengths and are vertically misaligned, compared to those grown on ZnO buffer layer. These differences are attributed to lack of complete c-axis orientation of crystallites in GaN buffer layer, its lattice mismatch with that of ZnO and a hindered nucleation process of ZnO on GaN surface, owing to a finite nucleation barrier and limited surface diffusion. Photoluminescence spectrum of ZnO nanorods on GaN buffer layer, however, exhibits a much stronger near-band-edge luminescence and drastically suppressed defect luminescence compared to the luminescence spectrum of the nanorods grown on ZnO buffer layer. Deconvolution of the photoluminescence peaks and Raman studies indicate significant reduction of oxygen vacancies and gallium incorporation in the ZnO nanorods grown on GaN buffer layer. These observations suggest the possibility of exchange reaction mediated by the aqueous medium, particularly during the initial stages of growth. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:26:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:26:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS, 555122-125</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2013.10.152</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17189</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>