<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15749</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:10:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Factors influencing the crushing strength of some Aegean sands</dc:title><dc:creator>ERZIN, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATEL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIGA, MG</dc:creator><dc:creator>YILMAZ, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVAS, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>Aegean sands</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anatolian sands</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crushing strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>Particle morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sphericity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Roundness</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRANULAR-MATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Engineering properties of sands mainly depend on the integrity of the particles, which in turn has a strong bearing on their crushing strength. Seven different Aegean sands were tested for mineralogy, particle shape, size and specific gravity and the influence of aspect ratio, particle composition, particle shape and size on the crushing strength was examined. As the Aegean sands have a small range of sphericity and roundness, crushing strength tests were also performed on five Anatolian sands. A multiple regression analysis was carried out and an equation proposed to determine the crushing strength value of the Aegean sands. The computed values were found to be in good agreement with those obtained from the experimental investigations. It is concluded that the equation is sufficiently accurate to be a useful, time- and cost-effective way of obtaining crushing strength estimations at the preliminary stage of site investigations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF ENGINEERING GEOLOGY AND THE ENVIRONMENT, 71(3)529-536</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-012-0424-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15749</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>