<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16341</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:19:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>N-Methyl-21-thiaporphyrins</dc:title><dc:creator>KAUR, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEE, WZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Macrocycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Porphyrinoids</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fluorescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sulfur heterocycles</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITED-STATE PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL-CHARACTERIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>21-THIAPORPHYRIN COMPLEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREE-BASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PORPHYRINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRA</dc:subject><dc:description>We synthesized five N-methyl-meso-tetraaryl-21-thiaporphyrins in 55-60% yield by treating the appropriate meso-tetraaryl-21-thiaporphyrin with CH3I. The N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins were characterized by HRMS, 1D and 2D NMR spectroscopy, absorption spectroscopy, fluorescence spectroscopy, and electrochemical techniques, and the structure of one of the compounds was obtained by X-ray crystallography. 1D and 2D NMR spectroscopy were used to identify all of the resonances observed in the H-1 NMR spectra of the N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins. NMR studies indicated that the methylation occurred at the pyrrole ring that is opposite to the thiophene ring. In the H-1 NMR spectra, the methylation resulted in significant upfield shifts of the pyrrole and thiophene protons; the maximum shifts were noted for the protons of the N-methylated pyrrole ring of the N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins. The X-ray structure of one of the N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins revealed significant deviation of the N-methylated pyrrole ring from the reference plane defined by the four meso carbon atoms, and the porphyrin ring is strongly distorted compared to the 21-thiaporphyrin ring. The absorption studies revealed that the N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins showed four Q bands and one strong Soret band, which were bathochromically shifted compared to those of the 21-thiaporphyrins. The electrochemical studies on the N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins indicated that the oxidation potentials became less positive and there were negligible shifts in the reduction potentials; the HOMO-LUMO energy gap decreased compared with that of the 21-thiaporphyrins. The N-methyl-21-thiaporphyrins are weakly fluorescent with low quantum yields and singlet-state lifetimes. The spectral and electrochemical studies indicated that N-methylation of the pyrrole ring of 21-thiaporphyrins significantly alters the electronic properties of the 21-thiaporphyrin macrocycle.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:19:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:19:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF ORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 2014(11)2261-2267</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1434-193X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1099-0690</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ejoc.201301863</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16341</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>