<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7304</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-20T11:58:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of titanium based biocomposite by powder metallurgy processing with in situ forming of Ca-P phases</dc:title><dc:creator>KARANJAI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNDARESAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, GVN</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, TRR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>hydroxyapatite coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>calcium</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphorus</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydroxylapatite</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocomposite</dc:subject><dc:subject>load bearing implants</dc:subject><dc:description>Composites of titanium and calcium-phosphorus phases were developed by powder metallurgy processing and evaluated for bioactivity. Titanium hydride powder and precursors of calcium and phosphorus in the form of calcium carbonate and di-ammonium hydrogen orthophosphate were mixed in different proportions, compacted and calcined in different atmospheres. The calcined compacts were subsequently crushed, recompacted and sintered in vacuum. In situ formation of bioactive phases like hydroxylapatite, tricalcium phosphate and calcium titanate during the calcination and sintering steps was studied using X-ray diffraction. The effect of calcination atmosphere on density, interconnected porosity, phase composition and modulus of rupture of sintered composites was examined. The sintered composites were immersed in simulated body fluid for 7 days to observe their in vitro behaviour with XRD and FTIR spectroscopic identification of deposits. Composites with 10 wt% precursors sintered from vacuum calcined powder gave the best results in terms of bioactive phases, density and strength. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T19:06:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T19:06:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING, 447(1-2), 19-26</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2006.10.154</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7304</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>