<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7135</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Variation in shoulder and hip joint axis in relation to vertebral column axis and changes in spinal curvature while carrying water by head, shoulder and waist mode</dc:title><dc:creator>RAY, GG</dc:creator><dc:creator>ATREYA, V</dc:creator><dc:description>Present study was conducted on 5 women engaged in water carrying activity either for themselves or for there livelihood. The aim of the study was to find out the variation in shoulder and hip joint axis in relation to vertebral column axis and also changes in spinal curvature while carrying water by head, shoulder and waist mode. The whole body center of gravity (CG) was determined by using the segmental method based on video photograph while carrying the load. The spinal curvature was determined by using the flexicurve. The highest upward (z axis) shift in CG was observed for the head mode and more the load was, more was the shift. Incase of waist mode with the increment of load, more shift in the whole body CG was observed towards the load CG in Y axis which was basically due to the volume of the load. Incase of shoulder mode the shift in CG was observed both in Z and Y axis. Shift in the hip joint axis was also observed in shoulder and the waist mode of load carrying along with the lateral shift of the vertebral column. In case of shoulder mode the lateral shift of the vertebral column observed was 14.8 degrees, 17.2 degrees, 17.9 degrees and same for the waist mode was 14.4 degrees, 14.1 degrees, 13.0 degrees and 17.8 degrees respectively for 10, 15, 20 and 25 kg load. To find out the effect of load carrying on anterio-posterio spinal curvature, changes in the angles at cervical and lumbar regions while carrying load was compared against the without load condition. Significant difference was observed in cervical curvature for head 25 kg and shoulder 20 kg. No significant difference was observed in any other combinations. Survey on body ache and body pain revealed that women carrying water by head mode had high degree of pain in head, neck and hands. Severe body pain was observed in upper arm, lower arm, palm, and waist in case of shoulder mode. In case of waist mode pain in the waist, elbow upper arm, lower arm and wrist was observed. From the lateral vertebral column shift, shift in the hip and shoulder axis joint with reference to the normal standing erect condition and body pain as complaint by the workers, it could therefore be concluded that carrying water by shoulder and waist mode are potentially dangerous from the view point of spinal injury.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T05:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T05:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GLOBAL ERGONOMICS, (), 91-97</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/B978-008043334-9/50018-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7135</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>