<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9638</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Inelastic seismic resistance of reinforced concrete stack-like structures</dc:title><dc:creator>GOYAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>stacks</dc:subject><dc:subject>chimneys</dc:subject><dc:subject>towers</dc:subject><dc:subject>ductility</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic design</dc:subject><dc:subject>inelastic response</dc:subject><dc:description>A method is presented to quantify the inelastic seismic resistance of reinforced concrete stack-like structures by non-linear earthquake analysis. The deformed configuration of stack is idealized as an assemblage of beam elements and actual stress-strain relationships of concrete and reinforcing steel are used to evaluate element matrices. Repeated non-linear analyses are performed by gradually increasing the intensity of acceleration time histories to a level where collapse of the stack is observed in primary stresses. The set of time histories thus obtained are then used to define the ultimate intensity of ground motion that the stack can sustain if inelastic deformations are permitted. A procedure is presented to quantify the difference between inelastic seismic resistance and elastic seismic resistance in terms of displacement ductility capacity factors. For seismic design using available inelastic resistance, values of curvature ductility factor demand for the cross-sections of stacks are also presented. (C) 1997 by , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T22:04:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T22:04:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING &amp; STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS, 26(5), 501-513</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-8847</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9845(199705)26:5&lt;501::AID-EQE665&gt;3.0.CO;2-L</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9638</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9638</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>