<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1734</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>TL and ESR characteristics of BaSO4 : Eu co-doped with Na/P : influence of method of preparation</dc:title><dc:creator>SHINDE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANAYE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATT, BC</dc:creator><dc:subject>phosphors</dc:subject><dc:description>Two new thermoluminescent (TL) phosphors BaSO4:Eu,P and BaSO4:Eu,Na were prepared by three different methods, e.g. recrystallisation, co-precipitation and sintering at high temperature. The phosphors exhibit variations in the thermoluminescent characteristics and also in their electron spin resonance (ESR) spectra. Both phosphors show changes in their glow curve shape and TL sensitivity with the method of preparation and with the concentration of co-dopant (sodium/phosphorus). Maximum TL sensitivity (approximate to 5 times that of CaSO4:Dy) was obtained in the case of BaSO4:Eu,Na (0.7, 2.5 mol%), prepared by sintering in air at 900 degrees C. ESR spectra of both phosphors prepared by the method of co-precipitation and sintering, showed the presence of SO2-(A) and SO2-(B) ESR centres after gamma irradiation at room temperature. SO2-(A) centres are found to decay at about 170 degrees C and correlate well with the 165 degrees C glow peak. SO2-(B) centres decay around 220 degrees C and relate well with the 215 degrees C TL peak. BaSO4:Eu,P prepared by the method of recrystallisation exhibits only SO2-(A) defect centres in conformity with the observed single glow peak at 170 degrees C. BaSO4:Eu,Na phosphor showing an individual peak at 165 degrees C or 215 degrees C could not be synthesised.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NUCLEAR TECHNOLOGY PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T12:23:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T12:23:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>RADIATION PROTECTION DOSIMETRY,84,215-218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0144-8420</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14897</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1734</dc:identifier><dc:source>12th International Conference on Solid State Dosimetry,BURGOS, SPAIN,JUL 05-10, 1998</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>