<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16869</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:26:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparative electromagnetic analysis of ridge waveguide transitions for RF power couplers</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHUR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>Waveguide iris coupler</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ridge waveguide coupler</dc:subject><dc:subject>Waveguide to cavity coupler</dc:subject><dc:subject>RF power coupler</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ridge waveguide transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAVITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Ridge waveguide transitions have been used in the high power couplers of many ongoing high intensity proton accelerator projects worldwide. Because of their smaller size and high energy densities, they require strict dimensional tolerances during fabrication and operating conditions. In order to study their electromagnetic characteristics, two different types of transitions with a straight ridge and a tapered ridge are compared using full wave simulations. Apart from the return loss and resonant frequency variation with dimensions, comparative studies on the phase shift, insertion losses, electric and magnetic field distributions and multipacting are also reported. This analysis will be useful in selecting the appropriate ridge waveguide transition for the RF couplers of accelerator cavities. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:26:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:26:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION A-ACCELERATORS SPECTROMETERS DETECTORS AND ASSOCIATED EQUIPMENT, 73699-106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-9002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-9576</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1010/j.nima.2013.10.050</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16869</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>