<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5282</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improving filtrate quality using agrobased materials as coagulant aid</dc:title><dc:creator>RAGHUWANSHI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDLOI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, AJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALVIYA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>alzheimers-disease</dc:subject><dc:subject>drinking-water</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>agrobased materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>coagulant aid</dc:subject><dc:subject>filtration</dc:subject><dc:subject>water quality</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, an evaluation of agrobased materials (ABM) as a coagulant aid in conjunction with alum has been conducted to determine their efficacy in water treatment. The agrobased materials evaluated are Surjana seed (Moringa oleifera), Nirmali seed (Strychnos potatorum) and maize (Zeemays). Experiments have been conducted simulating a conventional water treatment train consisting of coagulation-flocculation-settling and granular media filtration. Emphasis has been given to the filtration aspect of the treatment train using synthetic turbid water. The filter performance was defined by water quality and head loss development across the filter bed. When Nirmali seed or maize was used as a coagulant aid, the alum dose required was 25 and 15 mg/L, respectively, and the filtrate turbidity achieved was less than 0.2 NTU, whereas alum alone with a dose of 45 mg/L achieved filtrate turbidity levels higher than 1 NTU. Thus, the use of ABM improved the filtrate quality. Head loss in filter with Surjana seed and Maize as coagulant aids was comparable to that of alum alone, whereas it was higher when Nirmali seed was used as a coagulant aid.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CANADIAN ASSOC WATER QUALITY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T11:27:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T11:27:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER QUALITY RESEARCH JOURNAL OF CANADA, 37(4), 745-756</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1201-3080</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5282</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5282</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>