<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16473</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:15:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ce3+ sensitized GdPO4:Tb3+ with iron oxide nanoparticles: a potential biphasic system for cancer theranostics</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRADHAN, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>UP-CONVERSION LUMINESCENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>TARGETED DRUG-DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>INORGANIC NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FE3O4 NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTROLLED-RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANORODS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCARRIERS</dc:subject><dc:description>We report a biphasic system (BPS) consisting of PEGylated Tb3+-doped GdPO4 nanorice sensitized with Ce3+ (PEG-NRs) and glutamic acid coated iron oxide nanoparticles (IONPs) with multifunctional capabilities. The mesoporous PEG-NRs exhibit green light luminescence properties and a high degree of aqueous stability. Their drug loading and release capacities were investigated for anti-cancer chemo doxorubicin (DOX). Their mesoporous nature and availability of plenty of negatively charged functional groups (-COO-) on the surface of PEG-NRs facilitate approximately 94 wt% DOX loading. In vitro studies carried out for PEG-NRs and their biphasic integrated system with iron oxide using HeLa and MCF-7 cell lines demonstrated their cell killing efficacy. The green luminescence observed under confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM) confirms the cellular uptake of PEG-NRs by HeLa cell lines and their accumulation in the cytoplasm. Approximately 50-55% of HeLa and MCF-7 cell death was observed after 24 h of incubation with DOX loaded BPS (2 mg IONPs and 0.25 mg PEG-NRs + DOX), which further increased to about 90% when exposed to an AC magnetic field (ACMF) for 25 min. Our findings demonstrate that the therapeutic efficacy of BPS loaded with DOX could be a powerful multimodal system for imaging and synergistic chemo-thermal cancer therapy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:15:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:15:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 43(30)11728-11738</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4dt00792a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16473</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>