<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15487</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:55:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Classification of place of articulation in unvoiced stops with spectro-temporal surface modeling</dc:title><dc:creator>KARJIGI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Place of articulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Unvoiced stops</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spectro-temporal features</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPEECH RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSONANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERCEPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FEATURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>UTTERANCES</dc:subject><dc:description>Unvoiced stops are rapidly varying sounds with acoustic cues to place identity linked to the temporal dynamics. Neurophysiological studies have indicated the importance of joint spectro-temporal processing in the human perception of stops. In this study, two distinct approaches to modeling the spectra-temporal envelope of unvoiced stop phone segments are investigated with a view to obtaining a low-dimensional feature vector for automatic place classification. Classification accuracies on the TIMIT database and a Marathi words dataset show the overall superiority of classifier combination of polynomial surface coefficients and 2D-DCT. A comparison of performance with published results on the place classification of stops revealed that the proposed spectro-temporal feature systems improve upon the best previous systems' performances. The results indicate that joint spectro-temporal features may be usefully incorporated in hierarchical phone classifiers based on diverse class-specific features. (c) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:55:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:55:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SPEECH COMMUNICATION, 54(10)1104-1120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.specom.2012.04.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15487</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>