<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2911</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-21T06:38:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Maximum likelihood detection for cooperative diversity in MIMO relay channels</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, GVV</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANWANI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>wireless communications</dc:subject><dc:subject>cooperative diversity</dc:subject><dc:subject>mimo relay</dc:subject><dc:subject>space-time coding</dc:subject><dc:description>Antenna sharing by multiple users using cooperative diversity has been shown to mimic the performance of traditional multiple input, multiple output (MIMO) systems. While this was originally done using a single antenna at each relay, the benefits of cooperative diversity based on multiantenna relays has been a subject of considerable interest. Maximum likelihood (ML) detectors for cooperative diversity through single antenna relays are well known. In this paper, we propose to combine the benefits of cooperative diversity, and transmit and receive diversity offered by MIMO systems. This is done within the ML based decode and forward (DF) cooperative diversity framework, by using multiple antennas at each relay, through ML based processing on the source-relay link and space-time coding on the relay-destination link. Through simulations, we then show that the performance of MIMO Relay based systems is superior to those having a single antenna at each relay.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T21:16:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T21:16:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>68TH IEEE VEHICULAR TECHNOLOGY CONFERENCE, FALL 2008,1770-1774</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1722-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1090-3038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2911</dc:identifier><dc:source>68th IEEE Vehicular Technology Conference,Calgary, CANADA,SEP 21-24, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>