<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18338</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:11:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Scalable Segment Routing-A New Paradigm for Efficient Service Provider Networking Using Carrier Ethernet Advances</dc:title><dc:creator>BIDKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUMASTE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHODASARA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, JP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOMANI, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRETCH</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROUTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENERGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Carrier Ethernet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Compact routing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Omnipresent Ethernet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Segment routing</dc:subject><dc:description>Segment routing has recently been proposed in the IETF toward making IP/MPLS networks service-oriented while simplifying network operations. Segment routing computes paths at the source node using node identifiers and adjacency identifiers conjoined together to create a source-routed path. We propose a scalable transport paradigm as an enabler toward implementing segment routing in provider networks. We propose omnipresent Ethernet, our modification of carrier Ethernet (which is based on source-routed, binary-routed labels embedded in an Ethernet frame), to implement segment routing. We identify some of the scalability issues of the segment-routing proposal in the context of source-routing overhead. To absolve scalability issues of segment routing, two routing schemes that implement multidomain source-routing techniques are proposed. The hierarchical segment-routing (H-SR) scheme is proposed, which deploys a limited number of special nodes called swap nodes that are capable of label swapping to implement routing. The swap-node placement problem is formulated as an integer linear program to minimize the total routing distance within a network. Three heuristic techniques for swap-node selection based on centrality paradigms are presented. The H-SR scheme is further improved by a proposed multisegment-routing (M-SR) scheme that assumes all nodes in the network to be capable of label swapping. The H-SR and M-SR schemes are shown to significantly enhance the scalability of segment routing. A test-bed is built using carrier Ethernet hardware to support segment routing that validates the implementation of the proposed schemes. A simulation model to evaluate the schemes from a scalability perspective and their associated trade-offs is presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>OPTICAL SOC AMER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:11:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:11:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF OPTICAL COMMUNICATIONS AND NETWORKING, 7(5)445-460</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1943-0620</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1943-0639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1364/JOCN.7.000445</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18338</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>