<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1540</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Semiconducting carbon films from a natural source: camphor</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNDARAKOTEESWARAN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KICHAMBARE, PD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANDO, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHAO, XL</dc:creator><dc:subject>tubules</dc:subject><dc:subject>camphor</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>scanning electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor</dc:subject><dc:description>Thin films of carbon have been grown on alumina substrates by the pyrolysis of camphor at 900 degrees C for 2h in an argon atmosphere, followed by sintering for various time periods. The effect of sintering time on the surface morphology, conductivity, carrier concentration, mobility and bandgap of camphor-pyrolyzed films is discussed. Structural characterizations are performed on the basis of XRD and SEM analyses. Electrical conductivity measurements of these films, as a function of temperature, suggest them to be semiconductors. Hall-effect study of the as-grown films shows their carrier concentrations to be of the order of 10(17) cm(-3). The Hall mobilities of these films are found to vary from 1702 to 10263 cm(2) V-1 s(-1). The thermal bandgaps of these films are found to decrease with increasing sintering time. Thus, by controlled sintering of camphor-pyrolyzed carbon films, it is possible to obtain a semiconductor with the desired bandgap. Therefore, camphor-pyrolyzed semiconducting carbon films seem to be a promising material to develop a photovoltaic solar cell. (C) 1999 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:17:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:17:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DIAMOND AND RELATED MATERIALS,8,485-489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-9635</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0925-9635(98)00289-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14752</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1540</dc:identifier><dc:source>9th European Conference on Diamond, Diamond-like Materials, Nitrides and Silicon Carbide (Diamond 1998),IRAKLION, GREECE,SEP 13-18, 1998</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>