<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1565</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Studies on dechlorination of DDT (1,1,1-trichloro-2,2-bis(4-chlorophenyl)ethane) using magnesium/palladium bimetallic system</dc:title><dc:creator>GAUTAM, SUMIT KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, SUMATHI</dc:creator><dc:subject>dechlorination</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnesium</dc:subject><dc:subject>palladium</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnesium printing plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>reaction kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface active agents</dc:subject><dc:subject>toxicity</dc:subject><dc:description>The aim of our investigation was to compare the rates of dechlorination of DDT using Mg0/Pd4+ system in two different reaction phases, namely, water–acetone and 0.05% biosurfactant in water. Since palladium is expensive and its toxicity effects are not well known we also examined the reuse efficiency of Pd0 immobilized on alumina for dechlorinating DDT. Studies on the dechlorination of DDT in water–acetone (1:1, v/v) and 0.05% biosurfactant phases revealed that the reaction followed second order kinetics and rate of reaction is dependent upon both initial concentrations of the target compound and Mg0/Pd4+. The presence of acid enhanced the rate of reaction by providing protons and preventing passivation of metal that occurs due to deposition of magnesium hydroxide. GC–MS analyses revealed the formation of completely dechlorinated hydrocarbon skeleton of DDT namely, diphenylethane (DPE), as the end product in both reaction phases (water–acetone and 0.05% biosurfactant in water) thereby implying the removal of all five chlorine atoms (three alkyl and two aryl) of DDT. The optimum ratio of water and acetone to facilitate successful dechlorination reaction was found to be 9:1. Results suggested that salt form (K2PdCl6) of palladium had higher potential to dechlorinate DDT as compared to pellet (Pd0–alumina) form (efficiencies of 95 and 36%, respectively, for 100 ppm initial concentration of DDT). We noted that Pd0–alumina pellets could be reused at least four times for successful dechlorination of DDT provided Mg0 granules are present in sufficient quantity. Technical grade DDT (50 ppm) containing significant amounts of DDD was dechlorinated almost completely by the Mg0/Pd4+ (10 mg/0.2 mg/ml) within 1 h in water–biosurfactant phase. Our studies reveal that Mg/Pd system is a promising option due to its high reactivity and its ability to achieve complete dechlorination of DDT. This bimetallic system may be useful for designing indigenous permeable barriers or reactors for the treatment of DDT contaminated water.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-22T07:06:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:03:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-22T07:06:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:03:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Hazardous Materials 139(1), 146-153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.06.017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1565</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1565</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>