<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15205</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:54:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optical Bandgap Tunability of Silicon Nanocrystals Fabricated by Inductively Coupled Plasma CVD for Next Generation Photovoltaics</dc:title><dc:creator>MAVILLA, NR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>Inductively coupled plasma chemical vapor deposition (ICPCVD)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Raman spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon nanocrystal (Si-NCs)</dc:subject><dc:subject>tandem solar cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>UV-Vis spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMICAL-VAPOR-DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SI/SIO2 SUPERLATTICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITRIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATRIX</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:description>Superior optical properties of Si-nanocrystals (Si-NCs) compared with bulk Si, particularly tunability of bandgap by controlling size, can be exploited for realizing next-generation Si tandem solar cells. In view of this, optical bandgap tunability of Si-NCs fabricated by Inductively Coupled Plasma Enhanced Chemical Vapor Deposition (ICPCVD) is presented. The SiOx&lt;2/SiO2 superlattice approach was used for realizing Si-NCs with tight size control. Deposition time of SiOx sublayer and, hence, the related thickness (T-SRO), was used as a variable parameter to realize Si-NCs of varying sizes. Formation of Si-NCs was verified by transmission electron microscopy and Raman spectroscopy. Using XPS analysis, the stoichiometry parameter x was estimated to be 0.82 for SiOx sublayer. The optical bandgap E-Tauc estimated using Tauc analysis was observed to be tunable from 1.57 to 2.52 eV as the size of Si-NCs was varied from 5.8 (+/- 0.5) to 2 (+/- 0.4) nm, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:54:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:54:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE JOURNAL OF PHOTOVOLTAICS, 3(4)1279-1286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JPHOTOV.2013.2272876</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15205</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>