<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10948</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>INFLUENCE OF ISOTROPIC STRAIN-HARDENING ON PLANE-STRAIN DYNAMIC GROWTH IN ELASTIC-PLASTIC MATERIALS</dc:title><dc:creator>VENKATESHA, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>crack-growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>asymptotic analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>tip</dc:subject><dc:subject>fields</dc:subject><dc:subject>fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>solids</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, dynamic crack growth in an elastic-plastic material is analysed under mode I, plane strain, small-scale yielding conditions using a finite element procedure. The material is assumed to obey J2 incremental theory of plasticity with isotropic strain hardening which is of the power-law type under uniaxial tension. The influence of material inertia and strain hardening on the stress and deformation fields near the crack tip is investigated. The results demonstrate that strain hardening tends to oppose the role of inertia in decreasing plastic strains and stresses near the crack tip. The length scale near the crack tip over which inertia effects are dominant also diminishes with increase in strain hardening. A ductile crack growth criterion based on the attainment of a critical crack tip opening displacement is used to obtain the dependence of the theoretical dynamic fracture toughness on crack speed. It is found that the resistance offered by the elastic-plastic material to high speed crack propagation may be considerably reduced when it possesses some strain hardening.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T08:01:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T08:01:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 39(6), 1015-1026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0013-7944(91)90108-D</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10948</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>