<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-731</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>A double catgrip mixed L and D mini protein only 20 residues long</dc:title><dc:creator>RANA, SOUMENDRA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, BIJOY</dc:creator><dc:creator>DURANI, SUSHEEL</dc:creator><dc:subject>nuclear magnetic resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>circular dichroism</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthesis</dc:subject><dc:description>Stereochemistry limits but also defines proteins, as conformational constructs stereospecific for poly-L structure. Employed as a variable in sequence, stereochemistry could make proteins customizable in the letters of L and D amino acid alphabet. In proof of concept, we previously demonstrated stereochemical reengineering of canonical β-hairpins as bracelet and boat shaped molecules. Illustrating the prospect for functional design, a 20-residue four-stranded mini-β protein is now customized stereochemically as a canoe shaped molecule. A conformational construct of four side by side hydrogen-bonded strands in alternately Lβ, Dβ conformation, joined via Type-II/II′ β-turns, is planned to be preponderantly apolar in β-sheet favoring residues, interspersing two ion pairs, and suitably L and D in sequence. Synthesis followed by MD, NMR, CD, and MALDI-MS studies established the molecule as a canoe shaped fold in water, demonstrable in affinity of alkali and alkaline-earth metal ions as expected given its catgrip like elements. Another success in accomplishing a synthetic miniprotein complex in stereochemistry and stereospecific in conformation, exceptionally small yet functional in metal ion affinity, affirms the value in combined L and D alphabet in programming molecular shapes and functions stereochemically.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-21T11:28:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:19:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-21T11:28:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:19:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Bioorganic &amp; Medicinal Chemistry 15(11), 3874-3882</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0968-0896</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.bmc.2007.03.030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/731</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/731</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>