<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15111</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:32:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermoelectric spin accumulation and long-time spin precession in a noncollinear quantum dot spin valve</dc:title><dc:creator>MURALIDHARAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>GRIFONI, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>DRIVEN</dc:subject><dc:description>We explore thermoelectric spin transport and spin dependent phenomena in a noncollinear quantum dot spin valve setup. Using this setup, we demonstrate the possibility of a thermoelectric excitation of single spin dynamics inside the quantum dot. Many-body exchange fields generated on the single spins in this setup manifest as effective magnetic fields acting on the net spin accumulation in the quantum dot. We first identify generic conditions by which a zero bias spin accumulation in the dot may be created in the thermoelectric regime. The resulting spin accumulation is then shown to be subject to a fieldlike spin torque due to the effective magnetic field associated with either contact. This spin torque that is generated may yield long-time precession effects due to the prevailing blockade conditions. The implications of these phenomena in connection with single spin manipulation and pure spin current generation are then discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:32:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:32:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 88(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-235X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.88.045402</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15111</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>