<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11343</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stability of sandwich plates by mixed, higher-order analytical formulation</dc:title><dc:creator>DAFEDAR, JB</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUFTI, AA</dc:creator><dc:subject>laminated composite</dc:subject><dc:subject>buckling analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>panels</dc:subject><dc:subject>faces</dc:subject><dc:subject>loads</dc:subject><dc:subject>buckling</dc:subject><dc:subject>higher-order theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>local buckling</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>wrinkling</dc:subject><dc:description>A unified mixed, higher-order analytical formulation has been presented in this paper to predict general buckling as well as wrinkling of a general multi-layer, multi-core sandwich plate having any arbitrary sequence of stiff layers and cores. Assumptions of thin stiff layers and anti-plane core, which are usually made in the analysis of sandwiches, have been eliminated in the present formulation. Displacements as well as the transverse stress continuities have been enforced in the formulation by incorporating them as the degrees-of-freedom. The modal transverse stresses have been obtained directly as eigen vectors and thus their separate calculations have been advantageously avoided. Two sets of mixed models have been proposed on the basis of individual layer as well as equivalent single layer (ESL) theories by selectively incorporating non-linear components of Green's strain tensor. Solutions from the models have been shown to be in excellent agreement with the available three-dimensional elasticity solutions as well as with the available experimental results. It has been demonstrated that the ESL theories cannot accurately evaluate the overall buckling as well as the wrinkling loads of sandwiches. Limitations of the typical simplifying assumptions have also been highlighted. (C) 2003  Elsevier Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-26T14:41:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-26T14:41:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF SOLIDS AND STRUCTURES, 40(17), 4501-4517</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0020-7683(03)00283-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11343</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11343</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>