<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15456</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:39:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis and electronic properties of meso-furyl boron dipyrromethenes</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAIKH, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Meso-furyl boron dipyrromethene</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogen bonding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dihedral angle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stoke's shift</dc:subject><dc:subject>Easier reductions</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT BODIPY DYES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHARGE-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROGENERATED CHEMILUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOPHYSICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMISTRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBSTITUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Four meso-furyl boron-dipyrromethenes (BODIPYs) were synthesized and characterized. The X-ray structures solved for three meso-furyl BODIPYs indicated the presence of an intramolecular hydrogen bond between meso-furyl 'O' and 'H' of boron-dipyrromethene core resulting in decrease of dihedral angle between the meso-furyl group and boron-dipyrromethene core leading to better electronic interaction. However, the hydrogen bonding is absent in solution as confirmed by NMR studies in different solvents. The presence of meso-furyl group alters the electronic properties of BODIPY which reflected in the down-field shifts in H-1 NMR, bathochromic shifts in absorption and emission bands compared to the meso-tolyl BODIPY. The electrochemical studies indicated that the meso-furyl BODIPYs are easier to reduce compared to meso-tolyl BODIPYs. DFT studies showed that the HOMO-LUMO energy gap is decreased in meso-furyl BODIPYs compared to meso-tolyl BODIPY which is in agreement with the experimental observations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B. V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:39:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:39:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANICA CHIMICA ACTA, 383257-266</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2011.11.017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15456</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>