<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1443</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrochemical denitrificaton of simulated ground water</dc:title><dc:creator>DASH, BARADA PRASANNA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, SANJEEV</dc:creator><dc:subject>electrochemical electrodes</dc:subject><dc:subject>ammonia</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrogen</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>ph effects</dc:subject><dc:description>Electrochemical denitrification of ground water was studied with an objective to maximize nitrate transformation to nitrogen gas. Aluminum, graphite, iron and titanium were selected as electrode materials. While aluminum, iron and titanium electrodes showed 70–97% nitrate reduction, with graphite electrode the removal was only 8%. Nitrate was transformed to ammonia with iron and aluminum electrodes but with titanium electrodes nitrogen was apparently the major end product. Iron electrodes exhibited the maximum reducing condition (ORP=−463 mV) and titanium showed the minimum (ORP=–206 mV). Nitrate reduction with titanium electrodes was retarded in the presence of chloride ions possibly due to formation of hypochlorite ions. The first-order nitrate transformation rate constant with respect to time decreased with decrease in current density. However, when the rate constant was expressed with respect to charge passed (Coulomb/l) it was nearly same under different experimental conditions (current density and pH). The study indicates that the process might be suitable for denitrification of drinking water.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-05T08:53:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:48:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-05T08:53:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:48:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Water Research 39(17), 4065-4072</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0043-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.watres.2005.07.032</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1443</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1443</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>