<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1558</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ionic transport behaviour of POE-POPG-NaI blends for batteries</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAULMER, RDA</dc:creator><dc:subject>polymer electrolytes</dc:subject><dc:subject>conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid electrolyte batteries</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer blends and transport number</dc:subject><dc:description>Ternary polymer blends in the POE-POPG-NaI system are prepared and characterised, The optimised compositions are completely amorphous. The nature of the films is analysed using thermal analysis, X-ray diffraction and electrical transport studies. The amorphous composition showed highest conductivity of nearly 3 x 10(-5) (ohm-cm)(-)1 at room temperature. The composition with highest conductivity was selected for transport number studies using two different techniques. One of the techniques is the combination of AC impedance and polarisation while the other was ITIC method. Transport number for sodium ion was found to be more than 0.9. The applicability of the electrolyte was tested in a prototype cell. The initial open circuit voltages (OCV) of the experimental cell was 2.1 Volts and the cells were stable upto 8 months. Composition dependence of the above propel-ties is investigated and will also be discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CENTRAL ELECTROCHEM RES INST</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T00:00:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T00:00:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF ELECTROCHEMISTRY,12,743-746</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-1654</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14771</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1558</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd National Conference on Solid State Ionics,MADRAS, INDIA,FEB 15-17, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>