<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16108</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:49:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Average worth estimation of the selected subset of Poisson populations</dc:title><dc:creator>AL-MOSAWI, RR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANUBHOGUE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VELLAISAMY, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>estimation after selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>average worth</dc:subject><dc:subject>difference inequality</dc:subject><dc:subject>inadmissibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Poisson population</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPONENTIAL POPULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FAMILIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:description>Let Pi(1), ... , Pi(p) be p(p &gt;= 2) independent Poisson populations with unknown parameters theta(1), ... , theta(p), respectively. Let X-i denote an observation from the population Pi(i), 1 &lt;= i &lt;= p. Suppose a subset of random size, which includes the best population corresponding to the largest (smallest) theta(i), is selected using Gupta and Huang [On subset selection procedures for Poisson populations and some applications to the multinomial selection problems, in Applied Statistics, R. P. Gupta, ed., North-Holland, Amsterdam, 1975, pp. 97-109] and (Gupta et al. [On subset selection procedures for Poisson populations, Bull. Malaysian Math. Soc. 2 (1979), pp. 89-110]) selection rule. In this paper, the problem of estimating the average worth of the selected subset is considered under the squared error loss function. The natural estimator is shown to be biased and the UMVUE is obtained using Robbins [The UV method of estimation, in Statistical Decision Theory and Related Topics-IV, S. S. Gupta and J.O. Berger, eds., Springer, NewYork, vol. 1, 1988, pp. 265-270] UV method of estimation. The natural estimator is shown to be inadmissible, by constructing a class of dominating estimators. Using Monte Carlo simulations, the bias and risk of the natural, dominated and UMVU estimators are computed and compared.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:49:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STATISTICS, 46(6)813-831</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/02331888.2011.555552</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16108</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>