<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17391</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:44:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dispersion, Migration, and 'Network-Like' Structure Formation of Multiwall Carbon Nanotubes in Co-Continuous, Binary Immiscible Blends of Polyamide 6 and Acrylonitrile-Butadiene-Styrene Copolymer During Simultaneous Melt-Mixing</dc:title><dc:creator>POYEKAR, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHARE, RA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANWAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIMON, GP</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, JK</dc:creator><dc:subject>POLYMER BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLIZATION BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SELECTIVE LOCALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILLED POLYCARBONATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MORPHOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYPROPYLENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:description>Multiwall carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) were melt-mixed in polyamide 6 (PA6) and acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene (ABS) copolymer blends using a simultaneous mixing protocol in order to investigate the state of dispersion of MWNTs in PA6/ABS blends. The blend composition was varied from 40/60 (wt/wt) to 60/40 (wt/wt) in PA6/ABS blends, which showed co-continuous' morphology in the presence of MWNTs. State of dispersion of MWNTs in these blends was assessed through bulk electrical conductivity measurements, morphological analysis, solution experiments, and UV-vis spectroscopic analysis. MWNTs were subsequently modified with a novel organic modifier, sodium salt of 6-aminohexanoic acid (Na-AHA), to improve the state of dispersion of MWNTs. Blends with unmodified MWNTs exhibited the DC electrical conductivity in the range approximate to 10(-11) to approximate to 10(-5) S/cm, whereas blends with Na-AHA-modified MWNTs exhibited DC electrical conductivity in the range approximate to 10(-7) to approximate to 10(-5) S/cm. The reduction in MWNTs agglomerate' size (approximate to 73.7 m for 40/60 blend with unmodified MWNTs to approximate to 59.9 m in the corresponding blend with Na-AHA-modified MWNTs) was observed through morphological analysis. The rheological studies showed increased complex viscosity and storage moduli in lower frequency region in case of blends with Na-AHA-modified MWNTs confirming a refined network-like' structure of MWNTs. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 55:443-456, 2015. (c) 2014 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:44:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:44:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE, 55(2)443-456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1548-2634</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.23904</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17391</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>