<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14602</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:45:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Type II phosphatidylinositol 4-kinase beta is an integral signaling component of early T cell activation mechanisms</dc:title><dc:creator>SINHA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOJJIREDDY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RATHEESH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHIPLUNKAR, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAHMANYAM, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>Lipid kinases</dc:subject><dc:subject>T cell activation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Calcium signaling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cell adhesion</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECEPTOR-ZETA-CHAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTIN CYTOSKELETON</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTIGEN RECEPTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPLENIC LYMPHOCYTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMBRANE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORGANIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GOLGI</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHORYLATION</dc:subject><dc:description>The early signaling events in T cell activation through CD3 receptor include a rapid change in intra cellular free calcium concentration and reorganization of actin cytoskeleton. Phosphatidylinositol 4-kinases (Ptdlns 4-kinases) are implicated as key components in these early signaling events. The role of type II PtdIns 4-kinase beta in CD3 receptor signaling was investigated with the help of short hairpin RNA sequences. Cross-linking of CD3 receptors on Jurkat T Cells with monoclonal antibodies showed an early increase in type II PtdIns 4-kinase activity and co-localization of type II PtdIns 4-kinase beta with CD3 zeta. Transfection of Jurkat T Cells with shRNAs inhibited CD3 receptor mediated type II PtdIns 4-kinase activation with a concomitant reduction in intra cellular calcium release, suggesting a role for type II PtdIns 4-kinase beta in CD3 receptor signal transduction. Knock-down of type II PtdIns 4-kinase beta with shRNAs also correlated with a decrease in PtdIns 4-kinase activity in cytoskeleton fractions and reduced adhesion to matrigel surfaces. These results indicate that type II Ptdlns 4-kinase beta is a key component in early T cell activation signaling cascades. Published by Elsevier Masson SAS.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER FRANCE-EDITIONS SCIENTIFIQUES MEDICALES ELSEVIER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:45:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:45:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHIMIE, 95(8)1560-1566</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.biochi.2013.04.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14602</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>