<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11594</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hybrid (hydrodynamic plus permanent magnetic) journal bearings</dc:title><dc:creator>HIRANI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMANTA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>axial force of permanent magnetic bearings</dc:subject><dc:subject>sector-shaped magnetic bearings</dc:subject><dc:subject>test setup for horizontal journal bearings</dc:subject><dc:subject>modelling of magnetic bearings</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation of magnetic bearings</dc:subject><dc:description>Survey of patents on bearings indicates the maturity of hydrodynamic and rapid development of magnetic bearings. Active magnetic bearings are costlier compared with permanent magnetic bearings. To understand the performance characteristics of permanent magnetic bearings, an experimental setup has been developed. Experimental studies on radial permanent magnetic bearings demonstrated the drawbacks, such as high axial thrust and low load capacity. This has led the authors to hybridize the permanent magnet with hydrodynamic technology and to explore the possibility of achieving the low starting torque of a permanent magnetic bearing and the medium to high load carrying capacity of a hydrodynamic bearing in a single bearing arrangement. Simulation is carried out in order to reduce axial force-effect and enhance the radial force supported by the permanent magnetic bearing. Results of simulation on permanent magnetic bearing have been compared with that of published research papers. Finally an algorithm has been developed to investigate the coupling of forces generated by permanent magnets and hydrodynamic actions. Results of load sharing have been reported. The experimentally measured displacements of the shaft running at 500, 2000, and 3000 r/min have been plotted. The effect of hydrodynamics on shaft orbit has been illustrated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERING PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T08:02:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T08:02:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART J-JOURNAL OF ENGINEERING TRIBOLOGY, 221(J8), 881-891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-6501</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1243/13506501JET282</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11594</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11594</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>