<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1719</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurement of spectrum with particle image velocimetry</dc:title><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, AMIT</dc:creator><dc:subject>jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>reynolds number</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbulence</dc:subject><dc:subject>vortex flow</dc:subject><dc:description>The purpose of this paper is to show that the measurement of turbulent spectrum using wholefield velocity techniques such as particle image velocimetry (PIV) is possible. Toward this end, data from the axial plane of a self-similar turbulent axisymmetric jet, at a Reynolds number, based on Taylor microscale of 30 has been analyzed. The two-dimensional velocity data are first high-pass filtered, which educes the vortices. An automated method is then used to identify the vortices and measure their properties. By directly measuring the energy of the vortices, it is possible to plot the turbulence spectrum. The spectrum presented here shows the presence of energy containing and inertial regimes. However, the smallest scales have not been resolved in the measurements. The slope of the spectrum in the inertial subrange is about −1.6. The number of vortices in the two regimes have also been measured. The number of vortices in the energy containing regime is substantially smaller than those in the inertial subrange. The technique has been verified by analyzing another dataset. These results show that the direct measurement of vortex properties with reasonable confidence is possible using PIV and an appropriate vortex eduction technique.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Springer</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-11-26T04:42:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:52:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-11-26T04:42:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:52:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Experiments in Fluids 39(5), 836-840</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1432-1114</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00348-005-0018-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1719</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1719</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>