<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9849</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>A combined study of preparation and characterization of carbon molecular sieves (CMS) for carbon dioxide adsorption from coals of different origin</dc:title><dc:creator>KIM, TH</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYALAKSHMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SON, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RYU, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, JD</dc:creator><dc:subject>activated carbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>methane</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon dioxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>diffusivity</dc:subject><dc:description>Removal of carbon dioxide from the atmosphere as well as waste gas streams from industrial and power stations has become the present day's world-wide attraction for many reasons, the most important being the trapping of heat from the sun by CO2 and hence disruption of global warming effect. Activated carbon and CMS samples were prepared from coal samples of different origin. The effects of the various process parameters to prepare CMS from various coals were studied. Pre-oxidation of the coal, activation using CO2 and pore narrowing through coke deposition by benzene cracking were the major process parameters used to prepare the CMS in this work. The CO2 adsorption capacity of the samples was studied using gravimetric as well as volumetric methods. The adsorption capacity Of CO2 on the CMS samples prepared was found to be 1.6 mmol/g of the adsorbent with an uptake ratio at equilibrium adsorption for CO2/CH4, &gt;&gt; 20. The morphology of the pore structure of the samples was studied using the Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM). The N-2 adsorption on the samples at liquid N-2 temperature was found to be very poor and hence surface area measurement was done using CO2 adsorption data. The BET surface area thus calculated was found to be 20% less than the DA surface area calculated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KOREAN SOC INDUSTRIAL ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T11:30:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T11:30:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF INDUSTRIAL AND ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY, 9(5), 481-487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1226-086X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9849</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9849</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>