<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16934</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:53:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>IBLC effect leading to colossal dielectric constant in layered structured Eu2CuO4 ceramic</dc:title><dc:creator>SALAME, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DRAI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAKASH, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Powders: chemical preparation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grain size</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dielectric properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>CACU3TI4O12 CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AC CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERROELECTRICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPENDENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GD2CUO4</dc:subject><dc:subject>CUO</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREQUENCY</dc:subject><dc:description>Dielectric (epsilon(r)') studies of phase pure T'-type Eu2CuO4 ceramics of two markedly different grain sizes (D), prepared by (i) conventional powder mixing and (ii) citrate complexation-Pechini process, have been carried out in the frequency range 0.1 Hz to 1 MHz, and at temperatures -100 degrees C to 150 degrees C. epsilon(r)' is found to be highly grain size dependent. For the sample with coarse bar-like grains (D-2 similar to 17 x 6 mu m(2)) epsilon(r)' is &gt; 10(3), and for the finer grain size sample with bimodal distribution (D-1 similar to 1 mu m, D-2 similar to 3 mu m) epsilon(r)' is similar to 10(5); for both the samples, high epsilon(r)' value is nearly frequency independent over 500 Hz &lt;= f&lt;100 kHz and T &gt;= 30 degrees C. The impedance spectroscopy (IS) study has clearly shown that both, the coarse- and the fine-grained samples consist of semiconducting grains and insulating grain boundaries that primarily lead to an internal barrier layer capacitance (IBLC) effect. And thus, manifest colossal dielectric constant (epsilon(r)' &gt; 10(3)) in Eu2CuO4 ceramics. The smaller grain size (Pechini) sample, with over an order higher number of grains and grain boundary network, showing over an order higher epsilon(r)' (similar to 10(5)) compared to the coarse grained one, further endorses the IBLC effect. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd and Techna Group S.r.l. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:53:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:53:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CERAMICS INTERNATIONAL, 40(3)4491-4498</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0272-8842</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-3956</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2013.08.123</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16934</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>