<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11693</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cobalt-mediated selective C-H bond activation. Direct aromatic hydroxylation in the complexes [Co-III{o-OC6H3(R)N=NC5H4N}(2)]ClO4 center dot H2O (R = H, o-Me/Cl, m-Me/Cl or p-Me/Cl). Synthesis, spectroscopic and redox properties</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARATH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANTRA, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUNSHI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>carbon-carbon bond</dc:subject><dc:subject>ruthenium(ii) phenolate</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkyl hydroperoxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>family</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyclometalation</dc:subject><dc:subject>thiolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>ligands</dc:subject><dc:description>The reactions of low-spin complexes [(CoL3)-L-II][ClO4](2). H2O 1 [L = 2-(arylazo)pyridine, (R)C6H4N=NC5H4N (R = H, o-Me/Cl, m-Me/Cl or p-Me/Cl] with m-chloroperbenzoic acid (m-ClC6H4CO3H) in acetonitrile solvent at room temperature resulted in low-spin [(CoL)-L-III'(2)]ClO4. H2O 2 [L' = o-OC6H3(R)N=NC5H4N]. In complexes 2 the o-carbon-hydrogen bond of the pendant phenyl ring of both parent ligands L has been selectively and spontaneously hydroxylated. During the transformation of 1 to 2 the metal ion is oxidised from the starting Co-II to Co-III. The meridional configuration (cis-trans-cis with respect to the oxygen, azo and pyridine nitrogens respectively) of complexes 2 has been established by H-1 and C-13 NMR spectroscopy. When one methyl or chloro group was present at the meta position of the pendant phenyl ring of L the reaction resulted in two isomeric complexes due to free rotation of the singly bonded meta-substituted phenyl ring with respect to the azo group. In acetonitrile solvent, complexes 2 systematically display one d-d transition ((1)A(1g) --&gt; T-1(1g) near 850 nm, two metal to ligand charge-transfer transitions in the visible region and intraligand transitions in the UV region. In acetonitrile solution all complexes 2 exhibit irreversible Co-III --&gt; Co-IV oxidation near 2 V and reversible Co-III reversible arrow Co-II reduction near 0.0 V versus Ag-AgCl. The ligand-based expected four azo (N=N) reductions are observed sequentially for all the complexes at the negative side of the reference Ag-AgCl. Complexes 2 can be quantitatively and stereoretentively reduced to the low-spin cobalt(II) congeners, [(CoL)-L-II'(2)] 2(-) electrochemically as well as chemically by using hydrazine hydrate. These complexes display eight-line EPR spectra in acetonitrile solution at 77 K. Complex 2a(-) exhibits a ligand to metal charge-transfer transition at 534 nm and intraligand transition at 345 nm. Two possible d-d transitions, E-2 --&gt; T-2(1) and E-2 --&gt; T-2(2) are observed at 700 and 800 nm respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T08:30:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T08:30:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE CHEMICAL SOCIETY-DALTON TRANSACTIONS, (16), 2643-2650</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-9246</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/a802995d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11693</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11693</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>