<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12085</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluating cut slope failure by numerical analysis - a case study</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GULATI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DONTHA, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARDWAJ, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>stability analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>flac3d</dc:subject><dc:subject>slope stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite difference method</dc:subject><dc:subject>principle stress tensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>factor of safety</dc:subject><dc:description>Slope failure is very common phenomenon in hilly regions, especially in young techno active mountainous like Himalayas. It is hazardous because of the accompanying progressive movement of the slope-forming material. In order to minimize the landslide effects, slope failure analysis and stabilization requires in depth understanding of the process that governs the behavior of the slope. The present article mainly deals with the analysis of the stability of road cut slopes of Rudraprayag Area, Uttarakhand, India. The area experiences local as well as regional slides every year. Extensive field study was carried out along the road cut slopes. Laboratory experiments were conducted to determine the various Physio-mechanical properties of rock mass. These properties have been used as input parameters for the numerical simulation of slope using FLAC3D (Fast Lagrangian Analysis of Continua) including geological discontinuities. The computed deformations and the stress distribution along the failure surface are compared with the field observations. The study indicates that the overall slope is unstable except at the location E where slope is critically stable. The effects of instability have been thoroughly considered and remedial measures have been recommended.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T12:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T12:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURAL HAZARDS, 47(2), 263-279</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-030X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-008-9219-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12085</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12085</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>