<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18330</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:07:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Model studies on cellular reinforced fly ash walls</dc:title><dc:creator>LAL, BRR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, JN</dc:creator><dc:subject>SOIL SEGMENTAL WALLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fly ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>Environment</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cellular reinforcement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Backfill</dc:subject><dc:subject>Facing panel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Water bottles</dc:subject><dc:description>In India, thermal power stations produce enormous quantity of fly ash as a byproduct of combustion. It requires huge disposal area and creates environmental problems. In India, where land to population ratio is too small, acquiring huge area of land for the disposal of fly ash is not easy. The utilization of fly ash and its disposal in an environment friendly manner is a foremost concern for developing country like India. In the present study, a series of model experiments were carried out for proper utilization of fly ash as an alternative backfill material in the cellular reinforced fly ash wall. Locally available waste plastic water bottles were used to prepare the cellular reinforcement. The diameter of bottles used for cellular reinforcement is 50 mm and with varying heights of 10 and 20 mm. The effect of change in length and spacing of the cellular reinforcement on the horizontal displacement of full height facing panel and settlement of the backfill were studied. For all the types of reinforcement cases, the variation in length and spacing of the reinforcement showed significant effect on the horizontal displacement of facing panel and on settlement of the backfill. The cellular reinforcement of height 20 mm showed better performance over 10 mm height cellular reinforcement.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MANEY PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:07:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:07:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF GEOTECHNICAL ENGINEERING, 9(3)289-297</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1938-6362</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1939-7879</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1179/1939787914Y.0000000064</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18330</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>