<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17108</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:44:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tool wear mechanisms in machining of three titanium alloys with increasing beta-phase fraction</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>Tool wear</dc:subject><dc:subject>chip-tool contact length</dc:subject><dc:subject>wear mechanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>diffusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>coating delamination</dc:subject><dc:subject>titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>beta-phase fraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>TI-6AL-4V ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CBN TOOLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:description>Mechanical and microstructural properties of titanium alloys change with beta-phase fraction. This in turn influences the dominant tool wear mechanisms in their machining. This work therefore involves turning experimentation on three titanium alloys with varying beta-phase fraction, namely, alpha, alpha + beta and beta-rich alloys using coated carbide tools, to identify dominant wear mechanisms, which hitherto have not been adequately investigated. The dominant wear mechanisms were investigated using scanning electron microscopy and energy-dispersive X-ray analysis of worn tool surfaces and were also correlated with the cutting forces during machining. Abrasion, abrasion with built-up edge and plastic deformation of cutting edge appeared to be the dominant tool wear mechanisms in alpha, alpha+ beta and beta-rich alloy, respectively. At the same time, diffusion of Sn, V and Mo from alpha, alpha+ beta and beta-rich alloys to tool face, respectively, was observed. The chip-tool contact length predicted using the analytical models from the literature matched closely with the experimental values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:44:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:44:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART B-JOURNAL OF ENGINEERING MANUFACTURE, 228(9)1090-1103</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0954-4054</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2041-2975</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0954405414522796</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17108</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>