<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1994</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>2-D simulation of multilayered MEMS structures</dc:title><dc:creator>APTE, PR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>mems structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>multi-layer structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>ansys simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>MEMS device structures, particularly those made using Surface-Micromachining, consist of thin layers of insulator, silicon, silicon dioxide, silicon nitride, metal or poly-silicon held at few points onto a thick silicon substrate. These heterogeneous layers resemble closely to laminas of composites used in building structures. For these heterogeneous material systems, involving Metal- Insulator-Semiconductor layers, there is usually an inherent two dimensional thermal contraction of the various layers upon cooling from a growth temperature of 1000 to 1200 C down to room temperature. The thermal stress, so developed, could result in static deformation as well change the dynamic characteristics of the micro-parts. Thin heteroepitaxial layers, with lattice mismatch with the single crystal substrate, can also result in a built in stress. External effects like electrostatic potentials and magnetic fields applied to a layered structure can also result in contractions or extensions of specific layers that respond to applied fields. A generic formulation of governing equations of equilibrium and compatibility has been developed for laminated structures with various in-built stress effects like difference in temperature of formation and use; difference in lattice constants of heteroepitaxial layers; effects that involve dimensional changes like piezoelectric effect and magnetostriction. This paper aims at demonstrating, through simulations of a test structure of a doubly suspended resonator, how these multi-layer structures could exploit the static deformations to result in a robust (temperature- insensitive) dynamic response. The static deformation for temperature changes in a bi-layer of aluminum and silicon dioxide is simulated on ANSYS. The results of ANSYS match very well with a fabricated test device.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T00:02:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T00:02:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS, STRUCTURES, AND SYSTEM, PTS 1 AND 2,5062,761-772</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-4868-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.514905</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15274</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1994</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Smart Materials, Structures and Systems,BANGALORE, INDIA,DEC 12-14, 2002</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>