<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6971</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulated body fluid (SBF) adsorption onto a-SiC : H thin films deposited by hot wire chemical vapor deposition (HWCVD)</dc:title><dc:creator>SWAIN, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATTANAYAK, DK</dc:creator><dc:subject>silicon-carbide</dc:subject><dc:subject>coating materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>platelet</dc:subject><dc:subject>adhesion</dc:subject><dc:subject>hwcvd</dc:subject><dc:subject>sbf</dc:subject><dc:subject>xps</dc:subject><dc:subject>mr</dc:subject><dc:subject>contact angle</dc:subject><dc:description>Hydrogen amorphous silicon carbon (a-SiC:H) film deposited by the Hot Wire Chemical Vapor Deposition (HWCVD) technique on silicon substrates were soaked in simulated body fluid (SBF). Characterization of the film with different soaking durations in SBF was carried out by Fourier Transform Infrared (MR) spectroscopy, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and contact angle measurements. It was found that the relative amounts of carbon in the a-SiC:H film surface decreases with increase in soaking period. XPS results showed the adsorption of Ca and Mg on the a-SiC:H surface. This indicates the formation of negatively charged surface possibly due to formation of silanol groups or dissolution of carbon to SBF confirming the bioactivity of the material. Contact angle decreased from 74 degrees to 65 degrees during 30 days of soaking in the body fluid. Present study is an attempt to observe the interaction of a-SiC:H film prepared by HWCVD technique with the body environment for its future suitability as artificial heart valve and stent coating materials. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T17:04:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T17:04:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS LETTERS, 62(20), 3484-3486</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-577X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2008.03.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6971</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6971</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>