<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11488</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermal characteristics of a class F fly ash</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, MVBBG</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOLAY, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:description>It is necessary to evaluate thermal properties of geotechnical materials, viz. soils and rocks, for power cables and oil pipe lines and disposal of nuclear wastes. A situation may arise where the heat dissipation through the soils and rocks may not be satisfactory, leading to adoption of a backfill. Fly ash can be used in conjuction with aggregates to design a proper backfill material. The thermal characteristics of this material, in terms of its resistivity, play an important role in the design of a thermally stable backfill, i.e., Fluidized Thermal Backfill (FTB). As such it is desired to establish thermal response of the fly ash based on its physical and moisture- holding characteristics. In this paper an effort has been made to evaluate the thermal resistivity of a Class F fly ash using a laboratory thermal needle/probe. The effect of density of compaction and the moisture content on the thermal response of the fly ash has been also studied. (C) 1998 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T01:05:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T01:05:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CEMENT AND CONCRETE RESEARCH, 28(6), 841-846</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-8846</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11488</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>