<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3038</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Measurements of photon-atom elastic scattering cross-sections in the photon energy range 1 kev to 4 mev</dc:title><dc:creator>BRADLEY, DA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GONCALVES, OD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANE, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>capture gamma-rays</dc:subject><dc:subject>angle rayleigh-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>synchrotron x-rays</dc:subject><dc:subject>59.5 kev photons</dc:subject><dc:subject>anomalous-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>coherent-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>form-factors</dc:subject><dc:subject>59.54-kev photons</dc:subject><dc:subject>inelastic-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>momentum-transfer</dc:subject><dc:description>We review the current status of measurements of photon-atom elastic scattering cross-sections for the restricted photon energy range 1 keV up to 4 MeV. Among the key experimental factors which influence the accuracy and precision of a particular type of measurement are the choice of source, detector and scattering geometry. We have examined the interests which motivate the making of measurements, looking at issues at the atomic, molecular and solid state level, Discrepancies have been noted to exist between experiments and between experiments and theory and explanations for these have been sought. It is apparent that over the last fifteen pears or so there has been a substantial increase in the number of reported studies of elastic scattering cross-sections for photons of energies &lt; 100 keV impinging on high purity targets. These measurements have largely focused on scattering amplitudes in the vicinity of absorption edges. For the same range of photon energies, molecular correlations in amorphous media represent another active area of investigation. At higher photon energies, measurements have more generally involved small angles of scattering, the main interest being Rayleigh scattering from high purity targets. Account of Delbruck scattering amplitudes has been found necessary for a satisfactory explanation of experimental values of elastic scattering cross-sections. In the case of lead, at photon energies of about 1.3 MeV and large angles of scattering, the real Delbruck amplitude is about 10% of the Rayleigh amplitude, (C) 1999 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T22:50:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T22:50:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>RADIATION PHYSICS AND CHEMISTRY,56,125-150</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0969-806X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0969-806X(99)00276-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13870</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3038</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>