<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11691</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cluster analysis of Delhi's ambient air quality data</dc:title><dc:creator>SAKSENA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>precipitation</dc:subject><dc:description>The purpose of this study was to study the spatial patterns of ambient air quality in Delhi in the absence of extensive datasets needed for space-time modeling. A spatial classification was attempted on the basis of ambient air quality data of nine years ( 1998 is latest year for which published data were available) for three criteria pollutants - nitrogen dioxide, sulfur dioxide, and suspended particulate matter. Monitoring stations take 24-hour samples twice a week. Published monthly average concentration data were used in this study. A hierarchical agglomerative algorithm using the average linkage between groups method and the Euclidean distance metric was used. Cluster analysis indicated that till 1998, by and large, two distinct classes existed. The results of cluster analysis prompted an investigation of systematic biases in the monitored data. No statistically significant differences in the mean concentration of all pollutants were observed between stations belonging to different land-use types ( residential and industrial). This fact would be useful, if and when the authorities consider modifying the network or expanding it in Delhi. The results also support the recommendation that Delhi have a uniform standard across all areas. This study has provided a methodology for Indian researchers and practitioners to do an exploratory study of spatial patterns of air pollution and data quality issues in Indian cities using the National Ambient Air Quality Monitoring System data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T08:21:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T08:21:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING, 5(3), 491-499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1464-0325</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b210172f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11691</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11691</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>