<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9681</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic response of sliding structures to bidirectional earthquake excitation</dc:title><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>support motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>sliding structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>pure-friction</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>bidirectional interaction</dc:subject><dc:description>Seismic response of a one-storey structure with sliding support to bidirectional (i.e. two horizontal components) earthquake ground motion is investigated. Frictional forces, which are mobilized at the sliding support, are assumed to have ideal Coulomb-friction characteristics. Coupling effects due to circular interaction between the frictional forces are incorporated in the governing equations of motion. Effects of bidirectional interaction of frictional forces on the response are investigated by comparing the response to two-component excitation with the corresponding response produced by the application of single-component excitations in each direction independently. It is observed that the response of the sliding structure is influenced significantly by the bidirectional interaction of frictional forces. Further, it is shown that the design sliding displacement may be underestimated if the bidirectional interaction of frictional forces is neglected and the sliding structures are designed merely on the basis of single-component excitation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T00:33:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T00:33:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING &amp; STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS, 25(11), 1301-1306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-8847</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9845(199611)25:11&lt;1301::AID-EQE618&gt;3.3.CO;2-V</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9681</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9681</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>