<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13883</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T03:38:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Energy integration across multiple water allocation networks with negligible contaminant effects</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, GC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>HEAT-EXCHANGER NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MINIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>REUSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy targeting</dc:subject><dc:subject>process optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>water networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>pinch analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat exchanger network</dc:subject><dc:subject>total site integration</dc:subject><dc:description>Total site integration is considered for energy conservation opportunities across different individual processes. Heat can be integrated through heat exchangers or through non-isothermal mixing of streams. On the other hand, heat can also be integrated across the processes through direct or indirect integration. A methodology is proposed for heat integration across multiple water allocation networks (WANs), where effect of contaminant can be neglected, incorporating the combination of isothermal or non-isothermal mixing as well as direct or indirect integration. The proposed methodology accounts assisted heat transfer between the pinches for improved site-level heat integration. Energy recovery algorithm is applied for energy integration and determination of process grand composite curve (GCC) for each individual process. The method of site-level GCC is extended and modified for targeting the utility requirement in overall plant of WANs. (C) 2011 Curtin University of Technology and John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T03:38:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T03:38:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ASIA-PACIFIC JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL ENGINEERING,6(3)527-536</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1932-2143</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/apj.552</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13883</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>