<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4226</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Literal approximations to aircraft dynamic modes</dc:title><dc:creator>ANANTHKRISHNAN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>UNNIKRISHNAN, S</dc:creator><dc:description>Derivation of literal approximations to the aircraft dynamic modes remains one of the central problems in the theory of aircraft flight dynamics, and one that has never been satisfactorily resolved. Although approximations to the fast modes (short period, roll) are generally good, the slow modes (phugoid, dutch roll, spiral) seem to have several competing approximations, none of which are uniformly satisfactory. This paper examines the fundamental assumptions behind the traditional approach to the derivation of literal approximations. A major flaw in all previous derivations resulting in incorrect slow-mode approximations is uncovered. In following a formal procedure, improved literal approximations are derived for the slow modes. In this process, a new condition for onset of directional departure is obtained, which is related to the dutch-roll frequency. Predictions from the literal approximations derived in this paper are compared with actual numerical values for an example aircraft to illustrate conditions under which the approximations work well, and to point out the fundamental limitations of the literal approximations derived by the traditional approach.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST AERONAUT ASTRONAUT</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T09:45:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T09:45:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GUIDANCE CONTROL AND DYNAMICS, 24(6), 1196-1203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0731-5090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2514/2.4835</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4226</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>