<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9276</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Re-look to conventional techniques for trapping efficiency estimation of a reservoir</dc:title><dc:creator>JOTHIPRAKASH, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARG, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>western himalayan region</dc:subject><dc:subject>sedimentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>reservoir sedimentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>trap efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>brown's method</dc:subject><dc:subject>brune's method</dc:subject><dc:description>All reservoirs are. subjected to sediment inflow and deposition up to a certain extent leading to reduction in their capacity. Thus, the important practical problem related to the life of reservoir is the estimation of sedimentation quantity in the reservoirs. Large number of methods and models are available for estimation of reservoir sedimentation process. However, each model differs greatly in terms of their complexity, inputs and other requirements. In the simplest way, the fraction of sediment deposit in the reservoir can be determined through the knowledge of its trap efficiency. Trap efficiency (T,) is the proportion of the incoming sediment that is deposited or trapped in a reservoir. Most of the T, estimation methods define a relationship of the T, of the reservoir to their capacity and annual inflow, generally through curves. In this study, the empirical relationships given by Brune and Brown were used and compared for estimating the trap efficiency of Gobindsagar Reservoir (Bhakra Dam) on Satluj River in Bilaspur district of Himachal Pradesh, in the Himalayan region of India. A new set of regression equations has been developed for Brune's method and compared with Brown and other available Brune's equations. It has been found that Brune's equations developed in the present study estimated better than the other Brune's equations reported in literature. Later, in the present study it was found that Brown's approach was over estimating the T, Hence it was again modified for Gobindsagar reservoir. It was also identified that sediments coming to this particular reservoir were mainly of coarse nature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IRTCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T06:55:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T06:55:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF SEDIMENT RESEARCH, 23(1), 76-84</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1001-6279</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1001-6279(08)60007-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9276</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9276</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>