<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18410</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T11:00:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Parametric Investigation of Batch Adsorption of Proteins onto Polymeric Particles</dc:title><dc:creator>TAN, MXL</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGYEI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DANQUAH, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>BOVINE SERUM-ALBUMIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLID-SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PH</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOCOMPATIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUILIBRIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCHANGERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>batch adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquid-solid mass transfer</dc:subject><dc:description>Background: Effective bimolecular adsorption of proteins onto solid matrices is characterized by in-depth understanding of the biophysical features essential to optimize the adsorption performance. Results: The adsorption of bovine serum albumin (BSA) onto anion-exchange Q-sepharose solid particulate support was investigated in batch adsorption experiments. Adsorption kinetics and isotherms were developed as a function of key industrially relevant parameters such as polymer loading, stirring speed, buffer pH, protein concentration and the state of protein dispersion (solid/aqueous) in order to optimize binding performance and adsorption capacity. Experimental results showed that the first order rate constant is higher at higher stirring speed, higher polymer loading, and under alkaline conditions, with a corresponding increase in equilibrium adsorption capacity. Increasing the stirring speed and using aqueous dispersion protein system increased the adsorption rate, but the maximum protein adsorption was unaffected. Regardless of the stirring speed, the adsorption capacity of the polymer was 2.8 mg/ml. However, doubling the polymer loading increased the adsorption capacity to 9.4 mg/ml. Conclusions: The result demonstrates that there exists a minimum amount of polymer loading required to achieve maximum protein adsorption capacity under specific process conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BENTHAM SCIENCE PUBL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:00:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:00:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT PHARMACEUTICAL BIOTECHNOLOGY, 16(9)816-822</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1389-2010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18410</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>