<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17761</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:30:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Isolation and characterization of nanosheets containing few layers of the Aurivillius family of oxides and metal-organic compounds</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEDHARA, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, BE</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOIRANGTHEM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CNR</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTRON-MICROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXFOLIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRAMEWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TITANATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aurivillius oxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Layered bismuth oxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>Exfoliation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Few-layer metal-organic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Layered phosphonates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Layered copper complexes</dc:subject><dc:description>Nanosheets containing few-layers of ferroelectric Aurivillius family of oxides, Bi(2)A(n-1)B(n)O(3n+3) (where A = Bi3+, Ba2+ etc. and B=Ti4+, Fe3+ etc.) with n=3, 4, 5, 6 and 7 have been prepared by reaction with n-butyllithium, followed by exfoliation in water. The few-layer samples have been characterized by Tyndall cones, atomic force microscopy, optical spectroscopy and other techniques. The few-layer species have a thickness corresponding to a fraction of the c-parameter along which axis the perovskite layers are stacked. Magnetization measurements have been carried out on the few-layer samples containing iron. Few-layer species of a few layered metal-organic compounds have been obtained by ultrasonication and characterized by Tyndall cones, atomic force microscopy, optical spectroscopy and magnetic measurements. Significant changes in the optical spectra and magnetic properties are found in the few-layer species compared to the bulk samples. Few-layer species of the Aurivillius family of oxides may find uses as thin layer dielectrics in photovoltaics and other applications. (C) 2014 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC ELSEVIER SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:30:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:30:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SOLID STATE CHEMISTRY, 224(SI)21-27</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-4596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1095-726X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2014.02.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17761</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>