<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17392</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:45:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>The Simultaneous Addition of Styrene Maleic Anhydride Copolymer and Multiwall Carbon Nanotubes During Melt-Mixing on the Morphology of Binary Blends of Polyamide6 and Acrylonitrile Butadiene Styrene Copolymer</dc:title><dc:creator>JOGI, BF</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>POYEKAR, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTSCHKE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIMON, GP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>POLYMER BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLIZATION BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIXED BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOCALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPATIBILIZER</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYCARBONATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NYLON-6</dc:subject><dc:subject>RUBBER</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of simultaneous addition of multiwall carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) and a reactive compatibilizer (styrene maleic anhydride copolymer, SMA) during melt-mixing on the phase morphology of 80/20 (wt/wt) PA6/ABS blend has been investigated. Morphological analysis through scanning and transmission electron microscopic analysis revealed finer morphology of the blends in presence of SMA + MWNTs. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopic analysis indicated the formation of imide bonds during melt-mixing. Non-isothermal crystallization studies exhibited the presence of a majority faction of MWNTs in the PA6 phase of 80/20 (wt/wt) PA6/ABS blend in presence of SMA + MWNTs. Rheological analysis, dynamic mechanical thermal analysis, and thermogravimetric analysis have demonstrated the compatibilization action of simultaneous addition of a reactive compatibilizer (SMA copolymer) and MWNTs in PA6/ABS blends. An attempt has been made to investigate the role of simultaneous addition of SMA copolymer and MWNTs on the morphology of 80/20 (wt/wt) PA6/ABS blend through various characterization techniques. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 55:457-465, 2015. (c) 2014 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:45:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:45:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE, 55(2)457-465</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1548-2634</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.23905</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17392</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>