<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1805</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Low temperature silicon nitride deposited by Cat-CVD for deep submicron metal-oxide-semiconductor devices</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMBHAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>WAGHMARE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, RO</dc:creator><dc:subject>chemical-vapor-deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>microcrystalline silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon nitride</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical vapor deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>dielectric properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-oxide-semiconductor structure</dc:subject><dc:description>Silicon nitride as a gate dielectric can improve the performance of ULSI CMOS devices by decreasing the gate leakage currents. In this paper we report a a-SiN:H gate dielectric fabricated using Cat-CVD at a relatively low substrate temperature of similar to 250 degreesC, using silane and ammonia as the source gases. The films were deposited at various gas pressures, (NH3/SiH4) flow rate ratios and at different filament temperatures (T-F). The deposition parameters, i.e. total gas pressure and gas composition (silane+ammonia) were optimized to deposit insulating and transparent films with high break-down strength. The structural properties of these films were studied by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy and ultraviolet-visible (UV-vis) spectroscopy. Films with bandgap as high as 5.5 eV were obtained. The optimized conditions were used to deposit ultrathin films of the order of 8 rim thickness for deep-submicron CMOS technology. Electrical properties such as C-V and I-V measurements were studied on metal-nitride-semiconductor (MNS) capacitor structures. These characterization results on MNS capacitors show break-down fields of the order of 10 MV cm(-1) and good interface properties. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science BN. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T05:57:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T05:57:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS,395,270-274</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0040-6090(01)01281-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15053</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1805</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st International Conference on Cat-CVD (Hot Wire CVD) Process,KANAZAWA, JAPAN,NOV 14-17, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>