<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5252</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>An expert system for fault diagnosis and restoration of Iran's 400 KV network</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>JADID, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>power-system</dc:subject><dc:subject>power system</dc:subject><dc:subject>fault diagnosis</dc:subject><dc:subject>restoration</dc:subject><dc:subject>expert system</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper reports development of an expert system for fault diagnosis and restoration with a modified model which can cater to realistic power system and accommodate all possible complexities. To account for the existing substation structures and switching arrangements we redefine various types of nodes and links. Several protective schemes with standard relay jargon and PLC signals, recloser operation status, and isolators have been considered. Object oriented data structures have been used and the inbuilt Database Management System facilitates the smooth and fast data retrieval. The expert system has been evolved through extensive interaction with the field experts. As the po,ocr system restoration includes current topology determination, analytical tools like load flow, voltage and power flow control, and finally has to generate switching sequence, it involves numeric as well as symbolic processing linkage which is achieved through a blackboard mechanism. The developed expert system is tested on Iran's 400 KV network in off-line mode. Move than 150 actual events were considered. Few of them have been reported here illustrating the working of this expert system, along with comments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>C R L PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T09:43:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T09:43:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING INTELLIGENT SYSTEMS FOR ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING AND COMMUNICATIONS, 5(2), 107-114</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0969-1170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5252</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5252</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>