<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11728</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Glucose response of dissolved-core alginate microspheres: towards a continuous glucose biosensor</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAUDHARY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MCSHANE, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>energy-transfer assay</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vivo</dc:subject><dc:subject>affinity sensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>blood-glucose</dc:subject><dc:subject>concanavalin-a</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyelectrolyte microcapsules</dc:subject><dc:subject>macromolecule encapsulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>dexamethasone release</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanofilm coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding</dc:subject><dc:description>Microparticle optical sensors hold potential as implantable smart materials for in vivo analysis. In this work, the reversible response of dissolved-core alginate microspheres containing a homogeneous fluorescence resonance energy transfer (FRET)-based competitive binding assay for glucose was evaluated. The layer-by-layer self assembly technique was used to deposit multilayered nanofilm coatings on the alginate microspheres containing the assay, thereby stabilizing the sensor system when the alginate was de-crosslinked. The response to glucose was then determined in DI water and simulated interstitial fluid (SIF) using a flow cell to establish controlled, dynamic flow conditions for demonstrating reversibility. The glucose sensitivity under dynamic conditions was estimated to be 0.52%/mM glucose in DI water and 0.6%/mM glucose in simulated interstitial fluid; in both cases, the analytical response range was 0-30mM glucose, covering both physiological (normoglycemia) and pathophysiological range (hyperglycemia and hypoglycemia). The sensor demonstrated a repeatable and reproducible response when tested over a period of one month, under dynamic flow conditions. Finally, in vitro cytotoxicity assays performed with L929 mouse fibroblast cell lines suggested that the dissolved-core alginate microsphere sensor system with nanofilm coating has sufficient biocompatibility for use as implantable glucose biosensors.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T11:27:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T11:27:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANALYST, 135(10), 2620-2628</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-2654</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c0an00109k</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11728</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11728</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>