<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4667</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of various pedo-transfer functions for developing soil-water characteristic curve of a silty soil</dc:title><dc:creator>THAKUR, VKS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SREEDEEP, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>hydraulic conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>unsaturated soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>bulk-density</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>silty soil</dc:subject><dc:subject>field tensiometer</dc:subject><dc:subject>dew point potentiameter</dc:subject><dc:subject>soilvision</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil-water characteristic curve</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper describes development of the soil-water characteristic curve (SWCC) of a silty soil by measuring its matric suction Psi(m), corresponding to different gravimetric water contents w. To achieve this, a field tensiometer and a dew point potentiameter (WP4) were employed. For this soil, the SWCC was determined indirectly using the estimation algorithms known as pedo-transfer functions (PTFs), which are based on volume-mass properties and the grain-size distribution characteristics, and are available in a commercial database SoilVision. In addition to this, experimental results were used for developing the SWCC of the soil, using various fitting functions cited in the literature and available in the database. An attempt has been made in this technical note to demonstrate the usefulness of these three methods for obtaining the SWCC of the silty soil. The study reveals that the PTFs developed previously to estimate SWCCs match very well with the experimental results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC TESTING MATERIALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T08:07:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T08:07:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOTECHNICAL TESTING JOURNAL, 30(1), 25-30</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0149-6115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4667</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4667</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>