<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12436</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>A layerwise shear deformation theory for two-layered cross-ply laminated plates</dc:title><dc:creator>SHIMPI, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHUGAL, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>composite plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>3-dimensional elasticity</dc:subject><dc:subject>transverse shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>beams</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>configurations</dc:subject><dc:subject>propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>stresses</dc:subject><dc:subject>element</dc:subject><dc:description>A layerwise trigonometric shear deformation theory for flexural analysis of two-layered laminated plates, taking into account transverse shear deformation effects, is presented. The present theory has only three variables, that is, two variables less than those in the first-order shear deformation theory. The displacement field uses a sinusoidal function in terms of thickness coordinate to represent the shear deformation. The noteworthy feature of the theory is that the transverse shear stresses can be obtained directly from the use of constitutive relations with reasonable accuracy, satisfying the shear stress free surface conditions at the top and bottom surfaces of the plate and continuity conditions at interface between the layers. The transverse shear stresses can also be obtained, with better accuracy, by integrating equilibrium equations. The theory obviates the need for a shear correction factor. The governing equations and boundary conditions are Obtained using the principle of virtual work. A two-layered cross-ply laminated plate is considered for the numerical study to demonstrate the efficacy of the theory. The results obtained using the present theory are discussed critically with those of other theories and are found to agree well with the exact elasticity results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T19:26:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T19:26:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MECHANICS OF COMPOSITE MATERIALS AND STRUCTURES, 7(4), 331-353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1075-9417</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10759410050201690</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12436</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12436</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>