<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1428</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydrogen in chemical vapour deposited carbon nanotubes : an active site for functionalization</dc:title><dc:creator>TITUS, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>CABRAL, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADALENO, JC</dc:creator><dc:creator>COELHO, MC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BABU, PR</dc:creator><dc:creator>BLAU, WJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GRACIO, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>thin hydrocarbon films</dc:subject><dc:subject>single</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical vapor deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemically modified carbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>infrared spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:description>The presence of hydrogen in as-grown carbon nanotubes (CNTs) synthesized by microwave plasma (MP) chemical vapour deposition (CVD) technique is demonstrated. Our results showed that the MPCVD, as-grown CNTs were hydrogenated consisting of C-H bonds; whereas, the tubes synthesized by arc discharge consisted of non-hydrogenated multi-walled CNTs. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) and micro-Raman spectroscopy techniques were used to detect C-H bonding in the as-grown CNTs. The effective functionalization of as-grown hydrogenated CNTs grown using a microwave CVD process is first time demonstrated by laser assisted CVD process. It was found that the laser-assisted CVD process resulted in the termination of hydrogen and the oxidation of as-grown CNT structure leading to the carboxylic group attachment. The FTIR results show the presence of -OH and C=O bonds in the functionalized samples. However, the non-hydrogenated CNTs could not be effectively functionalized by the same process, probably due to the fact that it did not contain active sites pre-requisite for functionalization, as did the CVD grown samples. The functionalization of CVD grown tubes is believed to take place at the 'active' hydrogen-terminated sites on the CNT surfaces.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T06:13:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T06:13:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY,8(8)4017-4022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1533-4880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jnn.2008.AN34</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1428</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Advanced Nano-Materials,Bombay, INDIA,JAN 08-10, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>