<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1577</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Design of wind power generation systems for industrial application incorporating resource uncertainty</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEDARE, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>heat-exchanger design</dc:subject><dc:subject>space</dc:subject><dc:description>The technical challenge in designing an onsite power generation system incorporating renewable energy technology for overall sustainability is the inherent unpredictability of the renewable resource. Integration of a battery bank as energy storage can alleviate the mismatch between the load and power generation. By accounting for the system operating and geometrical constraints, the entire set of feasible design options can be identified on a plot of battery capacity vs. rated power of wind generator. Such a diagram is known as the design space. The present study illustrates the generation of design space for different reliability levels for wind-battery systems using chance constrained programming. The proposed approach can generate and evaluate a range of possible design alternatives which can speed up the decision making process and also provide a clear understanding of the system design limitations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AIDIC SERVIZI SRL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T01:55:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T01:55:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PRES'09: 12TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PROCESS INTEGRATION, MODELLING AND OPTIMISATION FOR ENERGY SAVING AND POLLUTION REDUCTION, PTS 1 AND 2,18,647-652</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-88-95608-04-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1974-9791</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3303/CET0918105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14788</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1577</dc:identifier><dc:source>12th Conference on Process Integration, Modelling and Optimisation for Energy Saving and Pollution Reduction,Rome, ITALY,FEB 10-MAY 13, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>