<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2140</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Developing flow region of axisymmetric turbulent jets</dc:title><dc:creator>PANI, BS</dc:creator><dc:subject>potential core</dc:subject><dc:subject>compound jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>annular shear layer</dc:subject><dc:subject>point source</dc:subject><dc:subject>co-flowing jets</dc:subject><dc:description>In the developing zone of a circular jet diffusing in a co-flowing stream, the flow velocity changes from the jet velocity U(0) to the uniform ambient velocity U(a). The thickness of the potential core gradually diminishes in the streamwise direction and beyond the potential core length, x(0), no uniform flow region exists across the jet. The flow parameters at the location x0 act as the initial condition for the analysis of jets in the fully developed region. The excess velocity within the shear layer exhibits similarity and the integral technique is often adopted for prediction of the length of the potential core. The length of the potential core found from various theoretical models differs significantly. The present investigation is an adaptation of Reichardt's hypothesis and the point source technique. Using a single coefficient of expansion the velocity distribution in the annular shear layer is predicted. The transition from the developing to the developed flow zone takes place in a seamless fashion. The length of the potential core is estimated based on the predictions of the maximum velocity on the axis of the jet.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TSINGHUA UNIVERSITY PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T09:12:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T09:12:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN WATER RESOURCES AND HYDRAULIC ENGINEERING, VOLS 1-6,630-634</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-7-302-18662-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-89465-0_109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15373</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2140</dc:identifier><dc:source>16th Asia and Pacific Division Congress of the International Association of Hydraulic Engineering and Research/3rd IAHR International Symposium on Hydraulic Structures,Nanjing, PEOPLES R CHINA,OCT 20-23, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>