<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6380</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Anaerobic biogranulation in a hybrid reactor treating phenolic waste</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>granular methanogenic sludge</dc:subject><dc:subject>uasb reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic-compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>process design</dc:subject><dc:subject>p-cresol</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>wastewaters</dc:subject><dc:subject>operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzoate</dc:subject><dc:subject>anaerobic</dc:subject><dc:subject>granulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>coal effluent</dc:subject><dc:description>Granulation was examined in four similar anaerobic hybrid reactors 15.5 L volume (with an effective volume of 13.5 L) during the treatment of synthetic coal wastewater at the mesophilic temperature of 27 +/- 5 degrees C. The hybrid reactors are a combination of UASB unit at the lower part and an anaerobic filter at the upper end. Synthetic wastewater with an average chemical oxygen demand (COD) of 2240 mg/L, phenolics concentration of 752 mg/L and a mixture of volatile fatty acids was fed to three hybrid reactors. The fourth reactor, control system, was fed with a wastewater containing sodium acetate and mineral nutrients. Coal waste water contained phenol (490 mg/L); m-, o-, p-cresols (123.0, 58.6,42 mg/L); 2,4-, 2,5-, 3,4- and 3,5-dimethyl phenols (6.3, 6.3, 4.4 and 21.3 mg/L) as major phenolic compounds. A mixture of anaerobic digester sludge and partially granulated sludge (3:1) were used as seed materials for the start up of the reactors. Granules were observed after 45 days of operation of the systems. The granules ranged from 0.4 to 1.2 mm, in diameter with good settling characteristics with an SVI of 12 mL/g SS. After granulation, the hybrid reactor performed steadily with phenolics and COD removal efficiencies of 93% and 88%, respectively at volumetric loading rate of 2.24 g COD/L d and hydraulic retention time of 24 h. The removal efficiencies for phenol and m/p-cresols reached 92% and 93% (corresponding to 450.8 and 153 mg/L), while o-cresol was degraded to 88% (corresponding to 51.04 mg/L). Dimethyl phenols could be removed completely at all the organic loadings and did not contribute much to the residual organics. Biodegradation of o-cresol was obtained in the hybrid-UASB reactors. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T09:13:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T09:13:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HAZARDOUS MATERIALS, 137(3), 1488-1495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2006.04.034</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6380</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6380</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>