<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15814</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:43:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Role of reducing environment in the chemical growth of zinc selenide thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, LP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PINGALE, PC</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAMBLE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>LENDAVE, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANE, ST</dc:creator><dc:creator>PIRGONDE, BR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ZnSe thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polycrystalline wurtzite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrazine hydrate</dc:subject><dc:subject>LO and TO modes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optical gap</dc:subject><dc:subject>BATH DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:description>Chemical deposition of ZnSe (Zn/Se ratio, 0.57 &lt;= x &lt;= 0.99) thin films highlighting influence of reducing environment on the structural properties and surface morphology is presented. Hydrazine hydrate was used as a reducing agent to initiate growth process and to reduce selenosulfate to Se2- ions that permits formation of non-stoichiometric ZnSe film layers. ZnSe films thus obtained are adherent, homogeneous and diffusely reflecting with light brown coloured tinge. These films were characterized through XRD, SEM, EDS and AFM techniques to reveal the structural and morphological informations. As-grown films are polycrystalline wurtzite with (1 0 1) preferred orientation. d-values change considerably whereas I/I-max is more or less constant. The average lattice parameters have similar trend of variation with Zn/Se ratio. Non-uniform distribution of spherical ZnSe crystallites was observed through SEM. The micrographs further indicated marginal agglomeration of crystallites forming globule like overgrowth. AFM studies spotlighted influence of reducing environment on the surface roughness of the films. The bulk ZnSe exhibits LO and TO phonon bands at 252 cm(-1) and 205 cm(-1) respectively as indicated by Raman studies. The optical band gap is decreased a little and is correlated to variation in the excess metallic Se-phase. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:43:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:43:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS LETTERS, 92308-312</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2012.10.098</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15814</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>