<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2595</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Centrifuge model tests on geotextile reinforced slope subjected to differential settlements</dc:title><dc:creator>VISWANADHAM, BVS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KONIG, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIANTAFYLLIDIS, T</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper deals about the study of deformation behaviour of geotextile reinforced slopes subjected to differential settlements. A special device for inducing differential settlements during centrifuge test for a reinforced soil structure has been designed and calibrated. In order to simulate the failure to reinforcement layers ratio of length of the reinforcement to height is maintained as 0.85 and the slope is constructed with a scaled-down geotextile material by using a wrap-around technique to represent a flexible facing. Sand with 85% relative density was used as structural fill material. Two centrifuge model tests were carried-out at 40 g on geotextile reinforced sand slopes by varying the type of reinforcement and by maintaining slope inclination (2V:1H), vertical spacing of reinforcement layers as constant. Results of the centrifuge test indicate that even after inducing a central settlement equivalent to 1.0 m in prototype dimensions, the geotextile reinforced slope retains its integrity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:37:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T11:37:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Physical Modelling in Geotechnics - 6th ICPMG '06, Vol 1,597-602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-415-41586-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15996</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2595</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th International Conference on Physical Modelling in Geotechnics (ICPMG 2006),Hong Kong, PEOPLES R CHINA,AUG 04-06, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>