<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3671</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kinetic stabilization of microtubule dynamics by estramustine is associated with tubulin acetylation, spindle abnormalities, and mitotic arrest</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>refractory prostate-cancer</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase-ii</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vivo</dc:subject><dc:subject>antimicrotubule activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>individual microtubules</dc:subject><dc:subject>suppresses dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>cell proliferation</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinetochore pairs</dc:subject><dc:subject>assembly invitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>alpha-tubulin</dc:subject><dc:description>Estramustine (EM) alone or in combination with other anticancer agents is clinically used for the treatment of hormone refractory prostate cancer. Furthermore, EM has been shown to potently inhibit the proliferation of different types of cancer cells in culture apparently by targeting microtubules; however, the antiproliferative mechanism of action of EM is not clear. In this work, we have shown that EM strongly suppressed the dynamic instability of individual microtubules in MCF-7 cells by reducing the rates of growing and shortening excursions and increasing the time microtubule spent in the pause state. At its half maximal proliferation inhibitory concentration (IC50), EM exerted strong suppressive effects on the dynamics of microtubules in MCF-7 cells without detectably affecting either the organization or the polymerized mass of microtubules. At relatively high concentrations (5 X IC50), EM significantly depolymerized microtubules in the cells. Furthermore, the microtubules were found highly acetylated, supporting the conclusion that they were stabilized by the drug. EM treatment induced spindle abnormalities in MCF-7 cells, and a major population of the arrested mitotic cells was multipolar. EM also perturbed the microtubule-kinetochore interaction, thereby activating the spindle assembly checkpoint and leading to apoptotic cell death.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER ASSOC CANCER RESEARCH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T12:04:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T12:04:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CANCER RESEARCH, 68(15), 6181-6189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-5472</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-0584</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3671</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3671</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>