<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10930</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hybrid reactor for priority pollutant nitrobenzene removal</dc:title><dc:creator>MAJUMDER, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>nitroaromatic compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>pathway</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrobenzene</dc:subject><dc:subject>trickling filter</dc:subject><dc:subject>activated sludge process</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid reactor</dc:subject><dc:description>The performance of a hybrid reactor, comprising of trickling filter and activated sludge process, in treating nitrobenzene wastewater was investigated. Acetate induced cells of mixed consortia was acclimatized with gradual increase of nitrobenzene concentration up to 90mg/l in 100 days using sodium acetate as co-substrate and considering COD and nitrobenzene concentration as paramount parameters for assessing the growth of biofilm and acclimation. A removal of 60-95.80% COD and 80-90.23% nitrobenzene was observed during acclimation. During hydraulic retention time (HRT) studies, the optimum HRT was found to be 29.55 h at which a maximum of 95.83% COD and 97.93% nitrobenzene removal was observed. Other studies included optimization of C:N ratio, substrate: co-substrate ratio, effect of shock loading and estimation of volatilization losses. The optimum C:N ratio was found to be 100:20 at which maximum 97.93% removal of nitrobenzene was observed. At optimum HRT (29.55 h) and optimum C:N ratio (100:20) optimum substrate: co-substrate ratio was found to be 1:33. From the shock load studies it can be concluded that the system can withstand shock load up to two times of usual nitrobenzene concentration. A loss of 9.44% nitrobenzene was observed due to volatilization and mass balance gave an efficiency of 87.49% biological removal of nitrobenzene. (C) 2003</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-25T06:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-25T06:57:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESEARCH, 37(18), 4331-4336</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0043-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0043-1354(03)00436-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10930</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10930</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>