<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4031</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Reconstruction of Pt(13) Clusters into Pt(2)(CO)(m) on CO Addition in NaY Zeolite</dc:title><dc:creator>AKDOGAN, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIU, X</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERTAGNOLLI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>RODUNER, E</dc:creator><dc:subject>platinum pair complex</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray-absorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbonyl clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>paramagnetic-resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen chemisorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>shape resonances</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-catalysts</dc:subject><dc:subject>y-zeolite</dc:subject><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:description>Pt(13) clusters with extraordinarily high magnetization are interesting samples in the area of CO chemistry. For the first time paramagnetic platinum carbonyl samples were prepared and characterized by electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy to improve the understanding of the CO adsorption effect on the structure of small Pt particles with X-ray absorption spectroscopy and Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) methods. In contrast to existing studies on the reduced Pt cluster-CO interaction in the literature, the structure of the paramagnetic Pt sample before CO adsorption is entirely known. The well-defined Pt(13) cluster in NaY zeolite reconstructs into small Pt(2)(CO)(m) aggregates under CO atmosphere at room temperature. X-Band EPR spectroscopy shows that the multiplet spectrum of the Pt(13) cluster at g(iso) = 2.35 disappears, and a new spectrum belonging to the Pt(2)(CO)(m) sample appears at g(iso) = 1.98. Extended X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy supports the Pt(13) Cluster destruction upon admission of CO and the formation of a dimeric platinum carbonyl complex with a nearest-neighbor coordination number that decreases from ca. 5.8 to 0.9. FTIR spectroscopy is a very sensitive technique for the C-O vibrational frequency. It reveals that Pt(2)(CO)(m) species have one type of linear and two types of bridge bonded CO groups. Initially, a weak band at 2108 cm(-1) shows that Pt has a small positive charge, which is converting into zero charge upon CO desorption-adsorption cycles. The surprisingly sharp bands in the CO bridge bond region facilitate assignment, in contrast to the bands of CO bonds of other neutral platinum carbonyl samples.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T18:06:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T18:06:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY C, 113(6), 2352-2359</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1932-7447</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp807566a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4031</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>