<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15864</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:08:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Growth of pseudocubic perovskite-type SrRuO3 thin films on quartz substrate using pulsed laser deposition method</dc:title><dc:creator>DARYAPURKAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOLTE, JT</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHEMICAL SOLUTION DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPITAXIAL SRRUO3</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYCRYSTALLINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SRTIO3</dc:subject><dc:description>Strontium ruthenium oxide (SrRuO3) thin films have been grown using pulsed laser deposition technique on silicon, Pt coated silicon and quartz substrates. The effect of substrate temperatures on the structural, microstructure, and electrical properties of the SrRuO3 films on quartz substrate has been investigated using XRD, SEM, AFM and four-probe method, respectively. The lowest resistivity at room temperature for the SrRuO3 thin film on quartz substrate has been achieved at substrate temperature of 700 A degrees C. Furthermore, the comparisons of SrRuO3 thin films deposited on various substrates have been done with respect to structural, microstructural and electrical properties. XRD patterns exhibit that all thin films are a single phase, pseudo-cubic perovskite structure. Study of surface morphology shows that grain size and roughness varies with respect to substrate. It is observed that SrRuO3 thin films yield larger grain size and root mean square roughness on Pt/Si substrate. Investigation of electrical properties shows that SrRuO3 thin films can serve the purpose of the bottom electrode in dielectric and ferroelectric devices.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:08:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE-MATERIALS IN ELECTRONICS, 24(12)4698-4703</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-4522</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-482X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10854-013-1462-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15864</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>