<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8580</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>A comparative study of ANN and Neuro-fuzzy for the prediction of dynamic constant of rockmass</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANCHAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAIGAL, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>p-wave velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>p-wave velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>neuro-fuzzy</dc:subject><dc:subject>artificial neural network</dc:subject><dc:subject>compressive strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>density</dc:subject><dc:subject>hardness</dc:subject><dc:description>Physico-mechanical properties of rocks have great significance in all operational parts in mining activities, from exploration to final dispatch of material. Compressional wave velocity (p-wave velocity) and anisotropic behaviour of rocks are two such properties which help to understand the rock response under varying stress conditions. They also influence the breakage mechanism of rock. There are different methods to determine the p-wave velocity and anisotropy in situ and in the laboratory. These methods are cumbersome and time consuming. Fuzzy set theory, Fuzzy logic and Neural Networks techniques seem very well suited for typical geotechnical problems. In conjunction with statistics and conventional mathematical methods, hybrid methods can be developed that may prove to be a step forward in modeling geotechnical problems. Here, we have developed and compared two different models, Neuro-fuzzy systems (combination of fuzzy and artificial neural network systems) and Artificial neural network systems, for the prediction of compressional wave velocity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-01T23:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-01T23:55:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 114(1), 75-86</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02702010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8580</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8580</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>