<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-751</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Composite structures under ballistic impact</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHRIRAO, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>ballistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy absorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>friction</dc:subject><dc:subject>strain rate</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, investigations on the ballistic impact behaviour of two-dimensional woven fabric composites has been presented. Ballistic impact behaviour of plain weave E-glass/epoxy and twill weave T300 carbon/epoxy composites has been compared. The analytical method presented is based on our earlier work. Different damage and energy absorbing mechanisms during ballistic impact have been identified. These are: cone formation on the back face of the target, tensile failure of primary yarns, deformation of secondary yarns, delamination, matrix cracking, shear plugging and friction during penetration. Analytical formulation has been presented for each energy absorbing mechanism. Energy absorbed during each time interval and the corresponding reduction in velocity of the projectile has been determined. The solution is based on the target material properties at high strain rate and the geometry and the projectile parameters. Using the analytical formulation, ballistic limit, contact duration at ballistic limit, surface radius of the cone formed and the radius of the damaged zone have been predicted for typical woven fabric composites.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-21T11:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:29:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-21T11:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:29:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Composite Structures 66(1-4),  579-590</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compstruct.2004.05.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/751</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/751</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>