<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12309</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Switched finite time control of a class of underactuated systems - Introduction</dc:title><dc:creator>BANAVAR, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANKARANARAYANAN, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>nonholonomic dynamic-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>variable structure control</dc:subject><dc:subject>exponential stabilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>chained systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>mobile robots</dc:subject><dc:subject>discontinuous control</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>lyapunov approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface vessel</dc:subject><dc:description>Underactuated mechanical systems have lesser number of control inputs than their degrees-of-freedom. Examples of such systems include underwater vehicles, surface vessels, mobile robots, satellites and robotic manipulators. This monograph addresses the problem of stabilizing a class of underactuated systems which are not linearly controllable. Systems with drift and without drift are considered. The main contribution is a switched finite-time control algorithm to stabilize this class of systems. The control law ensures global attractivity and relative stability. The notion of relative stability is weaker than conventional Lyapunov stability and is based on the properties of the trajectories of the closed-loop system that originate in a set of the phase-space. The philosophy of the control strategy is to define a set of surfaces whose intersection is a connected set and contains the equilibrium. The control objective then is to move the trajectory from anywhere in the state-space to this set in finite time. The theory of continuous finite-time differential equations is used to ensure that the system reaches this set in finite time and without chattering. The closed-loop system is then rendered asymptotically stable in this set. To demonstrate the applicability of our technique, we consider the following three well-studied examples - the first is a drift-less system, while the second and third system possess drift. -Nonholonomic Integrator (NI) - This is a benchmark example of a nonholonomic, underactuated system which mimics the kinematic model of a mobile robot. - Extended Nonholonomic Double Integrator (ENDI) - While the NI mimics the kinematic model, the ENDI mimics the dynamic model of a mobile robot. The system is underactuated and has a velocity level nonholonomic constraint. - Underwater vehicle (Surface vessel) - This is an example of an underactuated system with a second order nonholonomic constraint at the acceleration level. Other than the technique mentioned above, we also present a few other techniques to stabilize such systems and an output feedback scheme for one application.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T12:09:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T12:09:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SWITCHED FINITE TIME CONTROL OF A CLASS OF UNDERACTUATED SYSTEMS, 333(), 1-+</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0170-8643</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12309</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>