<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-702</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization of fly ash from various locations of electrostatic precipitator</dc:title><dc:creator>SHANTHAKUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHADKE, RC</dc:creator><dc:subject>electrostatic precipitators</dc:subject><dc:subject>flue gas conditioning</dc:subject><dc:subject>fly ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>characterization</dc:subject><dc:description>Electrostatic precipitation is a well established technique to control the emission of particulate matter (fly ash or dust particles) from coal-fired thermal power stations. Flue gas conditioning, FGC, is a technique that involves addition of chemical agents to the flue gas in order to increase the collection efficiency of the Electrostatic Precipitators, ESPs. Several efforts have already been made by earlier researchers to characterize the fly ash from hoppers, to ascertain its suitability for various engineering applications. However, how characteristics of the fly ash inside the ESP, from one location to another, change has not yet been investigated in details. Such investigations would help in understanding the influence of flue gas conditioning on functioning of ESPs. With this in view, attempts were made to characterize the fly ash collected at various locations of the ESP unit of a power plant (viz., hopper, bottom portion, collection plate and Induced Draft (ID) fan). The study brings out the influence of flue gas conditioning on overall characteristics of the fly ash.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-18T09:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:35:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-18T09:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:35:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG: Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 2261-2268</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/702</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/702</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>