<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-785</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Photoisomerization of amphiphilic azobenzene derivatives in Langmuir Blodgett films prepared as polyion complexes, using ionic polymers</dc:title><dc:creator>SHEMBEKAR, VISHAKHA R</dc:creator><dc:creator>CONTRACTOR, AQ</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJOR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALWAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>isomerisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>carboxylic acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexation</dc:subject><dc:description>Polyion complexation in mixed Langmuir and Langmuir Blodgett (LB) films of photochromic amphiphilic azobenzene carboxylic acids, 11-[4-(4-hexylphenyl)azo] phenoxyundecanoic acid, 11-(4-phenylazo)phenoxyundecanoic acid, and diamine grafted poly(methylmethaacrylate) polymers has been studied. Monolayer behaviour of the pure components and mixed films was studied through pressure–area isotherms and LB films were characterized by spectroscopic, X-ray diffraction and Atomic force microscopy techniques. Aggregation (H-type), often observed in LB films of pure amphiphilic azo acids, was partly avoided in the mixed LB films as indicated by absorption spectral studies. Photoisomerization of the polyion complexed LB films was also studied. The results altogether demonstrate that amine grafted polymer enter into a polyion complexation with azo acid carboxylate group. LB films could be obtained by transfer of the composite monolayers and these LB films exhibited different levels of aggregation of the azo acids. Reversible photoisomerization was observed in LB films with unaggregated azo acid.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-26T06:04:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:54:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-26T06:04:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:54:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Thin Solid Films 510(1-2), 297-304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2005.12.210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/785</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/785</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>