<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11950</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Treatment of petrochemical wastewater by rotating biological contactor</dc:title><dc:creator>KUBSAD, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>rotating biological contactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>petrochemical wastewater</dc:subject><dc:subject>biological treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>cyanide removal</dc:subject><dc:description>A laboratory scale study has been conducted to assess the efficiency of rotating biological contactor (RBC) to treat the synthetic wastewater from a petrochemical industry producing acrylonitrile. The attached biomass was acclimatised by gradually increasing cyanide concentration from 5 to 40 mg 1(-1) with simultaneous increase in the concentration of chemical oxygen demand(COD)and ammonium nitrogen(NH4-&gt;-N). During acclimatization COD removal varied between 80-88 percent(%)while cyanide removal was more than 99%. The RBC was operated at varying hydraulic loading rates from 0.011 to 0.027 m(3) m(-2) d(-1). The performance of the RBC was monitored for various parameters like COD, 5-day biochemical oxygen demand at 20-degree centigrade (degrees C) [BOD5], cyanide, ammonium nitrogen etc., for all hydraulic loadings. At all hydraulic loadings the cyanide removal remained more than 99%. The removals obtained in terms of percentage, for cyanide, COD, BOD5, and NH4-&gt;-N were greater than (&gt;) 99, 95.2, 99.1 and 77, respectively at hydraulic loading of 0.011 m(3) m(-2) d(-1). The effect of substrate/ cyanide ratio on the performance of the process at five different ratios, 100/1, 80/1, 60/1, 40/1 and 20/1, showed more than 99% cyanide removal at ratio 20/1. The effect of COD/nitrogen (N) ratio was studied at four different ratios, 12/1, 10/1, 8/1 and 6/1, showed cyanide removal remained unaffected. The variation of biomass concentration within the system was also studied.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SELPER LTD, PUBLICATIONS DIV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T04:04:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T04:04:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL TECHNOLOGY, 26(12), 1317-1326</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-3330</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09593332608618614</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11950</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11950</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>