<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2395</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hybrid relay stations : a new paradigm of Multihop Cellular Networks</dc:title><dc:creator>MARATHE, NV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>multihop cellular network</dc:subject><dc:subject>capacity increase</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid relay station</dc:subject><dc:subject>dsl link</dc:subject><dc:subject>microcell</dc:subject><dc:description>Multihop Cellular Networks (MCN) have been proposed for quite a long time as of now. The major improvements these networks offer over the conventional cellular networks are the increase in capacity and coverage area. The new element installed in the setup is called as 'Fixed Relay Station' (FRS). These stations are supposed to act as relay terminals between the mobile terminals (MT) and the base station (BS). However as the communication between FRS and BS is over the wireless channel, there is an upper limit for the increase in capacity, which can be achieved by this approach. Therefore in our proposed architecture these relay stations are equipped with a low cost wired connectivity with simple twisted pair of copper cable connected to the local telephone exchange. The communication between these relay stations and BS will be via the wired DSL link. Hence these relay stations are therefore termed as Hybrid Relay Station (HRS). As the BS is also connected to the same local telephone exchange there are no issues associated with the connectivity between the FIRS and the BS. With appropriate placement of these HRS in the cell area substantial capacity increase can be achieved at a very small increase in the associated cost.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INT INST INFORMATICS &amp; SYSTEMICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T06:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T06:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INT CONF ON CYBERNETICS AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGIES, SYSTEMS AND APPLICATIONS/INT CONF ON COMPUTING, COMMUNICATIONS AND CONTROL TECHNOLOGIES, VOL 1,346-349</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-934272-07-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15934</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2395</dc:identifier><dc:source>4th International Conference on Cybernetics and Information Technologies, Systems and Applications/5th Int Conf on Computing, Communications and Control Technologies,Orlando, FL,JUL 12-15, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>