<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1542</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Climatological analysis to determine air pollution potential for different zones in India</dc:title><dc:creator>NATH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:description>India is a tropical country extending from 69 degrees E to 95 degrees E and 7 degrees N to 35 degrees N. The country due to its large size experiences multiplicity of climatological conditions depending upon latitude, longitude, topography and proximity to the sea. Hence, the need arises for analyzing the different climatogical zones from point of view of estimating air potential of each typical region. This would assist regulatory bodies, planners and developers in formulation of air pollution management strategies at national and regional levels. The temperature lapse rate of the atmosphere is an important climatological parameter and is an actual measure of atmospheric thermal stability or instability. Prevailing Mixing Heights, Ventilation Index, Air Pollution Potential Index for determining the dilution capacity or the assimilative capacity of the atmosphere at any location can be derived based on lapse rate measurements. High resolution temperature profile data were obtained by slow ascent balloons (balloon borne minisonde ascents) at various places in India. The environmental lapse rate was monitored periodically during day and night times to estimate the diurnal variation of the lapse rate. The balloons were tracked by optical theodolite in order to obtain vertical wind profiles. The data obtained has been analyzed to determine mixing heights, its diurnal nature, ground based inversion depths, and elevated inversion heights. The Ventilation Coefficient and Air Pollution Potential Index was also determined. Mapping of these parameters for the entire country has been done. On the basis of these isoplots one can identify three different regions, viz. (i) Coastal (ii) Landlocked interior and (iii) Hilly / Mountainous. Dispersion modeling for air pollution emissions can be done for these delineated zones. Thus, national regulatory bodies and planners can ascertain the assimilative capacity of the atmosphere as a function of the climatology of the site.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WIT PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:29:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:29:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>AIR POLLUTION VIII,8,483-492</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-85312-822-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1369-5886</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14754</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1542</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th International Conference on Air Pollution,CAMBRIDGE, ENGLAND,JUL 24-26, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>