<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16938</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:55:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Changes in the design and operational wind due to climate change, at the Indian offshore sites</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEO, MC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Offshore structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>Operational wind</dc:subject><dc:subject>Design wind</dc:subject><dc:subject>Climate change impact</dc:subject><dc:subject>Neural networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>WAVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:description>The increasing global warming is most likely to affect the magnitude and pattern of wind at a regional level and such an effect may or not follow the trend predicted at the global scale. Regional level exercises are therefore necessary while making decisions related to engineering infrastructure. In this paper an attempt is made to know the extent of change in design as well as operational wind conditions at two offshore locations along the west coast of India. The design wind speeds with return periods of 10, 50 and 100 years derived for two 30-year time slices in the past and future are compared. In two separate exercises the past and future wind at the local level is simulated by empirical downscaling as well as by interpolation of the general circulation model (GCM) output. Both sets of past and future data are fitted to the Generalized Pareto as well as Weibull distributions using the peak over threshold method to extract long term wind speeds with a specified return. It is noticed that at the given locations the operational and design wind may undergo an increase of around 11%-14% when no downscaling is adopted and 14%-17% when the GCM data are downscaled. Although these figures may suffer from a certain level of statistical uncertainty the study points out to take a relook into the safety margins kept in the design and operation of ocean structures in the light of global warming. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:55:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:55:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MARINE STRUCTURES, 3733-53</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0951-8339</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.marstruc.2014.02.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16938</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>