<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9387</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>EFFECT OF SUPERSTRATE MATERIAL ON A HIGH-GAIN ANTENNA USING ARRAY OF PARASITIC PATCHES</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>printed-circuit antennas</dc:subject><dc:subject>ebg resonator antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstrip antennas</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhancement methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>band</dc:subject><dc:subject>reflectarray</dc:subject><dc:subject>high-gain antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>directive antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>planar antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>wlan</dc:subject><dc:subject>multilayer</dc:subject><dc:subject>stacked antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>ism</dc:subject><dc:description>This article highlights the effect of superstrate material on a high-gain antenna using array of parasitic patches for wireless applications. The antenna structure consists of a microstrip antenna, which feeds an array of square parasitic patches fabricated on a ceramic or FR4 superstrate. The patches on a superstrate are suspended in air at dolt. The spacing between parasitic. patches and patch dimensions decrease with dielectric constant and, thus, a compact antenna with almost same gain can be designed with high dielectric superstrate. The structures with 5 x 5 array of square parasitic patches provide a gain of 17.5 dB on infinite ground plane in both the cases but the array dimension is 55 x 55 mm(2) in ceramic as compared to 115 x 115 mm(2) Antenna with ceramic superstrate on finite ground requires 25% less ground plane size as compared to FR4. Structure with FR4 superstrate is designed, fabricated, and tested. The measured VSWR is &lt;2 over 5.725-5.875 GHz frequency band. The antenna with 5 x 5 array of square parasitic patches provides a gain of 18.0 dB with 92% efficiency, SLL of -18.4 dB, and front to back lobe ratio of more than 20 dB. The proposed structure can be packaged inside an application platform. (C) 2009 . Microwave Opt Technol Lett 52: 82-88, 2010; Published online in Wiley InterScience (www.interscience.wiley.com). DOI 10.1002/mop.24850</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T04:43:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T04:43:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROWAVE AND OPTICAL TECHNOLOGY LETTERS, 52(1), 82-88</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0895-2477</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/mop.24850</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9387</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9387</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>