<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1884</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural and electronic properties of Graphene and Silicene : an FP-(L)APW plus lo Study</dc:title><dc:creator>BEHERA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>plane-wave method</dc:subject><dc:subject>constants</dc:subject><dc:subject>graphite</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>graphene</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicene</dc:subject><dc:subject>2d honey comb structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>first-principle calculations</dc:subject><dc:description>We report here the structural and electronic properties of graphene and silicene (the silicon analogue of graphene) investigated using first-principles calculations of their ground state energies employing full-potential (linearized) augmented plane wave plus local orbital (FP-(L)APW+lo) method. On structure optimization, we found that the graphene-like honeycomb- structure of Si is buckled (buckling parameter Delta similar or equal to 0.44 angstrom) in contrast with graphene whose structure is planar (Delta = 0.0 angstrom). In spite of the buckled-structure, silicene has an electronic structure similar to that of graphene. The results are in agreement with previous reports based on other methods. We have also calculated the lower bounds of the lattice constant "a" of these 2D systems, within the present method of study which are our new results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:24:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:24:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PHYSICS OF EMERGING FUNCTIONAL MATERIALS (PEFM-2010),1313,152-155</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7354-0868-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0094-243X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1884</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Physics of Emerging Functional Materials,Mumbai, INDIA,SEP 22-24, 2010</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>