<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16950</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:01:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of multiparticle bipolar electrolysis using single particle cell model</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>JUVEKAR, VA</dc:creator><dc:subject>Bipolar electrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Single electrode cell model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Particle interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multiple reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>BED ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DECOLORIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:description>In open bipolar electrolysis, suspended metal particles are polarized by electric held and as a result, each individual particle acts as an electrolytic cell on which redox synthesis can be performed. Process intensification could be achieved by packing a large number of particles in a small volume. To study the interactions among the bipolar electrodes, a single-electrode cell model is proposed in which bipolar sphere is enclosed in a hypothetical cylindrical cell, the axis of which is oriented along the direction of the electric field. Model is validated by comparing its predictions with those of the computationally more intensive multi-electrode cell model. Next, the effective conductivity of the medium, containing conducting particles, is predicted using the model and predictions are compared with experimental data as well as approximate analytical solutions reported in the literature. The model predicts that when the applied electric field is high, increase in the loading of bipolar particle improves the performance of individual electrodes and hence the performance of the reactor as a whole. Also, fluctuations in the particle distribution in the reactor result in the lowering of the performance. Hence it is preferable to use a fixed array of bipolar electrodes in a reactor. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:01:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:01:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING SCIENCE, 11072-82</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2509</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4405</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2013.12.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16950</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>