<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-814</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>4-Chlorobutanol induces unusual reversible and irreversible thermal unfolding of ribonuclease A: thermodynamic, kinetic, and conformational characterization</dc:title><dc:creator>MEHTA, RANJANA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, AGNITA</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAND KISHORE</dc:creator><dc:subject>denaturation</dc:subject><dc:subject>enthalpy</dc:subject><dc:subject>differential scanning calorimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>activation energy</dc:subject><dc:description>The thermal denaturation of ribonuclease A has been studied by differential scanning calorimetry in the presence of 4-chlorobutan-1-ol. The thermal transitions were observed to be reversible at pH 5.5 in the presence of low concentration (up to 50 mM) of the alcohol, irreversible in the intermediate (50 mM&lt;c&lt;250 mM) and again reversible in the presence of 250 mM and higher concentrations of 4-chlorobutan-1-ol. In the presence of 50 mM 4-chlorobutan-1-ol, ribonuclease A is present in two conformational states unfolding at different temperatures. The reversible thermal transitions have been fitted to a two-state native-to-denatured mechanism. Irreversible thermal transitions have been analyzed according to two-state irreversible native-to-denatured kinetic model. Using the irreversible model, rate constant as a function of temperature and energy of activation of the irreversible process have been calculated. Circular dichroism and fluorescence spectroscopic results corroborate the DSC observations and indicate a protein conformation with poorly defined tertiary structure and high content of secondary structure in the presence of 50 mM 4-chlorobutan-1-ol at a temperature corresponding to the second transition. Similar results have been observed at pH 3.9.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-27T11:09:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:08:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-27T11:09:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:08:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>International Journal of Biological Macromolecules 34(1-2), 13-20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0141-8130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2003.11.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/814</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/814</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>