<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16485</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:18:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Probing the magnetic and magnetothermal properties of M(II)-Ln(III) complexes (where M(II) = Ni or Zn; Ln(III) = La or Pr or Gd)</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMED, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAIDYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>LANGLEY, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURRAY, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAM, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE-MAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALLADIUM-CATALYZED SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOMEDICAL APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DILANTHANIDE COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>M-II-LN(III)-M-II M</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SLOW RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DY COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL-IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:description>We establish the coordination potential of the Schiff base ligand (2-methoxy-6-[(E)-2'-hydroxymethyl-phenyliminomethyl]-phenolate (H2L)) via the isolation of various M(II)-Ln(III) complexes (where M(II) = Ni or Zn and Ln(III) = La or Pr or Gd). Single crystals of these five complexes were isolated and their solid state structures were determined by single crystal X-ray diffraction. Structural determination revealed molecular formulae of [NiGd(HL)(2)(NO3)(3)] (1), [NiPr(HL)(2)(NO3)(3)] (2) and [Ni2La(HL)(4)(NO3)](NO3)(2) (3), [Zn2Gd(HL)(4)(NO3)](NO3)(2) (4), and [Zn2Pr(HL)(4)(NO3)](NO3)(2) (5). Complexes 1 and 2 were found to be neutral heterometallic dinuclear compounds, whereas 3-5 were found to be linear heterometallic tri-nuclear cationic complexes. Direct current (dc) magnetic susceptibility and magnetization measurements conclusively revealed that complexes 1 and 4 possess a spin ground state of S = 9/2 and 7/2 respectively. Empirically calculated Delta T-chi M derived from the variable temperature susceptibility data for all complexes undoubtedly indicates that the Ni(II) ion is coupled ferromagnetically with the Gd(III) ion, and anti-ferromagnetically with the Pr(III) ion in 1 and 2 respectively. The extent of the exchange interaction for 1 was estimated by fitting the magnetic susceptibility data using the parameters (g = 2.028, S = 9/2, J = 1.31 cm(-1) and zJ = +0.007), supporting the phenomenon observed in an empirical approach. Similarly using a HDVV Hamiltonian, the magnetic data of 3 and 4 were fitted, yielding parameters g = 2.177, D = 3.133 cm(-1), J = -0.978 cm(-1), (for 3) and g = 1.985, D = 0.508 cm(-1) (for 4). The maximum change in magnetic entropy (-Delta S-m) estimated from the isothermal magnetization data for 1 was found to be 5.7 J kg(-1) K-1 (Delta B = 7 Tesla) at 7.0 K, which is larger than the -Delta S-m value extracted from 4 of 3.5 J kg(-1) K-1 (Delta B = 7 Tesla) at 15.8 K, revealing the importance of the exchange interaction in increasing the overall ground state of a molecule for better MCE efficiency.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:18:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:18:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 43(46)17375-17384</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4dt02360a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16485</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>