<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1202</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Non-linear seismic response of base-isolated liquid storage tanks to bi-directional excitation</dc:title><dc:creator>SHRIMALI, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>water tanks</dc:subject><dc:subject>yield stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismology</dc:subject><dc:description>Seismic response of the liquid storage tanks isolated by lead-rubber bearings is investigated for bi-directional earthquake excitation (i.e. two horizontal components). The biaxial force-deformation behaviour of the bearings is considered as bi-linear modelled by coupled non-linear differential equations. The continuous liquid mass of the tank is modelled as lumped masses known as convective mass, impulsive mass and rigid mass. The corresponding stiffness associated with these lumped masses has been worked out depending upon the properties of the tank wall and liquid mass. Since the force-deformation behaviour of the bearings is non-linear, as a result, the seismic response is obtained by the Newmark's step-by-step method. The seismic responses of two types of the isolated tanks (i.e. slender and broad) are investigated under several recorded earthquake ground to study the effects of bi-directional interaction. Further, a parametric study is also carried out to study the effects of important system parameters on the effectiveness of seismic isolation for liquid storage tanks. The various important parameters considered are: (i) the period of isolation, (ii) the damping of isolation bearings and (iii) the yield strength level of the bearings. It has been observed that the seismic response of isolated tank is found to be insensitive to interaction effect of the bearing forces. Further, there exists an optimum value of isolation damping for which the base shear in the tank attains the minimum value. Therefore, increasing the bearing damping beyond a certain value may decrease the bearing and sloshing displacements but it may increase the base shear.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-22T09:01:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:14:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-22T09:01:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:14:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Nuclear Engineering and Design 217(1-2), 1-20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0029-5493(02)00134-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1202</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1202</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>