<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1312</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Two shear deformable finite element models for buckling analysis of skew fibre-reinforced composite and sandwich panels</dc:title><dc:creator>BABU, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, TARUN</dc:creator><dc:subject>boundary conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich structures</dc:subject><dc:description>Two shear deformable finite element models, one based on first-order shear deformation theory and the other based on a higher-order shear deformation theory, are developed for buckling analysis of skew laminated composite and sandwich panels. The procedure involves the development of transformation matrix between global and local degrees of freedom for the nodes lying on the skew edges and suitable transformation of element matrices. The accuracy of the present models is demonstrated by comparing with alternative solutions available in the literature. Extensive numerical results are presented for critical buckling loads of angle-ply and cross-ply skew laminates with various lamination parameters, boundary conditions and width-to-thickness ratios. New results on skew sandwiches, hitherto not reported in the literature, are obtained for different geometric parameters and skew angles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:39:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:01:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:39:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:01:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Composite Structures 46(2), 115-124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0263-8223(99)00039-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1312</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1312</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>