<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15362</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:41:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Process Parameters and Binder Concentration on Mechanical Properties of Phosphate Bonded Alumina</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIWARI, AN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Chemically bonded ceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aluminophosphate (AlPO4)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Young's modulus</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transverse rupture strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hardness</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COATINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:description>Alumina and alumina matrix composites typically require sintering temperature in excess of 1550 degrees C. Utilization of aluminium phosphate bonding provides process flexibility and significantly lowers sintering temperature (500 degrees to 1280 degrees C). While phosphate bonded alumina (PBA) may have a lower sintering temperature, its limitations include the presence of porosity in pressure less sintered samples leading to lowered strength and phase instability above approximately 1200 degrees C. The present study describes the effect of processing routes and binder concentration on density, hardness, Young's modulus and transverse rupture strength (TRS) of PBA. In this study, ultra fine Al2O3 (particle size approximate to 0.5 mu m) was reacted with H3PO4 to yield phosphate bond in a matrix of tabular Al2O3 (particle size approximate to 5 mu m) after final sintering at 1280 degrees C for 6 h. Green samples were compacted at pressures in the range of 96-290 MPa. The effect of aluminium phosphate binder concentration on mechanical properties of the PBA samples was measured at optimized pressure. The presence of different polymorphs of AlPO4 in the sintered product was confirmed by XRD.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN CERAMIC SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:41:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:41:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN CERAMIC SOCIETY, 72(2)130-135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0371-750X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2165-5456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/0371750X.2013.817602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15362</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>