<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18419</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T11:04:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Overburden-induced flattening structure in the Himalaya: mechanism and implication</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATIN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKUL, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>FOLD-THRUST-BELT</dc:subject><dc:subject>LESSER-HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>TECTONIC EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHUMAR ALLOCHTHON</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONTINENTAL-CRUST</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIKKIM HIMALAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>EASTERN BHUTAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>RANGIT DUPLEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN NEPAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNITED-STATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orogeny</dc:subject><dc:subject>overburden-induced flattening</dc:subject><dc:subject>recumbent fold</dc:subject><dc:subject>thrust sheet</dc:subject><dc:description>Small-scale structures in fold-thrust belt are mainly formed in response to the emplacement of thrust sheets. However, some small-scale structures may not be developed directly in response to the emplacement of thrust sheets, but might be genetically tied with the orogenic process. Metre-to centimetre-scale late-stage folds on foliation in phyllite with near-recumbent fold geometry are selectively developed with a specific spatial distribution, particularly in places where the foliation is steeply dipping, in the Ramgarh thrust sheet in the Darjiling-Sikkim Himalaya. The recumbent-fold structures appear to have been formed in response to overburden-induced vertical compressive deformation on steep dipping foliation, especially in the sub-vertical southern limb of the antiformal structure of the Lesser Himalayan Duplex in the Darjiling-Sikkim Himalaya. The role of gravity and overburden in the formation of these structures from worldwide orogenic belts may be considered to validate their genesis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:04:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:04:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 109(10)1814-1821</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18419</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>