<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-677</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Some investigations on cracking characteristics of soils</dc:title><dc:creator>VENKATARAMANA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>HANUMANTHA RAO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHINDE, SUDARSHAN B</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARENDRANATH, CS</dc:creator><dc:subject>cracking characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>fine grained soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>crack geometry</dc:subject><dc:description>Fine-grained soils, in particular, expansive soils are prone to cracking. For these soils swelling-shrinking potential is quite high and hence they exhibit adverse affect on overall stability of geotechnical structures. This phenomenon may also be responsible for alteration of various engineering properties of soils such as hydraulic conductivity, water and leachate penetration, solute transport, stability of slopes, etc. Previous studies demonstrate that several factors mainly moisture content, clay content and its type, particle size and its shape, tensile strength, etc., largely control the cracking characteristics of the soil mass. With this in view, researchers have mainly concentrated on quantifying and modeling the crack geometry. Also, most of the studies are confined to evaluation of the cracking potential of the soil when it achieves completely dry state. However, not many efforts have been made to investigate crack initiation in soils and its propagation with time. This paper presents details of the initial attempts made by the researchers at Indian Institute of Technology Bombay to investigate cracking characteristics of fine-grained soils.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:08:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:27:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:08:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:27:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG : Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 1532-1538</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/677</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/677</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>