<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14474</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:04:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of excavation stages on stress and pore pressure changes for an underground nuclear repository</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJPAI, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Hydro-mechanical</dc:subject><dc:subject>Underground geological repository</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flac3D</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coupled analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pore pressure</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper provides a brief overview of evolution of deformations, stresses, and pore pressures due to different excavation stages during construction of an URL. Excavation of a rockmass develops damage zone of finite width around the excavated zone which is associated with changes in permeability and affect the fluid flow mechanism. In this study, a coupled hydromechanical (HM) analysis for a water saturated porous rock mass has been done which is caused by sequential excavation and backfill of vertical disposal pit of an URL. For this purpose, an Atomic Energy of Canada Limited's in-floor concept for a deep geologic repository suitable for Indian condition has been used. Changes in rock deformations, stresses, strains and mechanically induced pore pressure in an undrained condition, during excavation, as well as those caused by mechanically induced rock deformations after backfill of the disposal pit have been modeled. A three-dimensional finite difference tool FLAC(3D) (Itasca Consulting Group Inc. FLAC-3D 1997) has been used for the analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:04:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:04:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ARABIAN JOURNAL OF GEOSCIENCES, 6(3)635-645</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-011-0382-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14474</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>