<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9486</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimization of Rifamycin B fermentation in shake flasks via a machine-learning-based approach</dc:title><dc:creator>BAPAT, PM</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANGIKAR, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>response-surface methodology</dc:subject><dc:subject>amycolatopsis-mediterranei</dc:subject><dc:subject>3-amino-5-hydroxybenzoic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosynthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>lovastatin</dc:subject><dc:subject>expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>culture</dc:subject><dc:subject>media balancing</dc:subject><dc:subject>decision tree</dc:subject><dc:subject>fermentation</dc:subject><dc:description>Rifamycin B is an important polyketide antibiotic used in the treatment of tuberculosis and leprosy. We present results on medium optimization for Rifamycin B production via a barbital insensitive mutant strain of Amycolatopsis mediterranei S699. Machine-learning approaches such as Genetic algorithm (GA), Neighborhood analysis (NA) and Decision Tree technique (DT) were explored for optimizing the medium composition. Genetic algorithm was applied as a global search algorithm while NA was used for a guided local search and to develop medium predictors. The fermentation medium for Rifamycin B consisted of nine components. A large number of distinct medium compositions Eire possible by variation of concentration of each component. This presents a large combinatorial search space. Optimization was achieved within five generations via GA as well as NA. These five generations consisted of 178 shake-flask experiments, which is a small fraction of the search space. We detected multiple optima in the form of 11 distinct medium combinations. These medium combinations provided over 600% improvement in Rifamycin B productivity. Genetic algorithm performed better in optimizing fermentation medium as compared to NA. The Decision Tree technique revealed the media-media interactions qualitatively in the form of sets of rules for medium composition that give high as well as low productivity. (C) 2004 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T11:24:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T11:24:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOTECHNOLOGY AND BIOENGINEERING, 86(2), 201-208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-3592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/bit.20056</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9486</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9486</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>