<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11680</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Applications of a high performance platinum nanocatalyst for the oxidation of alcohols in water</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITY, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPINATH, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>catalyzed aerobic oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic-reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular-oxygen</dc:subject><dc:subject>asymmetric hydrogenation</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanopalladium catalyst</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbonyl dianions</dc:subject><dc:subject>aqueous-media</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>efficient</dc:subject><dc:subject>green</dc:subject><dc:description>Nanoparticles of platinum (NP-Pt), have been synthesized by supporting high nuclearity anionic carbonyl cluster (Chini cluster) on a water soluble anion exchanger, and the performance of this material, 1, as an oxidation catalyst for alcohols in water has been studied. The E-factor for the synthesis of NP-Pt by this method has been calculated and compared with that of other NP-Pt recently reported in the literature. With 1 as a catalyst, oxidations of a variety of primary and secondary alcohols by dioxygen are achieved and high turnover numbers and selectivities are obtained. The performances of 1 in the oxidation of benzyl alcohol and 1-phenylethanol are compared with those of three other platinum catalysts. These are platinum nanoparticles 2 prepared by the hydrogen reduction of [PtCl(6)](2-) supported on the same water soluble polymer, 5% Pt on carbon, and 5% Pt on alumina, designated as 3 and 4, respectively. 1 has been found to be considerably more active than 2- 4 and also other reported water soluble platinum nanocatalysts. After many turnovers (similar to 1000 and similar to 165 for benzyl alcohol and 1-phenyl ethanol, respectively) partial deactivation (similar to 40%) is observed, but the deactivated catalyst can be fully regenerated by treatment with dihydrogen. The TEM data of fresh, deactivated and regenerated 1 show a correlation between the particle size and activity. A mechanism consistent with this and other experimental observations including XPS data is proposed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T13:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T13:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GREEN CHEMISTRY, 11(4), 554-561</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9262</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b815948c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11680</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11680</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>