<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14403</identifier><datestamp>2012-09-12T11:27:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Surge Analysis in a Large Lift Irrigation Project through Physical Modeling – A Case Study</dc:title><dc:creator>Chandramohan P.V</dc:creator><dc:creator>Eldho T.I</dc:creator><dc:creator>Jothiprakash, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>Deo, M.C.</dc:creator><dc:subject>lift irrigation scheme</dc:subject><dc:subject>surge analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>phsical modelling</dc:subject><dc:description>In the last few years, a large number of irrigation projects are initiated in India for sustainable agriculture water supply. In many of these schemes, lifting of water is required to large heights due to various geographical constraints. In most of the lift irrigation schemes, a surge pool is provided to absorb large amplitude oscillations. In case the conveyance is through a closed conduit, acceleration and deceleration of the flow during starting or shutting down of the pumps could create unexpected oscillations in the surge pool. In this study, the surge analysis of a large scale lift irrigation scheme is investigated through physical modeling. A physical model study of the Rajiv (Bheema) Lift Irrigation Scheme, Andhra Pradesh was made at the Hydraulics Laboratory, IIT Bombay. The model was run for various operating conditions of the prototype and possible surges. The model could satisfactorily simulate the various surge phenomena which may take place in the lift irrigation scheme for various pumps operating parameters. Salient observations and conclusions of the study are presented in this paper.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Indian Society for Hydraulics</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-09-12T11:03:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-09-12T11:03:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ISH Journal of Hydraulic Engineering, 13(3) 102-114</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2164-3040</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14403</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>