<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15678</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:34:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Gnidia glauca flower extract mediated synthesis of gold nanoparticles and evaluation of its chemocatalytic potential</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHIRE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KITTURE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GURAV, DD</dc:creator><dc:creator>JABGUNDE, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARDESI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHINDE, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAVALE, DD</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOPADE, BA</dc:creator><dc:subject>Gnidia glauca</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gold nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>UV-Visible spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transmission electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>High resolution transmission electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Elemental mapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>Energy dispersive spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dynamic light scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>X-ray diffraction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chemocatalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILVER NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GREEN SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTRACELLULAR BIOSYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTINOMYCETE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOTECHNOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINENSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>AU</dc:subject><dc:description>Background: Novel approaches for synthesis of gold nanoparticles (AuNPs) are of utmost importance owing to its immense applications in diverse fields including catalysis, optics, medical diagnostics and therapeutics. We report on synthesis of AuNPs using Gnidia glauca flower extract (GGFE), its detailed characterization and evaluation of its chemocatalytic potential. Results: Synthesis of AuNPs using GGFE was monitored by UV-Vis spectroscopy and was found to be rapid that completed within 20 min. The concentration of chloroauric acid and temperature was optimized to be 0.7 mM and 50 C respectively. Bioreduced nanoparticles varied in morphology from nanotriangles to nanohexagons majority being spherical. AuNPs were characterized employing transmission electron microscopy, high resolution transmission electron microscopy. Confirmation of elemental gold was carried out by elemental mapping in scanning transmission electron microscopic mode, energy dispersive spectroscopy and X-ray diffraction studies. Spherical particles of size similar to 10 nm were found in majority. However, particles of larger dimensions were in range between 50-150 nm. The bioreduced AuNPs exhibited remarkable catalytic properties in a reduction reaction of 4-nitrophenol to 4-aminophenol by NaBH4 in aqueous phase. Conclusion: The elaborate experimental evidences support that GGFE can provide an environmentally benign rapid route for synthesis of AuNPs that can be applied for various purposes. Biogenic AuNPs synthesized using GGFE exhibited excellent chemocatalytic potential.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BIOMED CENTRAL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:34:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:34:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOBIOTECHNOLOGY, 10</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1477-3155-10-17</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15678</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>