<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1677</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of aqua AMSR-E derived snow water equivalent over himalayan snow covered regions</dc:title><dc:creator>VIJAY KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, YS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARWADE, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SNEHMANI</dc:creator><dc:subject>glaciology</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrological techniques</dc:subject><dc:subject>remote sensing by radar</dc:subject><dc:subject>climate change</dc:subject><dc:subject>radiometers</dc:subject><dc:description>We have made an endeavor to investigate the snow water equivalent (SWE) variations in Himalayan mountain region which is the most difficult terrain to access during winter seasons. The area also covers the large glaciers such as Siachen and Gangotri. A time series multi scale of SWE L3 product derived from Aqua Advanced Microwave Scanning Radiometer (AMSR-E) data have been analysed for three consecutive winters during 2002 -2005 for Himalayan Snow cover region. A major emphasis is on the study of SWE trend in the two glacier areas viz. Siachen and Gangotri. It has been observed through AVISR- E 5-day product that snow cover area (SCA) over whole Himalayan region is very dynamic. AVISR-E derived 5-day SWE is analysed at the two test sites viz. Patsio (Lat 32deg 45 17.89" N and Lon 77deg, 15', 43.13"E) and Dhundi (Lat 32deg, 22, 05"N and Lon 77deg, 15 E) concurrently with the available in-situ data .The result indicates that in the peak winter days only we found reasonable co-relation. At the Patsio, minimum and maximum SWE observed are 26 mm and 108 mm respectively using in situ data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:24:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:00:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:24:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:00:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium, Denver, USA, 31 July - 4 August 2006, 702-705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-9510-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/IGARSS.2006.184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1677</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1677</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>