<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18208</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:52:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling Debris Motion in Vibration Assisted Reverse Micro Electrical Discharge Machining Process (R-MEDM)</dc:title><dc:creator>MASTUD, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOTHARI, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>EDM</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HOLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reverse micro electrical discharge machining (R-EDM)</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration assisted EDM</dc:subject><dc:subject>debris simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>dielectric flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>textured surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>micromachining</dc:subject><dc:description>Reverse microelectrical discharge machining (R-MEDM) process is a recent variant of microelectrical discharge machining process capable of fabricating high aspect ratio arrayed microfeatures and textured surfaces. Efficient flushing of the debris particles from the interelectrode gap is essential for process stability, but extremely small interelectrode gaps (similar to 5 mu m) make the dispelling of debris difficult, rendering the R-MEDM process infeasible for machining difficult-to-erode materials and creation of engineered/textured surfaces. It has been experimentally observed that the electrode vibrations facilitate the flushing of debris particles and improve the erosion rate, surface morphology, and dimensional accuracy of the machined features. Despite the obvious advantages, the vibration-assisted R-MEDM process, specifically the debris motion and dielectric flow under the effect of vibration, is not very well understood. Consequently, this paper is focused on computational modeling of the debris motion and its interaction with the dielectric fluid under low-amplitude vibrations imparted via a magnetorestrictive actuator. The effects of frequency and amplitude of the electrode vibration on the debris motion have been quantified. The higher local debris velocities and oscillatory motion due to flow reversal potentially reduce the debris agglomeration. As a result, the normal discharge duration, which is responsible for the material erosion, is increased and fabrication of arrayed features on difficult-to-erode materials and creation of surface texture over large areas become feasible.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:52:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:52:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MICROELECTROMECHANICAL SYSTEMS, 24(3)661-676</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1057-7157</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1941-0158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JMEMS.2014.2343227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18208</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>