<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14936</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:53:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>The role of reduced graphene oxide capping on defect induced ferromagnetism of ZnO nanorods</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAKASH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>FEW-LAYER GRAPHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-LAYER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLAR-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC-OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOWIRES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:description>In this study, the effect of different numbers of layers of reduced graphene oxide (RGO) on the ferromagnetic behavior of zinc oxide-reduced graphene oxide (ZnO-RGO) hybrid architectures has been investigated. Scanning and transmission electron microscopy along with x-ray diffraction of these hybrids confirm that ZnO nanorods are wrapped with different numbers of layers of RGO in a controlled way and their hexagonal phase is unaffected by these layers. Raman and photoelectron spectroscopy of these hybrids reveals that RGO does not alter the nonpolar optical phonon E-2 (high) mode and chemical state of Zn2+ in ZnO. Electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectra show that RGO passivates singly charged oxygen vacancies (V-OS(+)) in ZnO. It correlates the passivation efficiency of V-OS(+) to the number of RGO layers and this has been achieved up to 90% by similar to 31 layers of RGO. Due to passivation of V-OS(+) in ZnO by RGO, the ferromagnetic behavior (saturation magnetization and divergence between zero field cooled and field cooled) in ZnO-RGO hybrids is suppressed as compared to ZnO. Combining the EPR and magnetic behavior, a direct link between the passivation of the singly charged oxygen vacancies present on the surface of ZnO nanorods and the number of RGO layers is established.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:53:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:53:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 24(9)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/24/9/095705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14936</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>