<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17885</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:04:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Is Single-4-Ring the Most Basic but Elusive Secondary Building Unit That Transforms to Larger Structures in Zinc Phosphate Chemistry?</dc:title><dc:creator>DAR, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>OPEN-FRAMEWORK STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZIRCONIUM-PHOSPHATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-SIEVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL PHOSPHATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROTHERMAL SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TITANIUM PHOSPHATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASSISTED SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IRON PHOSPHATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION-EXCHANGE</dc:subject><dc:description>Haloaryl phosphates (X-dippH(2), X = Cl, Br, I) react with zinc acetate in the presence of collidine or 2-aminopyridine (2-apy) to yield zinc phosphate clusters [Zn(X-dipp)(collidine)]4 (X = Cl (1), Br (2), I (3)) and [Zn(X-dipp)(2-apy)](4)center dot 2MeOH (X = Cl (4), Br (5), I (6)), respectively. Single-crystal X-ray diffraction studies reveal that collidine and 2-apy capped zinc phosphates 1-6 exist as discrete tetrameric zinc phosphate molecules, exhibiting a cubane-shaped D4R core. In contrast, when the same reaction has been carried out in the presence of 4-cyanopyridine (4-CNpy), polymeric zinc phosphates {[Zn-4(X-dipp)(4)(4-CNpy)(2)(MeOH)(2)]center dot 2H(2)O}(n) (X = Cl (7), Br (8), I (9)) have been isolated. Compounds 7-9 are square-wave-shaped, one-dimensional polymers composed of fused S4R repeating units. The common structural motif found both in D4R cubanes 1-6 and polymers 7-9 is the S4R building block, which presumably undergoes further fusion because of the coordinative unsaturation at zinc and the simultaneous presence of free P=O. The closed shell cubanes 1-6 are obviously formed by a face-to-face dimerization involving two S4R units in which the two P=O groups are in cis-configuration. On the other hand, the one-dimensional (1-D) square-wave polymers 7-9 are formed from a face-to-face association of S4R building units in which the two P=O groups are in a trans-configuration. In order to stabilize these elusive S4R zinc phosphates, the reaction between Cl-dippH2 and zinc acetate was carried out in the presence of excess imidazole as an ancillary ligand (1:1:4), although only an imidazole decorated cubane cluster [Zn(Cl-dipp)(imz)]4.2MeOH (10) was isolated. The chelating N,N'-donor 1,10-phenanthroline ligand was used to eventually isolate cyclic S4R phosphate [Zn(mu(2)-Cl-dipp)(1,10-phen)(OH2)](2)center dot MeOH center dot H2O (11). The change of Zn2+ source to zinc nitrate and the phosphate source to 2,6-dimethylphenyl phosphate (dmppH2) led to the isolation of another polymeric phosphate [Zn(dmpp)(MeOH)](n) (12), with a zigzag backbone, formed through an edge-to-edge to polymerization of S4R building units with P=O groups in trans-configuration. The isolation of four different structural types of zinc phosphates A-D in the present study can be rationalized in terms of fusion of S4R rings in a variety of ways to either produce discrete clusters or 1-D polymers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:04:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:04:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 54(10)4882-4894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-510X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5b00495</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17885</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>