<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8936</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>The use of fuzzy numbers in reliability calculations</dc:title><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEKA, BC</dc:creator><dc:subject>uncertainty importance</dc:subject><dc:subject>component-reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>system components</dc:subject><dc:description>In reliability analysis, complexity of data handling arises due to the complexity of systems with large number of electronic components. Due to the sophistication of the devices with Integrated Circuits, there Is a scarcity of failure data to analyze the system and to compare with alternative designs. In this context, for example, we often need to consider failure of components which have never failed before, Fuzzy Arithmetic has the capacity of dealing with such situations. The theory of fuzzy sets has been widely used for providing a mathematical framework to concepts which are imprecise and uncertain. This paper presents a method based on fuzzy arithmetic to calculate reliability of a component or a system considering uncertainty associated with the variables. Distribution parameter uncertainty has been quantified using Fuzzy Number (FN) and reliability Is calculated at the component level. Possibility distribution Is developed for component reliability with fuzzy parameters of well known exponential and Weibull distribution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ELECTRONICS TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T06:59:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T06:59:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IETE TECHNICAL REVIEW, 18(1), 27-31</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0255-9609</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8936</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>