<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2928</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-29T05:37:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>The practical feasibility of using RFID in a metal environment</dc:title><dc:creator>ARORA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALLINSON, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRUSEY, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MCFARLANE, D</dc:creator><dc:description>Passive Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) has revolutionized the way in which products are identified. This paper considers the effect of metals on the performance of RFID at ultra high frequency (UHF). The paper establishes read patterns in space, highlighting the interference of RF waves due to three different metals, one ferrous and the other two non ferrous, when placed behind a transponder. The effect of thickness of the metal plate is also examined. Different metals have been found to have different interference effects although there are some similarities in their read patterns related to their material properties. Also experiments have been carried out to identify and establish various methods of improving this performance. Finally, differences between performance-measuring parameters, namely attenuating transmitted power and calculating read rate at a fixed attenuation are established and possible reasons of these observations are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T23:21:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T23:21:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2007 IEEE WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS &amp; NETWORKING CONFERENCE, VOLS 1-9,1681-1685</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-0658-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1525-3511</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16446</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2928</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE Wireless Communications and Networking Conference,Hong Kong, PEOPLES R CHINA,MAR 11-15, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>