<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-431</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Power factor improvement in one cycle controlled converter</dc:title><dc:creator>SREERAJ, ES</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>power convertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>power factor correction</dc:subject><dc:subject>power grids</dc:subject><dc:description>Grid connected unity power factor converters based on one cycle control (OCC) does not require the service of PLL or any other synchronization circuits for getting interfaced with the utility. As a result, these schemes are becoming more and more popular. However, as the power level handled by the converter increases, there is a marked deterioration in the power factor. To understand the cause of poor power factor while negotiating high-power loads quantitatively, mathematical models for these schemes are developed. After having understood the cause for poor power factor operation by studying the models developed, a modified OCC based converter has been proposed. The proposed scheme does not have the problem of poor power factor operation while negotiating high power loads. Detailed simulation studies are carried out to confirm the viability of the scheme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-22T05:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T21:15:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-22T05:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T21:15:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Symposium on Industrial Electronics (V 2), Montreal, Canada, 9-13 July 2006, 1454-1460</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0496-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ISIE.2006.295686</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/431</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/431</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>