<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1611</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>A proxy-based approach for dynamic content acceleration on the WWW</dc:title><dc:creator>DATTA, ANINDYA</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, KAUSHIK</dc:creator><dc:creator>THOMAS, HELEN</dc:creator><dc:creator>VANDERMEER, DEBRA</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, KRITHI</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESHA</dc:creator><dc:subject>world wide web</dc:subject><dc:subject>information resources</dc:subject><dc:subject>internet</dc:subject><dc:subject>cache storage</dc:subject><dc:subject>file servers</dc:subject><dc:description>Various dynamic content caching approaches have been proposed to address the performance and scalability problems faced by many Web sites that utilize dynamic content generation applications. Proxy-based caching approaches store content at various locations outside the site infrastructure and can improve Web site performance by reducing content generation delays, firewall processing delays, and bandwidth requirements. However, existing proxy-based caching approaches either: (a) cache at the page level, which does not guarantee that correct pages are served and provides very limited reusability, or (b) cache at the fragment level, which requires the use of pre-defined page layouts. To address these issues, several back end caching approaches have been proposed, including query result caching and fragment level caching. While back end approaches guarantee the correctness of results and offer the advantages of fine-grained caching, they neither address firewall delays nor reduce bandwidth requirements. The authors present an approach and an implementation of a dynamic proxy caching technique which combines the benefits of both proxy-based and back end caching approaches, yet does not suffer from their above-mentioned limitations (15 refs.).</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE Computer Society</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-07-18T06:37:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:48:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-07-18T06:37:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:48:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the  Fourth IEEE International Workshop on Advanced Issues of E-Commerce and Web-Based Information Systems, (WECWIS), Newport Beach, CA, USA, 26-28 June 2002, 159-164</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0 7695 1567 3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/WECWIS.2002.1021254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1611</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1611</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>