<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4663</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of zeolitization on compaction, consolidation, and permeation characteristics of a lagoon ash</dc:title><dc:creator>KOLAY, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>coal fly-ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolite</dc:subject><dc:subject>lagoon ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolites</dc:subject><dc:subject>compaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>miniature compactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>consolidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>permeability</dc:subject><dc:description>A common method of disposing of ash generated from coal-fired thermal power plants is wet disposal, where the ash is mixed with water to make a slurry and is disposed of in ash ponds or lagoons. Such a disposal system allows for ash-water interaction, and alkalis present in the ash react with water, leading to the formation of ash zeolites. Formation of zeolites alters the overall properties of the ash. Controlled laboratory experiments have been conducted on a lagoon ash to determine the effects of zeolitization on its physico-chemico-mineralogical properties. Further investigations have been carried out to demonstrate the effect of zeolitization of the ash on its geotechnical properties such as its compaction, consolidation, and permeation characteristics. Such a study is required for bulk utilization of the ash (as a fill material) where compaction, consolidation, and permeation properties are most important.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC TESTING MATERIALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T07:54:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T07:54:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF TESTING AND EVALUATION, 28(6), 425-430</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0090-3973</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4663</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4663</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>