<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17470</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:14:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling size and structure of nanoparticles formed from drying of submicron solution aerosols</dc:title><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWAR, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>DOUBLE-WALLED MICROSPHERES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW REACTOR METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPRAY-PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MORPHOLOGICAL CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>DROPLET EVAPORATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLE FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIPID MATRICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUG-DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>L-LEUCINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLINITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Droplet evaporation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shell thickness</dc:subject><dc:subject>Critical supersaturation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Equilibrium solubility</dc:subject><dc:description>Drying of submicron solution aerosols, under controlled conditions, has been explored to prepare nanoparticles for drug delivery applications. A computational model of solution drop evaporation is developed to study the evolution of solute gradients inside the drop and predict the size and shell thickness of precipitating nanoparticles. The model considers evaporation as a two-stage process involving droplet shrinkage and shell growth. It was corroborated that droplet evaporation rate controls the solute distribution within a droplet and the resulting particle structure (solid or shell type). At higher gas temperatures, rapid build-up of solute near drop surface from high evaporation rates results in early attainment of critical supersaturation solubility and a steeper solute gradient, which favours formation of larger, shell-type particles. At lower gas temperatures, formation of smaller, solid nanoparticles is indicated. The computed size and shell thickness are in good agreement with experimentally prepared lipid nanoparticles. This study indicates that solid or shell structure of precipitated nanoparticles is strongly affected by evaporation rate, while initial solute concentration in the precursor solution and atomized droplet size affect shell thickness. For the gas temperatures considered, evaporative cooling leads to droplet temperature below the melting point of the lipid solute. Thus, we conclude that control over nanoparticle size and structure, of thermolabile precursor materials suitable for drug delivery, can be achieved by controlling evaporation rates, through selection of aerosol processing conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:14:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:14:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOPARTICLE RESEARCH, 17(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1388-0764</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1572-896X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11051-014-2842-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17470</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>