<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16766</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:34:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spatial variation of probabilistic seismic hazard for Mumbai and surrounding region</dc:title><dc:creator>DESAI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Mumbai region</dc:subject><dc:subject>Probabilistic seismic hazard analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Peak ground acceleration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spectral acceleration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Uniform hazard response spectrum</dc:subject><dc:subject>Deaggregation</dc:subject><dc:subject>PENINSULAR INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRAL ACCELERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EARTHQUAKE MAGNITUDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOUTH-INDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARAMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BANGALORE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAXIMUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>LENGTH</dc:subject><dc:description>Mumbai city, the economical capital of India, is located on the west coast of stable intra-plate continental region of Peninsular India which has an experience of significant historical earthquakes in the past. The city stood as the fourth most populous city in the world. Recent seismo-tectonic studies of this city highlighted the presence of active West coast fault and Chiplun fault beneath the Deccan basalt. In the present study, spatial variability of probabilistic seismic hazard for Mumbai region (latitudes of 18.85-19.35A degrees N and longitudes of 72.80-73.15A degrees E at a grid spacing of 0.05A degrees) which includes Mumbai city, Suburban, part of Thane district and Navi Mumbai, in terms of ground motion parameters; peak horizontal acceleration and spectral acceleration at 1.0-s period for 2 and 10 % probability of exceedance in 50 years are generated. The epistemic uncertainty in hazard estimation is accounted by employing seven different ground motion prediction equations developed for worldwide shallow crustal intra-plate environments. Further, the seismic hazard results are deaggregated for Mumbai (latitude 18.94A degrees N, longitude 72.84A degrees E) to understand the relative contributions of earthquake sources in terms of magnitude and distance. The generated hazard maps are compared with the zoning specified by Indian seismic code (IS1893: Part 1 in Indian standard criteria for earthquake-resistant design of structures, Part 1-General provisions and buildings. Bureau of Indian Standards, New Delhi, India, 2002) for rocky site. Present results show an underestimation of potential seismic hazard in the entire study region by non-probabilistic zoning prescribed by IS1893: Part 1 with significantly higher seismic hazard values in the southern part of Navi Mumbai.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:34:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:34:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURAL HAZARDS, 71(3)1873-1898</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-030X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-0840</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-013-0984-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16766</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>