<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17315</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:31:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Addressing Mechanism of Fibrillization/Aggregation and Its Prevention in Presence of Osmolytes: Spectroscopic and Calorimetric Approach</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHARY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>THIOFLAVIN T-BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN AGGREGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMYLOID FIBRILS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-SYNUCLEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRION PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LYSOZYME</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIBRILLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INHIBITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Understanding the mechanism of protein fibrillization/aggregation and its prevention is the basis of development of therapeutic strategies for amyloidosis. An attempt has been made to understand the nature of interactions of osmolytes L-proline, 4-hydroxy-L-proline, sarcosine and trimethylamine N-oxide with the different stages of fibrillization of hen egg-white lysozyme by using a combination of isothermal titration calorimetry, differential scanning calorimetry, fluorescence spectroscopy, and transmission electron microscopy. Based on thioflavin T fluorescence emission intensities and microscopic images, the nucleation, elongation, and saturation phases of fibrillization have been identified. Isothermal titration calorimetry and differential scanning calorimetry have enabled a quantitative analysis of the nature of interactions of these osmolytes with various conformational states of lysozyme at different stages of fibrillization/aggregation. It is concluded that interaction of the osmolytes with lysozyme fibrils at both the nucleation and elongation stages are important steps in the prevention of fibrillization/aggregation. Identification of the nature of interactions is a key step towards the discovery and synthesis of target oriented potential inhibitors of these associations. This study is a first report in which calorimetry has been used to address interaction of potential inihibitiors with the protein at different stages of fibrillization.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PUBLIC LIBRARY SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:31:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:31:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PLOS ONE, 9(8)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1932-6203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0104600</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17315</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>