<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12186</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Transport of pollutant in open channel with short waves</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RASTOGI, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>LI, CW</dc:creator><dc:description>This study examines the effect of short period water waves on the longitudinal mixing of pollutants in open channel flow. These waves create orbital motions and therefore increase the magnitude of the dispersion coefficient. Experiments are conducted for non-wavy and wavy flow. The values of the longitudinal dispersion coefficients are determined by applying the method of least squares to the measured solute concentrations at various time intervals. For non-wavy flow, the measured values of longitudinal dispersion coefficient match closely with those computed from the empirical equation given by Seo [1]. For wavy flow, a new factor called the wave parameter (a/TU*, a = wave amplitude, T = wave period, U* = shear velocity) is found important and a nonlinear multiple regression analysis is used to derive a new expression for the wave induced longitudinal dispersion coefficient (WILDC). An uncertainty analysis is conducted as per IS Code 5168 and the confidence interval is determined. Linear water wave theory is applied to modify the existing expression of the longitudinal dispersion coefficient of Seo [1] by including the effect of short waves. A mathematical model for WILDC is then developed. Comparative study between wavy and non-wavy flow cases has been conducted. The results clearly show an increase in the magnitude of longitudinal dispersion coefficient in the presence of waves.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T20:39:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T20:39:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL FLUID MECHANICS, 3(3), 235-248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1567-7419</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1022850502058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12186</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12186</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>