<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5448</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Preliminary results of GPS studies for the January 2001 Gujarat earthquake</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, MN</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIKHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOMAR, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PILLAI, P</dc:creator><dc:description>The Global Positioning System (GPS) provides a valuable tool to monitor crustal deformations, and thereby aids in understanding the complex earthquake mechanisms. After the tragic earthquake that struck the Gujarat region of western India on 26th January 2001, immediate GPS observations were carried out in the area by the GPS team of Indian Institute of Technology Bombay (IITB), for estimating the post-earthquake deformations. Repeat observations of the GPS network were completed in February 2002. The aim was not only to understand the post-earthquake crustal deformation pattern, but also to establish precise GPS control for monitoring crustal dynamics in this earthquake-affected region in the future. The data has been processed and analyzed using scientific GPS data processing software: Bernese and GAMIT. The preliminary results from the analysis of the data from these two epochs, and future plan of work, are presented here. An extensive GPS network is being established in India under the 'National GPS for Geodynamics Programme' by Government of India. A brief overview of this programme is also provided.</dc:description><dc:publisher>COMMONWEALTH ASSOC SURVEYING LAND ECONOMY, C A S L E</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-20T10:55:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-20T10:55:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SURVEY REVIEW, 37(292), 490-497</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0039-6265</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5448</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5448</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>