<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16933</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T16:52:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural and electrical properties of sodium bismuth titanate (Na0.5Bi0.5TiO3) thin films optimized using the Taguchi approach</dc:title><dc:creator>DARYAPURKAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOLTE, JT</dc:creator><dc:creator>APTE, PR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dielectric properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ferroelectric properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pulsed Laser Deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Taguchi method</dc:subject><dc:subject>PULSED-LASER DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:description>Controllable Pulsed Laser Deposition (PLD) parameters have been optimized to grow sodium bismuth titanate (Na0.5Bi0.5TiO3) (NBT) thin films. Target to substrate distance, background gas pressure, substrate temperature, laser fluence, laser rate of repetition, annealing time and NBT targets with and without excess Bi have been chosen as the parameters using a Taguchi L-18 orthogonal array. Taguchi's Signal-to-Noise (S/N) ratios and analysis of variance (ANOVA) tools highlight the relevance of each parameter, and also yield the optimal setting of the parameters. The dominant parameters affecting dielectric properties are oxygen gas pressure and substrate temperature, whereas the distance between target to substrate and laser fluence appear as significant parameters. Fine tuning experiments and a subsequent verification experiment using the dominant and significant parameters result in the best values for the dielectric constant of 735, dielectric loss of 0.07 at 1 kHz and remnant polarization of 21.42 mu C/cm(2). (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd and Techna Group S.r.l. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:52:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T16:52:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CERAMICS INTERNATIONAL, 40(1)2441-2450</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0272-8842</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-3956</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2013.08.019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16933</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>