<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18001</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:03:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of hybrid nano-filler on the crystallization behaviour and interfacial interaction in polyamide 6 based hybrid nano-composites</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEKANTH, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANWAR, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTSCHKE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>MULTIWALL CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACRYLONITRILE-BUTADIENE-STYRENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO-CONTINUOUS BLENDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAMAN-SPECTROSCOPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISPERSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Expanded graphite (EG) and multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) based hybrid nano-composites were prepared with polyamide 6 (PA6) matrix via melt-mixing technique using a conical twin-screw micro-compounder. A novel organic modifier (lithium salt of 6-aminohexanoic acid; Li-AHA) was employed to modify MWNTs, which was utilized to intercalate Li-AHA modified MWNTs into the partially exfoliated EG gallery. Morphological investigation showed the intercalation of Li-AHA modified MWNTs into a partially exfoliated EG gallery in an EG/MWNTs-m2h hybrid, whereas the unmodified EG/MWNTs-h hybrid mixture exhibited a separate identity in the mixture. Improved interaction via melt-interfacial reaction between the acid end group of PA6 and the amine functionality of Li-AHA in the EG/MWNTs-m2h hybrid filler was confirmed by Fourier transform infrared spectroscopic analysis. The extent of melt-interfacial reaction was increased as a function of Li-AHA concentration in the filler. Wide angle X-ray diffraction analysis showed the existence of the alpha-crystalline phase of PA6. The incorporation of MWNTs, EG and EG/MWNTs hybrid in the PA6 matrix has favoured an alpha-crystalline structure of the PA6 phase. Crystallization studies have indicated a significant increase in the bulk crystallization temperature of the PA6 phase in the presence of MWNTs, EG and the EG/MWNTs hybrid filler. Moreover, the formation of PA6 'trans-crystalline lamellae' on the MWNTs surface was facilitated in the case of composites with MWNTs and the EG/MWNTs hybrid filler. An attempt has been made to investigate the role of the EG/MWNTs hybrid filler in influencing the crystallization behaviour of the PA6 phase in the hybrid nano-composites.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:03:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:03:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 17(14)9410-9419</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1463-9084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5cp00018a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18001</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>