<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1073</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spectroscopic properties of meso-thienylporphyrins with different porphyrin cores</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, ITI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>heteroporphyrins</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectroscopic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>meso-thienylporphyrins</dc:subject><dc:description>The absorption and fluorescence properties of a series of meso-thienylporphyrins with different porphyrin cores (N4, N3O, N3S and N2S2 cores) were studied and compared with the corresponding meso-tetraarylporphyrins. The replacement of six-membered phenyl groups with five-membered thienyl groups at meso-positions resulted in red shifts and broadening of absorption and emission bands, low quantum yields and decreased S1 state lifetimes and the maximum effects were observed for meso-tetrathienylporphyrin with N2S2 porphyrin core. Similar observations were noted for the dications of meso-thienylporphyrins compared to the dications of the corresponding meso-tetraarylporphyrins. These results suggest that the replacement of six-membered aryl group with five-membered thienyl groups at meso-positions, the electronic properties of the porphyrin were altered significantly.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-23T05:13:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:12:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-23T05:13:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:12:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology A: Chemistry 177(2-3), 156-163</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1010-6030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2005.05.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1073</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1073</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>