<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2713</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Centrifuge modeling of heat and mass transfer through soils</dc:title><dc:creator>KRISHNAIAH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:description>Migration of heat and mass transfer through geomaterials is of great interest in various civil and electrical engineering projects'. Efforts have been made by the researchers to model heat and mass transfer through geomaterials, particularly through soils, with the help of analytical, numerical models and by conducting conventional laboratory or field experiments. Though laboratory tests are inexpensive, quick and easy to perforin, they lack simulation of the prototype conditions in terms of in-situ stresses. To overcome this, field tests, which are relatively costly, time consuming and difficult to perform, are found to be of immense help. However, these tests also offer either little or no direct control over the boundary conditions. To overcome these difficulties researchers have demonstrated potential of centrifuge modeling in studying heat migration through geomaterials. In this paper, details of the studies related to heat and mass transfer through a partially saturated soil mass, in a geotechnical centrifuge, are presented. A thermal gradient in the radial direction has been imposed on the sample with the help of a line heat source. To simulate heat transfer through the soil mass, its temperature has been determined as a function of time. The study highlights the utility of a geotechnical centrifuge in modeling heat and mass transfer through the soil mass.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T21:21:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T21:21:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE TWELFTH ASIAN REGIONAL CONFERENCE ON SOIL MECHANICS AND GEOTECHNICAL ENGINEERING, VOL 1 AND 2,393-396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>981-238-559-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16132</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2713</dc:identifier><dc:source>12th Asian Regional Conference on Soil Mechanics and Geotechnical Engineering (12ARC),Singapore, SINGAPORE,AUG 04-08, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>