<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8602</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>BOUND-STATE SOLUTIONS OF THE 2-ELECTRON DIRAC-COULOMB EQUATION</dc:title><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>perturbation-theory calculations</dc:subject><dc:subject>relativistic pair equation</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimized mean fields</dc:subject><dc:subject>many-electron atoms</dc:subject><dc:subject>isoelectronic sequence</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy-levels</dc:subject><dc:subject>dirac-coulomb</dc:subject><dc:subject>bound state</dc:subject><dc:subject>minimax technique</dc:subject><dc:subject>virtual pairs</dc:subject><dc:description>We present a variational method for solving the two-electron Dirac-Coulomb equation. When the expectation value of the Dirac-Coulomb Hamiltonian is made stationary for all possible variations of the different components of a well-behaved trial function one obtains solutions representative of the physical bound state wave functions. The ground state wave function is derived from the application of a minimax principle. Since the trial function remains well-behaved, the method remains safe from the twin demons of variational collapse and continuum dissolution. The ground state wave function thus derived can be interpreted as a linear combination of different configurations. In particular, the admixing of intermediate states having one (two) electron(s) deexcited to a negative-energy orbital (orbitals) contributes a second-order level shift E0-(2) which can be identified with the second-order shift due to the Pauli blocking of the production of one (or two) virtual electron-positron pair(s). Thus the minimax solution corresponds to the renormalized ground state in quantum electrodynamics, with deexcitations to negative-energy orbitals taking the place of the avoidance of virtual pairs. If one extends the relativistic configuration interaction (RCI) treatment by additionally including negative-energy and mixed-energy eigenvectors of the Dirac-Hartree-Fock hamiltonian matrix in the two-electron basis, the calculated energy will be shifted from the conventional RCI value by an amount that is much smaller than E0-(2). For two-electron atoms, we have derived expressions for the all-spinor limit (delta-E) and the s-spinor limit (delta-E(s)) of this shift in leading orders. The all-spinor limit (delta-E) is of order alpha-4Z4 1/3 whereas the s-spinor limit (delta-E(s)) is of order alpha-4Z3 2/3. These leading components are related to the 1-pair component of E0-(2) in a simple way, and the relationships offer the possibility of computing energy due to virtual pairs. Numerical results are discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T01:01:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T01:01:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS, 38(1), 51-75</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-4289</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02847904</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8602</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>