<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11999</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>The trade-off between intracell and intercell moves in group technology cell formation</dc:title><dc:creator>ADIL, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJAMANI, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>similarity coefficient</dc:subject><dc:subject>manufacturing systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>group technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>cellular manufacturing</dc:subject><dc:subject>cell formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>intracell moves</dc:subject><dc:subject>intercell moves</dc:subject><dc:description>In cellular manufacturing, machines are organized into compact and independent product-based group technology (GT) cells. Production in smaller GT cells not only reduces travel distances but also facilitates better material and production control. Cell compactness and cell independence are two basic requirements of efficient GT cells. Most cell formation procedures consider maximizing cell independence as the objective. In doing so, these procedures impose an upper limit on cell size as a threshold value for cell compactness. This paper views cell compactness and cell independence in terms of intercell and intracell move costs. The trade-off between intracell and intercell move costs is explained in detail. A nonlinear mathematical model and simulated annealing algorithm are developed that minimize the total intracell and intercell move costs. In the calculation of move costs, production quantity, effect of cell size on intracell move, effect of sequence of operations, and multiple nonconsecutive visits to the same machine are considered. The results are compared with published results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC MANUFACTURING ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:38:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:38:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MANUFACTURING SYSTEMS, 19(5), 305-317</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0278-6125</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11999</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11999</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>