<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3681</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Combined Spectroscopic and ab Initio Investigation of Phenylacetylene-Methylamine Complex. Observation of sigma and pi Type Hydrogen-Bonded Configurations and Fluorescence Quenching by Weak C-H center dot center dot center dot N Hydrogen Bonding</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARTHIKEYAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, KS</dc:creator><dc:subject>ultraviolet double-resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>stretching vibrations</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzene dimer</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>energies</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>origin</dc:subject><dc:subject>amines</dc:subject><dc:description>Two distinct isomers for the binary complex between phenylacetylene and methylamine were observed. The first complex is characterized by the presence of a C-H center dot center dot center dot N hydrogen bond between the acetylenic C-H group and the N atom of methylamine. In the second complex the N-H group of methylamine interacts with the pi electron density of the benzene ring accompanied by a peripheral interaction between the methyl C-H group and the pi electron density of the C C bond. Stabilization energies and Gibbs free energies at the complete basis set (CBS) limit of the coupled cluster theory with single, double, and perturbative triple excitations [CCSD(T)] suggest that while the C-H center dot center dot center dot N hydrogen bonded complex is the global minimum, the N-H center dot center dot center dot pi hydrogen bonded complex is a high energy local minimum. The formation of the N-H center dot center dot center dot pi complex could be related to kinetic trapping or higher accessibility. Comparison of the laser induced fluorescence (LIF) excitation and the one-color-resonant two-photon ionization (1C-R2PI) spectra suggests that formation of C-H center dot center dot center dot N hydrogen bonding leads to fluorescence quenching in phenylacetylene, most probably due to dipolar coupling in the excited state. The binary complex between the phenylacetylene and methylamine shows interesting isomer-dependent fluorescent properties.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T13:18:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T13:18:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 114(42), 11347-11352</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp105439y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3681</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3681</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>