<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14583</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:36:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>One-Cycle-Controlled Single-Stage Single-Phase Voltage-Sensorless Grid-Connected PV System</dc:title><dc:creator>SREERAJ, ES</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Maximum-power-point tracking (MPPT)</dc:subject><dc:subject>one-cycle control (OCC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>photovoltaic (PV) inverter</dc:subject><dc:subject>single-phase grid-connected inverter</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER POINT TRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOVOLTAIC INVERTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PWM CONVERTER</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOPOLOGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECTIFIER</dc:subject><dc:description>Reforms in the electricity sector along with various renewable-energy-promotion policies have increased the importance of small grid-connected photovoltaic (PV) systems utilizing single-stage single-phase inverters. Ruggedness, reliability, and cost effectiveness are the desirable characteristics of such inverters used in distributed low-power applications. Schemes based on one-cycle control (OCC) which do not require the service of a phase-locked loop for interfacing the inverter to the grid are increasingly being employed for such applications. However, the OCC-based schemes reported earlier require sensing of the grid voltage which somewhat offsets one of the inherent strengths of OCC-based systems. In an effort to overcome the aforementioned limitation, an OCC-based grid-connected single-stage PV system is proposed in this paper which does not require to sense the grid voltage. Further, it requires less number of sensors (two) as compared to that required (four) in the earlier reported scheme for the implementation of the core controller comprising of OCC and maximum-power-point-tracking blocks. The viability of the proposed scheme is confirmed by performing simulation and experimental validation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INDUSTRIAL ELECTRONICS, 60(3)1216-1224</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIE.2012.2191755</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14583</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>