<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1256</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of nitrogen addition on the stress corrosion cracking behavior of 904 L stainless steel welds in 288 °C deaerated water</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGE, DEEPASHRI D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>tensile strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>stainless steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>tensile testing</dc:subject><dc:subject>high pressure effects</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper concerns with the effect of nitrogen addition to 904 L stainless steel (SS) welds on their stress corrosion cracking (SCC) behavior in high temperature (288 °C) and high pressure (1050 psi) water of high oxygen content (100 ppb) and high conductivity (2.5 μS/cm). For this study, 316 L SS base plate TIG welded with 904 L SS filler wire and with nitrogen contents of 0.027, 0.058 and 0.095 wt.% were used. Flat pin-loaded tensile specimens were fabricated from transverse welds, with the weld in the gauge length. Slow strain rate tests (SSRT) were carried out at a strain rate of 2.2 × 10−6 s−1. The study shows that the samples, when tested in air, failed at the weld fusion zone for 0.027 and 0.058 wt.% N and at the base metal for 0.095 wt.% N. In the environment, the samples failed in the base metal except the one with least nitrogen content (0.027 wt.%). With nitrogen addition, as the failure location shifted to the base alloy, the weld seemed to acquire SCC resistance and became even more resistant than the base alloy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-28T05:24:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:38:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-28T05:24:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:38:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Corrosion Science 48(8), 2317-2331</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0010-938X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.corsci.2005.08.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1256</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>