<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13847</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-08T18:47:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Supramolecular Tetrads Containing Sn(IV) Porphyrin, Ru(II) Porphyrin, and Expanded Porphyrins Assembled Using Complementary Metal-Ligand Interactions</dc:title><dc:creator>SHETTI, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL-CHARACTERIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENHANCED TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANION-BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>COORDINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAPPHYRIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLIGOMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARRAYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RUTHENIUM(II)</dc:subject><dc:description>Two examples of supramolecular tetrads containing Sn(IV) porphyrin, expanded thiaporphyrins such as sapphyrin and rubyrin, and Ru(II) porphyrin assembled using non-interfering cooperative tin(IV)-oxygen and ruthenium(II)-nitrogen coordination properties are described. These are the first examples in which the expanded porphyrins are used as axial ligands. The tetrads were prepared by adopting one step as well as stepwise approaches. In a one pot approach, the mono meso-pyridyl dihydroxy Sn(IV) porphyrin, meso-hydroxyphenyl expanded thiaporphyrin, and Ru(II) porphyrin were reacted in benzene under refluxing conditions followed by column chromatographic purification on alumina to afford tetrads. In a stepwise approach, the axial bonding type of triads containing Sn(IV)porphyrin as central unit and expanded thiaporphyrins as axial ligands were synthesized first by reacting meso-pyridyl dihydroxy Sn(IV) porphyrin with meso-hydroxyphenyl expanded thiaporphyrin in benzene at refluxing temperature. In the next step, the triads were reacted with Ru(II) porphyrin under mild reaction conditions to afford tetrads in decent yields. Both methods worked efficiently and produced stable, soluble tetrads in decent yields. One-dimensional (1D) and two-dimensional (2D) NMR techniques were used to confirm the identity of these novel tetrads. Absorption and electrochemical studies indicated that the components in tetrads interact weakly and retain their individual characteristic features. The steady state photophysical studies revealed that the quantum yield of Sn(IV) porphyrin in tetrads was reduced significantly because of non-radiative decay pathways operating in these systems.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-02-08T18:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-02-08T18:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY,50(5)1713-1722</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic102168f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13847</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>