<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10090</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development and study of nickel aluminide coatings on titanium</dc:title><dc:creator>JEEVANANDAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATGADDE, LG</dc:creator><dc:description>Nickel aluminide as well as boron containing nickel aluminide coatings were deposited on pure titanium through electroless deposition of pure Ni and Ni-B followed by physical vapour deposition of aluminium and a subsequent heat treatment at 600 degrees C for 5 hr. and 10 hr. The coating thicknesses were studied as a function of concentration elf reducing agents, viz. hydrazine and potassium borohydride, bath pH and plating time. Variation of boron content with pH was also studied, The coating composition wets analysed by ICP-AES technique. X-ray diffraction data confirm the formation of aluminides viz.. AlNi3, AlNi2Ti and AlNi. Phase changes with respect to time of heat treatment were also studied. Aluminide coatings were further characterised by electrochemical measurements. In case of nickel aluminide coatings, polarisation resistance(Rp) increases with time of heat treatment, while for Ni-B-aluminide it decreases with time of heat treatment, AC impendence studies also support these findings. The decrease in Rp and increase in I-corr for Ni-B aluminide coating with increase in time of heat treatment might be due to diffusion of B out of Al coating and the increase information of Ni3B as evidenced by increase in height of XRD pattern.</dc:description><dc:publisher>METAL FINISHERS ASSOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T17:46:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T17:46:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE METAL FINISHERS ASSOCIATION OF INDIA, 6(3), 181-186</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-5304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10090</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>