<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1698</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Interfacial polycondensation—modeling of kinetics and film properties</dc:title><dc:creator>DHUMAL, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>WAGH, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>abs resins</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexation</dc:subject><dc:subject>composite membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>encapsulation</dc:subject><dc:description>Interfacial polycondensation (IP) is an important technique used in the encapsulation of a variety of active ingredients and synthesis of thin film composite membranes. The present work seeks to advance our understanding of the mechanisms underlying the reaction, phase separation and film formation in this process, and hence, of how the film properties are influenced by preparation conditions. The model presented here incorporates all the essential physicochemical processes at a fundamental level through simple phenomenologies: ionic equilibria in the aqueous phase, resistances due to external mass transfer, diffusion through polymer film, interfacial reaction, thermodynamics of phase separation, and formation of a coherent film. The model has been tested against the data previously communicated [S.J. Wagh, Studies in interfacial polycondensation. Ph.D. Thesis. IIT Bombay, 2004; S.J. Wagh, S.S. Dhumal, A.K. Suresh, An experimental study of polyurea membrane formation by interfacial polycondensation, Journal of Membrane Science, submitted for publication] on polyurea microcapsules. The influence of the model parameters and preparation conditions, on the properties of the polymer and film and their development during reaction, have been studied. The study provides important insights into the process and should help in designing synthesis methodologies to suit the application.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-10-06T04:11:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:44:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-10-06T04:11:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:44:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Membrane Science 325(2), 758-771</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0376-7388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.memsci.2008.09.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1698</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1698</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>