<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2460</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Adding underlay aware fault tolerance to hierarchical event broker networks</dc:title><dc:creator>MADHU KUMAR, SD</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLUR, U</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIRAN, EK</dc:creator><dc:subject>overlay</dc:subject><dc:subject>underlay awareness</dc:subject><dc:subject>event broker networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>fault tolerance</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent studies have shown that the quality of service of overlay topologies and routing algorithms for event broker networks can be improved by the use of underlying network information. Hierarchical topologies are widely used in recent event-based publish-subscribe systems for reduced message traffic. We hypothesize that the performance and fault tolerance of existing hierarchical topology based event broker networks can be improved by augmenting the construction of the overlay and subsequent routing with the underlay information. In this paper we present a linear time algorithm for constructing a fault tolerant overlay topology for event broker networks that can tolerate single node and link failures and improve the routing performance by balancing network load. We test the algorithm on the SIENA event based middleware which follows the hierarchical model for event brokers. We present simulation results that support the claim that the use of underlay information can significantly increase the robustness of the overlay topology and performance of the routing algorithm for hierarchical event broker networks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INSTICC-INST SYST TECHNOLOGIES INFORMATION CONTROL &amp; COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T07:26:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T07:26:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ICSOFT 2007: PROCEEDINGS OF THE SECOND INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON SOFTWARE AND DATA TECHNOLOGIES, VOL PL/DPS/KE/MUSE,99-105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-989-8111-05-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2460</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Conference on Software and Data Technologies,Barcelona, SPAIN,JUL 22-25, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>