<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1757</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Superconductivity and magnetism in quaternary-F (F-Y or F-elements) transition-metal borocarbides and magnetic-properties of RNI(4)B (R-Y or RARE-EARTH)</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGARAJAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAZUMDAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSAIN, Z</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, SH</dc:creator><dc:creator>GODART, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PADALIA, BD</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYARAGHAVAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>superconductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition metal borocarbides</dc:subject><dc:description>Our recent pioneering discovery of bulk superconductivity (SC) in Y-Ni-B-C at an elevated temperature (T-c approximate to 12 K) has triggered intense research activity in borocarbide materials containing 4f and 5f elements. This was an offshoot of our studies of RNi(4)B (R=Y or rare earth) series of materials. Replacing Ni by Pd produces a superconducting phase in Y-Pd-B-C with record T-c (approximate to 23 K) in bulk intermetallics. Here we present the results of some of our investigations in borocarbide materials. Our specific heat studies suggest that YNi2B2C is a strong-coupling type II superconductor. The temperature dependence of H-c2(T) is rather unusual. mu-SR measurements indicate the possibility that Ni atoms carry a magnetic moment. SC and magnetism coexist in RNi(2)B(2)C (R=Ho, Er or Tm). CeNi2B2C is found to be a mixed-valence material. NdNi2B2C and GdNi2B2C, which we have been able to synthesize as a single phase, do not superconduct but order magnetically at T-m approximate to 4.5 K and T-m approximate to 19 K respectively. We have observed SC in Th-Ni-B-C and Th-Pd-B-C systems. There are at least two superconducting transitions in the Pd-containing systems Th-Pd-B-C and Y-Pd-B-C. YT2B2C (T=Co, Ir, Rh or Os) crystallize in a YNi2B2C-type structure but do not superconduct down to 4.2 K. Substitution studies show that Th (non-magnetic) and Gd (magnetic) suppress T-c by nearly the same extent. We also summarize our results on RNi(4)B series of materials which show remarkable physical properties.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T00:07:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T00:07:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ALLOYS AND COMPOUNDS,225,571-577</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-8388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0925-8388(94)07108-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1757</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Conference on f-Elements (ICFE-2),HELSINKI, FINLAND,AUG 01-06, 1994</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>