<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2021</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Three-dimensional guided waves in laminated composite plates excited from point source</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAYAK, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, AH</dc:creator><dc:subject>elastic-waves</dc:subject><dc:subject>propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>point source</dc:subject><dc:subject>3d green's function</dc:subject><dc:subject>wave attenuation</dc:subject><dc:subject>guided waves</dc:subject><dc:subject>modal summation technique</dc:subject><dc:description>Three dimensional wave propagation characteristics in laminated plates are studied considering this anisotropic and viscoelastic properties of fiber reinforced composite material. A Rayleigh-Ritz based stiffness method is used to discretize the plate in the vertical direction to determine propagation characteristics (wave number, phase velocity, group velocity) and mode shapes for a plane wave front. For 3-dimesional cases, wave propagation problem is decomposed into a series of two-dimensional plane wave problems with three displacements coupled. Double Fourier transform integral transformations are used to get the governing equation in a transformed wave number domain. Steady state elastodynamic Green's functions for the laminated composite plates are constructed through summing the contribution of all two-dimensional problems and the application of modal summation technique. Numerical integration of double infinite integrals is performed by summations over a finite range. The wave propagation characteristics for a 16-layer unidirectional fibre reinforced laminated composite plate show the orthotropic nature of the plate reflected in its 3-D wave propagation characteristics. It is also seen that the Green's functions for 3D waves are very different from those for plane strain 2D waves. Furthermore, the direction of propagation has a significant effect on the Green's function for surface displacements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T01:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T01:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Health Monitoring and Smart Nondestructive Evaluation of Structural and Biological Systems IV,5768,334-343</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-5749-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.599740</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15298</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2021</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Health Monitoring and Smart Nondestructive Evaluation of Structural and Biological Systems IV,San Diego, CA,MAR 07-09, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>