<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1514</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of solvent, pH, salts and resin fatty acids on the dechlorination of pentachlorophenol using magnesium–silver and magnesium–palladium bimetallic systems</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, UPENDRA D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, SUMATHI</dc:creator><dc:subject>dechlorination</dc:subject><dc:subject>fatty acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnesium</dc:subject><dc:subject>palladium</dc:subject><dc:subject>salts</dc:subject><dc:description>The effects of pH, organic co-solvent, salts such as sodium chloride, sodium sulfate, and co-pollutants, resin and fatty acids (RFAs) on the dechlorination of pentachlorophenol (PCP) by magnesium/silver (Mg/Ag) and magnesium/palladium (Mg/Pd) systems were examined in the present investigations. Such studies provide relevant information about the applicability of bimetallic systems for remediation of raw wastewaters (such as pulp bleaching effluents) or groundwater. Removal efficiencies of 10 mg L−1 PCP by Mg/Pd and Mg/Ag systems at the end of 1 h reaction were 93% and 78%, respectively, in the presence of acetone (1% v/v). On the other hand, the removal efficiencies were 86% and 70% for reactions conducted in alcoholic solvents (1% v/v) using Mg/Pd and Mg/Ag systems, respectively. The efficiencies of PCP removal by the two bimetallic systems could be correlated to the dipole moments of co-solvents used. The second order reaction rate constant for PCP removal by Mg/Ag system was highest (0.03 L mg−1 min−1) in the absence of any pH-control mechanism. Optimum pH for the dechlorination of PCP by Mg/Pd system was found to be ~5.5 and &gt;92% of the compound was removed within 15 min of reaction. Presence of chlorinated and non-chlorinated resin fatty acids (RFAs) resulted in substantial reduction in the rate and extent of PCP removal by Mg/Ag system whereas dechlorination by Mg/Pd remained unaffected. Presence of sodium sulfate or sodium chloride in the reaction phase reduced the rate and extent of PCP removal by Mg/Ag system. PCP dechlorination by Mg/Pd system was adversely impacted by the addition of sodium chloride and unaffected by the presence of sodium sulfate.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-17T04:07:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:17:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-17T04:07:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:17:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Hazardous Materials 156(1-3), 308-316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.jhazmat.2007.12.021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1514</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1514</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>