<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18351</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T10:30:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stress Analysis of Laminated Composite and Sandwich Beams using a Novel Shear and Normal Deformation Theory</dc:title><dc:creator>PAWAR, EG</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>TRANSVERSE-SHEAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>REFINED THEORIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FINITE-ELEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shear deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>transverse flexibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminated thick beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>transverse shear stress</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel Normal and Shear Deformation Theory (NSDT) for analysis of laminated composite and sandwich beams, taking into account shear deformation as well as normal deformation, is developed. The paper investigates flexural behaviors of thick laminated and sandwich beams under plane stress conditions using NSDT. A generalized displacement-based refined formulation is elucidated with inclusion of various warping functions in terms of thickness coordinates to represent shear and normal deformation effects. These effects become pronounced in thick laminated beams and particularly in sandwich beams with transversely flexible core. Present formulation satisfies the shear stress free surface conditions at the top and bottom surfaces of the beam with realistic through-the-thickness variation of transverse shear stresses. The results obtained are compared with higher order theories available in literature. It is observed that NSDT predicts displacement and stresses accurately compared to other higher order theories.</dc:description><dc:publisher>LATIN AMER J SOLIDS STRUCTURES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:30:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T10:30:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LATIN AMERICAN JOURNAL OF SOLIDS AND STRUCTURES, 12(7)1340-1361</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1679-7825</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1590/1679-78251470</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18351</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>