<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6472</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Curcuminoids-loaded lipid nanoparticles: Novel approach towards malaria treatment</dc:title><dc:creator>NAYAK, AP</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIYABOONCHAI, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATANKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADHUSUDHAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOUTO, EB</dc:creator><dc:subject>curcuma-longa l.</dc:subject><dc:subject>in-vivo</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasmodium-falciparum</dc:subject><dc:subject>encapsulated curcumin</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug-delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>fatty-acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>therapy</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>vitro</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanostructured lipid carriers</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid lipid nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>antimalarial agent</dc:subject><dc:subject>curcuminoids</dc:subject><dc:subject>parenteral delivery</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present work, curcuminoids-loaded lipid nanoparticles for parenteral administration were successfully prepared by a nanoemulsion technique employing high-speed homogenizer and ultrasonic probe. For the production of nanoparticles, trimyristin, tristerin and glyceryl monostearate were selected as solid lipids and medium chain triglyceride (MCT) as liquid lipid. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) revealed the spherical nature of the particles with sizes ranging between 120 and 250 nm measured by photon correlation spectroscopy (PCS). The zeta potential of the particles ranged between -28 and -45 mV depending on the nature of the lipid matrix produced, which also influenced the entrapment efficiency (EE) and drug loading capacity (LC) found to be in the range of 80-94% and 1.62-3.27%, respectively. The LC increased reciprocally on increasing the amount of MCT as confirmed by differential scanning calorimetry (DSC). DSC analyses revealed that increasing imperfections within the lipid matrix allowed for increasing encapsulation parameters. Nanoparticles were further sterilized by filtration process which was found to be superior over autoclaving in preventing thermal degradation of thermo-sensitive curcuminoids. The in vivo pharmacodynamic activity revealed 2-fold increase in antimalarial activity of curcuminoids entrapped in lipid nanoparticles when compared to free curcuminoids at the tested dosage level. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T16:06:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T16:06:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES, 81(1), 263-273</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-7765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfb.2010.07.020</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6472</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6472</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>