<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17022</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:44:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling matrix damage and fibre-matrix interfacial decohesion in composite laminates via a multi-fibre multi-layer representative volume element ((MRVE)-R-2)</dc:title><dc:creator>SONI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>FALZON, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Matrix damage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fibre-matrix debonding initiation and propagation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multi-scale modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Multi-fibre multi-layer representative volume element</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERIODIC BOUNDARY-CONDITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNIT-CELL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSVERSE COMPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEAR</dc:subject><dc:description>A three-dimensional multi-fibre multi-layer micromechanical finite element model was developed for the prediction of mechanical behaviour and damage response of composite laminates. Material response and micro-scale damage mechanism of cross-ply, (0/90](ns), and angle-ply, [+/- 45](ns), glass-fibre/epoxy laminates were captured using multi-scale modelling via computational micromechanics. The framework of the homogenization theory for periodic media was used for the analysis of the proposed 'multi-fibre multi-layer representative volume element' ((MRVE)-R-2). Each layer in (MRVE)-R-2 was represented by a unit cube with multiple randomly distributed, but longitudinally aligned, fibres of equal diameter and with a volume fraction corresponding to that of each lamina (equal in the present case). Periodic boundary conditions were applied to all the faces of the (MRVE)-R-2. The non-homogeneous stress-strain fields within the (MRVE)-R-2 were related to the average stresses and strains by using Gauss' theorem in conjunction with the Hill-Mandal strain energy equivalence principle. The global material response predicted by the (MRVE)-R-2 was found to be in good agreement with experimental results for both laminates. The model was used to study effect of matrix friction angle and cohesive strength of the fibre-matrix interface on the global material response. In addition, the (MRVE)-R-2 was also used to predict initiation and propagation of fibre-matrix interfacial decohesion and propagation at every point in the laminae. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:44:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:44:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF SOLIDS AND STRUCTURES, 51(2)449-461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-7683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-2146</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsolstr.2013.10.018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17022</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>