<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7944</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Heat transfer during film condensation of R-123 vapour on horizontal integral-fin tubes</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEPATHI, LK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAPAT, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUKHATME, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>condensation</dc:subject><dc:subject>integral-fin tubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>ozone-safe refrigerants</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper deals with an experimental study of heat transfer during condensation of R-123 vapour on horizontal integral-fin (HIF) tubes. R-123 is a substitute for R-11, which is required to be phased out The effect of a number of important geometrical parameters like the fin spacing, fin height, and fin shape has been investigated Data have also been obtained by condensing R-ll vapour on some of the tubes, thereby facilitating a direct comparison. For R-123 condensation, the best performance was obtained with a tube with fin base spacing, fin height and fin tip thickness of 0.33, 1.29 and 0.14mm respectively. This tube yielded an enhancement ratio of around 9 at Delta T of 4K. Further, the results indicate that the performance of the tubes yielding high heat flux values is sensitive to the shape of the fin profile, particularly at small fin dimensions. The tests conducted with R-11 yield a 10 to 15% better performance compared to R-123. This paper also deals with the development of a generalized correlation to determine the heat transfer performance of HIF tubes. The present experimental data as well as extensive data obtained by earlier investigators for other fluids were made use of in developing the correlation. The correlation predicts the heat transfer performance of all the fluids well and of refrigerants like R-123 and R-ll very well.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GORDON BREACH SCI PUBL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-30T11:02:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-30T11:02:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ENHANCED HEAT TRANSFER, 3(2), 147-164</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1065-5131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7944</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>