<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13798</identifier><datestamp>2012-01-18T04:50:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of citrate-stabilized Fe(3)O(4) nanoparticles: Conjugation and release of doxorubicin for therapeutic applications</dc:title><dc:creator>NIGAM, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BARICK, KC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>nanoparticle</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron oxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface functionalization</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug release</dc:subject><dc:subject>hyperthermia</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron-oxide nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetite nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorescence spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>model membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>citric-acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding</dc:subject><dc:subject>phospholipids</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>liposomes</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:description>We demonstrate a single-step facile approach for the fabrication of citric acid functionalized (citrate-stabilized) Fe(3)O(4) aqueous colloidal magnetic nanoparticles (CA-MNP) of size 8-10 nm using soft chemical route. The surface functionalization of Fe(3)O(4) nanoparticles with citric acid was evident from infrared spectroscopy, thermal and elemental analyses, and zeta-potential measurements. The drug-loading efficiency of CA-MNP was investigated using doxorubicin hydrochloride (DOX) as a model drug to evaluate their potential as a carrier system. The quenching of fluorescence intensity and decrease in surface charge of drug loaded CA-MNP strongly suggest the interaction/attachment of drug molecules with CA-MNP. More specifically, the present investigation discusses a method for entrapping positively charged drugs on to the surface of negatively charged CA-MNP through electrostatic interactionsandsuggeststhatbounddrugmoleculeswillbereleasedinappreciableamountsinthe mild acidic environments of the tumors. Furthermore, the aqueous colloidal stability, optimal magnetization, good specific absorption rate (under external AC magnetic field) and cytocompatibility with cells suggested that CA-MNP is appropriate candidate for biomedical applications. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-12-29T08:30:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-29T08:30:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS,323(2)237-243</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-8853</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmmm.2010.09.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/13798</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>