<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1777</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Specific interactions and reactive coupling induced dispersion of multiwall carbon nanotubes in co continuous polyamide6/ionomer blends</dc:title><dc:creator>BOSE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHARE, RA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTSCHKE, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>ethylene/methacrylic acid copolymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical-conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionomers</dc:subject><dc:subject>black</dc:subject><dc:subject>functionalization</dc:subject><dc:subject>percolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfactant</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>interface</dc:subject><dc:subject>blends</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionomers</dc:subject><dc:subject>mwnt</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyamide6</dc:subject><dc:description>An efficient strategy to achieve electrical conductivity in melt-mixed co-continuous blends is to restrict the conducting filler in a particular phase in the blends next to forming a percolated 'network-like' structure in that particular phase. However, strong inter-tube van der Waals' forces often lead to the aggregated structure leading to higher percolation threshold. In addition, the migration of the conducting filler during melt-mixing and the blending sequence significantly affect the bulk conductivity of the blends. SEM observation showed fine co-continuous structures associated with 50/50 blends of PA6/Surlyn with multiwall carbon nanotubes (MWNT). MWNT were localized in the vicinity of the ionic domains in the ionomer corresponding to a specific blending sequence when unmodified MWNT were used, however, in presence of Na-salt of 6-amino hexanoic acid (Na-AHA) modified MWNT, selective clustering was not observed may be due to the confinement of MWNT in the PA6 phase. To understand these complexities the electrical conductivity of melt-mixed blends of polyamide6/ionomer with MWNT was studied. However, it was observed that the blends with even 3 wt% unmodified MWNT showed insulating behaviour irrespective of the blending sequence adopted. in addition, the key role of a reactive modifier (Na-AHA) in facilitating uniform dispersion and subsequent 'network-like' formation by establishing specific interactions with MWNT was studied. it was found that the MWNT are selectively localized in the PA6 phase in the NA-AHA modified blends manifesting in higher electrical conductivity (similar to 10(-5) S/cm at 3 wt% MWNT) when using a specific blending sequence, due to melt-interfacial reaction between the similar to NH2 functionality of Na-AHA and the similar to COOH end groups of PA6. FTIR and Raman spectroscopic analysis also supported the existence of the specific interactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T01:48:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T01:48:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MACROMOLECULAR SYMPOSIA,263,11-20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1022-1360</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/masy.200850302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1777</dc:identifier><dc:source>European Polymer Conference From Polymer Structure and Rheology to Process Modeling,Gargnano, ITALY,MAY 27-JUN 01, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>