<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12006</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>JET IMPINGEMENT MIXING IN AN L-TYPE MIXHEAD - COMPARISON OF MIXING CRITERIA</dc:title><dc:creator>BASER, SA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHETTY, DG</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAKHAR, DV</dc:creator><dc:description>High velocity jet impingement mixing is a unique operation of the reaction injection molding process. The quality of mixing depends on processing parameters for a given system, and can have significant effect on the properties of the product. We have compared three methods used for characterization of mixing quality reported in the literature for a cross-linking polyurethane system processed on an industrial scale high pressure RIM machine, with an L-type mixhead. The methods are based on, (i) visual appearance of a molded sample, (ii) adiabatic temperature rise during reaction and, (iii) flexural modulus of elasticity of a molded sample. The visual appearance test was made quantitative by using a color matching optical system. The adiabatic temperature rise increases rapidly with nozzle Reynolds number (Re(nzl) for polyol, up to a critical value (Re(nzl) = 380) beyond which there is a slow increase. The latter is attributed to the geometry of the L-type mixhead. A simple analysis is presented to explain the limiting extent of mixing at high Re(nzl). The flexural modulus and the visual appearance of molded samples are found to improve until Re(nzl) = 500, implying a greater sensitivity to mixing as compared to the adiabatic temperature rise.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC PLASTICS ENG INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T07:06:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T07:06:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE, 33(24), 1611-1618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.760332405</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12006</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>