<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3548</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimum damping in a non-linear base isolation system</dc:title><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>seismic response</dc:subject><dc:description>Optimum isolation damping for minimum acceleration of a base-isolated structure subjected to earthquake ground excitation is investigated. The stochastic model of the El-Centro 1940 earthquake, which preserves the non-stationary evolution of amplitude and frequency content of ground motion, is used as an earthquake excitation. The base isolated structure consists of a linear flexible shear type multi-storey building supported on a base isolation system. The resilient-friction base isolator (R-FBI) is considered as an isolation system. The non-stationary stochastic response of the system is obtained by the time dependent equivalent linearization technique as the force-deformation behaviour of the R-FBI system is non-linear. The optimum damping of the R-FBI system is obtained under important parametric variations: i.e., the coefficient of friction of the R-FBI system, the period and damping of the superstructure; the effective period of base isolation. The criterion selected for optimality is the minimization of the top floor root mean square (r.m.s.) acceleration. It is shown that the above parameters have significant effects on optimum isolation damping. (C) 1996 Academic Press Limited</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SOUND AND VIBRATION, 189(4), 477-487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-460X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1006/jsvi.1996.0030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3548</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3548</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>