<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18216</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:56:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Sensing of Stimulus Artifact Suppressed Signals From Electrode Interfaces</dc:title><dc:creator>NAG, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIKDAR, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAKOR, NV</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-STIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMPLIFIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>REMOVAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>POTENTIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CULTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOOP</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stimulus artifact suppression</dc:subject><dc:subject>biphasic constant current stimulator</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrode-electrolyte interface</dc:subject><dc:subject>instrumentation and differential amplifier</dc:subject><dc:description>Stimulus artifacts inhibit reliable acquisition of biological evoked potentials for several milliseconds if an electrode contact is utilized for both electrical stimulation and recording purposes. This hinders the measurement of evoked short-latency biological responses, which is otherwise elicited by stimulation in implantable prosthetic devices. We present an improved stimulus artifact suppression scheme using two electrode simultaneous stimulation and differential readout using high-gain amplifiers. Substantial reduction of artifact duration has been shown possible through the common-mode rejection property of an instrumentation amplifier for electrode interfaces. The performance of this method depends on good matching of electrode-electrolyte interface properties of the chosen electrode pair. A novel calibration algorithm has been developed that helps in artificial matching of impedance and thereby achieves the required performance in artifact suppression. Stimulus artifact duration has been reduced down to 50 mu s from the stimulation-cum-recording electrodes, which is similar to 6x improvement over the present state of the art. The system is characterized with emulated resistor-capacitor loads and a variety of in-vitro metal electrodes dipped in saline environment. The proposed method is going to be useful for closed-loop electrical stimulation and recording studies, such as bidirectional neural prosthesis of retina, cochlea, brain, and spinal cord.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE SENSORS JOURNAL, 15(7)3734-3742</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1530-437X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-1748</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSEN.2015.2399248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18216</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>