<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1367</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis, self-assembly, and properties of Mn doped ZnO nanoparticles</dc:title><dc:creator>BARICK, KC</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>vapor-phase growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>ferromagnetic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>paramagnetic-resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanocrystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>superlattices</dc:subject><dc:subject>bulk</dc:subject><dc:subject>self-assembly</dc:subject><dc:subject>mn doped zno</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:description>We report here a novel process to prepare Mn doped ZnO nanoparticles by a soft chemical route at low temperature. The synthesis process is based on the hydrolysis of zinc acetate dihydrate and manganese acetate tetrahydrate heated under reflux to 160-175 degrees C using diethylene glycol as a solvent. X-ray diffraction analysis reveals that the Mn doped ZnO crystallizes in a wurtzite structure with crystal size of 15-25 nm. These nano size crystallites of Mn doped ZnO self-organize into polydisperse spheres in size ranging from 100-400 nm. Transmission Electron Microscopy image also shows that each sphere is made up of numerous nanocrystals of average diameter 15-25 nm. By means of X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and electron spin resonance spectroscopy, we determined the valence state of Mn ions as 2+. These nanoparticles were found to be ferromagnetic at room temperature. Monodisperse porous spheres (similar to 250 nm) were obtained by size selective separation technique and then self-assembled in a closed pack periodic array through sedimentation with slow solvent evaporation, which gives strong opalescence in visible region.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T00:39:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T00:39:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY,7(6)1935-1940</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1533-4880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jnn.2007.744</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1367</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Nano Science and Technology (ICONSAT 2006),New Delhi, INDIA,MAR 16-18, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>