<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10255</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Purification and characterization of a type II phosphatidylinositol 4-kinase from rat spleen and comparison with a PtdIns 4-kinase from lymphocytes</dc:title><dc:creator>VERGHESE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDIS, AZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAHMANYAM, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>t-cell activation</dc:subject><dc:subject>antigen receptor</dc:subject><dc:subject>signal-transduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>a431 cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphoinositide kinases</dc:subject><dc:subject>tyrosine phosphorylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein-kinase</dc:subject><dc:subject>membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>stimulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>turnover</dc:subject><dc:description>A PtdIns 4-kinase from rat spleen particulate fraction was purified to homogeneity and its molecular properties were compared with a PtdIns 4-kinase from splenic lymphocytes. The enzyme activity was solubilized from spleen particulate fraction with Triton X-100 and chromatographed sequentially on phosphocellulose, DEAE-sephacel, heparin acrylamide and hydroxyapatite columns. The purified enzyme preparation showed a 55 kDa band on SDS-PAGE with silver staining. Renaturation of the enzyme activity from SDS-PAGE showed that it comigrated with the 55 kDa protein. Characterization of the enzyme showed that it was a type II PtdIns 4-kinase. Polyclonal antibodies raised against PtdIns 4-kinase inhibited the enzyme activity in in vitro assays. Analysis of adult rat tissue particulate fractions on immunoblots showed restricted immunoreactivity among PtdIns 4-kinases. However, the immunoreactivity is conserved in lymphoid tissues from mouse to human, suggesting that lymphoid tissue has a distinct PtdIns 4-kinase. Activation of rat splenocytes with Con A showed two fold increase in PtdIns 4-kinase activity. Comparison of PtdIns 4-kinases from spleen and splenic lymphocytes showed identical chromatographic behaviour, molecular mass, immunoreactivity, K-m values for PtdIns and inhibition by adenosine.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T06:22:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T06:22:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF BIOCHEMISTRY &amp; BIOPHYSICS, 36(1), 1-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-1208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10255</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>