<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17458</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:08:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Impedance analysis and dielectric properties of Ce modified bismuth titanate lead free ceramics synthesized using solution combustion route</dc:title><dc:creator>SUBOHI, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, GS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MALIK, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KURCHANIA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>BI3.25LA0.75TI3O12 THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BI4TI3O12 CERAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:description>Cerium modified bismuth titanate ceramics were studied as potential lead-free ferroelectric materials over a broad temperature range. Polycrystalline samples of Bi4-xCexTi3O12 (x = 0.2, 0.4, 0.6, 0.8) (BCeT) were prepared using the solution combustion technique. The effect of Ce doping on their crystalline structure, ferroelectric properties and electrical conduction characteristics were explored. An increase in the dielectric constant and decrease in loss tangent is observed due to addition of Ce in bismuth titanate lattice up to a certain threshold doping concentration. The presence of pyrochlore phase decreases the density of ceramics with composition x = 0.8 which may be due to grain inhibitor property of Ce. The value of remnant polarization increases with increasing doping content up to x = 0.6 due to decrease in defect sites in the samples, further increase in cerium content induces leakage current which makes the sample lossy. The real-imaginary impedance plots are interpreted using RC model, this explains the contribution of the grain-bulk and the grain boundary resistivities to the total resistivity of the materials. Activation energy increases with increasing Ce concentration indicating a decrease in defect sites due to which the conductivity of the doped ceramics reduces.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:08:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:08:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE-MATERIALS IN ELECTRONICS, 26(11)9122-9133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-4522</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-482X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10854-015-3600-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17458</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>