<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2104</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Crack detection in geometrically segmented beams</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, TD</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>natural frequencies</dc:subject><dc:subject>transverse vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>cantilever beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>location</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration based detection of crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration modelling of cracked beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>edge crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>ndt of crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>segmented beam</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper a method for modelling of transverse vibration of a geometrically segmented slender beam of practical importance with and without a crack normal to its axis has been proposed using the Frobenius technique. Two beam configurations have been considered. One configuration deals with three segment beam; the two end segments are of uniform depth of different dimensions and the middle segment is of linearly variable depth. The other is a two segment beam; one segment is uniform and the other has a one edge taper. The thickness is uniform along the whole length. In the presence of a crack, the crack section is represented by a rotational spring. Thereby it is possible to solve both the forward and inverse problems, The results have been compared with the analytical solutions available in the literature wherever possible. A number of numerical examples are presented to demonstrate the accuracy of the method. In the inverse problem, for the first configuration, 3.0% error is observed in the detection of crack location and the maximum error is 20% in size prediction. In the second case the errors are around 1.5% and 21% respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TRANSTEC PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T05:20:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T05:20:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DAMAS 99: DAMAGE ASSESSMENT OF STRUCTURES,167-1,343-353</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-87849-839-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1013-9826</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15337</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2104</dc:identifier><dc:source>3rd International Conference on Damage Assessment of Structures (DAMAS 99),DUBLIN, IRELAND,JUN 28-30, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>