<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4175</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>General circulation model estimates of aerosol transport and radiative forcing during the Indian Ocean Experiment</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOUCHER, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEON, JF</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLOUIN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHAM, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>fossil-fuel combustion</dc:subject><dc:subject>indo-asian haze</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbonaceous aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>continental aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>tropospheric aerosol</dc:subject><dc:subject>emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>mass</dc:subject><dc:subject>distributions</dc:subject><dc:subject>indoex-1999</dc:subject><dc:subject>indian ocean</dc:subject><dc:subject>india</dc:subject><dc:subject>south asia</dc:subject><dc:subject>radiative impacts</dc:subject><dc:subject>fly ash</dc:subject><dc:description>[1] Aerosol sources, transport, and sinks are simulated, and aerosol direct radiative effects are assessed over the Indian Ocean for the Indian Ocean Experiment (INDOEX) Intensive Field Phase during January to March 1999 using the Laboratoire de Meteorologie Dynamique (LMDZT) general circulation model. The model reproduces the latitudinal gradient in aerosol mass concentration and optical depth (AOD). The model-predicted aerosol concentrations and AODs agree reasonably well with measurements but are systematically underestimated during high-pollution episodes, especially in the month of March. The largest aerosol loads are found over southwestern China, the Bay of Bengal, and the Indian subcontinent. Aerosol emissions from the Indian subcontinent are transported into the Indian Ocean through either the west coast or the east coast of India. Over the INDOEX region, carbonaceous aerosols are the largest contributor to the estimated AOD, followed by sulfate, dust, sea salt, and fly ash. During the northeast winter monsoon, natural and anthropogenic aerosols reduce the solar flux reaching the surface by 25 W m(-2), leading to 10 - 15% less insolation at the surface. A doubling of black carbon (BC) emissions from Asia results in an aerosol single-scattering albedo that is much smaller than in situ measurements, reflecting the fact that BC emissions are not underestimated in proportion to other ( mostly scattering) aerosol types. South Asia is the dominant contributor to sulfate aerosols over the INDOEX region and accounts for 60 - 70% of the AOD by sulfate. It is also an important but not the dominant contributor to carbonaceous aerosols over the INDOEX region with a contribution of less than 40% to the AOD by this aerosol species. The presence of elevated plumes brings significant quantities of aerosols to the Indian Ocean that are generated over Africa and Southeast and east Asia.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER GEOPHYSICAL UNION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T06:24:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T06:24:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH-ATMOSPHERES, 109(D16), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0148-0227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1029/2004JD004557</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4175</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4175</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>