<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15384</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:52:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Understanding the lability of a trans bound pyridine ligand in a saturated six-membered N-heterocyclic carbene based (NHC)PdCl2(pyridine) type complex: A case study</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KATARI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>N-heterocyclic carbene (NHC)</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEPPSI</dc:subject><dc:subject>DFT</dc:subject><dc:subject>Saturated six-membered NHC</dc:subject><dc:subject>Palladium</dc:subject><dc:subject>CROSS-COUPLING REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHARGE DECOMPOSITION ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIXED AQUEOUS-MEDIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALLADIUM COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEPPSI COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PD</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRECATALYST</dc:subject><dc:subject>NHC</dc:subject><dc:description>The lability of a trans "throwaway" pyridine ligand in a PEPPSI (Pyridine Enhanced Precatalyst Preparation, Stabilization and Initiation) themed saturated six-membered N-heterocyclic carbene complex namely, (1,3-difurfuryl tetrahydropyrimidin-2-ylidene)PdCl2(pyridine) (2), was investigated with the aid of a combined experimental and computational studies. In this regard, a new saturated six-membered N-heterocyclic carbene complex 2 was synthesized from the reaction of 1,3-difurfuryl tetrahydropyrimidin-1-ium chloride (I) with PdCl2 in the presence of KN(SiMe3)(2) as a base in pyridine. Significantly enough, the complex 2 represents the first structurally characterized example of a PEPPSI themed trans-(NHC)PdX2(pyridine) (X = halide) type of a complex supported over a saturated six-membered N-heterocyclic carbene ligand. The lability of a trans "throwaway" pyridine ligand in 2 was probed by a displacement reaction with PPh3 to yield the corresponding phosphine analog, (1,3-difurfuryl tetrahydropyrimidin-2-ylidene)PdCl2(PPh3) (3), at room temperature under ambient condition. Detailed density functional theory (DFT) studies aimed at understanding the lability of the trans "throwaway" pyridine ligand in 2, against a PPh3 ligand yielding 3, points towards a kinetic factor rather than a thermodynamic one as a reason for the lability of the pyridine in 2. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:52:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:52:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYHEDRON, 52524-529</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.poly.2012.08.038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15384</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>