<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9025</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Catalytic cracking of n-hexadecane on mixed Al-MCM-41/MFI catalyst systems with regard to selectivity for C-3 and C-3 products</dc:title><dc:creator>BHAVE, AN</dc:creator><dc:creator>KLEMT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RESCHETILOWSKI, W</dc:creator><dc:description>Recently, the large pore MCM-41 material has gained a considerable amount of interest, as a solution to the diffusion limitation provided by the conventional microporous cracking catalysts for the cracking of long-chain or bulky hydrocarbon feeds. The present work deals with the synthesis and characterization of novel mixed Al-MCM-41/MFI catalyst systems. Furthermore, the catalytic behavior of the as-synthesized Al-MCM-41/MFI mixed systems for cracking hydrocarbons by MAT (Micro Activity Test), standardized by ASTM D-3907, have been investigated in the present work. In situ formation of the meso- and microporous structures Al-MCM-41 and ZSM-5 have been obtained using a two-template [C16H33(CH3)(3)NBr and (CH3CH2CH2)(4)NBr] synthesis gel system. The mixed phases were obtained by optimizing template ratios and reaction temperature. The comparison with conventional zeolite Y and pure MCM-41 with regard to activity and selectivity showed a better activity and selectivity towards C-3 and C-4 fractions. The obtained results reveal a potential of mixed Al-MCM-41/ZSM-5 catalyst systems as cracking catalysts and, in turn, demand further optimization of physicochemical properties in the future in order to be exploited as commercial cracking catalysts.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INTERPERIODICA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T12:25:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T12:25:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PETROLEUM CHEMISTRY, 41(6), 401-404</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0965-5441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9025</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>