<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-80</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>The effect of high-K gate dielectrics on deep submicrometer CMOS device and circuit performance</dc:title><dc:creator>DESAI, MP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, NR</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARENDRA, SG</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMGOPAL RAO, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric insulators</dc:subject><dc:subject>monte carlo methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>capacitance</dc:subject><dc:description>The potential impact of high permittivity gate dielectrics on device short channel and circuit performance is studied over a wide range of dielectric permittivities (Kgate) using two-dimensional (2-D) device and Monte Carlo simulations. The gate-to-channel capacitance and parasitic fringe capacitances are extracted using a highly accurate three-dimensional (3-D) capacitance extractor. It is observed that there is a decrease in parasitic outer fringe capacitance and gate-to-channel capacitance in addition to an increase in internal fringe capacitance, when the conventional silicon dioxide is replaced by a high-K gate dielectric. The lower parasitic outer fringe capacitance is beneficial for the circuit performance, while the increase in internal fringe capacitance and the decrease in the gate-to-channel capacitance will degrade the short channel performance contributing to higher DIBL, drain leakage, and lower noise margin. It is shown that using low-K gate sidewalls with high-K gate insulators can decrease the fringing-induced barrier lowering. Also, from the circuit point of view, for the 70-nm technology generation, the presence of an optimum Kgate for different target subthreshold leakage currents has been identified.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-11-21T06:49:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:35:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-11-21T06:49:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:35:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE Transactions on Electron Devices 49 (5), 826-31</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9383</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/16.998591</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/80</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/80</dc:identifier><dc:language>en_US</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>