<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17031</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:49:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel method of estimation of adiabatic wall temperature for impinging premixed flame jets</dc:title><dc:creator>HINDASAGERI, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDULA, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Flame jet</dc:subject><dc:subject>Adiabatic wall temperature</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tube burner</dc:subject><dc:subject>Infrared thermography</dc:subject><dc:subject>Analytical-numerical method</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPINGEMENT HEAT-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:description>Impinging flame jets are widely used in industrial and domestic heating applications. Most of the studies in literature report heat flux and the wall temperature which are dimensional parameters. The proper way of presenting this data is in the form of Nusselt number and effectiveness which are non-dimensional parameters. In order to determine the Nusselt number (heat transfer coefficient), the knowledge of adiabatic wall temperature is essential. In the present work, a hybrid analytical-numerical method is proposed to evaluate the adiabatic wall temperature by computing the steady state adiabatic wall heat flux. Circular burner of 11.5 mm diameter is used for impingement on a flat quartz plate. The Reynolds number range is 600-2400, ratio of distance from tube burner tip to impingement plate to tube burner diameter is 2-6 and the equivalence ratio is 1. The adiabatic wall temperature estimated by the present hybrid analytical-numerical method is in good agreement (within 3-5%) with the experimentally measured adiabatic wall temperature. Radial distribution of Nusselt number and effectiveness for circular tube burner are presented based on the adiabatic wall temperature estimated by the present hybrid analytical-numerical method. (C) 2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HEAT AND MASS TRANSFER, 77185-193</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0017-9310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-2189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijheatmasstransfer.2014.05.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17031</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>