<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5450</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Two centuries of surveying and mapping in India</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, MN</dc:creator><dc:description>The history of surveying and mapping activities in India is, in a true sense, a record of the history of the development of the great Indian civilization itself From the ancient maps of India, belonging to the period of the great Mourya and Chandragopta dynasties, to the use of the advanced positioning and mapping space technologies of the modern age, historical records of mapping in the sub-continent tell a very fascinating story of the significant progress made in the art and science of map-making. With the establishment of Survey of India, the premier mapping agency of India, in the later part of the eighteenth century, these mapping activities formed the nucleus of all developmental projects. A brief glimpse of the significant progress made and the milestones reached in this silent revolution in the fields of surveying and mapping in the Indian subcontinent over the last two centuries is given here.</dc:description><dc:publisher>COMMONWEALTH ASSOC SURVEYING LAND ECONOMY, C A S L E</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-20T10:59:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-20T10:59:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SURVEY REVIEW, 38(300), 452-458</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0039-6265</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5450</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5450</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>