<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9235</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T03:06:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of clove oil-phospholipid mixtures on rheology of gum tragacanth - possible application for surfactant action on mucus gel simulants</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:subject>morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>viscosity</dc:subject><dc:subject>eugenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>cough</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfactant</dc:subject><dc:subject>clove oil</dc:subject><dc:subject>mucus gel simulant viscosity</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study evaluates the effectiveness of specialised biomaterials consisting of clove oil- phospholipid mixtures as possible substitute surfactants in diseases of altered mucus viscosity by studying their effect on the viscosity of mucus gel simulants in vitro. Test surfactants consisting of phospholipid-clove oil mixtures in the ratio of 1 part of oil to 9 parts of phospholipid were prepared. The phospholipids used were dipalmitoyl phosphatidylcholine (PC), phosphatidylethanolamine (PE) and phosphatidylglycerol (PG) and binary mixtures of PC: PE and PC:PG in the ratio of 2 parts of PC to 3 parts of PE or PG. The effects of the phospholipid-clove oil mixtures on the viscosity of mucus gel simulant (MGS: a polymeric gel consisting predominantly of gum tragacanth and simulating respiratory mucus), was studied by application of steady sheer rates ranging from 0.512 to 51.2/s in a concentric cylinder viscometer at 37 degreesC. The change in MGS viscosity, after incubation with surfactants, was found to have a non-Newtonian character and to follow the power law model with R-2 values &gt;0.8. The addition of clove oil-phospholipid mixtures caused a decrease in the MCS viscosity when compared with the effect of the phospholipid alone at low shear rates in case of PC, PC and PCPG. The combination of PC: PG with clove oil caused ratios of change in MGS viscosity &lt;1 i.c., caused a decrease in the MCS viscosity. PC:PG with clove oil was capable of lowering MGS viscosity and should be further researched as possible therapies for diseases of altered mucus rheology.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOS PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:36:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:36:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIO-MEDICAL MATERIALS AND ENGINEERING, 10(3-4), 189-197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-2989</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9235</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9235</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>