<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18423</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T11:06:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Statistical Analysis of Pedestrian Behaviour at Signalized Intersections</dc:title><dc:creator>MARISAMYNATHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDAGIRI, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>FLOW CHARACTERISTICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CROSSWALK</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pedestrian</dc:subject><dc:subject>signalized intersections</dc:subject><dc:subject>crossing speed</dc:subject><dc:subject>compliance</dc:subject><dc:subject>interaction</dc:subject><dc:description>In India pedestrian crashes mostly occurs when pedestrians cross the road, especially at signalized intersections. This study examines various factors affecting pedestrian crossing behaviours at signalized intersections under mixed traffic conditions. The pedestrian crossing movements were captured throughvideographic survey conducted at selected 8 signalized intersections in Mumbai, India The captured data consisting of around 2476 pedestrians and observed that the rate of pedestrian compliance with traffic signal was 53%. This study is oriented towards various levels of pedestrian crossing behaviour such as pedestrian arrival pattern, crossing speed, compliance behaviour and pedestrian-vehicular interaction at signalized intersections. In first level, the pedestrian arrival pattern was analysed to find best fit. In second level, the factors affecting pedestrian crossing speed were identified by suitable statistical test with respect to pedestrian and traffic characteristics. The third level involves the analysis of pedestrian compliance behaviour with respect to pedestrian gender, age, platoon, crossing type, crosswalk marking, crossing direction and crossing speed based on various statistical tests. The fourth level comprises of pedestrian-vehicular interactions in detail,based on conducted statistical test. The pedestrian-vehicular interaction was modelled by using binary logit model. Study results indicate that approaching vehicle direction and gap sizewere the highly influencing factors for interactions. Findings from this study will help to understand the pedestrian crossing behaviour at signalized intersections where the pedestrians noncompliance are predominant and recommends for adequate facilities to be provided to all pedestrians to cross the street with utmost safe, comfort and convenience.</dc:description><dc:publisher>UNIV STUDI TRIESTE, IST STUDIO TRASPORTI INTEGRAZIONE ECON EUROPEA-ISTIEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:06:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T11:06:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN TRANSPORT-TRASPORTI EUROPEI(57)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1825-3997</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18423</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>