<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15729</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:00:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Non-linear sliding surface: towards high performance robust control</dc:title><dc:creator>FULWANI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>FRIDMAN, L</dc:creator><dc:subject>VARIABLE-STRUCTURE SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRACKING CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINEAR-SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNCERTAIN SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INPUT SATURATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODE CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>FEEDBACK</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:description>The study proposes a method to design a non-linear sliding surface to achieve better transient response for a class of single-input and single-output (SISO) non-linear uncertain system represented in a Brunowsky canonical form. The proposed surface can also be used for linear uncertain systems with matched perturbations. The proposed surface increases the damping ratio of the closed-loop system from its initial low value; as the output approaches the setpoint from its initial value. Initially, the system is lightly damped resulting in a quick response and as the output approaches the setpoint, the system is overdamped to avoid overshoot. The existence of sliding mode is proved and a new control law is proposed to enforce sliding motion. The scheme is able to achieve low overshoot and short settling time simultaneously which is not possible with a linear sliding surface. To ease the synthesis of the non-linear surface, linear matrix inequalities-based algorithm is proposed. Effectiveness of the proposed scheme is illustrated by the simulation results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:00:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:00:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IET CONTROL THEORY AND APPLICATIONS, 6(2)235-242</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/iet-cta.2010.0727</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15729</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>