<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2209</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pothole detection and warning system : infrastructure support and system design</dc:title><dc:creator>RODE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOYAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>ARYA, K</dc:creator><dc:description>Many on-going projects in the field of vehicular networks are working in the direction of providing driver with relevant information about roads and traffic movements. In this paper, we propose a novel Wi-Fi based architecture for Pathole Detection and Warning System which assists the driver in avoiding potholes on the roads by giving prior warnings. The system consists of access points placed on the road-sides for broadcasting data, which can be received by the Wi-Fi enabled vehicles as they enter the area covered by the influence of the access points. The mobile nodes can also broadcast their response as feedback which when received by access point can be utilized for backend server processing. The pothole detection application proposed in this paper enables the driver to receive information of the potholes on the roads in the vicinity of the moving vehicle. The application can be integrated in the vehicle so as to alarm the driver in the form of a visual signal, audio signal or even trigger the braking si stein. Simulations demonstrate the advantages of using our approach for constructing pothole detection systems. Many, such similar applications can be deployed over the framework provided by the system to assist navigation on roads.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE COMPUTER SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T14:53:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T14:53:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ICECT: 2009 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ELECTRONIC COMPUTER TECHNOLOGY, PROCEEDINGS,286-290</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7695-3559-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ICECT.2009.152</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15447</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2209</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Electronic Computer Technology,Macau, PEOPLES R CHINA,FEB 20-22, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>