<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2760</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of landslide mass movement</dc:title><dc:creator>VENKATACHALAM, G</dc:creator><dc:description>Mass movement during landslides constitutes a major hazard specifically in hilly regions. The mass movement parameters like the mass, velocities, the run-out and distribution of debris is very important in assessment of the potential hazard due to any slide. The run-out. depends upon the momentum transfer within the mass. The paper describes the use of two approaches to model mass movement during landslides. In the first, a few slides are analysed using available mass movement models with a view to evaluate the motion parameters and an appropriate momentum transfer law is identified. In the second approach, distinct element method, a discontinuum numerical technique, is used for analysing the motion behaviour of moving rock blocks during rockslides. The results of the study indicate the usefulness of the approaches in analysing debris flow and rockslides respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A A BALKEMA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T11:22:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T11:22:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>EIGHTH INTERNATIONAL CONGRESS ON ROCK MECHANICS, VOL 3, PROCEEDINGS,1259-1262</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-5410-576-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2760</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th International Congress on Rock Mechanics - Frontiers of Rock Mechanics Towards the 21st-Century,TOKYO, JAPAN,SEP 25-30, 1995</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>