<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10372</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>(40)Ar-(39)Ar dating of volcanic rocks of the Shyok suture zone in north-west trans-Himalaya: Implications for the post-collision evolution of the Shyok suture zone</dc:title><dc:creator>BHUTANI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESAN, TR</dc:creator><dc:subject>india-asia collision</dc:subject><dc:subject>karakoram fault</dc:subject><dc:subject>indus suture</dc:subject><dc:subject>nw himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>continental-margin</dc:subject><dc:subject>eastern karakoram</dc:subject><dc:subject>pakistan himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>ladakh batholith</dc:subject><dc:subject>southern tibet</dc:subject><dc:subject>arc</dc:subject><dc:subject>(40)ar-(39)ar dating</dc:subject><dc:subject>shyok suture zone</dc:subject><dc:subject>khardung volcanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>shyok volcanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>trans-himalaya</dc:subject><dc:subject>india-asia collision</dc:subject><dc:subject>karakoram fault</dc:subject><dc:subject>ladakh</dc:subject><dc:description>(40)Ar-(39)Ar geochronological studies carried out on the Khardung volcanics of Ladakh, India and our earlier Ar-Ar results from the volcanics of the Shyok suture along with the available geological and geochemical data provide good constraints for post-collision evolution of the Shyok suture zone. Whole-rock samples from the Shyok volcanics yielded disturbed age-spectra and we have demonstrated earlier that the youngest tectonic event in the Shyok suture zone responsible for the thermal disturbance of these samples is Karakoram fault activation at similar to 14 Ma. Contrastingly whole-rock samples from the Khardung volcanics, which are in tectonic contact with these Shyok volcanics, and are exposed in the form of thick rhyolitic and ignimbritic flows, yielded undisturbed age-spectra and good plateau-ages. The whole-rock plateau-ages of two rhyolite samples are 52.8 +/- 0.9 and 56.4 +/- 0.4 Ma. We interpret these ages to be the time and duration of emplacement of these volcanics over thickened margin of the continental crust, which appears to be coeval with the initiation of the collision between the Indian and Asian plate. The lesser extent of post-emplacement isotopic re-equilibration in these samples unlike the Shyok volcanics indicate that these samples were present in different tectonic settings, away from the Karakoram fault, at the time of deformation in the Shyok suture zone. We propose that the two volcanic belts of contrasting nature were brought together in juxtaposition by the Karakoram strike slip faulting at similar to 14 Ma. (C) 2008</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-22T08:20:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-22T08:20:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ASIAN EARTH SCIENCES, 34(2), 168-177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1367-9120</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jseaes.2008.03.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10372</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>