<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17386</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:42:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biocompatible citric acid-coated iron oxide nanoparticles to enhance the activity of first-line anti-TB drugs in Mycobacterium smegmatis</dc:title><dc:creator>PADWAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAYA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTITUBERCULOSIS DRUGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTIBIOTIC-RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISONIAZID RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ETHIDIUM-BROMIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELL-WALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUBERCULOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFLUX</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERMEABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mycobacterium</dc:subject><dc:subject>anti-TB drugs</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug transport</dc:subject><dc:description>BACKGROUNDThe development of drug resistant Mycobacterium strains is a serious health concern causing impairment in tuberculosis (TB) therapy. UsingMycobacteriumsmegmatis as a model, the possible enhancement in the efficacy of first-line anti-TB drugs, isoniazid and rifampicin, is explored by using a combined strategy of treating the cells simultaneously with both drug and nanoparticles. The latter can target the tough cell wall of mycobacteria. RESULTSBiocompatible citric acid-coated iron oxide (magnetite) nanoparticles (CA-MNP) were synthesized by a co-precipitation routewith an average diameter of 9nm. The uptake of nanoparticles byM. smegmatiswas proportional to its concentration up to 32 mu g mL(-1). Real-time studies on fluorescent tracers demonstrate that the nanoparticles enhance membrane permeability, aiding in a higher influx of drugs into the cells. Intracellular rifampicin levels were enhanced 2-fold in the presence of CA-MNP, compared with that in the absence of CA-MNP. Similarly, reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels, measured as an indication of intracellular isoniazid, increased in cells treated with both nanoparticles and isoniazid, compared with when only the drug was used. CONCLUSIONCA-MNP in conjunction with either isoniazid or rifampicin displayed a synergistic effect in inhibiting bacterial growth, leading to a 2-fold reduction in the drug dosage. This study demonstrates that the enhanced uptake of existing anti-Tb drugs using nanoparticles is a possible option in tuberculosis treatment. (c) 2015 Society of Chemical Industry</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:42:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:42:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY AND BIOTECHNOLOGY, 90(10)1773-1781</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0268-2575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1097-4660</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jctb.4766</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17386</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>