<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1449</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of personal time-space prism vertex locations - a developing-country context</dc:title><dc:creator>NEHRA, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENDYALA, RM</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHINGRA, SL</dc:creator><dc:subject>constraints</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent developments in microsimulation modeling of activity and travel demand have called for the explicit recognition of time and space constraints under which individuals perform their activity and travel patterns. The estimation of time-space prism vertex locations-the perceived time constraints-is an important development in this context. Stochastic frontier modeling methodology offers a suitable framework for modeling and identifying the expected vertex locations of time-space prisms within which people execute activity-travel patterns. In this study, stochastic frontier models of time-space prism vertex locations are estimated for samples drawn from a household travel survey conducted in 2001 in the city of Thane on the west coast of India. The data from this survey offer an opportunity to study time constraints governing activity-travel patterns of individuals in a developing-country context. Comparisons between men and women, workers and nonworkers, and developed- and developing-country contexts were included to understand better how socioeconomic and sociocultural norms and characteristics affect time-space prism constraints.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TRANSPORTATION RESEARCH BOARD NATL RESEARCH COUNCIL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T17:46:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T17:46:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRAVEL DEMAND AND LAND USE 2004,(1898)19-27</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-309-09493-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0361-1981</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14714</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1449</dc:identifier><dc:source>83rd Annual Meeting of the Transportation-Research-Board,Washington, DC,JAN 11-15, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>