<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15537</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:23:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Carboxymethyl-Chitosan-Tethered Lipid Vesicles: Hybrid Nanoblanket for Oral Delivery of Paclitaxel</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAM, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAKRISHNAN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MORE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>IN-VIVO EVALUATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COATED LIPOSOMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUG-DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOAVAILABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICACY</dc:subject><dc:description>We describe the development and evaluation of a hybrid lipopolymeric system comprising carboxymethyl chitosan (CMC), covalently tethered to phosphatidylethanolamine units on the surface of lipid nanovesicles, for oral delivery of paclitaxel. The biopolymer is intended to act as a blanket, thereby shielding the drug from harsh gastrointestinal conditions, whereas the lipid nanovesicle ensures high encapsulation efficiency of paclitaxel and its passive targeting to tumor. CMC-tethered nanovesicles (LN-C-PTX) in the size range of 200-300 nm improved the gastro-intestinal resistance and mucoadhesion properties as compared with unmodified lipid nanovesicles (LN-PTX). Conjugation of CMC did not compromise the cytotoxic potential of paclitaxel yet facilitated the interaction and uptake of the nanovesicles by murine melanoma (B16F10) cells through an ATP-dependent process. CMC-conjugated nanovesicles, upon oral administration in rats, improved the plasma concentration profile of paclitaxel, with 1.5-fold increase in its bioavailability and 5.5 folds increase in elimination half life in comparison with Taxol. We also found that CMC in addition to providing a gastric resistant coating also imparted stealth character to the nanovesicles, thereby reducing their reticuloendothelial system (RES)-mediated uptake by liver and spleen and bypassing the need for PEGylation. In vivo efficacy in subcutaneous model of B16F10 showed significantly improved tumor growth inhibition and survival with CMC-tethered nanovesicles as compared with unmodified nanovesicles, both administered orally. LN-C-PTX exhibited therapeutic efficacy comparable to Taxol and Abraxane and also showed reduced toxicity and improved survival. Overall, these results suggest the therapeutic potential of CMC tethered nanovesicles as a platform for oral administration of paclitaxel and also unravel the ability of CMC to impart stealth character to the nanoparticles, thereby preventing their RES clearance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:23:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:23:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOMACROMOLECULES, 14(7)2272-2282</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/bm400406x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15537</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>