<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8911</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>End-to-end Quality of Service (QoS) Over Internet</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAVA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAPH, GP</dc:creator><dc:subject>inter-domain qos</dc:subject><dc:subject>inter-provider services</dc:subject><dc:subject>bgp</dc:subject><dc:subject>rcp</dc:subject><dc:subject>mpls</dc:subject><dc:description>With the significant increase in traffic on the internet in the recent past and the resources on the internet being shared, the need of end-to-end quality of service (QoS) guarantee has become critical. The existing QoS mechanisms provide the path selection mechanism in distributed manner which do not necessarily support the end-to-end QoS requirements. We build upon the routing control platform concepts to propose an evolutionary framework which provides help for optimal end-to-end QoS support. The proposed end-to-end QoS framework fall under three distinct planes: session control plane, network control plane, and data forwarding plane. This framework also introduces a novel concept of AS Designated QoS Provider Entities to assist each autonomous system in information exchange, decision making, and signaling spanning across these planes. In this paper, we describe architectural requirements, choices for end-to-end QoS framework, and implementation scheme.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ELECTRONICS TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T05:36:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T05:36:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IETE TECHNICAL REVIEW, 25(4), 216-221</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-4602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8911</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8911</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>