<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3766</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Consolidation of Charged Colloids during Drying</dc:title><dc:creator>SARKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIRUMKUDULU, MS</dc:creator><dc:subject>equation-of-state</dc:subject><dc:subject>sedimentation profiles</dc:subject><dc:subject>dispersions</dc:subject><dc:subject>resolution</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider the drying of latex dispersions containing submicrometer-sized particles dispersed in water. It is well known that the consolidation of colloidal particles is influenced by a number of factors such as particle size and shape and interparticle potential. In this work, we focus on the effect of surface charge on the consolidation front. Recent experimental and theoretical investigations on the sedimentation of charged colloidal spheres have shown that the large mass difference between noninteracting colloids and ions sets up a macroscopic electric field, thereby enhancing the diffusivity of the particles and resulting in an inflated sedimentation profile. Our experimental measurements of the concentration profile during drying-induced consolidation also reveal similar charge effects. We present a model for the consolidation of charged particles that accounts for the presence of an induced external electric Field. As expected, the predicted particle diffusivity is enhanced by the onset of the electric field at low particle concentration. Fluorescence and bright-field microscopy were used to detect the particle concentration variation in a dispersion dried in a capillary, and the measured profile agrees with the prediction confirming the influence of particle charge on consolidation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T20:42:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T20:42:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LANGMUIR, 25(9), 4945-4953</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0743-7463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/la804186m</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3766</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3766</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>