<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4952</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Space Development Modeling of Urban Regions in Developing Countries</dc:title><dc:creator>MIR, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, KVK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HUNT, JD</dc:creator><dc:subject>land-use</dc:subject><dc:description>It is quite useful to incorporate the transport parameters directly into the space development (SD) model for deciding the location of economic activities. Also, slum developments need special treatment in SD modeling as there are special ongoing drives for rehabilitation of slum population in developing regions resulting in fast changes in SD. The main objective of the present work is to develop a methodology for the development of a SD model for a developing region. The proposed methodology is tested by applying it to simulate the SD in the Mumbai Metropolitan Region (MMR) in India. Aggregate estimation procedure is adopted for estimation of logit allocation functions. The travel time of the zones from nearest railway stations is found to have a strong influence on SDs in MMR. The model is validated by comparing the estimated and observed space transformation and land consumption quantities at ward level. The proposed methodology has simulated SD and redevelopment successfully for MMR.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T14:35:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T14:35:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF URBAN PLANNING AND DEVELOPMENT-ASCE, 136(1), 75-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0733-9488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)0733-9488(2010)136:1(75)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4952</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4952</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>