<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9655</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling bivariate rainfall distribution and generating bivariate correlated rainfall data in neighbouring meteorological subdivisions using copula</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>tail-dependence coefficient</dc:subject><dc:subject>frequency-analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>archimedean copulas</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrology</dc:subject><dc:subject>rainfall</dc:subject><dc:subject>copula</dc:subject><dc:subject>multivariate analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>The rainfall patterns of neighbouring meteorological subdivisions of India are similar because of similar climatological and geographical characteristics. Analysing the rainfall pattern separately for these meteorological subdivisions may not always capture the correlation and tail dependence. Furthermore, generating the multivariate rainfall data separately may not preserve the correlation. In this study, copula method is used to derive the bivariate distribution of monsoon rainfall in neighbouring meteorological subdivisions. Different Archimedean copulas are used for this purpose and the best copula is selected based on nonparametric test and tail dependence coefficient. The fitted copula is then applied to derive the bivariate distribution, joint return period and conditional distribution. Bivariate rainfall data is generated with the fitted copula and it is observed with the increase of sample size, the generated data is able to capture the correlation as well as tail dependence. The methodology is demonstrated with the case study of two neighbouring meteorological subdivisions of North-East India: Assam and Meghalaya meteorological subdivision and Nagaland, Manipur, Mizoram and Tripura meteorological subdivision. Copyright (C) 2010 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T22:59:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T22:59:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HYDROLOGICAL PROCESSES, 24(24), 3558-3567</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-6087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/hyp.7785</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9655</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9655</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>