<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-756</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spectral and optical performance of electrochromic poly(3,4-ethylenedioxythiophene) (PEDOT) deposited on transparent conducting oxide coated glass and polymer substrates</dc:title><dc:creator>SINDHU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHA RAO, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHUJA, SHARATH</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANIL KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPAL, ESR</dc:creator><dc:subject>electric conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>switching</dc:subject><dc:description>Electrochromic devices utilizing conjugated polymers as electrochromic layers have gained increasing attention owing to their optical properties, fast switching times and contrast ratios. Polyethylenedioxythiophene (PEDOT) is an excellent material from its electrochromic properties, high conductivity and high stability in the doped form. Aqueous dispersions of PEDOT were either spin coated or electro-polymerized on transparent conducting oxide coated glass and polyethylene tetraphthalate (PET) film substrates. The spectro- and opto-electrochemical studies of the films on transparent conducting oxide coated glass/PET substrates were performed. These films have application in the fabrication of electrochromic windows (smart windows). Smart window devices having excellent switching characteristics over wide range of temperature are used for glazing applications. The aerospace industry is interested in the development of visors and windows that can control glare for pilots and passengers, especially if the coatings can be made on curved surfaces and electrically conducting.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-24T07:19:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:40:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-24T07:19:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:40:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Materials Science and Engineering: B 132(1-2), 39-42</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2006.02.030</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/756</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/756</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>