<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17597</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:19:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Antiperiodic oscillations in Chua's circuits using conjugate coupling</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGLA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARMANANDA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>DIFFERENTIAL-EQUATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXISTENCE</dc:subject><dc:description>Antiperiodic oscillations are particular of systems having antisymmetric eigenvector fields defined by: f((x) over bar) = f (-(x) over bar). It is known that the Chua's circuit also possesses the antisymmetric fields. Therefore, in this paper, we investigate the possibility of observing antiperiodic oscillations in independent and coupled Chua's oscillators. Chua's circuits have been coupled using the conjugate variables to find antiperiodic oscillations. Two different coupling schemes are being proposed. In the first scheme, the two Chua's circuits were directly coupled with each other. However, in the other scheme, the two Chua's circuits were coupled with a common dynamical environment. Both numerical results and their experimental corroboration have been presented. Results for antiperiodic oscillations in the independent Chua's circuit have been shown in the Appendix. Domains of antiperiodic oscillations with different number of maximas have been observed for different values of the system's parameters. Moreover, we also observed predictive scaling relations between different domains of antiperiodic oscillations. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:19:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:19:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHAOS SOLITONS &amp; FRACTALS, 75,212-217</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-0779</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2887</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chaos.2015.02.028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17597</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>