<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17518</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:38:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermal and inertial parameters of the flow field of a scramjet engine</dc:title><dc:creator>SURA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENEZES, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>Heat flux</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hypersonic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Scramjet</dc:subject><dc:description>Heat flux and pressure were measured on the internal walls of a scramjet engine at a hypersonic Mach number of 8 in a shock tunnel. Temperature-time history was recorded on model walls using fast-response thermocouples and the wall heat flux was deduced thereon from the temperature records. Pressure was measured at the same locations as that of heat flux using high-frequency pressure transducers. The surface measurements were used to analyze the internal flow field of the engine. The heat flux measurements revealed the regions of peak heating that may require additional thermal protection during the operation; the regions being the beginning of the constant area duct and the nozzle. The pressure measurements and the pertinent analysis indicated an optimum compression at intake through shock waves with a viable flow separation in the combustion chamber. The experimental data indicated an optimum design of the engine for a possible fuelled operation in future.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KOREAN SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MECHANICAL SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, 29(11)4943-4950</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1738-494X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1976-3824</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12206-015-1042-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17518</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>