<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15726</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:58:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analytical and numerical study for two-phase stratified-flow in a plane channel subjected to different thermal boundary conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>GADA, VH</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Analytical solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Level-set-method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stratified-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Forced-convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>Phase-change</dc:subject><dc:subject>LEVEL-SET METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EQUATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATTERN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PIPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>DUCT</dc:subject><dc:description>Analytical solution is proposed for two-phase stratified fully-developed flow in a plane channel for two problems: without and with phase change; discussed with the help of a physical model. The first problem - on flow of two immiscible liquids - is studied for the channel subjected to uniform-heat-flux boundary-condition; whereas, the second problem is studied also for constant-wall-temperature and convection-heat-transfer boundary-condition. For the first problem, fully-developed analytical solution is proposed only for heat-transfer; whereas, for the second problem, additionally fluid-flow solution is also derived. The present analytical solution is compared with numerical solution, obtained from a level set method based in-house code; and an excellent agreement is reported. The numerically obtained developing flow results are consistent with the physical-model and operating-conditions proposed here. The analytical solutions will be useful for benchmarking a numerical method for two-phase flow; and more importantly in those engineering applications, of stratified flow, where no heat-transfer/phase-change or minimum/maximum temperature is desired at the interface. (C) 2013 Elsevier Masson SAS. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER FRANCE-EDITIONS SCIENTIFIQUES MEDICALES ELSEVIER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:58:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:58:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF THERMAL SCIENCES, 7188-102</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2013.03.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15726</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>