<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17559</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:59:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Spectral pathways for exploration of secondary uranium: An investigation in the desertic tracts of Rajasthan and Gujarat, India</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARTI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALIMUTHU, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>ATOMIC EMISSION-SPECTROMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATMOSPHERIC CORRECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVAPORITE MINERALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WESTERN-AUSTRALIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYPERION IMAGERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RIVER-BASIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLAYA</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAMPLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>REFLECTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Uranium exploration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Duricrust</dc:subject><dc:subject>Imaging spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>gamma-Radiometry</dc:subject><dc:description>This study aims at identifying potential zones of secondary uranium enrichment using hyperspectral remote sensing, gamma-ray spectrometry, fluorimetry and geochemical techniques in the western Rajasthan and northern Gujarat, India. The investigated area has suitable source rocks, conducive past-, and present-climate that can facilitate such enrichment. This enrichment process involves extensive weathering of uranium bearing source rocks, leaching of uranyl compounds in groundwater, and their precipitation in chemical deltas along with duricrusts like calcretes and gypcretes. Spatial distribution of groundwater calcretes (that are rich in Mg-calcite) and gypcretes (that are rich in gypsum) along palaeochannels and chemical deltas were mapped using hyperspectral remote sensing data based on spectral absorptions in 1.70 mu m, 2.16 mu m, 2.21 mu m, 2.33 mu m, 2.44 mu m wavelength regions. Subsequently based on field radiometric survey, zones of U anomalies were identified and samples of duricrusts and groundwater were collected for geochemical analyses. Anomalous concentration of U (2345.7 Bq/kg) and Th (142.3 Bq/kg) are observed in both duricrusts and groundwater (U-1791 mu g/l, Th-34 mu g/l) within the palaeo-delta and river confluence. The estimated carnotite Solubility Index also indicates the secondary enrichment of U and the likelihood of occurrence of an unconventional deposit. (C) 2015 COSPAR. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:59:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:59:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN SPACE RESEARCH, 56(8)1613-1626</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0273-1177</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-1948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.asr.2015.07.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17559</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>