<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8025</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Distributed Velocity-Dependent Protocol for Multihop Cellular Sensor Networks</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDER, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAGYASI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>tree</dc:subject><dc:description>Cell phones are embedded with sensors form a Cellular Sensor Network which can be used to localize a moving event. The inherent mobility of the application and of the cell phone users warrants distributed structure-free data aggregation and on-the-fly routing. We propose a Distributed Velocity-Dependent (DVD) protocol to localize a moving event using a Multihop Cellular Sensor Network (MCSN). DVD is based on a novel form of connectivity determined by the waiting time of nodes for a Random Waypoint (RWP) distribution of cell phone users. This paper analyzes the time-stationary and spatial distribution of the proposed waiting time to explain the superior event localization and delay performances of DVD over the existing Randomized Waiting (RW) protocol. A sensitivity analysis is also performed to compare the performance of DVD with RW and the existing Centralized approach. Copyright (C) 2009 Deepthi Chander et al.</dc:description><dc:publisher>HINDAWI PUBLISHING CORPORATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T07:13:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T07:13:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EURASIP JOURNAL ON WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS AND NETWORKING, (), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1687-1499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2009/192985</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8025</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>