<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17698</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T14:13:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Superspin glass behavior of self-interacting CoFe2O4 nanoparticles</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASLAM, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>SURFACE SPIN DISORDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>VOGEL-FULCHER LAW</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cobalt ferrite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Superparamagnetic</dc:subject><dc:subject>Superspin glass</dc:subject><dc:description>Low-temperature magnetic properties of CoFe2O4 nanoparticles (3-16 nm) have been investigated by AC and DC magnetic measurements. The saturation magnetization (M-S) of ultra-small CoFe2O4 nanoparticles (3-9 nm) sharply increases at low temperature (10 K) compared to room temperature (RT) MS value. For example, the increment in M-S value for 3 nm CoFe2O4 nanoparticle is 22 emu/g and is null for 12 nm and larger sized nanoparticles. A similar trend of increment in MS is also seen in ultra-small size Fe3O4 and MnFe2O4 nanoparticles. However, the M-S enhancement in ultra-small CoFe2O4 nanoparticles is found much higher as compared to Fe3O4 and MnFe2O4 nanoparticles. The ultra-small sized nanoparticles arrange with a high packing density to induce a strong exchange as well as dipolar interactions, which renders the enhanced low temperature M-S with superspin glass (SSG) state. The exchange coupling strongly depends on magnetic anisotropy energy, which increases in the order Mn2+ &lt; Fe2+ &lt; Co2+ and thus the ultra-small CoFe2O4 nanoparticles show a large enhancement of M-S at low temperature due to strong exchange coupling. A noticeable enhancement of spin glass temperature (T-g) for ultra-small sized CoFe2O4 nanoparticles also confirms the presence of strong exchange coupling in this case. Fitting of the ac susceptibility chi'(T, f) data to a power-law scaling and Vogel-Fulcher model shows a satisfactory fit and the dynamic critical exponent takes value between 8.9 and 11.9 which are in a range typical for the spin-glass systems. Memory behavior in ultra-small CoFe2O4 nanoparticles suggest that the frequency dependent blocking process of ultra-small sized nanoparticles can be better described by power law model, while the interaction regime present in the 12 nm and above sized nanoparticles is ascribed to a Vogel-Fulcher model. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:13:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:13:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ALLOYS AND COMPOUNDS, 628,416-423</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-8388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2014.12.197</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17698</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>