<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2119</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Prediction of impact strength index, slake durability index and Schmidt hammer rebound number from P-wave velocity</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:subject>density</dc:subject><dc:description>The purpose of this study is to develop statistical relationship between P-wave velocity and other properties like impact strength index, slake durability index and Schmidt hammer rebound number. These are important properties to characterize a rock mass and are being used in geological and geo-technical engineering. P-wave velocity is one of the most important properties for the determination of other properties like impact strength index; slake durability index and Schmidt hammer rebound number. In this study, these properties were determined in the laboratory and each property was correlated with P-wave velocity. High correlations were observed, and empirical equations have been developed to predict Impact strength index, slake durability index and rebound values. The statistical analysis of data set by student's West confirms the dependency and interrelation among these parameters. These empirical relations will be useful to determine the important geotechnical parameters for safe design, smooth and stable excavation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:23:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:23:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Eurock 2006 Multiphysics Coupling and Long Term Behaviour in Rock Mechanics,149-153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-415-41001-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1201/9781439833469.ch20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15630</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2119</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Symposium of the International-Society-for-Rock-Mechanics,Liege, BELGIUM,MAY 09-12, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>