<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1230</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Test interval optimization of safety systems of nuclear power plant using fuzzy-genetic approach</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, KDURGA</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPIKA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>decision making</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuzzy sets</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithms</dc:subject><dc:description>Probabilistic safety assessment (PSA) is the most effective and efficient tool for safety and risk management in nuclear power plants
(NPP). PSA studies not only evaluate risk/safety of systems but also their results are very useful in safe, economical and effective design
and operation of NPPs. The latter application is popularly known as ‘‘Risk-Informed Decision Making’’. Evaluation of technical
specifications is one such important application of Risk-Informed decision making. Deciding test interval (TI), one of the important
technical specifications, with the given resources and risk effectiveness is an optimization problem. Uncertainty is inherently present in
the availability parameters such as failure rate and repair time due to the limitation in assessing these parameters precisely. This paper
presents a solution to test interval optimization problem with uncertain parameters in the model with fuzzy-genetic approach along with
a case of application from a safety system of Indian pressurized heavy water reactor (PHWR).</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:11:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:11:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety 92(7), 895-901</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0951-8320</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.ress.2006.05.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1230</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1230</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>