<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17796</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:47:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic stability of interconnected glove boxes</dc:title><dc:creator>SARASWAT, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, GR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>CONTACT PROBLEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRICTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Glove boxes are extensively used in a nuclear industry to handle hazardous materials. They are generally interconnected with each other through a flexible link and stand freely on the floor. To check the seismic stability of the interconnected glove boxes and evaluate safety margins in design, extensive full scale shake table testing of two interconnected glove boxes had been carried out. Objective was to observe effects of rigid body and elastic motions, arising due to base excitation, on stability and integrity of the system. It was observed that sliding was predominant mode of motion with associated low amplitude rocking motion. Elastic deformations were very limited to affect the integrity of the system. It was observed that to increase seismic stability of the interconnected glove box system, relative sliding displacement between the two should be controlled. Further to shake table testing, nonlinear time history finite element analysis was also carried out. Analysis results were found to be coherent with the corresponding test results. In addition to that, to determine a safe upper bound on sliding displacement, a numerical method is proposed. This paper discuss the test results to enhance understanding of seismic behavior of two interconnected glove boxes. Important interpretations are accentuated to give a clear understanding to the designers. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:47:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:47:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 293,357-370</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-759X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2015.08.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17796</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>