<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14149</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:35:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>On the existence of an invariant non-degenerate bilinear form under a linear map</dc:title><dc:creator>GONGOPADHYAY, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>CONJUGACY CLASSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>REALITY PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALGEBRAIC-GROUPS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Linear map</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bilinear form</dc:subject><dc:subject>Unipotents</dc:subject><dc:subject>Real elements</dc:subject><dc:description>Let V be a vector space over a field F. Assume that the characteristic of F is large, i.e. char(F) &gt; dim V. Let T V &gt; V be an invertible linear map. We answer the following question in this paper. When does V admit a T-invariant non-degenerate symmetric (resp. skew-symmetric) bilinear form ?We also answer the infinitesimal version of this question. Following Feit and Zuckerman 121, an element g in a group G is called real if it is conjugate in G to its own inverse. So it is important to characterize real elements in GL(V, F). As a consequence of the answers to the above question, we offer a characterization of the real elements in GL(V, F). Suppose V is equipped with a non-degenerate symmetric (resp. skew-symmetric) bilinear form B. Let S be an element in the isometry group 1(V, B). A non-degenerate S-invariant subspace W of (V, B) is called orthogonally indecomposable with respect to S if it is not an orthogonal sum of proper S-invariant subspaces. We classify the orthogonally indecomposable subspaces. This problem is nontrivial for the unipotent elements in I(V, B). The level of a unipotent T is the least integer k such that (T - 1)(k) = 0. We also classify the levels of unipotents in I(V,B). (C) 2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:35:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:35:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LINEAR ALGEBRA AND ITS APPLICATIONS,434(1)89-103</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0024-3795</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.laa.2010.08.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14149</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>