<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17276</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:10:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microwave-assisted exfoliation method to develop platinum-decorated graphene nanosheets as a low cost counter electrode for dye-sensitized solar cells</dc:title><dc:creator>SARANYA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIVASANKAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBRAMANIA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>REDOX ELECTROLYTE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FACILE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:description>Graphene nanosheets (GNs) are prepared from natural graphite by a simple ecofriendly microwave-assisted exfoliation technique. The as prepared GNs are decorated with platinum (Pt) nanoparticles by a simple chemical reduction method and used as a low-cost counter electrode (CE) material for dye-sensitized solar cells (DSSCs). Structure and morphology of the prepared GNs and Pt-decorated GNs (Pt-GNs) are evaluated by X-ray diffraction (XRD), Raman spectroscopy, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and selected area electron diffraction (SAED) studies. The electrochemical behavior of GNs and Pt-GNs are compared with std. Pt using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) studies. These studies indicate that the Pt-GNs-based counter electrode offered superior electrocatalytic activity towards the I-/I3(-) redox mediator with enhanced charge transfer rate and exchange current density at the electrode/electrolyte interface over std. Pt and GNs-based counter electrodes. DSSCs are fabricated with std. Pt, GNs and Pt-GNs to determine the photovoltaic performance under 1 Sun illumination (100 mW cm(-2), AM 1.5). It is found that the cell fabricated with 1 wt% Pt-decorated GNs as counter electrode showed an 11% improvement in photovoltaic cell efficiency compared with the cell assembled with std. platinum and other reported graphene-Pt-based composites as counter electrodes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 4(68)36226-36233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4ra05044d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17276</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>