<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3408</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>CONSTRUCTING RELIABLE COMMUNICATION-NETWORKS OF SMALL WEIGHT ONLINE</dc:title><dc:creator>CHANDRA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISHWANATHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>spanning-trees</dc:subject><dc:description>Suppose the vertices of a complete weighted graph are revealed to us one at a time, and we have to build a network with some desired properties on these vertices. We consider the cost of building a network which has these properties after the addition of each vertex and compare it to the cost incurred by an algorithm which builds a network that has the same properties only at the end, i.e., after all the vertices have been revealed. We examine online algorithms for constructing networks with three properties; high connectivity, low vertex degree, and small diameter, and evaluate these algorithms from the competitive perspective. We show that on n points drawn from any metric space, a greedy algorithm constructs a k-connected network with a competitive ratio of O(k(2) log n), and prove a lower bound of Omega(k log n) on the competitive ratio of any online algorithm. We also present an online algorithm with a competitive ratio of O(k(2) log n) to build a k-connected network with maximum vertex degree 3k and an online algorithm with a competitive ratio of O(k(2) log n) to build a k-connected network with a diameter no more than a constant times the diameter of the n points. (C) 1995 ,</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS INC JNL-COMP SUBSCRIPTIONS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T18:06:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T18:06:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ALGORITHMS, 18(1), 159-175</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0196-6774</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1006/jagm.1995.1005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3408</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3408</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>