<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16963</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:08:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimum size of nanorods for heating application</dc:title><dc:creator>SESHADRI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAOKAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Magnetic hyperthermia</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetic nanoparticle</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC HYPERTHERMIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CANCER-THERAPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COBALT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MFH</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANISOTROPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUID</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHAPE</dc:subject><dc:description>Magnetic nanoparticles (MNP's) have become increasingly important in heating applications such as hyperthermia treatment of cancer due to their ability to release heat when a remote external alternating magnetic field is applied. It has been shown that the heating capability of such particles varies significantly with the size of particles used. In this paper, we theoretically evaluate the heating capability of rod-shaped MNP's and identify conditions under which these particles display highest efficiency. For optimally sized monodisperse particles, the power generated by rod-shaped particlesis found to be equal to that generated by spherical particles. However, for particles which are not mono dispersed, rod-shaped particles are found to be more effective in heating as a result of the greater spread in the power density distribution curve. Additionally, for rod-shaped particles, a dispersion in the radius of the particle contributes more to the reduction in loss power when compared to a dispersion in the length. We further identify the optimum size, i.e the radius and length of nanorods, given a bi-variate log-normal distribution of particle size in two dimensions. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:08:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:08:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS, 362165-171</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-8853</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4766</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jmmm.2014.03.041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16963</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>