<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10570</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>BATCH-DIST - A COMPREHENSIVE PACKAGE FOR SIMULATION, DESIGN, OPTIMIZATION AND OPTIMAL-CONTROL OF MULTICOMPONENT, MULTIFRACTION BATCH DISTILLATION-COLUMNS</dc:title><dc:creator>DIWEKAR, UM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MADHAVAN, KP</dc:creator><dc:description>BATCH-DIST is a general-purpose simulation package for the design, simulation and optimization of multicomponent, multifraction batch distillation columns operating under different modes (constant reflux, variable reflux and optimal reflux policy). The package includes simulation models of varying degrees of complexity and rigor; efficient but simplified models (based on short-cut methods) for preliminary design and rapid analysis of column behavior, and rigorous models (based on solution of transient heat and mass balance differential equations) for verification and detailed column design. Besides simulation and design, BATCH-DIST can also accomplish optimization and optimal control of columns. Coded in Fortran 77, the package is flexible and user-friendly. BATCH-DIST has been extensively tested with benchmark cases involving binary and multicomponent systems, with nonideal behavior and in columns with appreciable holdup effects. Such test cases have clearly demonstrated that predictions of the simplified models in the package compare well with those of the rigorous models. This powerful and comprehensive package is expected to be computationally more efficient than existing packages.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T16:11:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T16:11:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTERS &amp; CHEMICAL ENGINEERING, 15(12), 833-842</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0098-1354(91)80028-T</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10570</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10570</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>