<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12279</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>SOURCE AND DISTRIBUTION OF METALS IN URBAN SOIL OF BOMBAY, INDIA, USING MULTIVARIATE STATISTICAL TECHNIQUES</dc:title><dc:creator>RATHA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHU, BK</dc:creator><dc:subject>contamination</dc:subject><dc:subject>sediments</dc:subject><dc:subject>pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil</dc:subject><dc:subject>size characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>pollution source</dc:subject><dc:subject>factor analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>discriminant analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>Simplification of a complex system of geochemical variables obtained from the soils of an industrialzed area of Bombay is attempted by means of R-mode factor analysis. Prior to factor analysis, discriminant analysis was carried out taking rock and soil chemical data to establish the anthropogenic contribution of metals in soil. Trace elements (Cd, Co, Cr, Cu, Fe, Mn, Ni, Pb, and Zn) are expressed in terms of three rotated factors. The factors mostly indicate anthropogenic sources of metals such as atmospheric fallout, emission from different industrial chimneys, crushing operations in quarries, and sewage sludges. Major elements (Na, Mg, Al, Si, P, K, Ca, Ti, Mn, and Fe) are also expressed in terms of three rotated factors indicating natural processes such as chemical weathering, presence of clay minerals, and contribution from sewage sludges and municipal refuse. Summary statistics (mean, standard deviation, skewness, and kurtosis) for the particle size distribution were interpreted as moderate dominance of fine particles. Mineralogical studies revealed the presence of montmorillonite, kaolinite, and illite types of clay minerals. Thus the present study provides information about the metal content entering into the soil and their level, sources, and distribution in the area.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T10:08:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T10:08:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL GEOLOGY, 22(3), 276-285</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0177-5146</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12279</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12279</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>