<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8190</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>A new quasi-resonant DC-link PWM inverter using single switch for soft switching</dc:title><dc:creator>JAFAR, JJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>converter</dc:subject><dc:subject>circuit</dc:subject><dc:subject>quasi-resonant inverter</dc:subject><dc:subject>soft switched inverter</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents a new quasi-resonant dc-link (QRDCL) inverter. Only one switching device is used to create zero voltage instants under all load conditions. The maximum voltage across the inverter devices is maintained at around (1.01-1.1) times the input source voltage. The circuit has the flexibility of selecting switching instants of the resonant link in synchronism with any PWM technique. Control technique does not require the help of inverter switches to create the zero voltage instants in the dc-link, and voltage and current sensors are eliminated from the control circuit. In this paper, the principle of operation and detailed analysis of the proposed QRDCL inverter are presented and design considerations for achieving soft switching are obtained. Detailed PSPICE simulation studies are carried out to study the feasibility of the proposed topology under various load conditions. The experimental results of the proposed QRDCL PWM inverter feeding three phase induction motor are given.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T17:50:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T17:50:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER ELECTRONICS, 17(6), 1010-1016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8993</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPEL.2002.805598</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8190</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>