<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1287</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Extended metal-organic solids based on benzenepolycarboxylic and aminobenzoic acids</dc:title><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAMURTHY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATHIYENDIRAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>WALAWALKAR, MG</dc:creator><dc:subject>porous solids</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkali</dc:subject><dc:subject>coordination polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>aminobenzoic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>benzene tetracarboxylic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkaline earth metals</dc:subject><dc:subject>supramolecular chemistry</dc:subject><dc:description>This article describes the recent results obtained in our laboratory on the interaction of polyfunctional ligands with divalent alkaline earth metal ions and a few divalent transition metal ions. Treatment of MCl2. nH(2)O (M = Mg, Ca, Sr or Ba) with 2-amino benzoic acid leads to the formation of complexes [Mg(2-aba)(2)] (1), [Ca(2-aba)(2)(OH2)(3)](infinity) (2), [{Sr(2-aba)(2)(OH2)(2)}(2). H2O)](infinity) (3), [Ba(2-aba)(2)(OH2)](infinity) (4), respectively. While the calcium ions in 2 are hepta-coordinated, the strontium and barium ions in 3 and 4 reveal a coordination number of nine apart from additional metal-metal interactions. Apart from the carboxylate functionality, the amino group also binds to the metal centres in the case of strontium and barium complexes 3 and 4. Complexes [{Mg(H2O)(6)} (4-aba)(2). 2H(2)O] (5), [Ca(4-aba)(2)(H2O)(2)] (6) prepared from 4-aminobenzoic acid reveal more open or layered structures. Interaction of 2-mercaptobenzoic acid with MCl2. 6H(2)O (M = Mg, Ca), however, leads to the oxidation of the thiol group resulting in the disulphide 2,2'-dithiobis(benzoic acid). New metal-organic framework based hydrogen-bonded porous solids [{M(btec) (OH2)(4)}(n). n(C4H12N2). 4nH(2)O] (btec = 1,2,4,5-benzene tetracarboxylate) (M = Co 9; Ni 10; Zn 11) have been synthesized from 1,2,4,5-benzene tetracarboxylic acid in the presence of piperazine. These compounds are made up of extensively hydrogen-bonded alternating layers of anionic M-btec co-ordination polymer and piperazinium cations. Compounds 2-11 described herein form polymeric networks in the solid-state with the aid of different coordinating capabilities df the carboxylate anions hydrogen bonding interactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T17:43:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T17:43:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INDIAN ACADEMY OF SCIENCES-CHEMICAL SCIENCES,112(3)273-290</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4134</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14473</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1287</dc:identifier><dc:source>Symposium on Modern Trends in Inorganic Chemistry,BANGALORE, INDIA,JAN 18-20, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>