<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16872</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:27:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Gelatin-PMVE/MA composite scaffold promotes expansion of embryonic stem cells</dc:title><dc:creator>CHHABRA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>JADHAV, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>Biocompatibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gelatin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polymethyl vinyl ether-alt-maleic anhydride</dc:subject><dc:subject>Embryonic stem cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>Pluripotency</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cell infiltration</dc:subject><dc:subject>TISSUE ENGINEERING APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CO-MALEIC ANHYDRIDE)</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLLAGEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>CULTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPATIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOMATERIALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAINTENANCE</dc:subject><dc:description>We introduce a new composite scaffold of gelatin and polymethyl vinyl ether-alt-maleic anhydride (PMVE/MA) for expansion of embryonic stem cells (ESCs) in an in vitro environment. To optimize the scaffold, we prepared a gelatin scaffold (G) and three composite scaffolds namely GP-1, GP-2, and GP-3 with varying PMVE/MA concentrations (0.2-1%) and characterized them by scanning electron microscopy (SEM), swelling study, compression testing and FTIR. SEM micrographs revealed interconnected porous structure in all the scaffolds. The permissible hemolysis ratio and activation of platelets by scaffolds confirmed the hemocompatibility of scaffolds. Initial biocompatibility assessment of scaffolds was conducted using hepatocarcinoma (Hep G2) cells and adhesion, proliferation and infiltration of Hep G2 cells in depth of scaffolds were observed, proving the scaffold's biocompatibility. Further Oct4B2 mouse embryonic stem cells (mESCs), which harbor a green fluorescence protein transgene under regulatory control of the Oct4 promotor, were examined for expansion on scaffolds with MTT assay. The GP-2 scaffold demonstrated the best cell proliferation and was further explored for ESC adherence and infiltration in depth (SEM and confocal), and pluripotent state of mESCs was assessed with the expression of Oct4-GFP and stage-specific embryonic antigen-1 (SSEA-1). This study reports the first demonstration of biocompatibility of gelatin-PMVE/MA composite scaffold and presents this scaffold as a promising candidate for embryonic stem cell based tissue engineering. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:27:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:27:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; ENGINEERING C-MATERIALS FOR BIOLOGICAL APPLICATIONS, 37184-194</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0928-4931</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-0191</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msec.2013.12.033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16872</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>