<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1392</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic and electronic properties of the magnetoresistive perovskites La0.67−xBixCa0.33MnO3</dc:title><dc:creator>WALSH, M  C</dc:creator><dc:creator>FOLDEAKI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GIGUERE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, DHIRENDRA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, S K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUNLAP, R  A</dc:creator><dc:subject>electronic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>ferromagnetic resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic permeability</dc:subject><dc:subject>paramagnetic resonance</dc:subject><dc:description>Magnetotransport, magnetic susceptibility and ferromagnetic resonance (FMR) studies of La0.67−xBixCa0.33MnO3 perovskites with x=0.03 to 0.16 are reported. The magnetoresistivity ratio shows a peak in all samples corresponding to the Curie transition. In samples with xgreater-or-equal, slanted0.13 a second peak at lower temperature is seen in the magnetoresistivity. Magnetic susceptibility measurements show Curie like behavior for all samples. Samples with low Bi content show a difference between field cooled and zero-field cooled measurements at low temperature. This difference diminishes with increasing x. FMR spectra show a single resonance above Tc. Samples with small Bi content show two resonances just below Tc but these resonances cannot be clearly resolved at lower temperatures due to line broadening. These two resonances also become less resolved with increasing x. No anomalous behavior corresponding to the low-temperature peak in the magnetoresistivity is seen in the magnetic susceptibility or FMR measurements. Results are interpreted in terms of the effects of Bi on the structure of grain boundaries.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-20T11:13:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:26:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-20T11:13:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:26:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Physica B: Condensed Matter 253(1-2), 103-110</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-4526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0921-4526(98)00374-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1392</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1392</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>