<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12087</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-15T12:03:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Existence criteria for reflection configurations in shock-vortex interactions</dc:title><dc:creator>BARIK, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>efficient implementation</dc:subject><dc:subject>capturing schemes</dc:subject><dc:subject>wave reflections</dc:subject><dc:subject>mach reflection</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>steady</dc:subject><dc:subject>pseudo-steady shock wave reflection</dc:subject><dc:subject>existence criteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>shock-vortex interactions</dc:subject><dc:description>The length scale criteria is widely accepted as an explanation for transition and hence existence of different shock wave reflection configurations in pseudo-steady flows. However, there has not been any attempt to validate this criteria using information obtained from a time-dependent numerical simulation. A high resolution time-dependent numerical simulation in pseudo-steady flow is carried out in the present work. Time-dependent numerical data is used to calculate flow features in a laboratory frame of reference to verify validity of the length scale criteria for existence of different shock wave reflection configurations in pseudo-steady flow. This analysis is then extended to the study of unsteady shock wave reflection configurations in shock-vortex interactions. It is shown that the existence of regular reflection (RR) and Mach reflection (MR) configurations in an unsteady flowfield resulting from shock-vortex interactions can also be explained locally based on limiting conditions similar to that prescribed by the length scale criteria for pseudo-steady flow.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T12:48:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T12:48:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SHOCK WAVES, 16(4-5), 309-320</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0938-1287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00193-006-0067-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12087</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>