<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17790</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:44:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Recrystallization and phase stability study of cesium tin iodide for application as a hole transporter in dye sensitized solar cells</dc:title><dc:creator>PEEDIKAKKANDY, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>X-RAY-DIFFRACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CSSNI3</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Perovskite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hole transport material</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solid state dye sensitized solar cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cesium tin iodide</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, we report synthesis and stability analysis of cesium tin iodide (CsSnI3) prepared through solid state and solution route methods for its application as a hole transport layer in dye sensitized solar cells (DSSC). Phase formation, chemical stability and degradation mechanism of CsSnI3 were studied using X-ray diffraction (XRD), Energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), field emission scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and Raman spectroscopy. Optical band gap of the material was studied using UV-vis spectroscopy and photoluminescence studies. CsSnI3 synthesized through solid state route was used as a hole transport material (HTM) for dye sensitized solar cells with cell efficiency up to 3%. Temperature dependent excitonic emission studies shows that B-gamma-CsSnI3 shows a linear increase in band gap with increasing temperature. (C) 2015 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:44:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:44:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE IN SEMICONDUCTOR PROCESSING, 33,103-109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1369-8001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4081</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2015.01.023</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17790</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>