<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14636</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:04:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Curcumin Modulates alpha-Synuclein Aggregation and Toxicity</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOTIA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHITE, GM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Curcumin</dc:subject><dc:subject>alpha-synuclein</dc:subject><dc:subject>amyloid</dc:subject><dc:subject>oligomers</dc:subject><dc:subject>toxicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Parkinson's disease</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMYLOID-BETA-PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SMALL-MOLECULE INHIBITORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARKINSONS-DISEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIBRIL FORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VIVO</dc:subject><dc:subject>HELICAL INTERMEDIATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLAVONOID BAICALEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT-PROBE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NILE RED</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLIGOMERS</dc:subject><dc:description>In human beings, Parkinson's disease (PD) is associated with the oligomerization and amyloid formation of alpha-synuclein (alpha-Syn). The polyphenolic Asian food ingredient curcumin has proven to be effective against a wide range of human diseases including cancers and neurological disorders. While curcumin has been shown to significantly reduce cell toxicity of alpha-Syn aggregates, its mechanism of action remains unexplored. Here, using a series of biophysical techniques, we demonstrate that curcumin reduces toxicity by binding to preformed oligomers and fibrils and altering their hydrophobic surface exposure. Further, our fluorescence and two-dimensional nuclear magnetic resonance (2D-NMR) data indicate that curcumin does not bind to monomeric alpha-Syn but binds specifically to oligomeric intermediates. The degree of curcumin binding correlates with the extent of alpha-Syn oligomerization, suggesting that the ordered structure of protein is required for effective curcumin binding. The acceleration of aggregation by curcumin may decrease the population of toxic oligomeric intermediates of alpha-Syn. Collectively; our results suggest that curcumin and related polyphenolic compounds can be pursued as candidate drug targets for treatment of PD and other neurological diseases.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:04:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:04:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACS CHEMICAL NEUROSCIENCE, 4(3)393-407</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/cn3001203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14636</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>