<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1157</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>New physics upper bound on the branching ratio of Bs→l+l− and Bs→l+l−γ</dc:title><dc:creator>ALOK, ASHUTOSH KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>UMA SANKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>standard model</dc:subject><dc:subject>semileptonic decays</dc:subject><dc:subject>electromagnetic decays</dc:subject><dc:subject>meson leptonic decay</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider the most general new physics effective Lagrangian for b→sl+l−. We derive the upper limit on the branching ratio for the processes Bs→l+l− where l=e,μ, subject to the current experimental bounds on related processes, B→(K,K*)l+l−. If the new physics interactions are of vector/axial-vector form, the present measured rates for B→(K,K*)l+l− constrain B(Bs→l+l−) to be of the same order of magnitude as their respective Standard Model (SM) predictions. On the other hand, if the new physics interactions are of scalar/pseudoscalar form, B→(K,K*)l+l− rates do not impose any useful constraint on B(Bs→l+l−) and the branching ratios of these decays can be as large as present experimental upper bounds. If future experiments measure B(Bs→l+l−) to be 10−8 then the new physics giving rise to these decays has to be of the scalar/pseudoscalar form. We also consider the effect of new physics on B(Bs→l+l−γ) subject to the present experimental constraints on B→(K,K*)l+l− and B→K*γ. New physics in form scalar/pseudoscalar, which makes a very large contribution to Bs→l+l−, makes no contribution at all to Bs→l+l−γ due to angular momentum conservation. New Physics in the form of vector/axial-vector operators is constrained by the data on B→(K,K*)l+l− and new physics in the form of tensor/pseudo-tensor is constrained by the data on B→K*γ. In both cases, enhancement of B(Bs→l+l−γ) much beyond the SM expectation is impossible. In conclusion, present data on B→(K,K*) transitions allow for large B(Bs→l+l−) but do not allow B(Bs→l+l−γ) to be much larger than its SM expectation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-08T06:49:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:51:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-08T06:49:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:51:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Nuclear Physics B - Proceedings Supplements 167, 241-243</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0920-5632</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nuclphysbps.2006.12.056</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1157</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1157</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>