<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14184</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:29:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Development of grain structure during superplastic deformation of an Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr alloy containing Sc</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVEENDRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>RECRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr-Sc alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Two-step strain rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Superplasticity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transmission electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electron backscattered diffraction</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent studies have shown that a suitably thermomechanically processed Al-Zn-Mg-Cu-Zr-Sc alloy having an essentially unrecrystallized grain structure may be subjected to superplastic deformation at a temperature and strain rate combination of 475 degrees C, 1.9 x 10(-2) s(-1) to obtain a total elongation of 650%. The present work demonstrates that the utilization of two-step strain rate at 425 degrees C during superplastic deformation of a similarly thermomechanically processed alloy increases the total elongation value to as high as 916%. The beneficial effect of two-step strain rate could further be realized at 350 degrees C to obtain a total elongation of 438%. Using electron backscattered diffraction, the present work provides a systematic assessment of the changes in (i) percentage recrystallization and (ii) recrystallized grain size with percentage elongation in the material superplastically deformed using both one- and two-step strain rates. (C) 2010 Acta Materialia Inc. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:29:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:29:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCRIPTA MATERIALIA,64(5)386-389</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1359-6462</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scriptamat.2010.10.038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14184</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>