<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1941</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Device simulation for radiation and hot carrier effects</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>EKBOTE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZAMAN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBBARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASI, J</dc:creator><dc:description>Device simulation is an important design tool for device structure and technology design. Traditional BIOS device simulators solve device equations only in the semiconductor, assuming the oxide to be ideal. Since fields in short channel MOSFETs are high, carriers can be injected in the oxide. In radiation environments, electron-hole pairs are generated in the oxide-itself. In such cases, accurate device simulation requires the solution of device equations in the oxide also. This is particularly important if we want to predict device degradation due to hot carrier and radiation effects. In this paper we describe two simulators - DESIRE for radiation effects and HOTMOS for hot carrier effects, which do solve device equations in the oxide as well as in the semiconductor region. Physical models included in these simulators are described. Simulation results are compared with measured data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T16:43:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T16:43:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICS OF SEMICONDUCTOR DEVICES, VOLS 1 AND 2,3316,974-979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-2756-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15178</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1941</dc:identifier><dc:source>IX International Workshop on the Physics of Semiconductor Devices (IWPSD),DELHI, INDIA,DEC 16-20, 1997</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>