<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9578</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>A METHOD TO SCHEDULE GENERATING-UNITS FOR COST-EFFECTIVE REDUCTION OF FOSSIL-FUEL EMISSIONS</dc:title><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>emission reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermal unit allocation</dc:subject><dc:description>Scheduling methods, which reduce undesirable emissions from fossil-fuel generating units, has been a matter of considerable interest to power utilities. This paper introduces the idea that overall emission-reduction for a system can be achieved by optimizing the emissions at a few most emissive units, instead of doing so at all units. Such an approach becomes effective provided a sufficiently large cluster of the emissive units are subjected to the emission-optimization process. One important aspect of the problem that is addressed in the paper concerns the development of a suitable objective function which takes into account the cost-effectiveness of emission reduction. Both overall generation cost, as well as the emission at selected generating units, are taken relative to the respective base-case (non-optimal emission) values. The relative-cost and relative-emission terms are then included in a common 'penalty function', which is dimensionless. Minimization of this penalty function leads to an optimal operating point, at which a comparison of the reduction in overall relative-emission to the increase in relative-cost indicates the cost-effectiveness of the corresponding generation schedule. The approach is tested for an existing three-region scenario that forms part of the Indian power system. Results indicate the extent to which individual emissions can be reduced vis-a-vis the corresponding increase in overall cost of generation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:50:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:50:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ENERGY RESEARCH, 17(5), 425-438</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0363-907X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/er.4440170510</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9578</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9578</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>