<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15394</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:57:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of shock and mixed loading on the performance of SND based sequencing batch reactors (SBR) degrading nitrophenols</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, PM</dc:creator><dc:subject>Nitrophenols</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thiosphaera pantotropha</dc:subject><dc:subject>Heterotrophic nitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aerobic denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>SBR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SND</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIOSPHAERA-PANTOTROPHA</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITROAROMATIC COMPOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>4-NITROPHENOL BIODEGRADATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HETEROTROPHIC NITRIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>P-NITROPHENOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENITRIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>4-CHLOROPHENOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEAKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of nitrophenolic shock loads on the performance of three lab scale SBRs was studied using a synthetic feed. Nitrophenols were biotransformed by Simultaneous heterotrophic Nitrification and aerobic Denitrification (SND) using a specially designed single sludge biomass containing Thiosphaera pantotropha. Reactors R1, R2 and R3 were fed with 200 mg/L concentration of 4-nitrophenol (4-NP), 2,4-dinitrophenol (2,4-DNP), and 2,4,6-trinitrophenol (2,4,6-TNP) whereas reactor R was used as a background control. Three nitrophenolic shock loadings of 400, 600 and 800 mg/L d were administrated by increasing the influent nitrophenolic concentration while keeping the hydraulic retention time as 48 h. The shocks were given continuously for a period of 4 days before switching back to normal nitrophenolic loading (200 mg/L d). The reactors were allowed to recover to normal performance level before administrating the next nitrophenolic shock load. The study showed that a nitrophenolic shock load, as high as 600 mg/L d was completely degraded by the 4-NP &amp; 2,4-DNP bioreactors while almost half degraded by the 2,4,6-TNP bioreactor without affecting the reactor's performance irreversibly. After resuming the normal nitrophenolic loading, it took almost 8-10 days for the reactors to recover from the shock effect. The study was further extended to evaluate the maximum possible mixed nitrophenolic loading (4-NP:2,4-DNP:2,4,6-TNP 1:1:1) to which a reactor (R3) containing 2,4,6-TNP acclimated single sludge biomass can be exposed without hampering the reactor performance irreversibly. The reactor was able to achieve pseudo-steady-state at a mixed nitrophenolic loading of 300 mg/L d with more than 90% removal of all the three nitrophenols, but could remove half of the mixed nitrophenolic loading of 600 mg/L d. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:57:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:57:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESEARCH, 46(7)2405-2414</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2012.02.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15394</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>