<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15725</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:58:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analytical and level-set method based numerical study on oil-water smooth/wavy stratified-flow in an inclined plane-channel</dc:title><dc:creator>GADA, VH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Oil-water flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Smooth-stratified flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wavy-stratified flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>Flow transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Level set method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Development length</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS-LIQUID FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-PHASE FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERFACIAL AREA</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMMISCIBLE LIQUIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLOSURE RELATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POISEUILLE FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-FLUID MODELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAMINAR FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>PIPES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUIDS</dc:subject><dc:description>Level-set method based transient 2D simulation of developing oil-water smooth-stratified (SS) and wavy-stratified (WS) flow in a horizontal and inclined plane-channel is done; for various inlet-velocity (u(in)), inlet-interface-height (H(in)), inclination-angle (0), reduced surface-tension (sigma &lt;= sigma(ow)) and reduced gravity (g &lt;= g(e)). At the certain critical value of the governing parameters, SS to WS flow transition is captured, analyzed and reasoned. Increase in u(in), H(in) and 0 and a decrease in sigma(ow) and g(e) are found to destabilize the SS flow. For fully-developed SS flow, a detailed analytical solution of interface-height, maximum axial-velocity, its transverse location, pressure-gradient and wall-shear stress is proposed for an inclined channel; an excellent agreement between the present analytical and numerical results is also reported. The SS flow analytical-results are also compared with the time-averaged WS flow numerical-results (near the channel-outlet), to understand the reasons for flow-transition. Flow development is studied with the help of axial variation of interface-height and maximum (over the cross-section of the channel) axial velocity: time-averaged for WS flow. Furthermore, the variation of development-length for SS flow and WS flow is studied. Finally, stretching of interface-area due to onset of WS flow is presented with the help of interfacial-area-concentration. Its calculation directly from the Dirac-delta function of the level set method is a novel-contribution. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:58:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:58:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF MULTIPHASE FLOW, 38(1)99-117</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijmultiphaseflow.2011.08.015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15725</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>