<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14372</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T10:11:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Repression of the glucose-inducible outer-membrane protein OprB during utilization of aromatic compounds and organic acids in Pseudomonas putida CSV86</dc:title><dc:creator>SHRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASU, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>GODBOLE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHEW, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>APTE, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>CARBON CATABOLITE REPRESSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AERUGINOSA PORIN OPRF</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREFERENTIAL UTILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENYLACETIC ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT-SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>METABOLISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATHWAYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHANNEL</dc:subject><dc:description>Pseudomonas putida CSV86 shows preferential utilization of aromatic compounds over glucose. Protein analysis and [(14)C]glucose-binding studies of the outer membrane fraction of cells grown on different carbon sources revealed a 40 kDa protein that was transcriptionally induced by glucose and repressed by aromatics and succinate. Based on 2D gel electrophoresis and liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry analysis, the 40 kDa protein closely resembled the porin B of P. putida KT2440 and carbohydrate-selective porin OprB of various Pseudomonas strains. The purified native protein (i) was estimated to be a homotrimer of 125 kDa with a subunit molecular mass of 40 kDa, (ii) displayed heat modifiability of electrophoretic mobility, (iii) showed channel conductance of 166 pS in 1 M KCl, (iv) permeated various sugars (mono-, di- and trisaccharides), organic acids, amino acids and aromatic compounds, and (v) harboured a glucose-specific and saturable binding site with a dissociation constant of 1.3 mu M. These results identify the glucose-inducible outer-membrane protein of P. putida CSV86 as a carbohydrate-selective protein OprB. Besides modulation of intracellular glucose-metabolizing enzymes and specific glucose-binding periplasmic space protein, the repression of OprB by aromatics and organic acids, even in the presence of glucose, also contributes significantly to the strain's ability to utilize aromatics and organic acids over glucose.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC GENERAL MICROBIOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T10:11:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T10:11:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROBIOLOGY-SGM,157()1531-1540</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-0872</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1099/mic.0.047191-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14372</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>