<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16014</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:01:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microstructural Developments Through Marforming in a Ni-Ti-Fe Shape Memory Alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>BASU, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, BC</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>ROLLED THIN PLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION-BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>B19' MARTENSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TWINNED DOMAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MULTIPLE STEPS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEXTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FATIGUE</dc:subject><dc:description>A hot-rolled Ni-Ti-Fe alloy was subjected to marforming: approximately 8 pct reduction (in thickness) in the martensite phase by laboratory rolling. Before the next marforming step, the sample was annealed to bring back calorimetric signatures of reversible austenite-martensite phase transformation. Significant differences in microstructure could be achieved by combinations of marforming and annealing. Such differences, on the other hand, originated from the marformed microstructure: two distinct regions of remarkably different substructures. The difference was mainly through the relative presence of defects: micro-twins and dislocations. The regions of lower defect densities got textured gradually, with marforming steps, to gamma (ND//aOE (c) 111 &gt;) fiber. The regions with high defect densities, on the other hand, provided non-gamma fine clustered grains after annealing. Though debates may continue on the exact nature and origin of micro-twins, the present study brought out their dominant role in determining almost all aspects of microstructural developments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:01:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:01:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 44A(9)4310-4322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-013-1780-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16014</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>