<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13992</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:00:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluating the Diffusion Coefficient of Sulfur in Low-Silica CaO-SiO(2)-Al(2)O(3) Slag</dc:title><dc:creator>MUHMOOD, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>IWASE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEETHARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:description>The chemical diffusion coefficient of sulfur in the ternary slag of composition 51.5 pct CaO-9.6 pct SiO(2)-38.9 pct Al(2)O(3) slag was measured at 1680 K, 1700 K, and 1723 K (1403 degrees C, 1427 degrees C, and 1450 degrees C) using the experimental method proposed earlier by the authors. The P(S2) and P(O2) pressures were calculated from the Gibbs energy of the equilibrium reaction between CaO in the slag and solid CaS. The density of the slag was obtained from earlier experiments. Initially, the order of magnitude for the diffusion coefficient was taken from the works of Saito and Kawai but later was modified so that the concentration curve for sulfur obtained from the program was in good fit with the experimental results. The diffusion coefficient of sulfur in 51.5 pct CaO-9.6 pct SiO(2)-38.9 pct Al(2)O(3) slag was estimated to be in the range 3.98 to 4.14 x 10(-6) cm(2)/s for the temperature range 1680 K to 1723 K (1403 degrees C to 1450 degrees C), which is in good agreement with the results available in literature DOI: 10.1007/s11663-011-9492-7 (C) The Minerals, Metals &amp; Materials Society and ASM International 2011</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:00:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:00:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS B-PROCESS METALLURGY AND MATERIALS PROCESSING SCIENCE,42(2)274-280</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5615</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11663-011-9492-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13992</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>