<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1303</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Proton events at geostationary altitude during 2005, their relationship to solar wind and IMF parameters, and their 'geoeffectiveness'</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJARAM, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, AC</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALYANA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RATHOD, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, CG</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRASAD, MYS</dc:creator><dc:subject>interplanetary magnetic-field</dc:subject><dc:subject>earths outer magnetosphere</dc:subject><dc:subject>relativistic electrons</dc:subject><dc:subject>acceleration</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>sun : activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>solar-terrestrial relations</dc:subject><dc:description>Solar wind and IMF parameters from the ACE satellite at the Earth's dayside Lagrangian point LI, are examined during solar proton events of 2005 for 'shock' structures. The GOES-10 satellite at geostationary orbit (G) sees proton events in the 10-30 MeV energy range only when the flux of these particles exceeds (5 x 10(-1)) protons/cm(2).sec.sr. (also known as pfu). Such events are invariably followed at G by REE (Relativistic Electron Events) which commence with an RED (Relative Electron Dropout). During REE, the enhanced flux of &gt; 2 MeV electrons can exceed (&gt; 5 x 104) pfu, and can cause operational anomalies on geostationary satellite instruments. Such large proton events also trigger off at Earth (E), ssc type of storms with typical signatures in the geomagnetic indices Dst and Kp, and large Forbush decreases in the Cosmic Ray Neutron Monitor (CRNM) Count. Relationships between the various Space Weather parameters recorded at L1, G and E during Proton events, assume special importance from the point of view of Satellite Anomaly predictions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN INST ASTROPHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T19:59:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T19:59:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>BULLETIN OF THE ASTRONOMICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA,35(4)487-498</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-9523</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1303</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd UN/NASA Workshop on International Heliophysical Year and Basic Space Science,Bangalore, INDIA,NOV 27-DEC 01, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>