<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18053</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T07:29:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Role of zinc oxide and carbonaceous nanomaterials in non-fullerene-based polymer bulk heterojunction solar cells for improved cost-to-performance ratio</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALAM, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAWAN, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>REDUCED GRAPHENE OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENHANCED PHOTOCATALYTIC ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOVOLTAIC CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONJUGATED POLYMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNO NANOSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHARGE SEPARATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISIBLE-LIGHT</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENCY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:description>Cost-effective carbonaceous allotropes other than fullerene (i.e. carbon quantum dots or C-dots), ZnO nanoparticles and their nanocomposites were synthesized as alternatives to expensive fullerene in polymer-based bull( heterojunction solar cells. A facile microwave-assisted hydrothermal route was used to synthesize nanomaterials in a short time span along with inexpensive precursors to reduce the cost. Taking into account the cost-to-performance ratio, devices were fabricated in direct configuration as ITO/PEDOT:PSS/PFO-DBT:ZnO (or C-dots, Z@G, Z@C-dots)/Al followed by device optimization to obtain optimized device parameters. The devices exhibit significant short-circuit current density (J(sc)), open-circuit voltage (V-oc) and power conversion efficiency (PCE). The best power conversion efficiency of 3.9% with J(sc) 14.8 mA cm(-2), V-oc, of 0.82 V and fill factor of 32% was obtained with Z@C-dots as acceptor at active layer concentration of 40 mg ml(-1) and weight ratio of 1 : 1. In addition, the phase analysis of the active-layer interface demonstrates the better compatibility of the organic:organic phase (i.e. polymer:C-dots with a device PCE of 2.8%) as compared to the organic:inorganic phase (i.e. polymer:ZnO with a device PCE of 1.41%). Moreover, the best performance of the organic:hybrid phase (i.e. polymer:Z@C-dots with a device PCE of 3.9%) is due to the exploitation of properties of both organic and inorganic components on the same platform. C-dots as an acceptor give an overall power conversion efficiency of 2.8%, whereas Z@G resulted in an efficiency of 3.1%. A fullerene-based device gives an efficiency of 4.2% (just 0.3% more in comparison to Z@C-dots), but the difference in material cost is more than 50 times, which thus results in a significant improvement in the cost-to-performance ratio of a Z@C-dots-based device than a device using fullerene as an acceptor. Therefore, the developed carbonaceous nanomaterials act as potential acceptors in non-fullerene-based polymer solar cells for possible applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:29:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T07:29:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY A, 3(44)22227-22238</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7496</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c5ta06802a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18053</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>