<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17110</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T04:45:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>High thermoelectric performance of (AgCrSe2)(0.5)(CuCrSe2)(0.5) nano-composites having all-scale natural hierarchical architectures</dc:title><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BASU, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATT, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHMAD, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MESHRAM, KN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEBNATH, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAVNEETHAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAYAKAWA, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASWAL, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>THERMAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BULK THERMOELECTRICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PANOSCOPIC APPROACH</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGCRSE2</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER</dc:subject><dc:description>Recent studies have shown that thermoelectric materials exhibit a high figure-of-merit if it consists of hierarchically organized microstructures that significantly lower the lattice thermal conductivity without any appreciable change in the power factor. Here, we report a new class of thermoelectric (AgCrSe2)(0.5)(CuCrSe2)(0.5) nano-composites synthesized via the vacuum hot pressing of a mixture of the constituents, which naturally consists of phonon scattering centers in a multiscale hierarchical fashion, i.e. atomic scale disorder, nanoscale amorphous structure, natural grain boundaries due to layered structure and mesoscale grain boundaries/interfaces. The presence of a natural hierarchical architecture of different length scales in the composite samples is confirmed by scanning electron and transmission electron microscopy. Detailed characterization reveals that in the composite samples there is a slight migration of Cu into the Ag site. Composite samples exhibit extremely low thermal conductivity similar to 2 mW cm(-1) K-1 at 773 K, which is nearly one third of the pure AgCrSe2 and CuCrSe2. The composite samples exhibit a high ZT similar to 1.4 at 773 K, which is attributed to the scattering of heat carrying phonons of all wavelengths via the natural hierarchical architecture of the material. The ease of synthesis of such high performance (AgCrSe2)(0.5)(CuCrSe2)(0.5) nanocomposites with a natural hierarchical architecture offers a promise for replacing conventional tellurides.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:45:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T04:45:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS CHEMISTRY A, 2(40)17122-17129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2050-7496</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4ta04056b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17110</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>