<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14196</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:35:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Reachability and controllability of a particle in a dielectrophoretic system</dc:title><dc:creator>SIMHA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANAVAR, RN</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANG, DE</dc:creator><dc:subject>Dielectrophoresis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Accessibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>Small time local controllability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Micro/nano particles</dc:subject><dc:description>A dielectrophoretic (DEP) force is a result of the interaction between a nonuniform electric field and a polarizable particle. As the electric field is dominant at the micro/nano scale, this force can be effectively used to manipulate and control particles on this scale. We consider the motion of a particle on an invariant line with the suspending medium being a fluid with a low Reynolds number. This DEP system has two states and two parameters: the two states are indicative of the particle's position and the induced dipole moment and the two parameters are a and c which depend upon the electric properties of the particle and the medium. The system is described by a set of ordinary differential equations with a quadratic term in the control variable (control being the applied voltage on the electrodes which induces the electric field) making the system non-affine in control. In the existing literature, the controllability studies of the DEP system have been restricted to reachability issues in the context of the time-optimal control problem. Here we present a comprehensive study of reachability, accessibility and controllability. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:35:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:35:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SYSTEMS &amp; CONTROL LETTERS,60(7)460-467</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-6911</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sysconle.2011.03.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14196</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>