<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16396</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:46:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>A model of laser ablation with temperature-dependent material properties, vaporization, phase explosion and plasma shielding</dc:title><dc:creator>MARLA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANDARKAR, UV</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>EXPANDED LIQUID-METALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMAL-MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACE-TENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRITICAL-POINT</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMBIENT GAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>VAPOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLUME</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINUM</dc:subject><dc:description>Laser ablation of metals using nanosecond pulses occurs mainly due to vaporization. However, at high fluences, when the target is heated close to its critical temperature, phase explosion also occurs due to homogeneous nucleation. Due to a wide variation in target temperature, the material properties also show a considerable variation. In this paper, a model of laser ablation is presented that considers vaporization and phase explosion as mechanisms of material removal and also accounts for the variation in material properties up to critical temperature using some general and empirical theories. In addition, plasma shielding due to inverse bremsstrahlung and photo-ionization is considered. The model predicts accurately (within 5 %) the phase explosion threshold fluence of Al. The predictions of ablation depth by the model are in reasonable agreement with experimental measurements at low fluences. Whereas, the degree of error marginally increases at high laser fluences.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:46:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:46:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS A-MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; PROCESSING, 116(1)273-285</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-8396</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1432-0630</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00339-013-8118-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16396</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>