<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8051</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fuzzy waste load allocation model: a multiobjective approach</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUJUMDAR, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>water-quality management</dc:subject><dc:subject>river system</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>uncertainty</dc:subject><dc:subject>search</dc:subject><dc:subject>conflicting objectives</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuzzy optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>goal programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiobjective programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>probabilistic global search lausanne (pgsl)</dc:subject><dc:subject>water quality</dc:subject><dc:description>Fuzzy Waste Load Allocation Model (FWLAM), developed in an earlier study, derives the optimal fractional levels, for the base flow conditions, considering the goals of the Pollution Control Agency (PCA) and dischargers. The Modified Fuzzy Waste Load Allocation Model (MFWLAM) developed subsequently is a stochastic model and considers the moments (mean, variance and skewness) of water quality indicators, incorporating uncertainty due to randomness of input variables along with uncertainty due to imprecision. The risk of low water quality is reduced significantly by using this modified model, but inclusion of new constraints leads to a low value of acceptability level, A, interpreted as the maximized minimum satisfaction in the system. To improve this value, a new model, which is a combination Of FWLAM and MFWLAM, is presented, allowing for some violations in the constraints of MFWLAM. This combined model is a multiobjective optimization model having the objectives, maximization of acceptability level and minimization of violation of constraints. Fuzzy multiobjective programming, goal programming and fuzzy goal programming are used to find the solutions. For the optimization model, Probabilistic Global Search Lausanne (PGSL) is used as a nonlinear optimization tool. The methodology is applied to a case study of the Tunga-Bhadra river system in south India. The model results in a compromised solution of a higher value of acceptability level as compared to MFWLAM, with a satisfactory value of risk. Thus the goal of risk minimization is achieved with a comparatively better value of acceptability level.</dc:description><dc:publisher>I W A PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T08:50:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T08:50:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HYDROINFORMATICS, 12(1), 83-96</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1464-7141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2166/hydro.2010.028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8051</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8051</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>