<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11832</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>SYNTHESIS AND CHARACTERIZATION OF THE LARGE-PORE MOLECULAR-SIEVE SAPO-46</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAKASH, AM</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASHTEKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTY, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHILUKURI, SVV</dc:creator><dc:subject>silicoaluminophosphates</dc:subject><dc:subject>acidity</dc:subject><dc:subject>al</dc:subject><dc:subject>si</dc:subject><dc:description>Synthesis of a novel large-pore SAPO-46 molecular sieve has been described. The effect of the organic template (di-n-propylamine) and silica concentration in the synthesis gel on the crystallinity and phase purity of SAPO-46 was studied. Samples were characterized by X-ray diffraction (XRD), magic-angle spinning (MAS) NMR spectroscopy, FTIR spectroscopy, thermal analysis (TG and DTA), chemical analysis, scanning electron microscopy and EDAX microprobe analysis, SAPO-46 had a lower thermal stability than SAPO-5, SAPO-37 and MgAPO-36. Silicon substitution for phosphorus at crystallographically distinct sites has been suggested to cause the creation of two different silicon environments in SAPO-46. The extent of silicon substitution was large and temperature-prog rammed desorption (TPD) of ammonia has shown high concentration of acid sites. SAPO-46 showed high activity for alkylation of toluene with methanol that was comparable with that of ZSM-5, but showed no para selectivity. However, as the reaction proceeded, para selectivity developed due coking at the pore mouth.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T20:10:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T20:10:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE CHEMICAL SOCIETY-FARADAY TRANSACTIONS, 91(6), 1045-1050</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0956-5000</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/ft9959101045</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11832</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11832</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>