<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15944</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:25:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pressure measurement technique and installation effects on the performance of wafer cone design</dc:title><dc:creator>BORKAR, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENUGOPAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wafer cone</dc:subject><dc:subject>Installation effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>Coefficient of discharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>Differential pressure devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOWMETERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FITTINGS</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study explores novel pressure averaging technique for wafer cone flowmeter design and its robustness in the presence of double 90 degrees bend (out-of-plane) and gate valve as a source of upstream flow disturbance. The wafer cone flowmeter is tested in a circular pipe (inside diameter of 101 mm) with water as the working medium for the flow Reynolds number ranging from 1.19 x 10(5) to 5.82 x 10(5). Influence of the half cone angle (alpha) on the coefficient of discharge (C-d) of wafer cone flowmeter is studied with this new pressure averaging technique. Half cone angles considered in this study are 30 degrees and 45 degrees with a constant constriction ratio (beta) of 0.75. The upstream static pressure tap is located at 1D upstream of the wafer cone. The downstream pressure averaging technique comprises eight circumferential holes of diameter 2 mm on the maximum diameter step of the wafer cone. The pressure taps are communicated through the support strut which serves as a downstream static pressure tap. The disturbance causing elements are individually placed at 1.5D, 5.5D, 9.5D and 13.5D upstream to the wafer cone flowmeter. The wafer cone flowmeter is also tested with gate valve opening of 25%, 50% and 75% for all the arrangements considered. The 30 degrees cone is found to be better than 45 cone for the range of Reynolds number covered in the present study. The results show that the 30 wafer cone flowmeter with novel downstream pressure averaging technique is insensitive to the swirl flow created by a double 90 degrees bend (out-of-plane) and requires an upstream length of 9.5D with a gate valve as a source of flow disturbance. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:25:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:25:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FLOW MEASUREMENT AND INSTRUMENTATION, 3052-59</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.flowmeasinst.2013.01.005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15944</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>