<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5929</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Numerical investigation of fluid flow and heat transfer over louvered fins in compact heat exchanger</dc:title><dc:creator>MALAPURE, VP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>flat-tube</dc:subject><dc:subject>geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>friction factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat exchangers</dc:subject><dc:subject>louvered fins</dc:subject><dc:subject>stanton number</dc:subject><dc:description>Numerical investigation of fluid flow and heat transfer characteristics over louvered fins and flat tube in compact heat exchangers is presented in this study. Three-dimensional simulations of single and double row tubes with louvered fins have been conducted. Simulations are performed for different geometries with varying louver pitch, louver an.-le, fin pitch and tube pitch and for different Reynolds number. Conjugate heat transfer and conduction through the fins are considered. The air-side performance of heat exchanger is evaluated by calculating Stanton number and friction factor. The results are compared with experiment and a good agreement is observed. The local Nusselt number variation along the top surface of the louver is calculated and effects of geometrical parameters on the average heat transfer coefficient is computed. Design Curves are obtained which can used to predict the heat transfer and the pressure drop for a given louver geometry. (C) 2006 Elsevier Masson SAS. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER FRANCE-EDITIONS SCIENTIFIQUES MEDICALES ELSEVIER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T16:58:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T16:58:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF THERMAL SCIENCES, 46(2), 199-211</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1290-0729</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijthermalsci.2006.04.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5929</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5929</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>