<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1164</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:09:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Boron modified 17-7 PH stainless steel via rapid solidification processing</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIWARI, AN</dc:creator><dc:subject>austenitic steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat-treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>technology</dc:subject><dc:description>Rapid quenching from the melt has been used to obtain an extended solid, solubility of boron in commercial semiaustenitic 17-7 PH stainless' steel. The resulted alloy ribbons exhibited improved hardness over their commercial precipitation hardening (PH) stainless steel counterpart at room temperature. Based on isochronal ageing, boron has been found to accelerate the kinetics of precipitation and improved microhardness substantially. The microstructural features present in the as-spun ribbons have been evaluated by combination of X-ray diffractometry (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) analyses. SEM analysis reveals a considerable refinement in microsegregation pattern with increasing boron concentration. TEM reveals a boride precipitate in the interdendritic areas.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN INST METALS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T07:21:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T07:21:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:09:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN INSTITUTE OF METALS,56(1)9-17</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-493X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14360</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1164</dc:identifier><dc:source>National Seminar on Recent Advances in Making, Shaping and Application of Stainless(NSSS 2001),VADODARA, INDIA,DEC 14-15, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>