<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-315</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>New scheme for IP routing and traffic engineering</dc:title><dc:creator>SARAPH, GIRISH P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, PUSHPRAJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>ip networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>asynchronous transfer mode</dc:subject><dc:subject>data communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiprotocol label switching</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel scheme for routing data packets in high-speed communication networks is presented and described in detail. Simulations have been performed on randomly constructed 25 and 100 node networks, which demonstrate excellent IP throughput and the capability to adapt to dynamic network conditions. The most important benefit of this scheme is to simplify the route look-up tasks and save on resources required for route processing, routing updates, data storage, memory access, and information exchange. The scheme can be used as a stand-alone IP routing protocol or used with the conventional IP, ATM, or MPLS for path selection, QoS support, and traffic engineering. It can quickly adapt to the dynamic load conditions of traffic congestion or link breakage to enable QoS support or priority-based differential services. The scheme may be implemented in software or hardware to give a simple, fast, and cheap solution. The simulations show that the solution is robust and highly scalable for large high-speed networks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-12T04:52:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T12:09:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-12T04:52:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T12:09:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Workshop on High Performance Switching and Routing, Torino, Italy, 24-27 June 2003, 227-232</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-7710-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/HPSR.2003.1226709</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/315</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/315</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>