<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1693</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Prediction of extrudate swell in polymer melt extrusion using an Arbitrary Lagrangian Eulerian (ALE) based finite element method</dc:title><dc:creator>GANVIR, VIVEK</dc:creator><dc:creator>LELE, ASHISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAOKAR, ROCHISH M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAUTHAM, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>channel flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>constitutive equations</dc:subject><dc:subject>equations of motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>dies</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:description>Accurate prediction of extrudate (die) swell in polymer melt extrusion is important as this helps in appropriate die design for profile extrusion applications. Extrudate swell prediction has shown significant difficulties due to two key reasons. The first is the appropriate representation of the constitutive behavior of the polymer melt. The second is regarding the simulation of the free surface, which requires special techniques in the traditionally used Eulerian framework. In this paper we propose a method for simulation of extrudate swell using an Arbitrary Lagrangian Eulerian (ALE) technique based finite element formulation. The ALE technique provides advantages of both Lagrangian and Eulerian frameworks by allowing the computational mesh to move in an arbitrary manner, independent of the material motion. In the present method, a fractional-step ALE technique is employed in which the Lagrangian phase of material motion and convection arising out of mesh motion are decoupled. In the first step, the relevant flow and constitutive equations are solved in Lagrangian framework. The simpler representation of polymer constitutive equations in a Lagrangian framework avoids the difficulties associated with convective terms thereby resulting in a robust numerical formulation besides allowing for natural evolution of the free surface with the flow. In the second step, mesh is moved in ALE mode and the associated convection of the variables due to relative motion of the mesh is performed using a Godunov type scheme. While the mesh is fixed in space in the die region, the nodal points of the mesh on the extrudate free surface are allowed to move normal to flow direction with special rules to facilitate the simulation of swell. A differential exponential Phan Thien Tanner (PTT) model is used to represent the constitutive behavior of the melt. Using this method we simulate extrudate swell in planar and axisymmetric extrusion with abrupt contraction ahead of the die exit. This geometry allows the extrudate to have significant memory for shorter die lengths and acts as a good test for swell predictions. We demonstrate that our predictions of extrudate swell match well with reported experimental and numerical simulations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-10-06T04:00:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:41:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-10-06T04:00:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:41:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Non-Newtonian Fluid Mechanics 156(1-2), 21-28</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0377-0257</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnnfm.2008.06.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1693</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1693</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>