<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-497</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Novel three phase flux reversal machine with full pitch winding</dc:title><dc:creator>MORE, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>electric current regulators</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage stabilizing circuits</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>permanent magnets</dc:subject><dc:subject>winding</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper proposes a concept of fictitious ‘Electrical Gear’ in analyzing the flux pattern of Flux Reversal Machine (FRM). Concept of novel full pitch winding is presented for FRM. Finite Element Method ( FEM ) analysis of conventional concentrated stator pole winding FRM and proposed full pitch winding FRM are carried out to validate the concept. Generator performance of full pitch winding FRM is compared with conventional concentrated stator pole winding FRM. Full pitch winding arrangement increases the inductance of the machine which results in poor voltage regulation. Series capacitive compensation is provided to the machine for better voltage regulation. Output power of compensated full pitch winding FRM is approximately twice as that of the conventional concentrated stator pole winding FRM. Physical dimensions, electrical and magnetic loadings are kept same in both the machines.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-24T04:20:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T19:31:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-24T04:20:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T19:31:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Power Electronics, Daegu, South Korea, 22-26 October 2007, 1007-1012.</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-1871-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICPE.2007.4692534</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/497</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/497</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>