<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2029</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Maintaining coherent views over dynamic distributed data</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>views</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic data dissemination</dc:subject><dc:subject>web</dc:subject><dc:subject>internet scale algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>data coherency</dc:subject><dc:description>Data delivered today over the web reflects rapid and unpredictable changes in the world around us. We are increasingly relying on content that provides dynamic, interactive, personalized experiences. To achieve this, the content of most web pages is created dynamically, by executing queries dynamically, using data that changes dynamically from distributed sources identified dynamically. A typical web page presents a "view" of the world constructed from multiple sources. In this paper, we examine the nature of dynamics of distributed data and discuss fresh approaches to maintain the coherency of the views seen by the users. Achieving such coherency while developing scalable low-overhead solutions poses challenges in terms of delivering data with the required fidelity in spite of data dynamics. How these challenges can be met by the judicious design of algorithms for data dissemination, caching, and cooperation forms the crux of our work.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T02:15:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T02:15:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DISTRIBUTED COMPUTING AND INTERNET TECHNOLOGY, PROCEEDINGS,5966,13-20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-642-11658-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15305</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2029</dc:identifier><dc:source>6th International Conference on Distributed Computing and Internet Technology,Bhubaneswar, INDIA,FEB 15-17, 2010</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>