<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5817</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling of earthquake damage using geotechnical centrifuges</dc:title><dc:creator>MADABHUSHI, SPG</dc:creator><dc:subject>quay walls</dc:subject><dc:description>Earthquakes can cause tremendous loss of human life and can result in severe damage to a wide variety of civil engineering structures. The behaviour of foundation systems and soil strata subjected to earthquake loading is complex. Dynamic centrifuge modelling is a powerful tool that offers a possibility of understanding the true behaviour of foundation systems under earthquake loading. In this paper the principles of dynamic centrifuge modelling are elucidated. Implementing dynamic centrifuge modelling needs specialized equipment and instrumentation and the details of such equipment are presented. The application of dynamic centrifuge modelling to investigate the seismic behaviour of embankments on liquefiable foundation and pile foundation subjected to liquefaction-induced lateral spreading are presented. Results from these two applications reveal the usefulness of dynamic centrifuge modelling in understanding the true failure mechanisms. It will be shown that such an understanding can have direct bearing on both advancement of knowledge as well as on geotechnical practice used in the design of future structures or in retrofit attempts on existing structures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CURRENT SCIENCE ASSN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T06:42:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T06:42:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 87(10), 1405-1416</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5817</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5817</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>