<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1493</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Explaining absence of texture development in cold rolled two-phase Zr–2.5 wt% Nb alloy</dc:title><dc:creator>KIRAN KUMAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATRAMANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>aspect ratio</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal orientation</dc:subject><dc:subject>grain boundaries</dc:subject><dc:subject>plastic flow</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, two distinct starting microstructures of Zr–2.5 wt% Nb have been used: (1) single-phase α hcp martensitic structure; and (2) two-phase, 10% bcc β and rest hcp α, Widmanstätten structure. In the second case, two types of α were present—near grain boundary predominantly single-phase α (about 5% of the total α) and α plates in an apparently continuous β matrix. Both (1) and (2) had similar starting crystallographic texture of the hcp α phase and were deformed by unidirectional and cross rolling. In the two-phase structure the changes in the bulk texture on cold rolling was found to be insignificant, while in the single-phase material noticeable textural changes were observed. Taylor type deformation texture models predicted textural changes in single-phase structure but failed to predict the observed lack of textural development in the two-phase material. Microtexture observations showed that α plates remained approximately single crystalline after cold rolling, while the β matrix underwent significant orientational changes. Relative hardening, estimated by X-ray peak broadening, was observed mainly in β phase; while aspect ratio of α plates remained unchanged with cold rolling—indicating absence of effective macroscopic strain in the hcp α plates. Based on microstructural and microtextural observations, a simple model is proposed in which the plastic flow is mainly confined to the β matrix within which the α plates are subjected to ‘in-plane rigid body rotation’. The model explains the observed lack of textural developments in the two-phase structure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:27:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:06:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-15T04:27:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:06:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Acta Materialia 51(3), 625-640</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0955-2219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2006.05.083</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1493</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>