<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14589</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:39:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>BUCKLING BEHAVIOR OF COMPOSITE LAMINATES (WITH AND WITHOUT CUTOUTS) SUBJECTED TO NONUNIFORM IN-PLANE LOADS</dc:title><dc:creator>SONI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Composite laminates with cutouts</dc:subject><dc:subject>critical buckling load</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonuniform in-plane load</dc:subject><dc:subject>POSTBUCKLING RESPONSE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECTANGULAR-PLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HOLES</dc:subject><dc:description>Critical buckling loads of composite laminates are usually calculated using analytical solutions based on the assumption of uniform in-plane loads, despite of the fact that real structures are often subjected to various nonuniform loads. The present work is focused on the buckling behavior of composite laminates, with and without cutouts, subjected to various nonuniform in-plane loads. The effect of the size of the cutouts, on the buckling behavior, has been studied using finite element method. Furthermore, parametric studies on the effects of plate aspect ratio, location of the cutout and the application of a nonuniform load combined with a shear load have also been studied. Higher buckling loads were observed in pure in-plane bending compared to uniformly/nonuniformly distributed loads. Consequently, it is important to consider nonuniformly distributed loading whenever applicable, to utilize complete strength of the composite laminate and to avoid premature failure of the composite laminate due to structural instability.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:39:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF STRUCTURAL STABILITY AND DYNAMICS, 13(8)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0219-4554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1793-6764</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/S0219455413500442</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14589</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>