<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15752</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:11:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis of orthogonally protected bacterial, rare-sugar and d-glycosamine building blocks</dc:title><dc:creator>EMMADI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>ONE-POT PROTECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALLADIUM-CATALYZED GLYCOSYLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGIOSELECTIVE PROTECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NOVO SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STREPTOCOCCUS-PNEUMONIAE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINKED BACILLOSAMINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFICIENT SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>C-POLYSACCHARIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHIGELLA-SONNEI</dc:subject><dc:subject>DOUBLE PARALLEL</dc:subject><dc:description>Bacterial glycoconjugates comprise atypical deoxy amino sugars that are not present on the human cell surface, making them good targets for drug discovery and carbohydrate-based vaccine development. Unfortunately, they cannot be isolated with sufficient purity in acceptable amounts, and therefore chemical synthesis is a crucial step toward the development of these products. Here we describe a detailed protocol for the synthesis of orthogonally protected bacterial deoxy amino hexopyranoside (2,4-diacetamido-2,4,6-trideoxyhexose (DATATDH), d-bacillosamine, d-fucosamine, and 2-acetamido-4-amino-2,4,6-trideoxy-dgalactose (AATAATAAT)), d-glucosamine and d-galactosamine building blocks starting from beta-d-thiophenylmannoside. Readily available beta-d-thiophenylmannoside was first converted into the corresponding 2,4-diols via deoxygenation or silylation at C6, followed by O3 acylation. The 2,4-diols were converted into 2,4-bis-trifluoromethanesulfonates, which underwent highly regioselective, one-pot, double-serial and double-parallel displacements by azide, phthalimide, acetate and nitrite ions as nucleophiles. Thus, d-rhamnosyl-and d-mannosyl 2,4-diols can be efficiently transformed into various rare sugars and d-galactosamine, respectively, as orthogonally protected thioglycoside building blocks on a gram scale in 1-2 d, in 54-85% overall yields, after a single chromatographic purification. This would otherwise take 1-2 weeks. d-Glucosamine building blocks can be prepared from beta-d-thiophenylmannoside in four steps via C2 displacement of triflates by azide in 2 d and in 66-70% overall yields. These procedures have been applied to the synthesis of l-serine-linked trisaccharide of Neisseria meningitidis and a rare disaccharide fragment of the zwitterionic polysaccharide (ZPSPS) A1 (ZPSPS A1) of Bacteroides fragilis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:11:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:11:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURE PROTOCOLS, 8(10)1870-1889</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1754-2189</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1750-2799</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/nprot.2013.113</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15752</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>