<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1238</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of heptanol and carbenoxolone on noradrenaline induced contractions in guinea pig vas deferens</dc:title><dc:creator>PALANI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHILDYAL, PARA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANCHANDA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>guineapig vas deferens</dc:subject><dc:subject>noradrenaline</dc:subject><dc:subject>gap junction</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbenoxolone</dc:subject><dc:description>We examined the effects of two putative gap junction blockers, heptanol and carbenoxolone, on noradrenaline-induced contractions in guinea pig vas deferens. The force generated due to the exogenously added noradrenaline (20 μM) consisted of two components: the tonic and the oscillatory. 2 mM heptanol abolished the oscillatory contractions and drastically suppressed both the maximum force (by 85.4 ±18.2%) as well as the tonic component (by 28.8 ± 5.1%) (P &lt; 0.01, n = 7). However, the effects of carbenoxolone (50 μM) were strikingly different, with the spikes of the oscillatory component being merged into a steady, “fused” contraction, without affecting the maximum force developed. The L-type Ca2+ channel blocker nifedipine (2 μM) abolished the oscillatory component of the contractions and significantly reduced the maximum force and tonic component (by 82.4 ± 6.8% and 19.7 ± 6.4% respectively; P &lt; 0.01, n = 4), in a manner similar to that elicited by heptanol. Our results indicate that (i) while carbenoxolone specifically blocks gap junctions, heptanol appears to exert its actions through non-gap junctional mechanisms, possibly by blocking VGCCs in smooth muscle; (ii) gap junctions play a significant modulatory role in the generation of noradrenaline-induced contractions in guinea pig vas deferens, particularly in the emergence of oscillatory contractions, while the maximum force developed may be independent of gap junctional contribution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:14:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:29:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:14:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:29:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Autonomic Neuroscience 137(1-2), 56-62</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1566-0702</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.autneu.2007.07.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1238</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1238</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>