<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1235</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of pH and ionic strength on the assembly and bundling of FtsZ protofilaments: a possible role of electrostatic interactions in the bundling of protofilaments</dc:title><dc:creator>BEURIA, TUSHAR K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, JAIMIN H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANTRA, MANAS KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, VINAY</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, DULAL</dc:creator><dc:subject>assembly</dc:subject><dc:subject>circular dichroism</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability criteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>monomers</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrostatic</dc:subject><dc:description>Assembly, bundling and stability of FtsZ protofilaments are important for the formation and functioning of the cytokinetic Z-ring during bacterial
division. We found that the bundling of FtsZ protofilaments decreased strongly with increasing pH from 6.0 to 7.9, while the assembly of FtsZ
monomers did not decrease considerably. In addition, the disassembly of FtsZ protofilaments was strongly suppressed at pH 6.0 as compared to
the elevated pHs. The far-UV circular dichroism spectra of the native FtsZ and the tryptophan emission spectra of mutated FtsZ (Y371W) did not
change by increasing pH from 6 to 7.9 indicating that the structure of FtsZ was not altered significantly. Further, the inhibition of bundling of FtsZ
protofilaments predominantly, and the inhibition of assembly to a lesser extent by salt indicated that electrostatic interactions are important for
the assembly and bundling of FtsZ protofilaments. These observations are supported by the results of computational docking of Escherichia coli
dimer structure. The results suggest that the basic intracellular pH (7.4–7.8) of E. coli may play a role in regulating the assembly dynamics of FtsZ
in the Z-ring by reducing protofilament stability and bundling in bacterial cytoplasm.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:13:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:28:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:13:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:28:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>International Journal of Biological Macromolecules 40(1), 30-39</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0141-8130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2006.05.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1235</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1235</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>