<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16799</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:51:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermo-chemical modelling of a village cookstove for design improvement</dc:title><dc:creator>HONKALASKAR, VH</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOHONI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANDARKAR, UV</dc:creator><dc:subject>biomass cookstove</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermo-chemical model</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomass combustion</dc:subject><dc:subject>twisted tapes</dc:subject><dc:subject>India</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRAW COMBUSTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WOOD PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDUCED SWIRL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENHANCEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>STOVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BED</dc:subject><dc:description>Cookstove operation comprises three basic processes, namely combustion of firewood, natural air draft due to the buoyancy induced by the temperature difference between the hearth and its surroundings, and heat transfer to the pot, stove body and surrounding atmosphere. Owing to the heterogenous and unsteady burning of solid fuel, there exist nonlinear and dynamic interrelationships among these process parameters. A steady-state analytical model of the cookstove operation is developed for its design improvement by splitting the hearth into three zones to study char combustion, volatile combustion and heat transfer to the pot bottom separately. It comprises a total of seven relations corresponding to a thorough analysis of the three basic processes. A novel method is proposed to model the combustion of wood to mimic the realities closely. Combustion space above the fuel bed is split into 1000 discrete parts to study the combustion of volatiles by considering a set of representative volatile gases. Model results are validated by comparing them with a set of water boiling tests carried on a traditional cookstove in the laboratory. It is found that the major thrust areas to improve the thermal performance are combustion of volatiles and the heat transfer to the pot. It is revealed that the existing design dimensions of the traditional cookstove are close to their optimal values. Addition of twisted-tape inserts in the hearth of the cookstove shows an improvement in the thermal performance due to increase in the heat transfer coefficient to the pot bottom and improved combustion of volatiles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:51:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:51:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMBUSTION THEORY AND MODELLING, 18(3)414-453</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1364-7830</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1741-3559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13647830.2014.921730</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16799</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>