<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7251</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel process for precipitation of ultra-fine particles using sub-critical CO(2)</dc:title><dc:creator>DALVI, SV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>compressed fluid antisolvent</dc:subject><dc:subject>ress-sc process</dc:subject><dc:subject>rapid expansion</dc:subject><dc:subject>supercritical solutions</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon-dioxide</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>cholesterol</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixtures</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>zinc acetate</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>depressurization</dc:subject><dc:subject>temperature reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>sub-critical co(2)</dc:subject><dc:subject>gas-expanded liquids</dc:subject><dc:description>Supercritical CO(2) has been utilized as solvent. cosolvent or antisolvent in several processes for production of ultra-fine solid particles with narrow size distribution. The key to the precipitation of such particles is to produce a very large, rapid and uniform supersaturation in the solution of a solid substance. This can be achieved either by a rapid and large reduction in the temperature of solution or by drastically increasing the CO(2) solubility for imparting the antisolvent effect. Most of these CO(2) processes require high-pressure pumps, specially designed nozzles and accurate control of process parameters. In order to obviate these requirements, a simple technique of precipitation by pressure reduction over the gas-expanded liquids (PPRGEL), such as CO(2)-expanded organic solutions has been utilized to impart a large. uniform and rapid reduction of temperature in the solution for instantaneous precipitation of ultra-fine particles. This process utilizes sub-critical CO(2) at relatively low pressures of 40-70 bar and near ambient temperature of 303 K for creating a temperature drop of 30-70 K in the solution within seconds, without using any specially designed nozzle or high-pressure pumps. The present paper validates the process principle for precipitation of Zinc acetate (ZnAc) nanoparticles from its organic solution in a mixed solvent of acetone and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO). Nanoparticles are produced with the average size of 20-250 nm (from 100 ml of solution in a high-pressure vessel of 1.09 L working volume), and vary in shapes such as long needles, rods and near spherical depending on pressure (40-70 bar at 303 K), solid concentration (0.01-0.05 g/ml) and addition of stabilizer. (c) 2009</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T14:45:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T14:45:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POWDER TECHNOLOGY, 195(3), 190-195</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-5910</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.powtec.2009.05.029</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7251</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7251</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>