<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14948</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:59:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of the effect of curvature on sensitivity of bio/chemical sensors based on embedded polymer semicircular waveguides</dc:title><dc:creator>PRABHAKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Embedded C-shaped waveguide</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microchannel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bend radius</dc:subject><dc:subject>Evanescent wave</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optical waveguide biosensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>SU-8 waveguide</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIELD ABSORPTION SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIBER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:description>U-bend optical fiber probes have been shown to be very responsive to refractive index variations around the core, which makes them ideally suited for biosensor applications. Similar U-shaped polymer waveguides have also been fabricated using standard micro-fabrication technology. In the present study, suitable bend radii for such U-shaped embedded polymer waveguide probes have been determined for bio/chemical sensing applications. Although the effect of bend radii have been studied earlier for U-bend optical fiber sensors, such an investigation has not yet been performed for embedded bent waveguides. A single step fabrication procedure was performed to pattern SU-8 photo resist into semicircular C-shaped waveguides (of various bending diameters) interfacing a microchannel network and ending in fiber-to-waveguide coupler structures. The refractive index (RI) sensitivity was found to double as the bending radius was reduced from 2 to 1 mm, however the interaction length did not have any effect on RI sensitivity. The evanescent absorbance per unit length was also found to double, when the bend radius was reduced from 2 to 1 mm. Finally, the efficacy of these 1 mm bending diameter embedded waveguides as evanescent wave absorbance based immuno-biosensors was studied by immobilizing HIgG molecules on the waveguides and allowing FITC tagged GaHIgG molecules to interact with them. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:59:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:59:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSORS AND ACTUATORS B-CHEMICAL, 1711303-1311</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.snb.2012.05.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14948</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>