<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1628</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermo-magnetic history effects in the vortex state of YNi(2)B(2)C superconductor</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOMY, CV</dc:creator><dc:creator>TAKEYA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GROVER, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>flux-line-lattice</dc:subject><dc:subject>2h-nbse2</dc:subject><dc:subject>ceru2</dc:subject><dc:subject>peak</dc:subject><dc:description>The nature of five-quadrant magnetic isotherms for H parallel to a is different from that for H parallel to c in a single crystal of YNi(2)B(2)C, pointing towards an anisotropic behaviour of the flux line lattice (FLL). For H parallel to a, a well defined peak effect (PE) and second magnetization peak (SMP) can be observed and the loop is open prior to the PE. However, for H parallel to c, the loop is closed and one can observe only the PE. We have investigated the history dependence of magnetization hysteresis data for H parallel to aby recording minor hysteresis loops. The observed history dependence Jc(H) across different anomalous regions are rationalized on the basis of superheating/supercooling of the vortex matter across the first-order-like phase transition and possible additional effects due to annealing of the disordered vortex bundles to the underlying equilibrium state.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T17:48:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T17:48:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>25TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON LOW TEMPERATURE PHYSICS (LT25), PART 5: SUPERCONDUCTIVITY,150,-</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-6588</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/150/5/052042</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14952</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1628</dc:identifier><dc:source>25th International Conference on Low Temperature Physics (LT25),Amsterdam, NETHERLANDS,AUG 06-13, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>