<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10301</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>New approach for analysis of cantilever sheet pile with line load</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOEL, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>earth pressures</dc:subject><dc:subject>wall movements</dc:subject><dc:subject>wall friction angle</dc:subject><dc:subject>partial earth pressure mobilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>cohesionless soil</dc:subject><dc:subject>penetration depth</dc:subject><dc:subject>equilibrium equations</dc:subject><dc:subject>displacement</dc:subject><dc:description>Free-standing cantilever sheet pile walls in cohesionless soils subjected to horizontal line load have traditionally been analyzed assuming full active and passive earth pressure mobilization on the sides of the embedded portion of the wall. In the conventional analysis, the vertical equilibrium of forces is not checked and the effect of the wall. friction angle is neglected because of the assumption of a smooth wall. In the present study, the limit equilibrium method has been used to estimate the minimum penetration depth required for a free-standing cantilever sheet pile wall subjected to horizontal line load, by considering the effect of wall friction angle, thereby satisfying all equilibrium conditions and considering the partial mobilization of earth pressures depending on the type and magnitude of the wall movement. The variation of earth pressure mobilization has been taken as a function of the displacement (rotation about both the top and the bottom) of the cantilever sheet pile wall, which in turn also governs the mobilized friction angles. A comparison has been made between the results of penetration depths obtained by the present study and those obtained by existing conventional solutions. New design values in nondimensional form are proposed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL RESEARCH COUNCIL CANADA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CANADIAN GEOTECHNICAL JOURNAL, 43(5), 540-549</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-3674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1139/T06-018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10301</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10301</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>