<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17945</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:34:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>The relevance of commuter and work/school exposure in an epidemiological study on traffic-related air pollution</dc:title><dc:creator>RAGETTLI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHULERIA, HC</dc:creator><dc:creator>TSAI, MY</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHINDLER, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE NAZELLE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUCRET-STICH, RE</dc:creator><dc:creator>INEICHEN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PEREZ, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRAUN-FAHRLANDER, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PROBST-HENSCH, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNZLI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>DAILY MOBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:subject>AREAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>air pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>bias</dc:subject><dc:subject>inhalation dose</dc:subject><dc:subject>mobility</dc:subject><dc:subject>NO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport</dc:subject><dc:description>Exposure during transport and at non-residential locations is ignored in most epidemiological studies of traffic-related air pollution. We investigated the impact of separately estimating NO2 long-term outdoor exposures at home, work/school, and while commuting on the association between this marker of exposure and potential health outcomes. We used spatially and temporally resolved commuter route data and model-based NO2 estimates of a population sample in Basel, Switzerland, to assign individual NO2-exposure estimates of increasing complexity, namely (1) home outdoor concentration; (2) time-weighted home and work/school concentrations; and (3) time-weighted concentration incorporating home, work/school and commute. On the basis of their covariance structure, we estimated the expectable relative differences in the regression slopes between a quantitative health outcome and our measures of individual NO2 exposure using a standard measurement error model. The traditional use of home outdoor NO2 alone indicated a 12% (95% Cl: 11-14%) underestimation of related health effects as compared with integrating both home and work/school outdoor concentrations. Mean contribution of commuting to total weekly exposure was small (3.2%; range 0.1-13.5%). Thus, ignoring commute in the total population may not significantly underestimate health effects as compared with the model combining home and work/school. For individuals commuting between Basel-City and Basel-Country, ignoring commute may produce, however, a significant attenuation bias of 4% (95% Cl: 4-5%). Our results illustrate the importance of including work/school locations in assessments of long-term exposures to traffic-related air pollutants such as NO2. Information on individuals' commuting behavior may further improve exposure estimates, especially for subjects having lengthy commutes along major transportation routes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:34:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:34:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EXPOSURE SCIENCE AND ENVIRONMENTAL EPIDEMIOLOGY, 25(5)474-481</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1559-0631</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1559-064X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/jes.2014.83</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17945</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>