<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16535</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:31:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Phosphorus Complexes of meso-Triaryl-25-oxamaragdyrins</dc:title><dc:creator>KALITA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEE, WZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKANTH, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPANDED PORPHYRIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SMARAGDYRINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANION</dc:subject><dc:description>The aromatic PO2 complexes of meso-triaryl-25-oxasmaragdyrins were synthesized by treating the free base 25-oxasmaragdyrins with POCl3 in toluene/triethylamine at refluxing temperature. The complexes are stable and characterized by X-ray and different spectroscopic techniques. In these complexes, the phosphorus(V) ion was bound to two pyrrolic nitrogen atoms of the smaragdyrin macrocycle and two oxygen atoms in tetrahedral geometry. The X-ray structure revealed that the smaragdyrin macrocycle showed significant distortion upon insertion of a PO2 unit, and the phosphorus atom lies 1.339 A above the mean plane defined by three meso-carbon atoms of the macrocycle. These complexes absorb strongly in the visible region and are 2.5 times more strongly fluorescent than free base 25-oxasmaragdyrins. The smaragdyrin macrocycle becomes electron-deficient upon complexation with a PO2 unit because these complexes are easier to reduce but difficult to oxidize compared to free base smaragdyrins. We designed and synthesized a covalently linked BODIPY-PO2-smaragdyrin dyad and demonstrated efficient energy transfer from the BODIPY unit to the PO2-smaragdyrin unit.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:31:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:31:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 53(17)9431-9438</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-510X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic501629n</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16535</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>