<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1683</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-25T06:41:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Finite-time semistability and consensus for nonlinear dynamical networks</dc:title><dc:creator>HUI, QING</dc:creator><dc:creator>HADDAD, WASSIM M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAT, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>control system synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>lyapunov methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper focuses on semistability and finite-time stability analysis and synthesis of systems having a continuum of equilibria. Semistability is the property whereby the solutions of a dynamical system converge to Lyapunov stable equilibrium points determined by the system initial conditions. In this paper, we merge the theories of semistability and finite-time stability to develop a rigorous framework for finite-time semistability. In particular, finite-time semistability for a continuum of equilibria of continuous autonomous systems is established. Continuity of the settling-time function as well as Lyapunov and converse Lyapunov theorems for semistability are also developed. In addition, necessary and sufficient conditions for finite-time semistability of homogeneous systems are addressed by exploiting the fact that a homogeneous system is finite-time semistable if and only if it is semistable and has a negative degree of homogeneity. Unlike previous work on homogeneous systems, our results involve homogeneity with respect to semistable dynamics, and require us to adopt a geometric description of homogeneity. Finally, we use these results to develop a general framework for designing semistable protocols in dynamical networks for achieving coordination tasks in finite time.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:53:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:35:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:53:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:35:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control 53(8), 1887-1900</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TAC.2008.929392</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1683</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>