<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14046</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:32:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Transient dynamic analysis of higher order sandwich and composite arches</dc:title><dc:creator>MARUR, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>FINITE-ELEMENT ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CURVED BEAMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESPONSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transient dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sandwich</dc:subject><dc:subject>Composite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laminated arch</dc:subject><dc:subject>Curved beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>Higher order theory</dc:subject><dc:description>A higher order refined model with isoparametric elements is proposed to study the transient dynamic response of laminated arches/curved beams. The strain field is modeled through cubic axial, cubic transverse shear and linear transverse normal strain components. As the cross-sectional warping is accurately modeled by this theory, the shear correction factor is rendered redundant. The stress-strain relationship is derived from an allotropic lamina in a three-dimensional state of stress, so that angle-ply laminates can be studied through one-dimensional elements. Consistent mass matrix is constituted for the equation of motion, which is solved by Newmark integration scheme. The higher order formulation is validated with available results and subsequently applied to arches with various curvatures, aspect ratios, boundary conditions, loadings and lamination schemes to evaluate its transient dynamic performance and suitable conclusions are drawn. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:32:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:32:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPOSITE STRUCTURES,93(4)1201-1216</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0263-8223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compstruct.2010.11.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14046</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>