<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2664</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>SAR interferometry for DEM generation and movemnet of Indian glaciers</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, YS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SNEHMANI</dc:creator><dc:subject>ice-sheet motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>radar interferometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>sar interferometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>dem</dc:subject><dc:subject>movement</dc:subject><dc:subject>glaciers</dc:subject><dc:description>Two famous glaciers viz. Gangotri and Siachen were studied for DEM generation and movement usiny ERS-1&amp;2 tandem data. While surrounding areas along the glaciers showed more decorrelation, glacier area showed a very good correlation between two image acquisitions. Contours obtained using ERS-1&amp;2 SAR tandem data closely match with topographic maps of the area. Two-pass differential method was used along with SRTM DEM to study the movement of the glaciers. According to the differential interferogram over Gangotri, 3 fringes equivalent to 8.4 em displacement in the radar look direction were observed, whereas for Siachen the fringes were about 8 which is equivalent to. 22 cm. The estimated DEMs and movements are to be verified using GPS measurements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T17:29:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T17:29:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IGARSS 2004: IEEE INTERNATIONAL GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING SYMPOSIUM PROCEEDINGS, VOLS 1-7: SCIENCE FOR SOCIETY: EXPLORING AND MANAGING A CHANGING PLANET,1128-1131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8742-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16073</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2664</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE International Geoscience and Remote Sensing Symposium,Anchorage, AK,SEP 20-24, 2004</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>