<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12190</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>A phenomenological model to represent the kinetics of growth by Corynebacterium glutamicum for lysine production</dc:title><dc:creator>GAYEN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:subject>multiple substrate environment</dc:subject><dc:subject>microbial-growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequential utilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosynthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>fermentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>overproduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>structured model</dc:subject><dc:subject>corynebacterium glutamicum</dc:subject><dc:subject>lysine trehalose</dc:subject><dc:description>Corynebacterium glutamicum is commonly used for lysine production. In the last decade, several metabolic engineering approaches have been successfully applied to C. glutamicum. However, only few studies have been focused on the kinetics of growth and lysine production. Here, we present a phenomenological model that captures the growth and lysine production during different phases of fermentation at various initial dextrose concentrations. The model invokes control coefficients to capture the dynamics of lysine and trehalose synthesis. The analysis indicated that maximum lysine productivity can be obtained using 72 g/L of initial dextrose concentration in the media, while growth was optimum at 27 g/L of dextrose concentration. The predictive capability was demonstrated through a two-stage fermentation strategy to enhance the productivity of lysine by 1.5 times of the maximum obtained in the batch fermentation. Two-stage fermentation indicated that the kinetic model could be further extended to predict the optimal feeding strategy for fed-batch fermentation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T04:18:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T04:18:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF INDUSTRIAL MICROBIOLOGY &amp; BIOTECHNOLOGY, 34(5), 363-372</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1367-5435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10295-007-0205-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12190</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12190</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>