<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16125</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:57:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Resolving the octant of theta(23) with T2K and NOvA</dc:title><dc:creator>AGARWALLA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAKASH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANKAR, SU</dc:creator><dc:subject>Neutrino Physics</dc:subject><dc:subject>CP violation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Beyond Standard Model</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEUTRINO OSCILLATION EXPERIMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINE-EXPERIMENT-SIMULATOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SILVER CHANNEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIXING MATRIX</dc:subject><dc:subject>MASS MATRIX</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYMMETRY</dc:subject><dc:description>Preliminary results of MINOS experiment indicate that theta(23) is not maximal. Global fits to world neutrino data suggest two nearly degenerate solutions for theta(23): one in the lower octant (LO: theta(23) &lt; 45 degrees) and the other in the higher octant (HO: theta(23) &gt; 45 degrees). v(mu) -&gt; v(e) oscillations in superbeam experiments are sensitive to the octant and are capable of resolving this degeneracy. We study the prospects of this resolution by the current T2K and upcoming NOvA experiments. Because of the hierarchy-delta(CP) degeneracy and the octant delta(CP) degeneracy, the impact of hierarchy on octant resolution has to be taken into account. As in the case of hierarchy determination, there exist favorable (unfavorable) values of delta(CP) for which octant resolution is easy (challenging). However, for octant resolution the unfavorable delta(CP) values of the neutrino data are favorable for the anti-neutrino data and vice-verse. This is in contrast to the case of hierarchy determination. In this paper, we compute the combined sensitivity of T2K and NOvA to resolve the octant ambiguity. If sin(2)theta(23) - 0.41, then NOvA can rule out all the values of theta(23) in HO at 2 sigma C.L., irrespective of the hierarchy and delta(CP). Addition of T2K data improves the octant sensitivity. If T2K were to have equal neutrino and anti-neutrino runs of 2.5 years each, a 2 sigma resolution of the octant becomes possible provided sin(2) theta(23) &lt;= 0.43 or &gt;= 0.58 for any value of delta(CP).</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:57:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:57:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HIGH ENERGY PHYSICS, (7)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/JHEP07(2013)131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16125</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>