<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1623</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Using likelihood L-statistics to measure confidence in audio-visual speech recognition</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMIA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:description>This paper describes recent work on decision fusion in audiovisual speech recognition. lit this work, a novel approach is proposed to combine audio and video channel information in audiovisual speech recognition scenario. We have considered frame-level phonetic classification problem using two single-stream Gaussian Mixture Models. Audio and video streams are adaptively weighted using a cumulative mean of the sample confidence values over past frames in addition to the present sample confidence value. The confidence values for audio and video decisions are computed using an L-statistics (linear combination of order-statistics) of log-likelihoods against phone models. It is shown through various experiments, on a database of about 15000 sentences from large vocabulary continuous speech, that the proposed approach results in better classification accuracy as compared to other approaches.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T01:05:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T01:05:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2001 IEEE FOURTH WORKSHOP ON MULTIMEDIA SIGNAL PROCESSING,27-32</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-7025-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/MMSP.2001.962707</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15563</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1623</dc:identifier><dc:source>4th IEEE Workshop on Multimedia Signal Processing (MMSP 01),CANNES, FRANCE,OCT 03-05, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>