<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6466</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T02:45:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>CROSOWAT - A DECISION TOOL FOR IRRIGATION SCHEDULE</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURTHY, JSR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, MM</dc:creator><dc:subject>simulation-model</dc:subject><dc:subject>water-use</dc:subject><dc:subject>crop</dc:subject><dc:subject>evapotranspiration</dc:subject><dc:subject>root growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>irrigation schedule</dc:subject><dc:description>A numerical model has been developed to predict the soil moisture content over the root zone depth as a function of time and to estimate the irrigation water requirements in humid basins under various management options. An implicit finite difference model for transient one dimensional flow, backed up by routines for computing various components of the field hydrological cycle such as evapotranspiration, effective rainfall, surface runoff, capillary rise, etc. is proposed. The paper describes the assumptions made, theoretical considerations of various submodules; system flowchart, hardware requirements and details of input-output. Comparison of the model predicted soil moisture profiles with the field observations is also given along with the results of numerical experiments carried out with the model in the form of sensitivity analysis for various model parameters. Statistical error analysis is also given to prove reliability of the model for estimation of irrigation water requirements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-24T15:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:00:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-24T15:38:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:00:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>AGRICULTURAL WATER MANAGEMENT, 27(3-4), 203-223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0378-3774</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0378-3774(95)01158-F</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6466</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6466</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>