<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18145</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:18:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Observation of S=1/2 quasi-1D magnetic and magneto-dielectric behavior in a cubic SrCuTe2O6</dc:title><dc:creator>KOTESWARARAO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>YOO, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASGUPTA, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHEN, BH</dc:creator><dc:creator>KIM, KH</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOU, FC</dc:creator><dc:subject>AUGMENTED-WAVE METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINEAR-CHAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SR2CUO3</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LICUVO4</dc:subject><dc:subject>CA2CUO3</dc:subject><dc:subject>SrCuTe2O6</dc:subject><dc:subject>frustration</dc:subject><dc:subject>S=1/2 uniform chains</dc:subject><dc:subject>magneto-dielectric behavior</dc:subject><dc:description>We investigate the magnetic, thermal, and dielectric properties of SrCuTe2O6, which is isostructural to PbCuTe2O6, a recently found, Cu-based 3D frustrated magnet with a cornersharing triangular spin network having dominant first and second nearest neighbor (nn) couplings (Koteswararao et al 2014 Phys. Rev. B 90 035141). Although SrCuTe2O6 has a structurally similar spin network, the magnetic data exhibit the characteristic features of a typical quasi-1D magnet, which mainly resulted from the magnetically dominant third nn coupling, uniform chains. The magnetic properties of this system are studied via magnetization (M), heat capacity (C-p), dielectric constant (epsilon'), and measurements along with ab initio band structure calculations. The magnetic susceptibility chi(T) data show a broad maximum at 32 K and the system orders at low temperatures T-N1 approximate to 5.5 K and T-N2 approximate to 4.5 K, respectively. The analysis of the chi(T) data gives an intra-chain coupling, J(3)/k(B), to be about approximate to -42 K with non-negligible frustrated inter-chain couplings (J(1)/k(B) and J(2)/k(B)). The hopping parameters obtained from the LDA band structure calculations also suggest the presence of coupled uniform chains. The observation of simultaneous anomalies in epsilon'(T) at T-N1 and T-N2 suggests the presence of a magneto-dielectric effect in SrCuTe2O6. A magnetic phase diagram is also built based on the M, C-p, and epsilon' results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:18:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:18:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 27(42)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-648X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/27/42/426001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18145</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>