<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-856</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kinetic investigations of the mechanism of dihydrogen driven catalytic reduction of methylene blue, safranine O, methyl viologen and ferricyanide using platinum carbonyl cluster anions (Chini-clusters) as catalyst</dc:title><dc:creator>SEN GUPTA, NALINAVA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHUR, PRADEEP</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOBLE, MUKESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, SUMIT</dc:creator><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>catalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectra</dc:subject><dc:description>[Bu4N]2[Pt12(CO)24] (1) catalyses the selective reduction of electron acceptors (S), methylene blue (MB+), safranine O (Saf+), methyl viologen (MV2+) and ferricyanide by dihydrogen. Macroscopic rate investigations for the cationic substrates in DMF, and for ferricyanide in DMSO have been carried out. In all cases, kobs is given by k1 [S] + k2, indicating that there are two catalytic cycles. In one of them, the formation of a complex between S and [Pt12(CO)24]2− in the rate determining step (rate constant k1) is followed by electron transfer and/or other fast steps. In the other catalytic cycle, the rate determining step (rate constant k2) involves formation of the solvated cluster anion [Pt12(CO)24]2−. The solvated cluster then undergoes fast reduction by dihydrogen and other reactions. The relative contributions of these two cycles depend on the substrate, and for MB+, Saf+, MV2+ and [Fe(CN)6]3− the contribution of the second cycle is about 99%, 55%, 77% and 97%, respectively. Both k1 and k2 of ferricyanide are about three orders of magnitude smaller than those of the cationic electron acceptors. The rates of reduction of MB+ and Saf+ have also been studied in the presence of added water. Rates increase as the presence of water provides an additional pathway for the reduction of [Pt12(CO)24]2− to [Pt9(CO)18]2−.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-04T11:37:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:28:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-04T11:37:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:28:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Inorganica Chimica Acta 359(12), 3895-3902</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0009-2614</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0009-2614(99)01064-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/856</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/856</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>