<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-454</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>A UPF power conditioner with maximum power point tracker for grid connected variable speed wind energy conversion system</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJU, AB</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>ac-dc power convertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>pwm power convertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>digital signal processing chips</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric current control</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a UPF power conditioner for an optimal extraction of output power from grid connected variable speed wind energy conversion system (VSWECS) is presented. The system consists of a variable speed wind turbine coupled to a permanent magnet synchronous generator (PMSG) through a gear box, two PWM power converters and a maximum power point tracker (MPPT). Output power from PMSG is first converted into DC, inverted and then it is fed to the grid. Both the power conversions are performed at unity power factor and the DC link voltage is maintained constant. PWM rectifier is controlled based on the principle to shape the phase current as phase voltage and PWM inverter is controlled by a hysteresis current controller. The control algorithm is implemented on TMS320F243 DSP and the viability of the scheme is confirmed through experimental studies. The complete system has been simulated for various wind velocities. Typical simulation and experimental results are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-22T05:51:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T23:24:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-22T05:51:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T23:24:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the First International Conference on Power Electronics Systems and Applications, Hong Kong, 9-11 November 2004, 107-112</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>962-367-434-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/454</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/454</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>