<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10122</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>THEORETICAL INVESTIGATION OF PENETRATION CHARACTERISTICS IN GAS METAL-ARC WELDING USING FINITE-ELEMENT METHOD</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, SC</dc:creator><dc:subject>heat-transfer</dc:subject><dc:subject>gma</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>drop</dc:subject><dc:description>In the modeling of the gas metal-are (GMA) welding process, heat inputs to the workpiece by the are and the metal transfers have been considered separately. The heat energy delivered due to the metal transfer has been approximated in the form of a cylindrical volumetric heat source, whose dimensions of the radius and the height are dependent on the molten metal droplet characteristics. The pinch instability theory (PIT) and the static force balance theory (SFBT) of drop detachment have independently been used to obtain the expressions for various characteristics of the drop, i.e., the drop radius, the drop velocity, and the drop frequency at various welding parameters. The occurrence or the nonoccurrence of finger penetration, routinely found in the GMA welding at high welding currents, has been satisfactorily explained by the cylindrical heat source model. The effect of various welding parameters, e.g., the welding current, the wire radius etc., on the weld bead penetration characteristics has been investigated. In this modeling effort, the heat conduction equation has been solved in three dimensions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MINERALS METALS MATERIALS SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T20:21:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T20:21:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS B-PROCESS METALLURGY AND MATERIALS PROCESSING SCIENCE, 26(3), 611-624</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5615</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF02653882</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10122</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10122</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>