<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5790</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>WOMEN ENGINEERS IN INDIA - PRESENT SCENARIO AND CURRENT TRENDS</dc:title><dc:creator>PARIKH, PP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUKHATME, SP</dc:creator><dc:description>An effort has been made on a national basis to collect, compile and analyse information about the participation of women in engineering courses and the engineering profession. Enrollment and participation data have been analysed for statewise and branchwise distributions and trends over the period of study (1975-1990) are indicated. The study is based on a sample population consisting of women who obtained their Bachelor's Degree in engineering during this period from anywhere in the country. It is concluded that the number of women participating in the engineering courses has grown from about 1% in 1975 to over 10% in 1990. However, this increase in the enrollment levels is not reflected in the data from IITs. Some of the other important findings of the study are that the largest number of women engineers is in Kerala, followed closely by Karnataka and Tamil Nadu. Branchwise, the Electrical Engineering and Electronics are the most preferred branches by women.</dc:description><dc:publisher>COUNCIL SCIENTIFIC INDUSTRIAL RESEARCH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T04:56:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T04:56:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SCIENTIFIC &amp; INDUSTRIAL RESEARCH, 53(3), 233-247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-4456</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5790</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5790</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>