<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1673</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>LiTPiC – Light-Trails and Photonic Integrated Circuits: issues of network design and performance</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>integrated optics</dc:subject><dc:subject>integrated optoelectronic</dc:subject><dc:subject>digital arithmetic</dc:subject><dc:subject>digital integrated circuit</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical fibre networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>integrated circuit</dc:subject><dc:description>A recent advance in high-speed networks is the concept of Photonic Integrated Circuits (PICs) on an Indium Phosphide substrate, allowing miniaturization and integration of multiple OE and EO modules in a chip. PICs have the potential to do away with the opto-electronic bandwidth mismatch as well as result in severe cost reduction, hence questioning the need for all-optical networking. In this paper we analyze the impact of this digital optical networking concept by combining PIC technology with an all-optical solution - light-trails, resulting in a new solution called LiTPiC (Light-Trail Photonic Integrated Circuit). LiTPiCs offer the best of both digital and all-optical worlds. By enabling selective (and on-demand) regeneration of the signal, we are able to enhance the reach of all-optical light-trails. In addition, we are able to partition light-trail buses into multiple geographically disjoint sub-buses called PIC-Trails, thus for the first time introducing wavelength reuse within a light-trail. The LiTPiC concept gives PICs a new direction - that of being a technology enabler for next generation services using ROADM (Reconfigurable Optical Add-Drop Multiplexer) architecture and a complementary solution to the light-trail technology.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:13:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:03:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-26T07:13:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:03:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 32nd IEEE Conference on Local Computer Networks, Dublin, Ireland, 15-18 October 2007, 37-44</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-3000-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/LCN.2007.133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1673</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1673</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>