<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14008</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:08:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Multifunctional alginate microspheres for biosensing, drug delivery and magnetic resonance imaging</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASLAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>IRON-OXIDE NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VIVO EVALUATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECOMBINANT CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLUCOSE-OXIDASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENCAPSULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FE3O4</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASSAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEXAMETHASONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMBRANE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetic nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alginate microspheres</dc:subject><dc:subject>Biosensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>MRI</dc:subject><dc:description>This research aims to develop and investigate a multifunctional implantable system capable of biosensing, drug delivery and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) for continuous monitoring, controlled anti-inflammatory drug delivery and imaging, respectively. A glucose biosensor, diclofenac sodium (Diclo) and magnetic nanoparticles (MNP) were used as the biosensor component, anti-inflammatory agent and MRI contrast agent, respectively. MNP were synthesized by the co-precipitation technique and loaded with the sensor and drug components into alginate microspheres using a commercial droplet generator. The multifunctional system was then characterized using optical microscopy, scanning electron microscopy, transmission electron microscopy, X-ray diffraction, vibrating sample magnetometry (VSM) and MRI. The MNP were found to be in the size range of 5-15 nm. The final system, comprising the biosensor, drug and MNP loaded inside alginate microspheres, was found to be in the size range of 10-60 mu m. Biosensing studies indicated an excellent glucose response curve, with a regression coefficient of 0.974 (0-10 mM of glucose, response time: 4 min). In vitro Diclo release shows that MNP loading in alginate microspheres increases the burst release percentage by 11-12% in both 60 and 10 pm particles. However, the duration of release for 85% drug release decreases with MNP loading by 7 and 6 days for 39 the 60 and 10 pm particles, respectively. Super-paramagnetism was confirmed by VSM, with 2.09 and 1.368 emu g(-1), respectively, for the 60 and 10 pm particles, with no hysteresis. MRI showed significant contrast for both sizes. The particles showed an excellent biocompatibility (&gt;80%) for all combinations of formulations. The system shows a great potential for biosensing with concurrent drug delivery and visualization for biomedical applications. (C) 2011 Acta Materialia Inc. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:08:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:08:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA BIOMATERIALIA,7(11)3955-3963</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-7061</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.actbio.2011.06.053</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14008</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>