<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17952</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:38:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of divalent Ba cation substitution with Sr on coupled 'multiglass' state in the magnetoelectric multiferroic compound Ba3NbFe3Si2O14</dc:title><dc:creator>RATHORE, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VITTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>FERROELECTRICITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLARIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEROVSKITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLASS</dc:subject><dc:description>(Ba/Sr)(3)NbFe3Si2O14 is a magneto-electric multiferroic with an incommensurate antiferromagnetic spiral magnetic structure which induces electric polarization at 26 K. Structural studies show that both the compounds have similar crystal structure down to 6 K. They exhibit a transition, T-N at 26 K and 25 K respectively, as indicated by heat capacity and magnetization, into an antiferromagnetic state. Although Ba and Sr are isovalent, they exhibit very different static and dynamic magnetic behaviors. The Ba-compound exhibits a glassy behavior with critical slowing dynamics with a freezing temperature of similar to 35 K and a critical exponent of 3.9, a value close to the 3-D Ising model above T-N, in addition to the invariant transition into an antiferromagnetic state. The Sr-compound however does not exhibit any dispersive behavior except for the invariant transition at T-N. The dielectric constant reflects magnetic behavior of the two compounds: the Ba-compound has two distinct dispersive peaks while the Sr-compound has a single dispersive peak. Thus the compounds exhibit coupled 'multiglass' behavior. The difference in magnetic properties between the two compounds is found to be due to modifications to super exchange path angle and length as well as anti-site defects which stabilize either ferromagnetic or antiferromagnetic interactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:38:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:38:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, 5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2045-2322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep09751</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17952</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>