<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1199</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Variable friction pendulum system for seismic isolation of liquid storage tanks</dc:title><dc:creator>PANCHAL, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANGID, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>fuel tanks</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameter estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>stiffness matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic response</dc:subject><dc:subject>pendulums</dc:subject><dc:description>Earthquake response of liquid storage steel tanks isolated with variable friction pendulum system (VFPS) is investigated under normal component of six recorded near-fault ground motions. The continuous liquid mass of the tank is modeled as lumped masses known as sloshing mass, impulsive mass and rigid mass. The corresponding stiffness constants associated with these lumped masses are worked out depending upon the properties of the tank wall and liquid mass. The governing equations of motion of the tanks isolated with variable friction pendulum system are derived and solved by Newmark's step-by-step method assuming linear variation of acceleration over small time interval. In order to verify the effectiveness of the VFPS in tanks, the seismic response of tanks isolated with VFPS is compared with that of the same tanks isolated using the conventional friction pendulum system (FPS). Furthermore, a parametric study is also carried out to critically examine the behaviour of tanks isolated with VFPS. The various important parameters considered are the tank aspect ratio, the isolation period and initial time period of the VFPS. In addition, the seismic response of tanks isolated with VFPS under trigonometric cycloidal pulses is also investigated. From these investigations, it is concluded that with the installation of VFPS in tanks, the seismic response of tanks during near-fault ground motions can be controlled within a desirable range. Finally, it is also observed that the response of tanks isolated with VFPS under the near-fault ground motions and trigonometric cycloidal pulses matches well only when the isolation period reaches high values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-22T08:59:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-22T08:59:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T21:12:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Nuclear Engineering and Design 238(6), 1304-1315</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2007.10.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1199</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1199</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>