<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-494</identifier><datestamp>2012-01-27T04:01:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel active resonant snubber for single switch unity power factor three-phase diode rectifiers</dc:title><dc:creator>SHUKLA, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>pwm power convertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>electromagnetic interference</dc:subject><dc:subject>feedforward</dc:subject><dc:subject>power engineering computing</dc:subject><dc:subject>power factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>rectifying circuits</dc:subject><dc:subject>resonant power convertors</dc:subject><dc:description>A new active feed-forward snubber for conventional three-phase PWM (pulse width modulated) boost rectifier using single switch operated in discontinuous conduction input current mode (DCM) is proposed. It is a resonant circuit consisting of a switch and passive components and it ensures that the main boost switch will be switched under zero-voltage (ZV) condition. Also, the boost diode operates under soft switching condition. Since the snubber circuit is a resonant circuit, the auxiliary switch itself has a soft turn-on and turn-off, resulting in reduced switching losses and electromagnetic interference (EMI). Performance of the converter circuit is predicted by simulating it on SABER. A laboratory prototype delivering 1 kW power at 245 Volts from 86.6 Vrms (L-L) is designed and developed. The simulation results obtained are verified experimentally.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-24T04:19:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T17:32:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-24T04:19:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T17:32:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE 35th Annual Power Electronics Specialists Conference (V 5), Aachen, Germany, 20-25 June 2004, 3818-3823.</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8399-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/PESC.2004.1355150</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/494</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/494</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>