<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17809</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:54:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ion transport study in polymer-nanocomposite films by dielectric spectroscopy and conductivity scaling</dc:title><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAKUR, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKLA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARX, DT</dc:creator><dc:subject>FREQUENCY-DEPENDENT CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>AC CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISORDERED SOLIDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLASSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROLYTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNIVERSALITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRA</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polymer nanocomposite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electoral properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ion hopping</dc:subject><dc:description>The dielectric and conductivity response of polymer nanocomposite electrolytes (films of PMMA(4)LiClO(4) dispersed with nano-CeO2 powder) have been investigated. The dielectric behavior was analyzed via the dielectric permittivity (epsilon ') and dissipation factor (tan delta) of the samples. The analysis has shown the presence of space charge polarization at lower frequencies. The real part of ac conductivity spectra of materials obeys the Jonscher power law. Parameters such as dc conductivity, hopping rate, activation energies and the concentration of charge carriers were determined from conductivity data using the Almond West formalism. It is observed that the higher ionic conductivity at higher temperature is due to increased thermally-activated hopping rates accompanied by a significant increase in carrier concentration. The contribution of carrier concentration to the total conductivity is also confirmed from activation energy of migration conduction and from Summerfield scaling. The ac conductivity results are also well correlated with TEM results. Published by Elsevier B.V.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICA B-CONDENSED MATTER, 468,50-56</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-4526</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-2135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.physb.2015.04.013</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17809</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>