<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14831</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T11:50:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Virtual Labs in proteomics: New E-learning tools</dc:title><dc:creator>RAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOSHY, NR</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>E-learning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gel-based proteomics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mass spectrometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Proteomics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tutorial</dc:subject><dc:subject>Virtual proteomics labs</dc:subject><dc:subject>LABORATORIES</dc:subject><dc:description>Web-based educational resources have gained enormous popularity recently and are increasingly becoming a part of modern educational systems. Virtual Labs are E-learning platforms where learners can gain the experience of practical experimentation without any direct physical involvement on real bench work. They use computerized simulations, models, videos, animations and other instructional technologies to create interactive content. Proteomics being one of the most rapidly growing fields of the biological sciences is now an important part of college and university curriculums. Consequently, many E-learning programs have started incorporating the theoretical and practical aspects of different proteomic techniques as an element of their course work in the form of Video Lectures and Virtual Labs. To this end, recently we have developed a Virtual Proteomics Lab at the Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, which demonstrates different proteomics techniques, including basic and advanced gel and MS-based protein separation and identification techniques, bioinformatics tools and molecular docking methods, and their applications in different biological samples. This Tutorial will discuss the prominent Virtual Labs featuring proteomics content, including the Virtual Proteomics Lab of IIT-Bombay, and E-resources available for proteomics study that are striving to make proteomic techniques and concepts available and accessible to the student and research community. This Tutorial is part of the International Proteomics Tutorial Programme (IPTP 14). Details can be found at: http://www.proteomicstutonals.orgb (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T11:50:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T11:50:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PROTEOMICS, 75(9)2515-2525</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jprot.2012.03.014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14831</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>