<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2799</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of laterally loaded pile group</dc:title><dc:creator>LAVANDE, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEWAIKAR, DM</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAWANT, VA</dc:creator><dc:description>Analysis of laterally loaded pile group is in reality a three dimensional continuum mechanics problem. It is possible to treat the problem as fully three dimensional in a finite element analysis. Although such a three dimensional analysis is possible, at this time, it can be quite expensive. For the purpose of application in analysis and design, it is preferable to use a procedure that can handle a number of significant complexities, but at the same time, is as simple and economical as possible. In the present paper, a simple straightforward approach is proposed. Beam column element, plate element and spring elements are used for simulation of pile, pile cap and soil, respectively. The group effect is considered by introducing softening factor. Effect of pile spacing, and number of piles in the group on load-deflection behaviour is studied.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A A BALKEMA PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T01:53:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T01:53:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOSHORE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON OFFSHORE AND NEARSHORE GEOTECHNICAL ENGINEERING,321-323</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-5809-211-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16201</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2799</dc:identifier><dc:source>Geoshore International Conference on Offshore and Nearshore Geotechnical Engineering,PANVEL, INDIA,DEC 02-03, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>