<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14553</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:20:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microsolvated transition state models for improved insight into chemical properties and reaction mechanisms</dc:title><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANAND, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLUSTER-CONTINUUM MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAYLIS-HILLMAN REACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIELS-ALDER REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIMETHYL-SULFOXIDE SOLUTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPLICIT SOLVATION MODELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRAGMENT POTENTIAL METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTON-TRANSFER REACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AB-INITIO CALCULATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-SOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Over the years, several methods have been developed to effectively represent the chemical behavior of solutes in solvents. The environmental effects arising due to solvation can generally be achieved either through inclusion of discrete solvent molecules or by inscribing into a cavity in a homogeneous and continuum dielectric medium. In both these approaches of computational origin, the perturbations on the solute induced by the surrounding solvent are at the focus of the problem. While the rigor and method of inclusion of solvent effects vary, such solvation models have found widespread applications, as evident from modern chemical literature. A hybrid method, commonly referred to as cluster-continuum model (CCM), brings together the key advantages of discrete and continuum models. In this perspective, we intend to highlight the latent potential of CCM toward obtaining accurate estimates on a number of properties as well as reactions of contemporary significance. The objective has generally been achieved by choosing illustrative examples from the literature, besides expending efforts to bring out the complementary advantages of CCM as compared to continuum or discrete solvation models. The majority of examples emanate from the prevalent applications of CCM to organic reactions, although a handful of interesting organometallic reactions have also been discussed. In addition, increasingly accurate computations of properties like pK(a) and solvation of ions obtained using the CCM protocol are also presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:20:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:20:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 14(37)12715-12736</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2cp41719g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14553</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>