<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14426</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T12:31:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>A survey of error-correction methods for next-generation sequencing</dc:title><dc:creator>YANG, X</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOCKALINGAM, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALURU, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>error correction</dc:subject><dc:subject>next-generation sequencing</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequence analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>BURROWS-WHEELER TRANSFORM</dc:subject><dc:subject>HUMAN GENOME</dc:subject><dc:subject>READ ALIGNMENT</dc:subject><dc:description>Error Correction is important for most next-generation sequencing applications because highly accurate sequenced reads will likely lead to higher quality results. Many techniques for error correction of sequencing data from next-gen platforms have been developed in the recent years. However, compared with the fast development of sequencing technologies, there is a lack of standardized evaluation procedure for different error-correction methods, making it difficult to assess their relative merits and demerits. In this article, we provide a comprehensive review of many error-correction methods, and establish a common set of benchmark data and evaluation criteria to provide a comparative assessment. We present experimental results on quality, run-time, memory usage and scalability of several error-correction methods. Apart from providing explicit recommendations useful to practitioners, the review serves to identify the current state of the art and promising directions for future research. Availability: All error-correction programs used in this article are downloaded from hosting websites. The evaluation tool kit is publicly available at: http://aluru-sun.ece.iastate.edu/doku.php?id=ecr.</dc:description><dc:publisher>OXFORD UNIV PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:31:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:31:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BRIEFINGS IN BIOINFORMATICS, 14(1)56-66</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1093/bib/bbs015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14426</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>