<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15863</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T15:08:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Linear non-hysteretic gating of a very high density 2DEG in an undoped metal-semiconductor-metal sandwich structure</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS GUPTA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>CROXALL, AF</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAK, WY</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEERE, HE</dc:creator><dc:creator>NICOLL, CA</dc:creator><dc:creator>FARRER, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>SFIGAKIS, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>RITCHIE, DA</dc:creator><dc:subject>2-DIMENSIONAL ELECTRON</dc:subject><dc:subject>HETEROSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GASES</dc:subject><dc:description>Modulation-doped GaAs-AlGaAs quantum-well-based structures are usually used to achieve very high mobility two-dimensional electron (or hole) gases. Usually high mobilities (&gt;10(7)cm(2) V(-1)s(-1)) are achieved at high densities. A loss of linear gateability is often associated with the highest mobilities, on account of some residual hopping or parallel conduction in the doped regions. We have developed a method of using fully undoped GaAs-AlGaAs quantum wells, where densities approximate to 6 x 10(11)cm(-2) can be achieved while maintaining linear and non-hysteretic gateability. The conducting channel of our device is induced entirely by a field-effect mechanism, when suitable voltages are applied to the top and bottom gates. We do not use any intentional dopants at all. Our method overcomes the problem of gating very high density two-dimensional electronic system. We show how these devices are useful for understanding mobility limiting mechanisms at very high densities and indicate the likely future applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:08:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T15:08:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SEMICONDUCTOR SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, 27(11)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0268-1242/27/11/115006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15863</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>