<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4946</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic passive earth pressures in soils</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, KSS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>coefficients</dc:subject><dc:description>Seismic passive earth pressure coefficients were computed by the method of limit equilibrium using a pseudostatic approach for seismic forces. Composite curved rupture surfaces were considered in the analysis. While earlier studies using this type of analysis were mainly for sands, seismic passive earth pressure coefficients were obtained in the present study considering the effects of cohesion, surcharge, and own weight. The minimum seismic passive force was obtained by adding the individual minimum values of these components and the validity of the principle of superposition was examined. Other parameters considered in the analysis were wall batter angle, ground surface slope, soil friction angle, wall friction angle, wall adhesion to soil cohesion ratio, and horizontal and vertical seismic accelerations. The seismic earth pressure coefficients were found to be highly sensitive to the seismic acceleration coefficients both in the horizontal and vertical directions. Results of the study are presented in the form of figures and tables. Comparisons of the proposed method with available theories in the seismic case are also presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T14:14:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T14:14:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF GEOTECHNICAL AND GEOENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEERING, 131(1), 131-135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1090-0241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)1090-0241(2005)131:1(131)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4946</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4946</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>