<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15815</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:43:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of slot cut broadband and dual-band rectangular microstrip antennas</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KADAM, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, KP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Broadband microstrip antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dual-band microstrip antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>Rectangular microstrip antenna</dc:subject><dc:subject>Step slot</dc:subject><dc:subject>Toothbrush-shaped slot</dc:subject><dc:subject>HALF U-SLOT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PATCH ANTENNA</dc:subject><dc:subject>PAIR</dc:subject><dc:description>The broadband and dual-band rectangular microstrip antenna is realized by cutting pair of toothbrush-shaped or step slots along the non-radiating edges of the patch. The toothbrush-shaped slot is said to introduce TM d0 mode in between the TM 10 and TM 20 modes of the rectangular patch and realizes broadband response. In step slot cut configuration, the slot introduces a mode near the TM 10 mode resonance frequency of the patch and realizes dual frequencies. In this paper, a detail analysis to study the effect of slots on the broadband and dual-band response in these rectangular microstrip antennas (RMSAs) is presented. It was observed that the slot does not introduce any mode but modifies the resonance frequency of higher order orthogonal mode and realizes broadband and dual-band response. The slot alters the direction of surface currents at higher order mode and gives similar radiation pattern characteristics over the broader bandwidth and at the dual frequencies. In broadband RMSA, a formulation of resonant length at modified TM 02 mode is proposed. The frequency calculated using the same closely agrees with the simulated result.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MEDKNOW PUBLICATIONS &amp; MEDIA PVT LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:43:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:43:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IETE JOURNAL OF RESEARCH, 59(3)193-200</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.4103/0377-2063.116078</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15815</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>