<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11654</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Multiple feedback loop design in the tryptophan regulatory network of Escherichia coli suggests a paradigm for robust regulation of processes in series</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARTIYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARY, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATESH, KV</dc:creator><dc:creator>DOYLE, FJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>signaling pathways</dc:subject><dc:subject>saccharomyces-cerevisiae</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantitative-analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacterial chemotaxis</dc:subject><dc:subject>gene-expression</dc:subject><dc:subject>operon</dc:subject><dc:subject>attenuation</dc:subject><dc:subject>performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexity</dc:subject><dc:subject>cell</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple feedback loops</dc:subject><dc:subject>robustness</dc:subject><dc:subject>tryptophan system</dc:subject><dc:subject>biological regulators</dc:subject><dc:subject>reverse engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems biology</dc:subject><dc:description>Biological networks have evolved through adaptation in uncertain environments. Of the different possible design paradigms, some may offer functional advantages over others. These designs can be quantified by the structure of the network resulting from molecular interactions and the parameter values. One may, therefore, like to identify the design motif present in the evolved network that makes it preferable over other alternatives. In this work, we focus on the regulatory networks characterized by serially arranged processes, which are regulated by multiple feedback loops. Specifically, we consider the tryptophan system present in Escherichia coli, which may be conceptualized as three processes in series, namely transcription, translation and tryptophan synthesis. The multiple feedback loop motif results from three distinct negative feedback loops, namely genetic repression, mRNA attenuation and enzyme inhibition. A framework is introduced to identify the key design components of this network responsible for its physiological performance. We demonstrate that the multiple feedback loop motif, as seen in the tryptophan system, enables robust performance to variations in system parameters while maintaining a rapid response to achieve homeostasis. Superior performance, if arising from a design principle, is intrinsic and, therefore, inherent to any similarly designed system, either natural or engineered. An experimental engineering implementation of the multiple feedback loop design on a two-tank system supports the generality of the robust attributes offered by the design.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T11:42:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T11:42:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE ROYAL SOCIETY INTERFACE, 3(8), 383-391</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1742-5689</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2005.0103</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11654</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11654</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>