<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11770</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>One, two, and three methylene phosphonic acid groups (-CH(2)PO(3)H(2)) on a mesitylene ring: synthesis, characterization and aspects of supramolecular aggregation</dc:title><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, MP</dc:creator><dc:subject>metal-organic framework</dc:subject><dc:subject>trimesic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid-state</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>organophosphonate</dc:subject><dc:subject>coordination</dc:subject><dc:description>The ease of substitution of -CH(2)Br group on the mesitylene ring in a stepwise manner has been exploited to prepare mesitylene mono-, bis-, and tris-methylene phosphonic acids C(6)H(2)Me(3)(CH(2)PO(3)H(2)) (1), C(6)HMe(3)(CH(2)PO(3)H(2))(2) (2), and C(6)Me(3)(CH(2)PO(3)H(2))(3) (3) in 80-90% yield, through a Michaelis-Arbuzov reaction followed by acid hydrolysis. Compounds 1-4 have been characterized by analytical and spectroscopic (IR, NMR, and MS) techniques. The X-ray structural investigations on all the three compounds reveal that the central mesitylene ring is a robust platform for hosting multiple methylene phosphonic acid groups. Mesitylene mono-methylene phosphonic acid 1, which can be considered as the sterically encumbered modification of benzyl phosphonic acid, interestingly associates as a one-dimensional tubular structure through extensive O-H center dot center dot center dot O hydrogen bonding between adjacent -PO(3)H(2) groups, albeit with no such interactions between the tubes due to the highly hydrophobic nature of the surface. The X-ray structure of mesitylene-1,3-diphosphonic acid 2 reveals that the molecules exhibit a syn-orientation of the -CH(2)PO(3)H(2), which are involved in extensive P-OH center dot center dot center dot O hydrogen bonding to result in a two-dimensional layered structure. The presence of three -PO(3)H(2) units on the same side of the mesitylene ring in 3 results in a three-dimensional framework solid. The present studies clearly reveal a linear relationship between the dimensionality of the supramolecular structure and the number of phosphonic acid moieties on the mesitylene ring.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T15:13:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T15:13:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NEW JOURNAL OF CHEMISTRY, 34(9), 1846-1854</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1144-0546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b9nj00691e</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11770</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11770</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>