<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9240</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hemorheological changes in nephrotic syndrome</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGESWARI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PUNIYANI, RR</dc:creator><dc:subject>blood viscosity</dc:subject><dc:subject>nephrotic syndrome</dc:subject><dc:subject>albumin</dc:subject><dc:description>Hemorheological parameters of childhood nephrotic syndrome cases, in relapse and remission (n = 60 in each group), were studied and their results were compared with those of an equal number of age and sex matched normal children free from any renal disease. During relapse, it was noticed that the viscosity parameters, viz. plasma viscosity, red cell rigidity and whole blood viscosity, were deranged when compared to the values obtained in the remission period. These observations were statistically analyzed using t-test with the level of significance p = 0.05. It was also noted that serum/plasma biochemistry played an important role with regards to the fluidity of blood. During relapse period, fibrinogen level was significantly high, which persisted at a high level even during remission when compared to normal controls. The high cholesterol and triglyceride levels during relapse were responsible for a high plasma viscosity, increased red cell rigidity and thereby contributed directly to a marked increase in whole blood viscosity. Total protein and albumin levels were significantly decreased during relapse when compared to remission period. Hence, hemorheological parameters can be used for early detection of cases prone to relapse and could be of prognostic significance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOS PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:58:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:58:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CLINICAL HEMORHEOLOGY AND MICROCIRCULATION, 19(1), 17-20</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1386-0291</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9240</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9240</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>