<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15200</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:51:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>The JEE conundrum</dc:title><dc:creator>MEHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Coaching classes</dc:subject><dc:subject>entrance and board examinations</dc:subject><dc:subject>normalization of marks</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress on children</dc:subject><dc:subject>undergraduate programmes</dc:subject><dc:description>The Joint Entrance Examination (JEE) conducted by the Indian Institute of Technology (IITs) is under review again. The reasons for this review have to do with the stress that children have to undergo in appearing for multiple entrance examinations and the impact of coaching classes (with the consequent neglect of school attendance and studies). While these issues are real and demand urgent solutions, the ideas put forward by the Ramasami Committee - having a single, all-India examination, and including class XII board examination marks, after due 'normalization', for admitting students to undergraduate science/engineering programmes - are based on questionable premises and superficial analysis, and, if implemented, may well cause more misery than solve the above-mentioned problems. In view of the complexity of the problem, and the constraints imposed by the huge scarcity of 'good' educational opportunities, finding workable and reasonable solutions is difficult. Re-design of the engineering entrance examination system merits a full discussion by the academic community at large and should not be decided by a committee of few people.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:51:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:51:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 103(1)29-36</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15200</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>