<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3518</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>A strategic design approach for optimization of regional hazardous waste management systems</dc:title><dc:creator>NEMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MODAK, PM</dc:creator><dc:subject>disposal</dc:subject><dc:subject>regional hazardous waste management</dc:subject><dc:subject>strategic planning</dc:subject><dc:subject>facility location</dc:subject><dc:subject>waste allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>cost minimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>risk minimization</dc:subject><dc:description>The planning and design of a regional hazardous waste management system involves selection of treatment and disposal technologies and sites, allocation of hazardous waste from generator to the sites and selection of thr transportation routes. To arrive at the optimum configuration of system components, the conventional approach uses the annual waste generation rate as the design criterion. This paper investigates limitations of this design criterion in detail and presents an improved strategic design approach. The strategic design approach is based on the adaptive use of cumulative hazardous waste generation and annual waste generation rates, Experience with the example problem solved shows its superiority over the conventional approach in terms of reduced cost as well as risk. Further, the solution identified by the proposed approach eliminates the possibility of exhaustion of disposal sites during the planning period, and therefore serves as a robust planning tool.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T20:31:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WASTE MANAGEMENT &amp; RESEARCH, 16(3), 210-224</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0734-242X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0734242X9801600303</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3518</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3518</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>