<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1900</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Depth-3 arithmetic circuits for S-n(2)(X) and extensions of the Graham-Pollack theorem</dc:title><dc:creator>RADHAKRISHNAN, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISHWANATHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>fields</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider the problem of computing the second elementary symmetric polynomial S-n(2)(X) =(Delta) Sigma (1 less than or equal toi &lt;j less than or equal ton) XiXj using depth-three arithmetic circuits of the form E-i=1(r) Pi (Si)(j=1) L-ij(X), where each L-ij is a linear form. We consider this problem over several fields and determine exactly the number of multiplication gates required. The lower bounds are proved for inhomogeneous circuits where the L-ij's are allowed to have constants; the upper bounds are proved in the homogeneous model. For reals and rationals the number of multiplication gates required is exactly n - 1; in most other cases, it is [n/2]. This problem is related to the Graham-Pollack theorem in algebraic graph theory. In particular, our results answer the following question of Babai and Frankl: what is the minimum number of complete bipartite graphs required to cover each edge of a complete graph an odd number of times? We show that for infinitely many n, the answer is [(n/2)].</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T13:39:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T13:39:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>FST TCS 2000: FOUNDATIONS OF SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY AND THEORETICAL COMPUTER SCIENCE, PROCEEDINGS,1974,176-187</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>3-540-41413-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15143</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1900</dc:identifier><dc:source>20th Conference on Foundations of Software Technology and Theoretical Computer Science,NEW DELHI, INDIA,DEC 13-15, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>