<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4357</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>High-resolution transmission electron microscopy mapping of nickel and cobalt single-crystalline nanorods inside multiwalled carbon nanotubes and chirality calculations</dc:title><dc:creator>TYAGI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHATAK, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATYAM, PV</dc:creator><dc:creator>LE NORMAND, F</dc:creator><dc:subject>surface-energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>metals</dc:subject><dc:description>The nickel and cobalt nanorods of the diameters in the range of 6 - 20 nm with lengths of 0.29 - 0.9 mu m are formed using multiwalled carbon nanotubes as templates. The nickel and cobalt nanorods as described in our letter are perfect single crystals inside the nanotube with their Miller planes inclined with respect to the tube axis in a particular fashion. The (111) planes of face-centered-cubic nickel and cobalt are inclined at angles 39.6 degrees and 39.4 degrees, respectively, while the hexagonal-closed-packed cobalt (002) planes incline at an angle 53.4 degrees. The inclination of these planes is studied in detail and results are discussed in terms of elastic energy and surface tension. The chirality of the carbon nanotubes, in intimate contact with the nanorod, is determined using the mapping of Ni and C atoms in a graphene sheet. We believe this could pave a way for synthesizing the tubes with known chirality. (c) 2005</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T07:07:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T07:07:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 86(25), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.1953881</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4357</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4357</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>