<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17324</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:35:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulation of Population-Based Commuter Exposure to NO2 Using Different Air Pollution Models</dc:title><dc:creator>RAGETTLI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TSAI, MY</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRAUN-FAHRLANDER, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE NAZELLE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHINDLER, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>INEICHEN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUCRET-STICH, RE</dc:creator><dc:creator>PEREZ, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>PROBST-HENSCH, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNZLI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHULERIA, HC</dc:creator><dc:subject>air pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>model comparison</dc:subject><dc:subject>traffic</dc:subject><dc:subject>travel mode</dc:subject><dc:subject>travel pattern</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERSONAL EXPOSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ULTRAFINE PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITROGEN-DIOXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLACK CARBON</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENVIRONMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLLUTANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>VEHICLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BICYCLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROUTES</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:description>We simulated commuter routes and long-term exposure to traffic-related air pollution during commute in a representative population sample in Basel (Switzerland), and evaluated three air pollution models with different spatial resolution for estimating commute exposures to nitrogen dioxide (NO2) as a marker of long-term exposure to traffic-related air pollution. Our approach includes spatially and temporally resolved data on actual commuter routes, travel modes and three air pollution models. Annual mean NO2 commuter exposures were similar between models. However, we found more within-city and within-subject variability in annual mean (+/- SD) NO2 commuter exposure with a high resolution dispersion model (40 +/- 7 mu g m(-3), range: 21-61) than with a dispersion model with a lower resolution (39 +/- 5 mu g m(-3); range: 24-51), and a land use regression model (41 +/- 5 mu g m (3); range: 24-54). Highest median cumulative exposures were calculated along motorized transport and bicycle routes, and the lowest for walking. For estimating commuter exposure within a city and being interested also in small-scale variability between roads, a model with a high resolution is recommended. For larger scale epidemiological health assessment studies, models with a coarser spatial resolution are likely sufficient, especially when study areas include suburban and rural areas.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MDPI AG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:35:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:35:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH AND PUBLIC HEALTH, 11(5)5049-5068</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1660-4601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijerph110505049</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17324</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>