<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6923</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Relative effect(s) of texture and grain size on magnetic properties in a low silicon non-grain oriented electrical steel</dc:title><dc:creator>PREMKUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAMAJDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANATHAN, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGAL, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHADRI, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>recrystallization texture</dc:subject><dc:subject>lamination steels</dc:subject><dc:subject>sheets</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>permeability</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminum</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>losses</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>texture</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>cold rolled non-grain oriented (crno)</dc:subject><dc:subject>grain size</dc:subject><dc:subject>watt loss and permeability</dc:subject><dc:description>Hot rolled low Si (silicon) non-grain oriented electrical steel was cold rolled to different reductions. Cold rolled material was subsequently recrystallized, 650degreesC and 2 h, and then temper rolled (to 7% reduction) for the final grain growth annealing and decarburization treatment at 850degreesC for 2-24h. The development of texture, grain size and magnetic properties were characterized at different stages of processing. Effect of texture on magnetic properties (watt loss and permeability) was observed to be best represented by the ratio of volume fractions of (I 1 1) &lt;uvw&gt; /(0 0 1) &lt;uvw&gt; fibers, as estimated by convoluting X-ray ODFs (orientation distribution functions) with respective model functions. Such a ratio was termed as generalized texture factor (if) for the non-grain oriented electrical steel. An effort was made to delink effects of grain size and texture, as represented by respective tf, on watt loss and permeability by careful analysis of experimental data. In general, low if and/or high grain size were responsible for low watt loss and high permeability. However, individual effect of grain size or if on magnetic properties was less significant at low tf or large grain size, respectively. An attempt was made to fit regression equations, namely-linear, exponential and power, relating magnetic properties with if and grain size, limiting the fitting parameters to 3. Least standard deviations, between experimental and predicted values, were obtained by power regression equations for both magnetic properties. (C) 2003  .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T14:02:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T14:02:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS, 264(1), 75-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-8853</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0304-8853(03)00142-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6923</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6923</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>