<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15342</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:31:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Estimation and validation of glacier surface motion in the northwestern Himalayas using high-resolution SAR intensity tracking</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOGDA, KA</dc:creator><dc:creator>LARSEN, Y</dc:creator><dc:subject>INTERFEROMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>VELOCITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEPAL</dc:subject><dc:description>We estimate two-dimensional (2D) glacier surface motion using synthetic aperture radar (SAR) X-band intensity tracking. It has been observed that the viability of SAR interferometry (InSAR) is often limited by coherence loss over glaciers in landlocked regions using SAR data pairs of more than 1 day temporal baseline. An alternative to InSAR is the intensity-tracking approach, which relies on intensity cross-correlation for the estimation of subpixel surface motion in range and azimuth direction. In this work, we apply this approach for 2D glacier surface motion estimation in the north-western (NW) Himalayas, using TerraSAR-X (TS-X) spotlight mode high-resolution data pairs of 11, 22, and 33 day temporal separation. The results are in good agreement with total station surveying measurements synchronous with the satellite data acquisition period. The technique is found to be highly appropriate for monitoring the flow rate of glaciers in the Himalayas on a multitemporal basis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:31:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:31:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF REMOTE SENSING, 34(15)5518-5529</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01431161.2013.792965</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15342</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>