<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5018</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling of surface roughness and the role of debris in micro-EDM</dc:title><dc:creator>KIRAN, MPSK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>material removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>machining process</dc:subject><dc:subject>discharge</dc:subject><dc:subject>micro-edm</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface roughness</dc:subject><dc:subject>single-spark</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasma</dc:subject><dc:subject>spark erosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>debris inclusion</dc:subject><dc:description>Surface roughness is one of the important quality characteristic of a micromachined component. This paper presents a model to predict surface roughness of micro-EDmachined surfaces. The model is based on the configuration of a single-spark cavity formed as a function of process parameters. Assuming the normal distribution of surface heights, the mu and sigma (R-q) of the surface profile arc evaluated after every spark. The model was further extended to capture the role of debt-is in inicro-EDM in changing electric potential at the micropeaks on the cathode surfaces. The chemical kinetics approach was used to evaluate the change in plasma enthalpy and composition as a result of debris inclusion in the dielectric. The corresponding energy distribution between the electrodes was used to predict configuration of the single-spark cavity and the consequent surface roughness using the earlier surface roughness model. The modeling results were found to agree well with the inicro-EDM validation experiments performed without and with the inclusion of artificial debris (iron particles) in the dielectric.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASME-AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T18:34:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T18:34:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MANUFACTURING SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING-TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASME, 129(2), 265-273</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1087-1357</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/1.2540683</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5018</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>