<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6810</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Novel approach for the bulk synthesis of nanocrystalline yttria doped thoria powders via polymeric precursor routes</dc:title><dc:creator>GANESAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIVEKANANDHAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GNANASEKARAN, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>PERIASWAMI, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVASA, RS</dc:creator><dc:subject>liquid-sodium</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>combustion synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>solid electrolytes</dc:subject><dc:subject>ceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxygen</dc:subject><dc:description>Three different polymeric precursor routes viz., (i) amorphous citrate process, (ii) Pechini process and (iii) polyethylene glycol assisted process were compared for synthesising nanocrystalline powders of 7.5 mol% yttria doped thoria (YDT). In each of the processes, parameters such as metal-to-fuel ratio or composition of fuel were varied and the effects were analysed. TG/DTA studies were conducted to identify the ignition temperatures of the precursors. Also, a novel experimental procedure with controlled combustion was devised for the preparation of powders based on the thermal analysis data. All the processes result in phase pure and nanocrystalline powders. The average crystallite size of the powders ranged between 9 and 18 nm. The powder samples were analysed for their carbon content and studied for their sinterability. Densities as high as 99% th.d. could be achieved by sintering the compacts of powders obtained from (i) amorphous citrate process with CA/M ratios 2.0 and 3.0, (ii) Pechini processes (independent of fuel composition) and (iii) PEG-assisted process using PEG 4000 at a relatively low temperature of 1500 degreesC for 2 h. (C) 2003</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T23:10:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T23:10:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NUCLEAR MATERIALS, 325(40604), 134-140</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jnucmat.2003.11.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6810</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6810</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>