<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18236</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:08:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dielectric Loaded TM01 to TE11 Mode Converter for S-band Applications</dc:title><dc:creator>CHITTORA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>BACKWARD-WAVE OSCILLATOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH-POWER MICROWAVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTENNAS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GUIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dielectric loaded waveguides</dc:subject><dc:subject>pulse power system</dc:subject><dc:subject>microwave propagation</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, a compact, high efficiency TM01 to TE11 mode converter is presented. In the proposed structure, dielectric material is loaded below a tapered centre conductor, in lower section of a circular waveguide. The input TM01 mode is initially transformed to TEM mode by the tapered centre conductor. The loaded dielectric material is designed to provide the desired phase shift for the mode conversion. Different dielectric materials are analyzed for loading to achieve high conversion efficiency and wide bandwidth. The proposed mode converter is fabricated with PTFE as dielectric for mode conversion and the results are verified through far field radiation pattern measurements. The mode conversion efficiency is more than 90% for 2.95-3.60 GHz band. Due to compactness and high conversion efficiency for wide bandwidth, it is suitable for S-band high power microwave (HPM) applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:08:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:08:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON DIELECTRICS AND ELECTRICAL INSULATION, 22(4)2057-2063</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1070-9878</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-4135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TDEI.2015.005038</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18236</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>