<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13923</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T04:59:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Solid State Polymerization of Poly(L-Lactide): Multiple-Fold Increase in Molecular Weight via an Efficient Catalyst System</dc:title><dc:creator>KATIYAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>NANAVATI, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>MELT/SOLID POLYCONDENSATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MELTING BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>LACTIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYLACTIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERS</dc:subject><dc:description>We report the synthesis of high molecular weight (MW), high crystallinity (X(c)) poly(L-lactic acid) (PLLA), with improved thermal stability, by solid state polymerization (SSP) of low MW PLLA prepolymer, pre-PLLA. SSP enabled pre-PLLA is synthesized by ring opening polymerization (ROP) of L-lactide using a ternary catalyst complex of L-lactide, stannous octoate, and L-lactic acid oligomer (OLLA). We demonstrate that this ROP, although a chain-growth reaction, yields pre-PLLA with end-groups, which enable step growth SSP. MW increases similar to 9 fold, with X(c) reaching beyond 90%, during the SSP process. Such high values of crystallinity could be due to the synchronization of the crystallization rate with that of the slower and longer lasting step-growth SSP. Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy confirms that SSP is indeed a step-growth reaction. In comparison, Zn(OLLA)(2) only couples two pre-PLLA chains during SSP. In addition, the radial spherulite growth rate has been quantified with annealing time of SSP synthesized PLLA. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 51:2078-2084, 2011. (C) 2011 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:59:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:59:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE,51(10)2078-2084</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.22133</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13923</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>