<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5940</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-20T11:37:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>MORPHOLOGICAL TRANSFORMATION OF SYRIAN-HAMSTER EMBRYO CELLS IN PRIMARY CULTURE BY MALACHITE GREEN CORRELATES WELL WITH THE EVIDENCE FOR FORMATION OF REACTIVE FREE-RADICALS</dc:title><dc:creator>PANANDIKER, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, KVK</dc:creator><dc:subject>malachite green</dc:subject><dc:subject>syrian hamster embryo cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>morphological transformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>free radical formation</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron spin resonance (esr) analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>spin-trapping agent</dc:subject><dc:description>Malachite green (MG) (green crystals with metallic luster and very soluble in water) is highly cytotoxic to mammalian cells and also acts as a liver tumor promoter. In view of its industrial importance and possible exposure to individuals, MG poses a potential environmental health hazard. We have studied the effect of MG on the formation of morphologically transformed colonies using Syrian hamster embryo (SHE) cell transformation assay. MG induced a dose-related increase in the formation of transformed foci, the optimum concentration being 0.05 mu g/ml. Electron spin resonance (ESR) analysis using 5,5-dimethyl-1-pyrroline N-oxide (DMPO) as a spin-trapping agent showed the formation of reactive free radicals during the in vitro metabolism of MG. The present study suggests a close relationship between the morphological transformation of SHE cells by MG and the possible involvement of reactive free radical formation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI IRELAND LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T17:43:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T17:43:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CANCER LETTERS, 74(1-2), 31-36</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3835</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0304-3835(93)90040-G</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5940</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5940</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>