<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5146</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Synthesis and modification of dibenzylglycine derivatives via the Suzuki-Miyaura cross-coupling reaction</dc:title><dc:creator>KOTHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEHERA, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>alpha-amino-acids</dc:subject><dc:subject>peptides</dc:subject><dc:subject>reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>chirality</dc:subject><dc:subject>esters</dc:subject><dc:subject>combinatorial chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>dibenzylglycine derivatives</dc:subject><dc:subject>ethyl isocyanoacetate</dc:subject><dc:subject>suzuki-miyaura coupling</dc:subject><dc:subject>unusual amino acid derivatives</dc:subject><dc:description>The objective of this paper is to describe in details of various available methods to prepare C-alpha,C-alpha-dibenzylglycines (Db(z)g) and then include our work involving the synthesis of side chain Db(z)g derivatives. alpha,alpha-Disubstituted amino acids (alpha,alphaAAs) are important members in the family of modified amino acids. Replacement of the alpha-hydrogens of glycine 1 by alkyl groups leads to alpha,alphaAAs. The steric hindrance of the quaternary centre of Aib 2 combined with the helix-forming capacity has attracted the attention of structural biologists and protein crystallographers. Db(z)g 3 is a special structural variant of Aib. The presence of two benzyl groups at C-alpha-position not only impart rigidity to the peptide backbone in which it is incorporated, but also acts as a useful vehicle for studying pi-pi interactions. Although several C-alpha,C-alpha-disubstituted glycines such as C-alpha,C-alpha-diethyl glycine (Deg), C-alpha,C-alpha-dipropyl glycine (Dpg) etc. have been studied in detail, not much has been known about Db(z)g because of limited availability of synthetic procedures. Various Db(z)g derivatives 19a-f have been prepared using ethyl isocyanoacetate 14 as a glycine equivalent (eq.). A useful and simple methodology has been developed using the Suzuki-Miyaura cross-coupling reaction for the modification of Db(z)g derivatives 17d, 19d, 22. Using this 'Building Block Approach' (Accounts of Chemical Research36, 2003, 342) one can generate a variety of Db(z)g derivatives 20a-f and 23a-e, which may find useful applications in combinatorial synthesis and QSAR studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BLACKWELL MUNKSGAARD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-19T02:31:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-19T02:31:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PEPTIDE RESEARCH, 64(2), 72-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1397-002X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/j.1399-3011.2004.00171.x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5146</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5146</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>