<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9757</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>EXPERIMENTAL AND FINITE-ELEMENT STUDY ON STABLE CRACK-GROWTH IN 3 POINT BENDING</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KESHBAT, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>mode brittle-fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress-strain field</dc:subject><dc:subject>tip deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>extension</dc:subject><dc:subject>criteria</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental and finite element results are presented on mode I and mixed mode (involving I and II only) stable crack growth under static loading through an aircraft grade aluminium alloy (D16AT) in three point bending. The results include load-displacement diagrams, J-integrals, plastic zones, tunneling (or crack front curving), etc. During experiment a substantial amount of tunneling is observed, the extent of which increases as the extension progresses in both mode I and mixed mode. The tunneling reduces as a0/w increases. The crack extends initially almost along a straight line at an angle with the initial crack in a mixed mode. The maximum load is observed to be as high as 1.6 times the initiation load in the whole range examined. From the finite element study it is seen that, in a mixed mode, the J-integral at the onset of extension is the lowest compared with the values at the later stages. The plastic zone size grows as the stable extension progresses; the growth is approximately the maximum along the crack extension line. The direction of initial crack extension in a mixed mode can be predicted through an elastic finite element analysis and using the criterion of maximum tangential principal stress. The study also indicates that the load-displacement diagram associated with a mixed mode stable crack growth can be predicted reasonably accurately using the criterion of crack opening angle.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:17:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:17:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>1993</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF FRACTURE, 60(2), 179-194</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0376-9429</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF00012445</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9757</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9757</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>