<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12405</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Field application of phenol formaldehyde gel in oil reservoir matrix for water shut-off purposes</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHILAR, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOUKADI, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>BEMANI, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>field application</dc:subject><dc:subject>gel</dc:subject><dc:subject>oil reservoir</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenol formaldehyde</dc:subject><dc:subject>water shut-off</dc:subject><dc:description>A few wells from a major western India on-shore oil field are either on the verge of being shut in or have already been abandoned due to excessive water-cut (WCT) levels. Low injectivity and extreme temperatures (149C) make it difficult for water shut-off by conventional polymer gel injection. A water-thin monomer-based in situ gelation system has been developed and successfully tried in one of the wells that ceased production due to 100% WCT. The average production of 420 barrel of oil per day (BOPD) with less than 1% WCT, in the first year of production back in 1996, has declined to less than 8 BOPD (with 98% WCT) prior to shut-in in year 2002. A rise in the oil-water contact level in combination with a coning effect was diagnosed as a possible cause of the high WCT, which was later controlled by a newly developed gelant treatment. In fact, the average post-treatment production for the first 3 months was nearly 200 BOPD. Thereafter, production gradually stabilized in the neighborhood of 115 BOPD with a WCT of 48%. Cheap chemicals and a fast treatment method have resulted in a payback time span of 5 days and made an additional profit of U.S. $0.6 M. The water shut-off job resulted in an impressive commercial success; technical success, however, was less than satisfactory due to the fact that, in spite of using a water-thin monomeric solution, only 40% of the designed volume could be injected due to low injectivity resulting in an abnormal pressure build-up. In addition to the gel development and treatment experiences, this article describes in detail the results of further lab investigations carried out to identify the possible reasons causing injection failure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T17:22:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T17:22:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY SOURCES PART A-RECOVERY UTILIZATION AND ENVIRONMENTAL EFFECTS, 30(19), 1779-1787</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1556-7036</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15567030701268476</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12405</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12405</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>