<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-544</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-19T10:53:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mobility degradation due to interface traps in plasma oxynitride PMOS devices</dc:title><dc:creator>ISLAM, AE</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHETA, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAPATRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ALAM, MA</dc:creator><dc:subject>mosfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>plasma devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor device reliability</dc:subject><dc:description>Mobility degradation due to generation of interface traps (Deltamueff(NIT)) is a well-known phenomenon that has been theoretically interpreted by several mobility models. Based on these analysis, there is a general perception that Deltamueff(NIT) is relatively insignificant (compared to Deltamueff due to ionized impurity) and as such can be safely ignored for performance and reliability analysis. Here, we investigate the importance of considering Deltamueff(NIT) for reliability analysis by analyzing a wide variety of plasma oxynitride PMOS devices using both parametric and physical mobility models. We find that contrary to popular belief this correction is fundamentally important for robust and uncorrupted estimates of the key reliability parameters like threshold-voltage shift, lifetime projection, voltage acceleration factor, etc. Therefore, in this paper, we develop a generalized algorithm for estimating Deltamueff(NIT) for plasma oxynitride PMOS devices and systematically explore its implications for NBTI-specific reliability analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-01-05T13:00:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T06:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-01-05T13:00:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T06:49:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Reliability Physics Symposium, Phoenix, USA, 27 April-1 May 2008, 87-96</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2049-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/RELPHY.2008.4558868</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/544</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/544</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>