<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4465</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-06T03:32:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stoichiometry of the diamond/silicon interface and its influence on the silicon content of diamond films</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARDA, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>VAIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIST, HD</dc:creator><dc:creator>VELUCHAMY, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MINOURA, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>ray photoelectron-spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical vapor-deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>polycrystalline diamond</dc:subject><dc:subject>amorphous-carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface</dc:subject><dc:subject>nucleation</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogen</dc:subject><dc:description>Thin films of diamond were grown by microwave plasma chemical vapor deposition at growth pressures of 10, 20, 40, and 60 Torr keeping the substrate temperature constant at 975 degrees C. Increase in the growth pressure reduced the size of the plasma ball resulting in an increase in the microwave power density (MPD). The films were characterized by scanning electron microscopy, micro-Raman, and photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy. A systematic variation was observed in surface morphology and quality of the films. The intensity of the peak at 1.68 eV in the PL spectra of the films, which is assigned to Si impurities was also observed to increase consistently with the MPD. The stoichiometry of the diamond/silicon interface was studied by x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and found to be a sensitive function of the MPD. XPS results showed the formation of nonstoichiometric SiC along with other carbon phases in the initial stages of the growth. A correlation was observed between the composition of the interface and the intensity of the 1.68 eV peak. The above results are explained in terms of the increase in the impingement flux density of atomic hydrogen with the MPD. (C) 1998</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T15:53:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T15:53:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 83(2), 1120-1124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.366803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4465</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4465</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>