<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14079</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:59:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pentacoordinated copper-sparteine complexes with chelating nitrite or nitrate ligand: Synthesis and catalytic aspects</dc:title><dc:creator>INDRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHADURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>SELECTIVE OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>(-)-SPARTEINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BENZALDEHYDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STYRENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPOXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COBALT(II)</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDUCTASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Copper</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sparteine</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPR spectra</dc:subject><dc:subject>Crystal structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Catalysis</dc:subject><dc:description>Copper(II)-sparteine complexes, [Cu(II){(-)Sp}(NO(2))Cl] (1) and [Cu(II){(-)Sp}(NO(3))Cl] (2) (Sp = sparteine) with chelating nitrite and nitrate ligands, respectively, have been synthesized and structurally characterized. The penta-coordinated 1 or 2 exhibits distorted square pyramidal geometry and shows characteristic EPR spectra with g(parallel to): 2.27 and g(perpendicular to): 2.06. 1 and 2 behave similarly towards the catalytic epoxidation of alkenes as well as oxidation of alcohols. Though the epoxidation of cyclohexene using 1 or 2 as a catalyst and tertiarybutyl hydroperoxide (TBHP) as an oxidant at 298 K in acetonitrile results in 100% cyclohexene oxide product, under identical reaction conditions styrene selectively transforms to benzaldehyde (similar to 90%) instead of any styrene oxide. However, at higher temperature (353 K) the selectivity of cyclohexene to corresponding epoxide formation decreases appreciably and additional products, cyclohexanol and cyclohexanone are formed. Furthermore, 1 or 2 effectively catalyzes the oxidation of benzyl alcohol to benzoic acid and cyclohexanol to cyclohexanone in presence of molecular oxygen (O(2)) as an oxidant at 353 K in acetonitrile. (C) 2011 Elsevier B. V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:59:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:59:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANICA CHIMICA ACTA,374(1)415-421</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1693</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ica.2011.03.027</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14079</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>