<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9611</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic response analysis of tube array in partially filled calandria</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOYAL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>tanks</dc:subject><dc:subject>tube array</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic response</dc:subject><dc:subject>calandria</dc:subject><dc:subject>tuned damper tube</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluid-structure interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrodynamic effects</dc:subject><dc:description>An efficient procedure is presented for dynamic response analysis of horizontal tube array in partially filled calandria including hydrodynamic interaction effects. The procedure is general enough to consider the transfer of energy between the fluid-coupled tubes, and effects of moderator sloshing on the magnitude and the distribution of hydrodynamic forces. It has been demonstrated that the conventional added mass approach fails to represent behaviour of the tube array correctly, and it is therefore necessary to consider the flexibility of all the tubes along two directions simultaneously. The procedure presented can simulate the added damping effects due to hydrodynamic interaction. The possible use of a tuned damper tube is suggested for controlling sloshing effects for tube array in a calandria where tube frequencies and sloshing frequencies are closely spaced. The presence of surface damping in the tuned tube further brings down the response, and the suggested procedure can be effectively used to control unwarranted sloshing effects. Copyright (C) 1999 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T20:15:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T20:15:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING &amp; STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS, 28(3), 287-309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-8847</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9845(199903)28:3&lt;287::AID-EQE817&gt;3.0.CO;2-Y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9611</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9611</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>