<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15141</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:22:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modelling and performance of three-phase 6/14 pole flux reversal machine</dc:title><dc:creator>MORE, DS</dc:creator><dc:creator>FERNANDES, BG</dc:creator><dc:subject>PERMANENT-MAGNET MOTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRIVES</dc:subject><dc:description>A three-phase flux reversal machine (FRM) is modelled using the d-q theory. A fictitious 'electrical gear' concept is used to simplify modelling and analysis of this machine. The d-q equivalent circuits are proposed based on this gear ratio. A power density of the machine is improved with full pitch winding. The torque obtained with full pitch winding is twice that of concentrated stator pole winding for same input current. FRM with full pitch winding (FPFRM) is compared with the conventional concentrated stator pole winding FRM (CSPFRM). The results obtained using the proposed d-q circuits are compared with those obtained from FEM analysis. A steady-state performance of FPFRM and CSPFRM is evaluated with proposed d-q circuits. To validate the modelling based on d-q equivalent circuits, a 6/14 pole FRM is fabricated with the conventional concentrated stator pole winding and full pitch winding for wind power application. The analytical results are compared with finite element method (FEM) analysis results and experimental results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:22:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:22:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IET ELECTRIC POWER APPLICATIONS, 7(2)131-139</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/iet-epa.2012.0058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15141</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>