<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17587</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:14:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Solution Precursor Plasma Spray (SPPS) technique of catalyst coating for hydrogen production in a single channel with cavities plate type methanol based microreformer</dc:title><dc:creator>NEHE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIVAKUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>MICRO-FUEL PROCESSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>STEAM REFORMER</dc:subject><dc:subject>REACTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BED</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROREACTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrogen production</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methanol reformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plate type microreformer</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solution Precursor Plasma Spray (SPPS)</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper proposes the development of a new and innovative configuration based on single channel with cavities plate type wall-coated microreformer (dimensions: 90 mm x 50 mm x 30 mm). Microchannels are patterned on the SS plate and fabricated to make a vaporizer unit. The reformer is in the form of two SS plates placed one above the other. The water-methanol mixture enters from the top cover plate and gets vaporised in the channels cut on the vaporiser plate. The mixture then flows through the reformer plates on which the cavities are engraved to enhance mixing of water-Methanol vapors. The catalyst is deposited on the fins of the reformer plates using a new promising technique for depositing nanostructured films namely, Solution Precursor Plasma Spray (SPPS) technique. The performance of the microreformer unit is investigated at various operating conditions of inlet feed flow rate, molar ratio of water to methanol and reforming temperature. The developed microreformer unit is able to generate enough hydrogen to produce a power output of 27 W. The proposed design can also overcome the issue of shape and size of manifolds and ensure equi-flow distribution for multiple microchannel type microreformer designs and appears simple and suitable from fabrication viewpoint. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:14:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:14:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING JOURNAL, 277,168-175</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1385-8947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-3212</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2015.04.121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17587</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>