<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16824</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:03:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Apoptotic cascade inspired lipid nanovesicles show synergism with encapsulated paclitaxel in chemoresistant colon carcinoma</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAM, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESHMUKH, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>colon carcinoma</dc:subject><dc:subject>drug resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>lipid nanovesicles</dc:subject><dc:subject>paclitaxel</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphatidylserine</dc:subject><dc:subject>proapoptotic</dc:subject><dc:subject>P-GLYCOPROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREAST-CANCER</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUG-RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CYTOCHROME-C</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VIVO</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIPOSOMES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHATIDYLSERINE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:description>Inspired from the apoptotic cascade, we developed phosphatidylserine (PS)-based proapoptotic lipid nanovesicles, capable of bypassing drug resistance and exhibiting synergistic anticancer activity with encapsulated paclitaxel in chemoresistant human colon adenocarcinoma (HCT-15). Materials &amp; methods: Nanovesicles were developed and evaluated both in vitro and in vivo for their proapoptotic activity, synergism with encapsulated paclitaxel and ability to bypass drug resistance. Results: 110 +/- 7 nm sized nanovesicles were found to be proapoptotic and synergistic with paclitaxel, and bypassed drug resistance. The formulation, with synergistic inputs from PS and paclitaxel, downregulated Ki-67 and inhibited angiogenesis leading to apoptosis by activating caspase-3 and downregulating Bcl-2, resulting in DNA fragmentation. The nanovesicles, while increasing the systemic circulation time of paclitaxel by 6.9-fold reduced systemic toxic effects of paclitaxel and were found to be nonimmunogenic. Conclusion: These results suggest the therapeutic potential of PS-based proapoptotic nanovesicles encapsulating paclitaxel in chemoresistant human colon carcinoma.</dc:description><dc:publisher>FUTURE MEDICINE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:03:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:03:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOMEDICINE, 9(12)1789-1805</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1743-5889</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1748-6963</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2217/NNM.13.182</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16824</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>