<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-386</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>A circuit theoretical approach to hybrid mode switching control of a pseudo CCM boost converter</dc:title><dc:creator>SREEKUMAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, VIVEK</dc:creator><dc:subject>dc-dc power convertor</dc:subject><dc:subject>control system synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>switching convertors</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage control</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the modeling of a boost converter operating in pseudo continuous current mode using hybrid automaton and proposes the voltage regulation problem as a hybrid control problem. The pseudo continuous current mode (PCCM) operation is treated as an intermediate stage between the continuous current mode (CCM) and discontinuous current mode (DCM) operation of a boost converter. From hybrid perspective, the control problem, the regulation of the output voltage, is framed as a guard selection problem and the guards are defined based on a simple circuit theoretical approach. A typical DC-DC boost converter is selected and the operation of the converter under the proposed control is demonstrated. It is observed that the control thus derived provides a good voltage regulation by operating the converter in a stable limit cycle for a given operating condition. The resulting switching operation has a variable frequency for different operating conditions. The simulation method, analysis and control design are explained and the results are presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-18T04:48:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T16:38:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-18T04:48:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T16:38:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Industrial Technology, Mumbai, 15-17 December 2006, 791-795</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0726-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICIT.2006.372344</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/386</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/386</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>