<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5097</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of rotation, aspect ratio, channel orientation, and rib pitch-to-height ratio on pressure drop and heat transfer characteristics in a rotating channel with ribs on one principal wall</dc:title><dc:creator>ARUN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>rectangular duct</dc:subject><dc:subject>square ribs</dc:subject><dc:subject>roughness</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>friction</dc:subject><dc:description>The present investigation involves the study of the effects of rotation, channel aspect ratio, orientation angle, and rib pitch-to-height ratio on the friction factor and heat transfer in a rotating one-wall-ribbed channel. The rib angle with respect to the mainstream flow direction is 90 degrees. Channels of aspect ratio one and two with two rib pitch-to-height ratios (Ple) of 5 and 10 at a constant rib height-to-hydraulic diameter ratio (elD) of 0.1 are considered. Friction factors are obtained by experimental pressure drop measurements with water as the working fluid and the heat transfer results are obtained by numerical modeling using the v(2)-f turbulence model with air as the working fluid. Experiments are conducted for the Reynolds number ranging from 13,000 to 17,000 with the rotation number varying from 0-0.38. Orientation angle is varied from 0 degrees to 180 degrees in steps of 30 degrees to change the channel orientation for pressure drop measurements. Friction factor ratios of the rectangular channel are slightly higher (around 3-10%) than those of the square channel for a given rotation number, rib pitch-to-height ratio, and orientation angle. Friction factors of a rib pitch-to-height ratio of 5 are higher than those of 10 in both square and rectangular channels at orientation angles of 45 degrees and 90 degrees under conditions of rotation. Numerical prediction of heat transfer distribution is carried out at a constant Reynolds number of 30,000 with rotation number varying within 0-0.3 and three orientation angles of 0 degrees, 45 degrees, and 90 degrees. Under conditions of rotation, it is observed that the square channels oriented at 00, with a rib pitch-to-height ratio of 10 results in higher heat transfer augmentation whereas at 45 degrees 0 and 90 degrees orientation angles, rectangular channels with a rib pitch-to-height ratio of 10 results in higher heat transfer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BEGELL HOUSE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T23:17:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T23:17:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ENHANCED HEAT TRANSFER, 14(1), 27-51</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1065-5131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5097</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5097</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>