<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16818</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:00:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Classification of Melodic Motifs in Raga Music with Time-series Matching</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROSS, JC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULI, KK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDIT, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>ISHWAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLUR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURTHY, HA</dc:creator><dc:subject>raga-characteristic phrases</dc:subject><dc:subject>melodic motifs</dc:subject><dc:subject>machine learning</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYPHONIC MUSIC</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXTRACTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Ragas are characterized by their melodic motifs or catch phrases that constitute strong cues to the raga identity for both the performer and the listener, and therefore are of great interest in music retrieval and automatic transcription. While the characteristic phrases, or pakads, appear in written notation as a sequence of notes, musicological rules for interpretation of the phrase in performance in a manner that allows considerable creative expression, while not transgressing raga grammar, are not explicitly defined. In this work, machine learning methods are used on labelled databases of Hindustani and Carnatic vocal audio concerts to obtain phrase classification on manually segmented audio. Dynamic time warping and HMM based classification are applied on time series of detected pitch values used for the melodic representation of a phrase. Retrieval experiments on raga-characteristic phrases show promising results while providing interesting insights on the nature of variation in the surface realization of raga-characteristic motifs within and across concerts.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROUTLEDGE JOURNALS, TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:00:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:00:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NEW MUSIC RESEARCH, 43(1)115-131</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0929-8215</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1744-5027</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09298215.2013.873470</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16818</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>