<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2409</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Real time simulation of power electronic systems on multi-core processors</dc:title><dc:creator>DIXIT, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDORKAR, MC</dc:creator><dc:subject>educational technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>real time systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>hardware in loop simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>power system simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>parallel programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>parallel processing</dc:subject><dc:subject>processor scheduling</dc:subject><dc:subject>rtos</dc:subject><dc:description>Real-time simulation is an important issue in the design of power electronic systems, especially in the context of hardware-in-loop (Hit) simulation. This paper is concerned with the development of a real-time simulation environment that is low-cost and can be easily set up in an educational laboratory. Any real-time simulation environment needs three essential components: a mechanism to accept a description of the system to be simulated, a digital hardware platform to carry out the simulation, and real-time software to manage the simulation. This paper addresses these three issues from the viewpoint of an educational laboratory setup. Real-time simulation has typically been carried out on complex and specialized multiprocessor systems, running dedicated real-time software. However, the current availability of low-cost, high-speed multi-core digital processor systems has made it possible to use standard computing hardware for this purpose. This has been aided further by the availability of real-time operating systems with multi-core execution capability. This paper discusses the issues involved in setting up a real-time simulator based on multi-core processors, and presents the details of an educational laboratory setup. As an example, the paper shows the simulation of an induction motor drive system. Experimental plots are presented. A timing analysis of the simulation is also presented, along with timing accuracy measurements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T15:00:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T15:00:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>2009 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON POWER ELECTRONICS AND DRIVE SYSTEMS, VOLS 1 AND 2,621-626</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-4166-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15751</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2409</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th International Conference on Power Electronics and Drive Systems (PEDS 2009),Taipei, TAIWAN,NOV 02-05, 2009</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>