<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16007</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:57:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Temporal variability and climatology of hydrodynamic, water property and water quality parameters in the West Johor Strait of Singapore</dc:title><dc:creator>BEHERA, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHUN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PALANI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TKALICH, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Principal component analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Variability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Salinity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Turbidity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chlorophyll-a</dc:subject><dc:subject>West Johor Strait, Singapore</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRINCIPAL COMPONENT ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHORT-TERM VARIABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SAN-FRANCISCO-BAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHLOROPHYLL-A</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEKONG RIVER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHYTOPLANKTON</dc:subject><dc:subject>DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESTUARIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEDIMENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOMASS</dc:subject><dc:description>The study presents a baseline variability and climatology study of measured hydrodynamic, water properties and some water quality parameters of West Johor Strait, Singapore at hourly-to-seasonal scales to uncover their dependency and correlation to one or more drivers. The considered parameters include, but not limited by sea surface elevation, current magnitude and direction, solar radiation and air temperature, water temperature, salinity, chlorophyll-a and turbidity. FFT (Fast Fourier Transform) analysis is carried out for the parameters to delineate relative effect of tidal and weather drivers. The group and individual correlations between the parameters are obtained by principal component analysis (PCA) and cross-correlation (CC) technique, respectively. The CC technique also identifies the dependency and time lag between driving natural forces and dependent water property and water quality parameters. The temporal variability and climatology of the driving forces and the dependent parameters are established at the hourly, daily, fortnightly and seasonal scales. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:57:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MARINE POLLUTION BULLETIN, 77(1-2)380-395</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0025-326X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-3363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2013.09.043</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16007</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>