<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16304</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:00:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic isolation of two dimensional periodic foundations</dc:title><dc:creator>YAN, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>LASKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHENG, Z</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENQ, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>TANG, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>MO, YL</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHI, Z</dc:creator><dc:subject>BAND-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAPS</dc:subject><dc:description>Phononic crystal is now used to control acoustic waves. When the crystal goes to a larger scale, it is called periodic structure. The band gaps of the periodic structure can be reduced to range from 0.5 Hz to 50 Hz. Therefore, the periodic structure has potential applications in seismic wave reflection. In civil engineering, the periodic structure can be served as the foundation of upper structure. This type of foundation consisting of periodic structure is called periodic foundation. When the frequency of seismic waves falls into the band gaps of the periodic foundation, the seismic wave can be blocked. Field experiments of a scaled two dimensional (2D) periodic foundation with an upper structure were conducted to verify the band gap effects. Test results showed the 2D periodic foundation can effectively reduce the response of the upper structure for excitations with frequencies within the frequency band gaps. When the experimental and the finite element analysis results are compared, they agree well with each other, indicating that 2D periodic foundation is a feasible way of reducing seismic vibrations. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:00:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:00:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 116(4)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8979</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7550</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4891837</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16304</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>