<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17322</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:34:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Performance of two fluid model based numeric tool with pressure and enthalpy as independent variables for simulation of two phase flow in axial and radial direction</dc:title><dc:creator>GOKHALE, OS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANIK, BP</dc:creator><dc:description>Several numeric tools have been developed and reported in literature for simulation of two phase flow conditions. Most of the tools make use of the classical homogeneous equilibrium model of two phase flow which is reported to perform better under high pressure conditions with relatively small temperature gradients. System codes such as RELAP make use of two fluid model of two phase flow. Such system codes model the flow of two phases in one dimension in the axial direction. The provision of modeling flow in the direction perpendicular to the axial flow direction exists with the approximation of not considering the flux terms in the momentum equations in the perpendicular direction. This approach is reported to work well for situations with predominant single directional flows. To analyze certain situations with predominant flow in axial as well as radial directions a numeric tool (FLOW) has been developed. The approach employs the same momentum equation for axial as well as radial direction incorporating the flux terms in both directions. The pressure and the enthalpy of the fluid are used as independent variable in the formulation of the tool. The results are found to be in good agreement with 3D CFD simulations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CARL HANSER VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:34:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:34:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>KERNTECHNIK, 79(2)123-127</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0932-3902</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3139/124.110418</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17322</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>