<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16719</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T14:11:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of Interfacial LSMO Nanoparticles/Layer on the Vortex Pinning Properties of YBCO Thin Film</dc:title><dc:creator>JHA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHARE, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>PINTO, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>YBCO thin film</dc:subject><dc:subject>Interface modification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Critical current</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vortex pinning</dc:subject><dc:subject>MULTILAYERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUBSTRATE</dc:subject><dc:description>YBa2Cu3O7-delta (YBCO) thin films have been deposited on bare and La0.67Sr0.33MnO3 (LSMO) modified single crystal SrTiO3 (STO) substrates. The effect of randomly distributed ferromagnetic LSMO nanoparticles and a complete LSMO layer, present at STO/YBCO interface, on the superconducting properties of YBCO thin films has been investigated by temperature dependent magnetization studies. The YBCO thin film on LSMO nanoparticles decorated STO substrate shows significant improvement in the critical current density and pinning force density as compared to the YBCO thin film deposited on bare STO substrate and this improvement is more significant at higher applied magnetic field. However, the LSMO/YBCO bilayer showed the improved flux pinning properties only up to a magnetic field of 1.5 T above which it deteriorates. In the case of LSMO/YBCO bilayer, the underlying LSMO layer gives rise to magnetic inhomogeneities due to domain structure, which leads to improved flux pinning properties limited to lower field. However, in the case of LSMO nanoparticles decorated substrate, the presence of LSMO nanoparticles at YBCO/STO interface seems to introduce magnetic inhomogeneities as well as structural defects, which might be acting as correlated pinning sites leading to improved flux pinning properties of the YBCO thin film over a wide range of applied magnetic field.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:11:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T14:11:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SUPERCONDUCTIVITY AND NOVEL MAGNETISM, 27(4)1021-1026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-1939</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-1947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10948-013-2384-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16719</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>