<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14693</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:33:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of Tb doping on the luminescence characteristics of ZnO nanoparticles</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SPASOVA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>FARLE, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sol-gel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Impurities</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surface groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optoelectronics</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUANTUM DOTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFECTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:description>Structural and optical properties of the Tb-doped ZnO nanoparticles with average diameter approximate to 4 nm have been systematically investigated. Our X-ray diffraction studies show a contraction of the ZnO lattice with the increase of the Tb mole-fraction x for x &lt;= 0.02 and an expansion beyond x approximate to 0.02. The photoluminescence spectra are found to be comprised of a near band edge ultra violet luminescence (UVL) and a broad green luminescence (GL) band. Under the atmospheric condition, the intensity of the GL band is found to increase with the Tb mole-fraction over the entire doping range. On the other hand, under the vacuum condition, it has been observed that the GL intensity decreases with the increase of x up to x approximate to 0.02 but further increase of x leads to a gradual revival of the GL emission. Our study suggests that for x &gt; 0.02, GL results due to the physisorption of certain groups on the surface of the nanoparticles (GL-groups). It is also found that in this Tb mole-fraction regime, Tb incorporates mostly on the surface of the nanoparticles and affects the UVL to GL intensity ratio by influencing the attachment of the GL-groups. However, for x &gt; 0.02, GL originates not only from the GL-groups but also from certain point defects, which are likely to be generated due to the incorporation of Tb in the core of the nanoparticles. A simple rate equation model is introduced to get a quantitative understanding about the variation of the density of the centers responsible for the GL emission as a function of x under the atmospheric and the vacuum conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:33:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:33:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOPARTICLE RESEARCH, 14(2)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11051-011-0676-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14693</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>