<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1245</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>A comprehensive framework for evaluation of piping reliability due to erosion-corrosion for risk-informed inservice inspection</dc:title><dc:creator>GOPIKA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BIDHAR, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>electric resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>structure (composition)</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray diffraction analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric conductivity</dc:subject><dc:description>Risk-Informed In-Service Inspection (RI-ISI) aims at prioritizing the components for inspection within the permissible risk level thereby
avoiding unnecessary inspections. The two main factors that go into the prioritization of components are failure frequency and the
consequence of the failure of these components. The study has been focused on piping component as presented in this paper. Failure
frequency of piping is highly influenced by the degradation mechanism acting on it and these frequencies are modified as and when
maintenance/ISI activities are taken up. In order to incorporate the effects of degradation mechanism and maintenance activities, a Markov
model has been suggested as an efficient method for realistic analysis. Emphasis has been given to the erosion–corrosion mechanism, which
is dominant in Pressurized Heavy Water Reactors. The paper highlights an analytical model for estimating the corrosion rates and also for
finding the failure probability of piping, which can be further used in RI-ISI.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:16:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:33:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-24T09:16:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:33:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Reliability Engineering &amp; System Safety 82(2), 187-193</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0951-8320</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0951-8320(03)00163-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1245</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1245</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>