<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17438</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T11:08:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Frequency effects on microparticle motion in horizontally actuated open rectangular chambers</dc:title><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEILD, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>ACOUSTIC RADIATION FORCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOTAL ANALYSIS SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROFLUIDIC SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLE SEPARATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STANDING-WAVE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MANIPULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microparticle manipulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acoustic streaming</dc:subject><dc:subject>Capillary wave</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acoustic wave</dc:subject><dc:description>The motion of a particle in a liquid subjected to periodic vibrations is determined by its interaction with the periodic (in time) and spatially varying first-order flow field and the ensuing second-order field. The dominating force either allows the particle to collect in stable locations or remain dispersed in the liquid bulk. In this work, we investigate the characteristics of a microparticle's response to these first- and second-order effects across frequencies ranging from 100 Hz to 100 MHz. The movement of sedimented particles is analyzed through the simulation of capillary wave fields and acoustic wave fields in a horizontally actuated open rectangular chamber. The changing effect of the first-order field on the particle's motion, from being the dominant mechanism at low frequencies to being ineffective at the higher frequencies, is demonstrated by considering time-averaged forces acting on the particle, over a cycle. Further, the time-averaged effects of the second-order field, termed as streaming field, are analyzed in both capillary-wave- and acoustic-wave-based collection mechanisms; this analysis provides valuable information regarding the minimum particle size that can be collected in a chamber, through the respective mechanisms. Intriguingly, it is observed that the collection of nanometer-sized particles requires excitation at either end of the frequency spectrum.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER HEIDELBERG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T11:08:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T11:08:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROFLUIDICS AND NANOFLUIDICS, 19(5SI)1209-1219</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1613-4982</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1613-4990</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10404-015-1640-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17438</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>