<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12461</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>An assessment of brightness temperature data quality of MSMR of IRS-P4 satellite</dc:title><dc:creator>RAO, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>AL JASSAR, HK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARVEKAR, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARDUL, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>SABBAH, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>DANIEL, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>soil-moisture</dc:subject><dc:subject>microwave emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>polarization</dc:subject><dc:subject>retrieval</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>ghz</dc:subject><dc:description>Frequency dependence of brightness temperature (T-B) in the range 6 - 21GHz is studied as a function of surface roughness, vegetation cover and soil moisture using theoretical models. Frequency dependence of T-B is plotted from Multi-channel Scanning Microwave Radiometer (MSMR) T-B data of Indian Remote Sensing Satellite (P-series) IRS-P4 for different target types such as ocean, desert, forest, agricultural and snow regions. MSMR responds to the variations of the target parameters; however, it is noticed that the T-B data at 18GHz deviate from the theoretically predicted trend. The effect of atmosphere ( water vapour) is taken into account in the theoretical trend. However, the frequency dependence of T-B plots from Scanning Multi- channel Microwave Radiometer (SMMR) of Nimbus-7 closely resemble the theoretical trend. This indicates that the relative calibration of 18GHz TB of IRS-P4 has some problem and needs to be looked into. Approximate offset values for each land type are computed and presented here. A general comparison of T-B of MSMR and SMMR indicates that T-B of MSMR is higher by 4K, which needs to be further investigated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T21:02:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T21:02:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF REMOTE SENSING, 27(2), 277-292</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0143-1161</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/01431160500180756</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12461</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12461</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>