<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14380</identifier><datestamp>2012-07-17T16:39:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of Spatio-Temporal Variations of Rainfall Pattern in Mumbai City, India”</dc:title><dc:creator>ZOPE P.T.I</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOTHIPRAKASH, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>Rainfall intensity, Return period, Recurrence interval, Intensity-duration-frequency</dc:subject><dc:description>In India, coastal metro cities like Mumbai are becoming increasingly vulnerable to hazards related to extreme events in weather and climate related to global warming including frequent floods and water logging. Thus estimates of rainfall intensities of different durations and recurrence intervals are needed for realistic estimates of floods and for hydrological design. The aim of the present study is to perform statistical analysis of rainfall for various durations and return periods, prediction of maximum probable precipitation for different return periods, and analysis of rainfall trend and intensity pattern for Mumbai city. The records of the observed annual maximum daily rainfall were analyzed statistically for different rainfall return periods (2, 3, 5, 10, 20, 50 and 100 years) during the period 1901 to 2008 for Colaba rain gauge station, 1951 to 2008 for Santacruz rain gauge station and annual maximum hourly rainfall from 1969 to 2008 for both rain gauge stations. The results obtained can be used for effective design of drainage system with different rainfall intensities and return periods at different flooding locations of Mumbai city to mitigate the flooding problem</dc:description><dc:publisher>Jerad Publications</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-07-17T10:20:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-07-17T10:20:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Environmental Research and Development,6(3)545-553</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14380</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>