<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1639</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>RF and microwave dielectric properties of (Zn(0.95)M(0.05))(2)TiO(4) (M = Mn(2+), Co(2+), Ni(2+) or Cu(2+)) ceramics</dc:title><dc:creator>BUTEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAKASH, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>AIYAR, RPRC</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUDHEENDRAN, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAMES, KCR</dc:creator><dc:subject>transition</dc:subject><dc:subject>zn2tio4</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>resonators</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>spinels</dc:subject><dc:subject>zn</dc:subject><dc:subject>ceramics</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>permittivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrical measurements</dc:subject><dc:description>Here, we report our results on the synthesis and properties of pure and 3d transition metal substituted zinc ortho-titanate (Zn(1-x)M(x))(2)TiO(4) dielectrics. Polycrystalline (Zn(0.95)M(0.05))(2)TiO(4) (M = Mn(2+), Co(2+), Ni(2+) or Cu(2+)) samples of sintered density &gt;= 94%, were prepared by ceramic powder mixing and solid state reaction followed by sintering (in air) between 1060 and 1180 degrees C. The XRD patterns of the furnace cooled samples revealed single ortho-titanate tetragonal inverse spinet phase. The SEM micrographs showed fairly uniform grains between 5 and 25 mu m depending upon the composition. Dielectric measurements on the samples were made at low frequencies (1 kHz to 1 MHz) from 30 to 450 degrees C. The dielectric constant (epsilon(r)') and dielectric loss (tan delta), at all the frequencies, were found to rise with progressive increase in sample's temperature albeit the rise being less at higher frequencies (&gt;= 100 kHz). The room temperature values of epsilon(r)' were between 21 and 26 (depending on the 3d M(2+) ion) and remained almost constant in the entire low frequency range &lt;= 100 kHz. Both epsilon(r)' and tan delta were found to decrease with increasing frequency at higher temperatures (&gt;200 degrees C). At microwave frequencies (7.0-7.5 GHz), the room temperature values of epsilon(r)' for all the (Zn(0.95)M(0.05))(2)TiO(4) samples were found to be in the range 18-20 and the unloaded quality factor (Q(u).f) values ranged between 2100 and 9650 GHz. The (Zn(0.95)M(0.05))(2)TiO(4) (M = Mn(2+) or Cu(2+)), samples exhibited over four times improvement in quality factor vis-a-vis pure Zn(2)TiO(4), which is attributed to relative increase in grain size and density in case of Cu(2+), and reduction in tetragonality of the unit cell for Mn(2+) substitution. (C) 2009 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T18:39:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T18:39:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING B-ADVANCED FUNCTIONAL SOLID-STATE MATERIALS,168,151-155</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5107</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2009.11.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14961</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1639</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Specialty Advanced Materials and Polymers for Aerospace and Defense and Applications (SAMPADA-2008),Pune, INDIA,DEC 08-12, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>