<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17795</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:47:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental determination of thermal contact conductance between pressure and calandria tubes of Indian pressurised heavy water reactors</dc:title><dc:creator>DUREJA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAWASKAR, DN</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINHA, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>ROUGH SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:description>Thermal contact conductance (TCC) is one of the most important parameters in determining the temperature distribution in contacting structures. Thermal contact conductance between the contacting structures depends on the mechanical properties of underlying materials, thermo-physical properties of the interstitial fluid and surface condition of the structures coming in contact. During a postulated accident scenario of loss of coolant with coincident loss of emergency core cooling system in a tube type heavy water nuclear reactor, the pressure tube is expected to sag/balloon and come in contact with outer cooler calandria tube to dissipate away the heat generated to the moderator. The amount of heat thus transferred is a function of thermal contact conductance and the nature of contact between the two tubes. An experimental facility was designed, fabricated and commissioned to measure thermal contact conductance between pressure tube and calandria tube specimens. Experiments were conducted on disc shaped specimens under axial contact pressure in between mandrels. Experimental results of TCC and a linear correlation as a function of contact pressure have been reported in this paper. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 284,60-66</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2014.11.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17795</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>