<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11948</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>SIMULTANEOUS NITRIFICATION-DENITRIFICATION IN A ROTATING BIOLOGICAL CONTACTOR</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, AB</dc:creator><dc:subject>rotating biological contactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerobic denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>thiosphaera-pantotropha</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrifiers</dc:subject><dc:description>Simultaneous nitrification\aerobic denitrification studies or a high strength synthetic nitrogenous fertilizer wastewater in a single stage were carried out using a rotating biological contactor (RBC). Mixed culture biofilm consisting of Nitrifiers and Thiosphaera pantotropha (a heterotrophic nitrifer and aerobic denitrifier) was acclimated to 1386 mg 1-1 of TKN &amp; 400 mg l-1 of nitrate nitrogen. The effect of different nitrogen loadings and hydraulic retention times (HRTs) on percentage removal of TKN and nitrate nitrogen simultaneously, was investigated. A maximum TKN removal of 95.6 percent could be achieved at a nitrogen loading of 9.36 gN m-2 d-1 and HRT of 2 days. The results showed that the process is zero order with respect to nitrogen removal. The HRT studied were in the range of 0.5-3 days. The corresponding percentage TKN removal ranged from 43.9-93.7. Nitrate removal of 97-98% could also be achieved simultaneously. Nitrite accumulated significantly throughout these studies. Nitrogen loading and hydraulic retention time were found to be important process control parameters. A theoretical estimation of Nitrifiers and T. pantotropha was also carried out based on nitrification and denitrification rates observed during these studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SELPER LTD, PUBLICATIONS DIV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T03:56:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T03:56:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL TECHNOLOGY, 15(2), 145-153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-3330</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11948</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11948</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>