<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16972</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:12:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hot working and geometric dynamic recrystallisation behaviour of a near-alpha titanium alloy with acicular microstructure</dc:title><dc:creator>BALASUNDAR, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAGHU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Near-alpha titanium alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMI 834</dc:subject><dc:subject>Globularisation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Avrami analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Acicular microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE DEFORMATION-BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLOBULARIZATION KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW-STRESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TI-6AL-4V</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMI834</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRECIPITATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANISMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:description>The hot working behaviour of near-a titanium alloy - TITAN 29A (equivalent to IMI 834) with an acicular starting microstructure was evaluated by carrying out hot compression tests over a range of temperatures (850-1060 degrees C) and strain rates (3 x 10(-4)-10(0)/s). Using the flow curves, processing maps were generated to identify the safe processing window for the material. The material exhibits a deterministic domain between 920 and 1030 degrees C at low strain rates of 3 x 10(-4)-10(-3)/s where it undergoes geometric dynamic recrystallisaton (GDRX) or globularisation of a lamellae. The initiation and evolution of globularisation was investigated using the flow curve analysis method. The work hardening rate (theta)-flow stress (sigma) curve was used to estimate the critical strain (epsilon(c)) required for initiation of globularisation and the saturation stress (sigma(sat)) for dynamic recovery (DRV). The recrystallised or globularised volume fraction (X) was estimated from the difference between the calculated DRV and experimental DRX curves. The estimated globularised volume fraction modelled using Avrami equation was found to match with the microstructural observations. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:12:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING, 600135-144</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2014.01.088</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16972</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>