<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15717</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:54:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of zeolites on thermal decomposition of ammonia borane</dc:title><dc:creator>GANGAL, AC</dc:creator><dc:creator>EDLA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>IYER, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>BINIWALE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASHISTHA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>Ammonia borane</dc:subject><dc:subject>Zeolite-X</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chabazite</dc:subject><dc:subject>Decomposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ball milling</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMICAL HYDROGEN STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCLUSTERS CATALYST</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRAMEWORK</dc:subject><dc:description>Chemical hydrides due to their light weight and high storage capacity are considered to be promising hydrogen storage materials for both mobile and stationary applications. Ammonia Borane (AB) is a novel material with very high hydrogen content (19.6 wt %) per mass. The decomposition of AB takes place in three steps at desorption temperatures of about 100 degrees C, 140 degrees C and above 1000 degrees C respectively releasing 1 mol of hydrogen in each step. The major obstacle towards the use of AB as a hydrogen store is its irreversibility and slow kinetics. With the additives the decomposition temperature could be reduced and the kinetics can be improved. Effect of addition of Zeolites on decomposition of Ammonia Borane at different temperatures is reported in this paper. It was observed that the kinetics behaviour is greatly affected by addition of Zeolites with considerable reduction in the induction or warm-up period. Copyright (C)2011, Hydrogen Energy Publications, LLC. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF HYDROGEN ENERGY, 37(4)3712-3718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2011.04.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15717</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>