<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18225</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:01:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improved Off-Current and Modeling in Sub-430 degrees C Si p-i-n Selector for Unipolar Resistive Random Access Memory</dc:title><dc:creator>MANDAPATI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHRIVASTAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUSHAMA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SCHULZE, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANGULY, U</dc:creator><dc:subject>EPITAXY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RRAM</dc:subject><dc:subject>Emerging memories</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistive random access memory</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon epitaxy</dc:subject><dc:subject>selector device</dc:subject><dc:description>Despite the excellent performance of silicon-based selector devices, high epitaxy temperature (T-epi &gt; 700 degrees C) is the key constraint for Si selector technology compatibility with back-end-of-the-line (BEOL) process. Recently, we have demonstrated the high performance sub-430 degrees C epitaxial Si p-i-n selector. In this letter, we identify a two-step mechanism that affects the off-current (I-OFF) performance of low temperature epitaxial Si p-i-n diodes using molecular beam epitaxy (MBE). First, the Tepi dependent i-region encroachment by surface dopant segregation shows excellent agreement with the surface diffusion model and demonstrates its validity down to 400 degrees C. Second, the trap assisted tunneling model is used to evaluate the impact of the modified i-region thickness (due to surface dopant segregation) on I-OFF. Improved ideality factor (2x) and I-OFF performance (10(2) x) of sub-430 degrees C p-i-n diode is related to contamination control-a critical challenge in BEOL processing. Based on the experimentally validated model, we present the I-OFF dependence on the i-region thickness. We show that i-region thickness of 50 nm produces sufficiently low leakage, while higher i-region produces marginal I-OFF improvement. Thus, the low temperature epitaxial Si p-i-n junction technology is a promising step toward BEOL compatible Si selector technology.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:01:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:01:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE ELECTRON DEVICE LETTERS, 36(12)1310-1313</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0741-3106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-0563</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/LED.2015.2491221</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18225</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>