<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15674</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:32:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>From chemosensing in microorganisms to practical biosensors</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAIN, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>ESCHERICHIA-COLI</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANTIBODY</dc:subject><dc:description>Microorganisms like bacteria can sense concentrations of chemoattractants in their medium very accurately. They achieve this through interaction between the receptors on their cell surfaces and chemoattractant molecules (like sugar). Physical processes like diffusion set some limits on the accuracy of detection, which was discussed by Berg and Purcell in the late seventies. We re-examine their work in order to assess what insight it may offer for making efficient, practical biosensors. We model the functioning of a typical biosensor as a reaction-diffusion process in a confined geometry. Using available data first we characterize the system by estimating the kinetic constants for the binding and unbinding reactions between the chemoattractants and the receptors. Then we compute the binding flux for this system, which Berg and Purcell had discussed. Unlike in microorganisms where the interval between successive measurements determines the efficiency of the nutrient searching process, it turns out that biosensors depend on long time properties like signal saturation time, which we study in detail. We also develop a mean field description of the kinetics of the system.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:32:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:32:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW E, 86(5)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevE.86.051910</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15674</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>