<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1483</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>CIPP - a versatile analytical model for VBR traffic in ATM networks</dc:title><dc:creator>MANIVASAKAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARANDIKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>point</dc:subject><dc:subject>cipp</dc:subject><dc:subject>interarrivals</dc:subject><dc:subject>self-similarity</dc:subject><dc:subject>vbr video traffic modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>atm networks</dc:subject><dc:description>Correlated Interarrival time Process (CIPP) has been proposed in Ref. 1, for modeling both the composite arrival process of packets in broadband networks and the individual source modeling. The CIPP - a generalization of the Poisson process - is a stationary counting process and is parameterized by a correlation parameter 'rho' which represents the degree of correlation in adjacent interarrivals in addition to 'lambda' the intensity of the process. In this paper, we present the performance modeling of VER video traffic in ATM networks, using CIPP/M/1 queue. We first give the expressions for stationary distributions for CIPP/M/1 queue. Then, we derive: the queueing measures of interest. We simulate a queue with smoothed VER video trace data as input (with exponential services) to compare with;he theoretical measures derived above. Experimental results show that the CIPP/M/1 queue, models well the ATM multiplexer performance with the real world VER video traffic input.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T19:15:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T19:15:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PERFORMANCE AND CONTROL OF NETWORK SYSTEMS III,3841,122-129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-3434-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.360362</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15211</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1483</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Performance and Control of Network Systems III,BOSTON, MA,SEP 20-21, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>