<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17958</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:41:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ice-templated synthesis of multifunctional three dimensional graphene/noble metal nanocomposites and their mechanical, electrical, catalytic, and electromagnetic shielding properties</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>AEPURU, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>LITHIUM ION BATTERIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUEL-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FACILE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERCONNECTED GRAPHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>METHANOL OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMICAL-REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANODE MATERIAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSHEETS</dc:subject><dc:description>In-situ homogeneous dispersion of noble metals in three-dimensional graphene sheets is a key tactic for producing macroscopic architecture, which is desirable for practical applications, such as electromagnetic interference shielding and catalyst. We report a one-step greener approach for developing porous architecture of 3D-graphene/noble metal (Pt and Ag) nanocomposite monoliths. The resulting graphene/noble metal nanocomposites exhibit a combination of ultralow density, excellent elasticity, and good electrical conductivity. Moreover, in order to illuminate the advantages of the 3D-graphene/noble metal nanocomposites, their electromagnetic interference (EMI) shielding and electrocatalytic performance are further investigated. The as-synthesized 3D-graphene/noble metal nanocomposites exhibit excellent EMI shielding effectiveness when compared to bare graphene; the effectiveness has an average of 28 dB in the 8.2-12.4 GHz X-band range. In the electrooxidation of methanol, the 3D-graphene/Pt nanocomposite also exhibits significantly enhanced electrocatalytic performance and stability than compared to reduced graphene oxide/Pt and commercial Pt/C.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:41:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:41:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS, 5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2045-2322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep17726</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17958</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>