<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11996</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Carbon source-dependent modulation of NADP-glutamate dehydrogenases in isophthalate-degrading Pseudomonas aeruginosa strain PP4, Pseudomonas strain PPD and Acinetobacter lwoffii strain ISP4</dc:title><dc:creator>VAMSEE-KRISHNA, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHALE, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>chlamydomonas-reinhardtii</dc:subject><dc:subject>allosteric regulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>purification</dc:subject><dc:subject>phthalate</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>enzyme</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>metabolism</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>acid</dc:subject><dc:description>Acinetobacter lwoffii strain ISP4 metabolizes isophthalate rapidly compared with Pseudomonas aeruginosa strain PP4 and Pseudomonas strain PPD. Isophthalate has been reported to be a potent competitive inhibitor of glutamate dehydrogenase (GDH). Exogenous supplementation of isophthalate with glutamate or alpha-ketoglutarate at 1 mM concentration caused strains PP4 and PPID to grow faster than in the presence of isophthalate alone; however, no such effect was observed in strain ISP4. When grown on isophthalate, all strains showed activity of NADP-dependent GDH (NADP-GDH), while cells grown on glucose, 2x yeast extract-tryptone broth (2YT) or glutamate showed activities of both NAD-dependent GDH (NAD-GDH) and NADP-GDH. Activity staining, inhibition and thermal stability studies indicated the carbon source-dependent presence of two (GDH(I) and GDH(II)), three (GDH(A), GDH(B) and GDH(C)) and one (GDH(P)) forms of NADP-GDH in strains PP4, PPD and ISP4, respectively. The results demonstrate the carbon source-dependent modulation of different forms of NADP-GDH in these bacterial strains. This modulation may help the efficient utilization of isophthalate as a carbon source by overcoming the inhibitory effect on GDH.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC GENERAL MICROBIOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:29:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:29:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROBIOLOGY-SGM, 154(), 3329-3337</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1350-0872</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1099/mic.0.2008/022087-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11996</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11996</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>