<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1992</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hysteresis modelling in piezoceramic actuator systems</dc:title><dc:creator>RAGHAVAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>GANDHI, PS</dc:creator><dc:subject>hysteresis</dc:subject><dc:subject>hysteresis modelling</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoceramic</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural shape control</dc:subject><dc:subject>actuator</dc:subject><dc:subject>active control</dc:subject><dc:subject>smart structures</dc:subject><dc:description>Piezoceramics are potential sensors and actuators for a wide range of applications in smart structures and systems, including shape control of radar and satellite antennas, mirrors, and MEMS actuators. Piezoceramic materials are ferroelectric, and they fundamentally exhibit hysteresis characteristics when displacement is plotted against an applied electric field. The maximum error due to hysteresis is found to be as much as 10-15% of the path covered if the actuators are run in an open-loop fashion. These errors affect the performance of the systems in which they are used as actuators. For example, when piezoceramic actuators are bonded with flexible structures for structural shape control purposes, errors of such magnitudes are not desirable. Thus, the nonlinear hysteretic input-output behavior leads to performance degradation of the system in the applications mentioned above. Hence, this work considers modelling of the hysteresis of a piezoccramic-actuated system with a view to develop model-based control algorithms to improve the performance of systems using these elements. Piezoceramic hysteresis has only recently been modelled effectively using the Preisach mathematical model. The system for which hysteresis is modelled is a cantilever beam on which two piezoceramic actuators are bonded and the beam's tip displacement is used as the output parameter. The end purpose is shape control where input variations are quasi-static, hence only the static case of input variation is considered. The predicted results using the model obtained for this system, in general, are in agreement with the experimentally measured values. This work would pave the way for use of the. model for active vibration control purposes, where the input variation is dynamic, using a variant of the Preisach model for the case of dynamic input variation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T23:54:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T23:54:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS, STRUCTURES, AND SYSTEM, PTS 1 AND 2,5062,560-567</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-4868-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.514647</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15272</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1992</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Smart Materials, Structures and Systems,BANGALORE, INDIA,DEC 12-14, 2002</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>