<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13856</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-08T18:52:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Magnetic Exchange Interactions and Magneto-Structural Correlations in Heterobridged mu-Phenoxo-mu(1,1)-Azide Dinickel(II) Compounds: A Combined Experimental and Theoretical Exploration</dc:title><dc:creator>SASMAL, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAZRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANUDO, EC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHANTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE-MAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL-COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAUSSIAN-BASIS SETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPIN GROUND-STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FERROMAGNETIC INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYNUCLEAR COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINUCLEAR COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DI-2-PYRIDYL KETONE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COUPLING-CONSTANTS</dc:subject><dc:description>This investigation presents the syntheses, crystal structures, magnetic properties, and density functional theoretical modeling of magnetic behavior of two heterobridge mu-phenoxo-mu(1,1)-azido dinickel(II) compounds [Ni(2)(II)(L(1))(2)(mu(1,1)-N(3))(N(3))(H(2)O)]center dot CH(3)CH(2)OH (1) and [Ni(2)(II)(L(2))(2)(mu(1,1)-N(3))(CH(3)CN)(H(2)O)] (ClO(4))center dot(H(2)O center dot CH(3)CN (2), where HL(1) and HL(2) are the [1 + 1] condensation products of 3-methoxysalicylaldehyde and 1-(2-aminoethyl)-piperidine (for HL1)/4(2-aminoethyl)-morpholine (for HL(2)), along with density functional theoretical magneto-structural correlations of mu-phenoxo-mu(1,1)-azido dinickel(II) systems. Compounds 1 and 2 crystallize in orthorhombic (space group Pbca) and monoclinic (space group P2(1)/c) systems, respectively. The coordination environments of both metal centers are distorted octahedral. The variable-temperature (2-300 K) magnetic susceptibilities at 0.7 T of both compounds have been measured. The interaction between the metal centers is moderately ferromagnetic; J = 16.6 cm(-1), g = 2.2, and D = 7.3 cm(-1) for 1 and J = 16.92 cm(-1), g = 2.2, and D(Ni1) = D(Ni2) = 6.41 cm(-1) for 2. Broken symmetry density functional calculations of exchange interaction have been performed on complexes 1 and 2 and provide a good numerical estimate of J values (15.8 cm(-1) for 1 and 15.35 cm(-1) for 2) compared to experiments. The role of Ni-N bond length asymmetry on the magnetic coupling has been noted by comparing the structures and J valnes of complexes 1 and 2 together with previously published dimers 3 (Eur. J. Inorg. Chem. 2009, 4982), 4 (Inorg. Chem. 2004, 43, 2427), and 5 (Dalton Trans. 2008, 6539). Our extensive DFT calculations reveal an important clue to the mechanism of coupling where the orientation of the magnetic orbitals seems to differ with asymmetry in the Ni-N bond lengths. This difference in orientation leads to a large change in the overlap integral between the magnetic orbitals and thus the magnetic coupling. DFT calculations have also been extended to develop several magneto-structural correlations in this type of complexes and the correlation aim to focus on the asymmetry of the Ni-N bond lengths reveal that the asymmetry plays a proactive role in governing the magnitude of the coupling. From a completely symmetric Ni-N bond length, two behaviors have been noted: with a decrease in bond length there is an increase in the ferromagnetic coupling, while an increase in the bond lengths leads to a decrease in ferromagnetic interaction. The later correlation is supported by experiments. The magnetic, properties of 1, 2, and three previously reported related compounds have been discussed in light of the structural parameters and also in light of the theoretical correlations determined here.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-02-08T18:52:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-02-08T18:52:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY,50(15)7257-7267</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic200833y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13856</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>