<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14065</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:42:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>A methodology for analysis of impacts of grid integration of renewable energy</dc:title><dc:creator>GEORGE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>Renewable energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Grid integration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Load duration curve</dc:subject><dc:description>Present electricity grids are predominantly thermal (coal, gas) and hydro based. Conventional power planning involves hydro-thermal scheduling and merit order dispatch. In the future, modern renewables (hydro, solar and biomass) are likely to have a significant share in the power sector. This paper presents a method to analyse the impacts of renewables in the electricity grid. A load duration curve based approach has been developed. Renewable energy sources have been treated as negative loads to obtain a modified load duration curve from which capacity savings in terms of base and peak load generation can be computed. The methodology is illustrated for solar, wind and biomass power for Tamil Nadu (a state in India). The trade-offs and interaction between renewable sources are analysed. The impacts on capacity savings by varying the wind regime have also been shown. Scenarios for 2021-22 have been constructed to illustrate the methodology proposed. This technique can be useful for power planners for an analysis of renewables in future electricity grids. (C) 2010 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:42:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:42:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY POLICY,39(3)1265-1276</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-4215</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2010.11.054</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14065</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>