<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14506</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:21:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Blood plasma separation in elevated dimension T-shaped microchannel</dc:title><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHAKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, SG</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Plasma separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Red blood cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microchannel</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bifurcation law</dc:subject><dc:subject>Plasma skimming</dc:subject><dc:subject>T-channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrodynamic separation</dc:subject><dc:subject>RED-CELL DISTRIBUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROFLUIDIC DEVICE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHIP</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROVASCULATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRACTIONATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGGREGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MESENTERY</dc:subject><dc:description>In recent years, microfluidic chips have proven ideal tools for biochemical analysis, which, however, demands a unique and compatible plasma separation scheme. Various research groups have established continuous flow separation methods in microfluidic devices; however, they have worked with relatively small dimension microchannels (similar to the blood cell diameter). The present work demonstrates separation of plasma by utilizing the hydrodynamic separation techniques in microchannels with size of the order of mm. The separation process exploits the phenomenon, which is very similar to that of plasma skimming explained under Zweifach-Fung bifurcation law. The present experiments demonstrates for, the first time, that applicability of the Zweifach-Fung bifurcation law can be extended to dimensions much higher than the suspended particle size. The T-microchannel device (comprising perpendicularly connected blood and plasma channels) were micro-fabricated using conventional PDMS micro-molding techniques. Three variables (feed hematocrit, main channel width, and flow rate distributions) were identified as the important parameters which define the device's efficiency for the blood plasma separation. A plasma separation efficiency of 99.7 % was achieved at a high flow ratio. Novel concepts of 2-stage or multiple plasma channel designs are also proposed to yield high separation efficiency with undiluted blood. The possible underlying principle causing plasma separation (viz. aggregation and shear thinning) are investigated in detail as part of this work. The results are significant because they show nearly 100 % separations in microchannels which are much easier to fabricate than previously designed devices.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:21:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:21:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOMEDICAL MICRODEVICES, 15(3)415-425</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10544-013-9738-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14506</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>