<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14671</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:22:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of Orientation, Thickness, and Composition on Properties of Ductile Iron Castings</dc:title><dc:creator>SHINDE, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>Ductile</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inoculation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orientation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solidification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Wall</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLIDIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:description>In this work, the effects of casting orientation (horizontal, side, and vertical), section thickness (416mm) and composition (Cu, Mn) were investigated on the cooling rate, microstructure, and mechanical properties (tensile strength, yield strength, elongation, hardness) of hypereutectic ductile iron castings. Overall, horizontal castings were found to cool faster than side and vertical castings. Thermal analysis (using cooling curves) showed a wide difference among the four sections. Thinner sections exhibited significant undercooling and thereby carbide formation, leading to poor ductility. The combined effect of Cu and Mn showed an increase in the amount of pearlite to 82% and nodularity to 94% along with a reduction in nodule count to 323 and the amount of ferrite. Also, increased tensile strength (659MPa) and hardness (264 BHN) were observed along with a drop in ductility to 2.5% in 4mm thin section, helping offset carbide formation. Thermal analysis was found to be a useful tool in understanding the combined effect of orientation, thickness variations and processing parameters.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:22:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:22:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS AND MANUFACTURING PROCESSES, 28(5)539-544</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10426914.2012.746701</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14671</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>