<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2769</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>The effect of extent of nitridation on the consolidation of mechanically alloyed Ti-TiN nano-composite powders</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVIKUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DABHADE, VV</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, TRR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>nanocrystalline</dc:subject><dc:description>Titanium - titanium nitride nano-composite powders were prepared by attrition milling of elemental titanium in nitrogen atmosphere. The milling process was carried out at a speed of 450 rpm for 75 hours and interrupted at regular intervals of 15 hours to characterize the powders. The powders milled for various durations were characterized by X-ray diffraction (XRD), Scanning electron microscopy (SEM), Transmission electron microscopy (TEM), Inductively coupled plasma atomic emission spectroscopy (ICP-AES) and X-ray fluorescence spectroscopy (XRF) for the determination of formation of phases, particle shape and size, impurity pickup and the extent of nitridation. The nano-composite powders of varying extent of nitridation were then uniaxially cold compacted and sintered in argon atmosphere to find out the effect of extent of nitridation on the compaction and sintering behaviour of the Ti-TiN nano-composite powders.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SCIENCE PUBLISHERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T23:05:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T23:05:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRENDS IN MECHANICAL ALLOYING,61-69</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-57808-211-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16158</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2769</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Trends in Mechanical Alloying,JAIPUR, INDIA,FEB , 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>