<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15558</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:34:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>ZEOLITIZATION CHARACTERISTICS OF FLY ASHES FROM WET- AND DRY- DISPOSAL SYSTEMS</dc:title><dc:creator>JHA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>alkali activation</dc:subject><dc:subject>lagoon ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>hopper ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>fly ash zeolites</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZEOLITE SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAGOON ASH</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROTHERMAL SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION</dc:subject><dc:description>The fly ash disposal at thermal power plants is either through wet- or dry-disposal systems. As these disposal practices result in different characteristics for the fly ashes, their interaction with alkalis, and hence the zeolitization potential, will be different. In order to demonstrate this, investigations were conducted to study the physical, chemical, mineralogical and morphological characteristics of the residues of the fly ashes collected from the lagoons and hoppers of the same thermal power plant, after their hydrothermal treatment. Field-emission-gun scanning electron microscopy and X-ray diffraction analysis of these residues demonstrated that the hopper ash attains an exceptionally high cation-exchange capacity and SiO2I Al2O3 ratios (SAR), which correspond to the formation of major fly ash zeolites as compared to its counterpart. In other words, the study presented here helps to establish the superiority of hopper ash over lagoon ash for synthesizing fly ash zeolites and their enhanced quantity and quality.</dc:description><dc:publisher>UNIV MARIBOR</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:34:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:34:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA GEOTECHNICA SLOVENICA, 9(2)62-71</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15558</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>