<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-650</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nonlinear predictive control of irregularly sampled multirate systems using blackbox observers</dc:title><dc:creator>SRINIVASARAO, MEKA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARDHAN, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDI, RD</dc:creator><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>error analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>data reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>estimation</dc:subject><dc:description>This work aims the development of an inferential nonlinear model predictive control (NMPC) scheme based on a nonlinear fast rate model that is identified from irregularly sampled multirate data, which is corrupted with unmeasured disturbances and measurement noise. The model identification is carried out in two steps. In the first step, a MISO fast rate nonlinear output error (NOE) model is identified from the irregularly sampled output data. In the second step, a time varying nonlinear auto-regressive (NAR) type model is developed using the residuals generated in the first step. The deterministic and stochastic components of the observer are parameterized using generalized ortho-normal basis filters (GOBF). The identified NOE and NAR models are combined to form MISO state observers. We then proceed to use these identified observers to formulate a nonlinear MPC strategy for controlling irregularly sampled multirate systems. The identified observers are used to generate inter-sample estimates of the irregularly sampled outputs and for performing future trajectory predictions. The efficacy of the proposed modeling and control scheme is demonstrated using simulations on a benchmark continuous fermentation process. This process exhibits input multiplicity and change in the sign of steady state gain in the operating region. The validity of the proposed modeling and control scheme is also established by conducting identification and control experiments on a laboratory scale heater-mixer setup. The proposed NMPC gives satisfactory regulatory as well as servo performance over a wide operating range in the irregularly sampled multirate scenario.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-16T07:04:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:55:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-16T07:04:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:55:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Process Control 17(1), 17-35</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-1524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jprocont.2006.08.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/650</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/650</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>