<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9574</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>A gradientless technique for optimal distribution of piezoelectric material for structural control</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SP</dc:creator><dc:subject>shape control</dc:subject><dc:subject>pzt actuators</dc:subject><dc:subject>beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>placement</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>smart materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural control</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal transducer shapes</dc:subject><dc:subject>gradientless techniques</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage residuals</dc:subject><dc:subject>modal transducers</dc:subject><dc:description>Application of smart piezoelectric materials in structural control is gaining momentum. Optimum placement and actuation of the smart material is an aspect of paramount importance in such structures. In this paper, we present an iterative technique to optimize the shape of piezoelectric actuators in order to achieve the desired shape of the structure. A C-0-continuous eight-node plate finite element with five degrees of freedom is employed. A gradientless shape design procedure based on the residual voltages is developed. It aims at minimizing the quadratic measure of the global displacement residual error between the desired and the current structural configuration. The actuators gradually adapt to a shape that is most efficient in resisting the external excitation. The present technique can be well suited for any static and time-varying excitation. In vibration control it is often necessary to create modal sensors and actuators in order to observe or excite some specific modes. Such modal sensors and actuators alleviate spillover problems and thus they avoid exhaustive signal processing. Several numerical examples for static as well as dynamic cases are presented to demonstrate the efficacy of the present technique. Copyright (C) 2003 John Wiley Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:33:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:33:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL FOR NUMERICAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING, 57(12), 1737-1753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5981</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/nme.743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9574</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9574</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>