<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14678</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:25:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>A comprehensive method to find RPO trajectory and incentive scheme for promotion of renewable energy in India with study of impact of RPO on tariff</dc:title><dc:creator>SHEREEF, RM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:subject>Renewable Purchase Obligation trajectory</dc:subject><dc:subject>Renewable Energy Incentive scheme</dc:subject><dc:subject>Impact of RPO on tariff</dc:subject><dc:description>Renewable Purchase Obligation (RPO) regime in India started in 2011 with the announcement of benchmark RPO (BRPO) of states for the Financial Year (FY) 2011 by respective State Electricity Regulatory Commissions (SERC), to promote Renewable Energy (RE). The report submitted to Forum of Regulators (FoR) in this regard has recommended uniform rate of increase of BRPO of states and studied the impact of RPO on tariff for FY 2011-2015. However, more rigorous analysis is needed for fixing BRPO in a scientific manner and for fair allocation of incentives to promote RE. This paper attempts to evaluate all states on a common platform to find BRPO, giving due weightage to the state-wise energy demand and RE generation, ensuring minimum change in BRPO of consecutive years and hence less impact of RPO on tariff. To encourage the states to align their actual RPO with BRPO, a financial incentive scheme is proposed giving due weightage to RE consumption, RE capacity addition and RPO compliance of the states. The methods are illustrated for the Indian states using real system data. A study of RPO's impact on electricity tariff of Indian states is also conducted and reported for FY 2011-2015, considering Renewable Energy Certificate (REC). (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:25:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:25:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENERGY POLICY, 61686-696</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0301-4215</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-6777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enpol.2013.06.039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14678</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>