<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14990</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:21:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Imino-Phenolic-Pyridyl Conjugates of Calix[4]arene (L-1 and L-2) as Primary Fluorescence Switch-on Sensors for Zn2+ in Solution and in HeLa Cells and the Recognition of Pyrophosphate and ATP by [ZnL2]</dc:title><dc:creator>PATHAK, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>HINGE, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, CP</dc:creator><dc:subject>LOWER RIM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SELECTIVE RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTRACELLULAR ZINC</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANION RECOGNITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LABILE ZINC</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VIVO</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOSPHATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:description>Pyridyl-based triazole-linked calix[4]arene conjugates, viz. L-1 and L-2, were synthesized and characterized. These two conjugates were shown to be selective and sensitive for Zn2+ among the 12 metal ions studied in HEPES buffer medium by fluorescence, absorption, and visual color change with the detection limit of similar to 31and similar to 112 ppb, respectively, by L-1 and L-2. Moreover, the utility of the conjugates L-1 and L-2 in showing the zinc recognition in live cells has also been demonstrateCI using He La cells as monitored by fluorescence imaging. The zinc complexes of L-1 and L-2 were isolated, and the structure of [ZnL1] has been established by single-crystal XRD and that of [ZnL2] by DFT calculations. TDDFT calculations were performed in order to demonstrate the electronic properties of receptors and their zinc complexes. The isolated zinc complexes, viz. [ZnL1] and [ZnL2], have been used as molecular tools for the recognition of anions on the basis of their binding affinities toward Zn2+. [ZnL2] was found to be sensitive and selective toward phosphate-bearing ions and molecules and in particular to pyrophosphate (PP and ATP among the other 18 anions studied; however, [ZnL1] was not sensitive toward any of the anions studied. The selectivity has been shown on the basis of the changes observed in the emission and absorption spectral studies through the removal of Zn2+ from [ZnL2] by PPi. Thus, [ZnL2] has been shown to detect PPi up to 278 +/- 10 ppb at pH 7.4 in aqueous methanolic (1/2 v/v) HEPES buffer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:21:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:21:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 51(9)4994-5005</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic202426v</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14990</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>