<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13888</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T04:41:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Shear Properties of Acrylic Under High Strain Rate Loading</dc:title><dc:creator>GELU, TA</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:subject>MATRIX COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRENGTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPOXY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TORSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECIMEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FAILURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TENSILE</dc:subject><dc:subject>acrylic</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear</dc:subject><dc:subject>stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>strain</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:description>Acrylic is being used in structural applications because of its higher resistance to projectile impacts. High strain rate shear loading is one of the critical conditions. In the present study, properties of typical acrylic under high strain rate shear loading are presented. Torsional Split Hopkinson Bar apparatus was used for the studies in the shear strain rate range of 290 per sec to 791 per sec. Thin-walled tubular specimens with hexagonal flanges were used for the experimental studies. Details of specimen configuration, data acquisition, and processing are presented. Shear strength is presented as a function of shear strain rate. It is observed that the shear strength at high strain rate is enhanced up to 25% compared with that at quasi-static loading in the range of parameters considered. Comparison of torque versus time behavior derived from signals obtained from strain gauges mounted on incident bar and transmitter bar is also presented. (C) 2011 Wiley Periodicals, Inc. J Appl Polym Sci 121: 1631-1639, 2011</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:41:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T04:41:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED POLYMER SCIENCE,121(3)1631-1639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8995</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/app.33719</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13888</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>