<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15469</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:46:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimal MSE solution for a decision feedback equalizer</dc:title><dc:creator>KAVITHA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, V</dc:creator><dc:description>Due to the inherent feedback in a decision feedback equalizer (DFE) the minimum mean square error (MMSE) or Wiener solution is not known exactly. The main difficulty in such analysis is due to the propagation of the decision errors, which occur because of the feedback. Thus in literature, these errors are neglected while designing and/or analyzing the DFEs. Then a closed form expression is obtained for Wiener solution and we refer this as ideal DFE (IDFE). DFE has also been designed using an iterative and computationally efficient alternative called least mean square (LMS) algorithm. However, again due to the feedback involved, the analysis of an LMS-DFE is not known so far. In this paper we theoretically analyze a DFE taking into account the decision errors. We study its performance at steady state. We then study an LMS-DFE and show the proximity of LMS-DFE attractors to that of the optimal DFE Wiener filter (obtained after considering the decision errors) at high signal to noise ratios (SNR). Further, via simulations we demonstrate that, even at moderate SNRs, an LMS-DFE is close to the MSE optimal DFE. Finally, we compare the LMS DFE attractors with IDFE via simulations. We show that an LMS equalizer outperforms the IDFE. In fact, the performance improvement is very significant even at high SNRs (up to 33%), where an IDFE is believed to be closer to the optimal one. Towards the end, we briefly discuss the tracking properties of the LMS-DFE.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INTERNATIONAL PUBLISHING AG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:46:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:46:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EURASIP JOURNAL ON ADVANCES IN SIGNAL PROCESSING,</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1687-6180-2012-172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15469</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>