<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14449</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T12:50:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Diametric changes in trends and patterns of extreme rainfall over India from pre-1950 to post-1950</dc:title><dc:creator>VITTAL, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>KARMAKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHOSH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Rainfall Extremes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Indian Monsoon</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUMMER MONSOON</dc:subject><dc:subject>1981 CENSUS</dc:subject><dc:subject>URBANIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPELLS</dc:subject><dc:description>Spatially aggregated extreme rainfall over India shows an increasing trend over the last 50years of the 20th century, while fine-resolution analysis reveals a spatially nonuniform trend. Analysis of 104years (1901-2004) extreme precipitation over India at 1 degrees resolution, using Extreme Value Theory, reveals that post-1950 extreme rainfall characteristics (intensity, duration, and frequency) and their trends are significantly different from those of before 1950, with spatial nonuniformity. Majority of the locations in India have post-1950 trends of extremes with a different sign as compared to pre-1950. Further investigations with statistical change point analysis reveal that fraction of grid points having post-1975 changes is maximum. Majority of the urbanized areas have post-1975 change points, while the same is not true for nonurban areas. As urbanization has intensified during 1971-1981 in India, these results indicate the possible impacts of urbanization on extreme rainfall trends and patterns.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER GEOPHYSICAL UNION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:50:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:50:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOPHYSICAL RESEARCH LETTERS, 40(12)3253-3258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/grl.50631</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14449</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>