<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1405</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Flow map and measurement of void fraction and heat transfer coefficient using an image analysis technique for flow boiling of water in a silicon microchannel</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, SG</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIDHARAN, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SP</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>2-phase flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>sinks</dc:subject><dc:subject>visualization</dc:subject><dc:subject>flux</dc:subject><dc:description>The present work focuses on the generation of the flow regime map for two-phase water flow in microchannels of a hydraulic diameter of 140 mu m. An image analysis algorithm has been developed and utilized to obtain the local void fraction. The image processing technique is also employed to identify and estimate the percentage of different flow regimes and heat transfer coefficient, as a function of position, heat flux and mass flow rate. Both void fraction and heat transfer coefficient are found to increase monotonically along the length of the microchannel. At low heat flux and low flow rates, bubbly, slug and annular flow regimes are apparent. However, the flow is predominately annular at high heat flux and high flow rate. A breakup of the flow frequency suggests that the flow is bistable in the annular regime, in that at a fixed location, the flow periodically switches from single-phase liquid to annular and vice versa. Otherwise, the occurrence of three regimes-single-phase liquid, bubbly and slug are observed. These results provide several useful insights about two-phase flow in microchannels besides being of fundamental interest.!</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T04:11:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T04:11:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MICROMECHANICS AND MICROENGINEERING,19(7)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-1317</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0960-1317/19/7/075004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14581</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1405</dc:identifier><dc:source>19th MicroMechanics Europe Workshop,Aachen, GERMANY,SEP 28-30, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>