<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2915</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>Sensing turbulence transit time by pulsed ultrasound for single-phase fluid flow measurement</dc:title><dc:creator>NEMADE, HB</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANJANEYULU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, PC</dc:creator><dc:description>A new technique for sensing turbulence in single-phase fluid flow by pulsed ultrasound is developed. The velocity component of turbulence perpendicular to the flow axis is sensed by two ultrasonic transducers mounted diametrically opposite on the pipe. The technique facilitates detecting variations in time of flight of two ultrasonic pulses transmitted simultaneously in the opposite directions and perpendicular to the flow axis. The flow velocity is obtained from the position of the peak in the cross correlation function of the turbulence signals sensed at two locations on the pipe. A numerical simulation of the technique based on a theoretical model has The technique has been measure volumetric flow noninvasively in a wafer circulation system with PVC pipes.</dc:description><dc:publisher>I E E E</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T21:37:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T21:37:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IMTC/97 - IEEE INSTRUMENTATION &amp; MEASUREMENT TECHNOLOGY CONFERENCE: SENSING, PROCESSING, NETWORKING, PROCEEDINGS VOLS 1 AND 2,1066-1071</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-3748-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1091-5281</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16423</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2915</dc:identifier><dc:source>IEEE Instrumentation and Measurement Technology Conference - Sensing, Processing, Networking (IMTC/97),OTTAWA, CANADA,MAY 19-21, 1997</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>