<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17460</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:09:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of annealing temperature on optical and electrical properties of nitrogen implanted p-type ZnMgO thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-BEAM EPITAXY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC-OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BUFFER LAYER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNO</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTODETECTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MGXZN1-XO</dc:subject><dc:description>p-type nitrogen doped Zn1-xMgxO (x = 0.15) thin films were prepared on n-type silicon substrates by RF sputtering. Plasma-immersion-ion technique and rapid-thermal process were used to implant nitrogen and annealing (700-1000 A degrees C) of these films respectively. Annealed samples at 700, 800, 900 and 1000 A degrees C showed effective improvement of the structural and optical properties. X-ray diffraction spectra showed improvement in &lt; 002 &gt; orientation of films with increase in annealing temperatures. In Raman spectra, the peak at 436 cm(-1) corresponds to E (2) (high) phonons mode of ZnMgO wurtzite structure and FWHM of this peak decreases with increase in annealing temperature, indicating improvement in crystalline quality. The scanning electron microscopy results demonstrate that nitrogen-implanted ZnMgO film annealed at 1000 A degrees C has better morphology in comparison to other films. Low-temperature (15 K) photoluminescence measurements revealed acceptor-bound exciton peak at 3.45 eV and donor-bound exciton peak around 3.52 eV. Increased intensity of acceptor-bound exciton peak with increasing annealing temperature proves that nitrogen implantation and subsequent annealing increase the acceptor concentration in the film, indicating tendency for p-type conduction at higher annealing temperature. The film annealed at 1000 A degrees C was observed to produce only acceptor-bound exciton emission and no donor-bound exciton emission was occurred. Hall-effect measurements showed p-type conductivity for annealed films in temperature range at 800-1000 A degrees C. The acceptor level at 3.45 eV in PL spectra is responsible for this p-type conduction in these films. The highest hole concentration of 1.91 x 10(15) cm(-3) has been achieved for film annealed at 1000 degrees C.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:09:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:09:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS SCIENCE-MATERIALS IN ELECTRONICS, 26(12SI)9759-9765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0957-4522</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1573-482X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10854-015-3646-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17460</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>