<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6889</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Polymer microcantilever biochemical sensors with integrated polymer composites for electrical detection</dc:title><dc:creator>SEENA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJORYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANT, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:subject>su-8</dc:subject><dc:subject>immobilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosensing</dc:subject><dc:subject>microcantilever</dc:subject><dc:subject>gauge factor</dc:subject><dc:subject>young's modulus</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoresistor</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>su-8</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer carbon black composite</dc:subject><dc:description>Micro fabricated sensors based on nanomechanical motion with piezoresistive electrical readout have become a promising biochemical sensing tool. The conventional microcantilever materials are mostly silicon-based. The sensitivity of the sensor depends on Young's modulus of the structural material, thickness of the cantilever as well as on the gauge factor of the piezoresistor. UV patternable polymers such as SU-8 have a very low Young's modulus compared to the silicon-based materials. Polymer cantilevers with a piezoresistive material having a large gauge factor and a lower Young's modulus are therefore highly suited for sensing applications. In this work, a spin coatable and photopatternable mixture of carbon black (CB) and SU-8, with proper dispersion characteristics, has been demonstrated as a piezoresistive thin film for polymer microcantilevers. Results on percolation experiments of SU-8/CB composite and fabrication of piezoresistive SU-8 microcantilevers using this composite are presented. With our controlled dispersion experiments, we could get a uniform piezoresistive thin film of thickness less than 1.2 mu m and resistivity of 2.7 Omega cm using 10 wt% of CB in SU-8. The overall thickness of the SU-8/composite/SU-8 is approximately 3 pm. We further present results on the electromechanical characterization and biofunctionalization of the cantilever structures for biochemical sensing applications. These cantilevers show a deflection sensitivity of 0.55 ppm/nm. Since the surface stress sensitivity is 4.1 x 10(-3) [N/m](-1), these cantilevers can well be used for detection of protein markers for pathological applications. (C) 2009 Elsevier Masson SAS. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-26T11:24:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-26T11:24:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOLID STATE SCIENCES, 11(9), 1606-1611</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1293-2558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2009.06.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6889</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6889</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>