<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15049</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:00:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>An innovative monolithic column preparation for the isolation of 25 kilo base pairs DNA</dc:title><dc:creator>ONGKUDON, CM</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DANQUAH, MK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Monolith</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chromatography</dc:subject><dc:subject>DNA isolation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fosmid DNA</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLASMID DNA</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHROMATOGRAPHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PURIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPENDENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DILUTE</dc:subject><dc:description>The use of large DNAs in preparing multivalent vaccines that will eventually give protective immunity against multiple pathogenic microbes is becoming a major debate nowadays. One of the important issues in ensuring the successful implementation of the new vaccine technology is the development of a chromatographic technique that can handle larger DNAs. This paper reports the development of a novel conical monolithic column format with pore and surface characteristics engineered for the isolation of 25 kbp DNA in a single step fashion. An effective method of eliminating wall channelling, a defect of most conventional monolithic chromatography systems which has caused significant loss of product, was applied to maximise DNA recovery. This method was based on a systematic reduction of wall channel size based on a predetermined correlation between column's back pressure and wall channel size of a particular monolith pore size. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:00:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:00:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHROMATOGRAPHY A, 1318156-162</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9673</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-3778</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.chroma.2013.10.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15049</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>