<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1265</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>Evaluation of sequencing batch reactor (SBR) and sequencing batch biofilm reactor (SBBR) for biological nutrient removal from simulated wastewater containing glucose as carbon source</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, BM</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>phosphorus removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphate removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>activated-sludge</dc:subject><dc:subject>system</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>cow dung</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhanced biological phosphorus removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>glucose</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequential batch reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequential batch biofilm reactor</dc:subject><dc:description>In general, conventional activated sludge (ASP) or enhanced biological phosphorus removing (EBPR) sludge has been used as seed culture for developing EBPR sludge and the time reported for development varies from months to year. In the present study cow-dung has been used as seed culture and EBPR sludge was developed within 36 days. The developed EBPR sludge has been used to evaluate the performance of sequential batch reactor (SBR) and sequential batch biofilm reactors (SBBR) for simultaneous nitrogen and phosphorus removal from synthetic wastewater containing glucose as carbon source. Three reactors were operated, SBR-1 containing only suspended biomass, SBBR-2 and SBBR-3 containing 5% and 10% polyurethane foam (PUF) media respectively along with suspended biomass. In all the reactors phosphorus removal was nearly the same and was more than 80%. In all the three reactors greater than 90% nitrification was achieved. Nitrogen removal in SBR-1 was 48% and in SBBR-2 and SBBR-3 it was more than 62%. On line monitoring of oxidation-reduction potential (ORP), pH and phosphorus during a cycle indicated that ORP and pH can be useful for real time control and optimization of the process.</dc:description><dc:publisher>I W A PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-19T16:22:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-19T16:22:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY,48(3)73-79</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0273-1223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14455</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1265</dc:identifier><dc:source>1st IWA International Young Researchers Conference,CRANFIELD, ENGLAND,SEP 09-10, 2002</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>