<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2108</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic analysis of single end bearing pile</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:description>Research in the area of pile foundation under seismic condition are still lacking though it is extremely important topic in the area of geotechnical engineering. In this paper, a comprehensive analysis of end bearing pile under seismic excitation is reported. The case of single end bearing pile without mass at the top of the pile is considered for the analysis. A seismic excitation of harmonic nature is considered at the base of the end bearing pile for the analysis. Based on Winkler model, a differential equation for pile displacement as a function of depth and time has been obtained by considering the equilibrium equations of a proposed mathematical model. Using the boundary conditions, the pile displacement as a function of depth and time is obtained. Also the variations of rotation, shear force and bending moment with pile depth at a particular time are obtained. An illustrative example shows the results of the analysis. The positions of maximum displacement, rotation, shear force and bending moment along the depth of the pile for a given seismic excitation can be found out.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WORLD SCIENTIFIC PUBL CO PTE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:15:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-25T06:15:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Geotechnical Engineering for Disaster Mitigation and Rehabilitation,275-280</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>981-256-469-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1142/98127016050027_0027</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15627</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2108</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Geotechnical Engineering for Disaster Mitigation and Rehabilitation,Singapore, SINGAPORE,DEC 12-13, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>