<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15836</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:54:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>A process and temperature compensated current reference circuit in CMOS process</dc:title><dc:creator>DAVE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Current reference circuit</dc:subject><dc:subject>Variation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Short-channel MOSFETs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monte Carlo simulations</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel current reference circuit that compensates for process and temperature variations without any extra trimming is proposed in this paper. Four thousand Monte Carlo simulations show that the maximum % error (deviation from the desired value) in the reference current is +/- 5.07% considering process variations (die-to-die, wafer-to-wafer and batch-to-batch). Considering process variations and temperature change from 0 degrees C to 100 degrees C both, the maximum error in the reference current is +/- 8.56%. The proposed circuit has been fabricated in 180 nm CMOS process. Measurement results on 50 dice at room temperature show that the mean of the proposed reference current is 9.39% away from its designed value. Mean of drain current of a fixed biased MOSFET fabricated in the same run is 35.41% away from its designed value. Measurements at four different temperatures, 27 degrees C, 50 degrees C, 75 degrees C and 100 degrees C, on these dice show that the maximum error in the reference current is 17% whereas that in the drain current of a fixed biased MOSFET is 126%. In other words, the proposed current reference circuit reduces the maximum error by a factor of 7 (from 126% to 17%) when process and temperature variations both are considered without trimming. With a simple trimming circuit the maximum variation in the reference current is reduced to +/- 3.17% (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:54:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:54:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROELECTRONICS JOURNAL, 43(2)89-97</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mejo.2011.11.008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15836</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>