<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14462</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T12:57:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>The hierarchical structure and properties of multifunctional carbon nanotube fibre composites</dc:title><dc:creator>VILATELA, JJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHARE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>WINDLE, AH</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHEMICAL-VAPOR-DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>THERMAL-CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRENGTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EPOXY</dc:subject><dc:description>The axial mechanical, electrical and thermal properties of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) can be exploited macroscopically by assembling them parallel to each other into a fibre during their synthesis by chemical vapour deposition. Multifunctional composites with high volume fraction of CNT fibres are then made by direct polymer infiltration of an array of aligned fibres. The fibres have a very high surface area, causing the polymer to infiltrate them and resulting in a hierarchical composite structure. The electrical and thermal conductivities of CNT/epoxy composites are shown to be superior to those of equivalent specimens with T300 carbon fibre (CF) which is widely used in industry. From measurements of longitudinal coefficient of thermal expansion (CTE) of the composites we show that the CTE of CNT fibres is approximately -1.6 x 10(-6) K-1, similar to in-plane graphite. The combination of electrical, thermal and mechanical properties of CNT fibre composites demonstrates their potential for multifunctionality. (C) 2011 Published by Elsevier Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:57:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CARBON, 50(3)1227-1234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2011.10.040</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14462</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>