<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2091</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Scattering of electromagnetic waves by small magnetic ellipsoidal particles - art. no. 70322C</dc:title><dc:creator>PURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>magnetic ellipsoidal particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>dipolar response</dc:subject><dc:subject>scattering matrix</dc:subject><dc:description>The scattering of electromagnetic (e.m.) waves by small ellipsoidal particles having non-zero dielectric or magnetic susceptibility have been studied extensively. The studies in case the particles have non-zero dielectric as well as magnetic susceptibility have been limited to small uncoated particles of spherical shapes. We present here a study of the scattering of e.m. waves by small ellipsoidal particles having non-zero dielectric as well as magnetic susceptibility. We refer to such particles as magnetic particles. The ellipsoidal particles in our case can have multiple ellipsoidal coatings having common focii and axes. By deriving analytical expressions for the magnetic and electric scattering coefficients for such particles, we show that there is drastic difference between the backscattering as well as forward scattering patterns of the non-magnetic and magnetic particles. We also compare the scattering patterns of magnetic ellipsoidal and spherical particles. Furthermore, we derive Maxwell-Garnett formula for multiply coated magnetic ellipsoidal particles. To our knowledge, our results are new and should be useful for plasmonics and meta-materials designs.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T04:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T04:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PLASMONICS: METALLIC NANOSTRUCTURES AND THEIR OPTICAL PROPERTIES VI,7032,C322-C322</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-8194-7252-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.794093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15328</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2091</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on Plasmonics - Metallic Nanostructures and their Optical Properties VI,San Diego, CA,AUG 10-14, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>