<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1217</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel dry method for surface modification of SU-8 for immobilization of biomolecules in Bio-MEMS</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALE, NITIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAL, RAKESH</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMGOPAL RAO, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, SOUMYA</dc:creator><dc:subject>microsystems</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical vapor deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>ammonia</dc:subject><dc:description>SU-8 has been primarily used for structural elements and microfludics components in MEMS. Microsystems for biological applications require immobilization of biomolecules on the MEMS structures. In order to functionalize SU-8 for such purposes, the surface needs to be modified. In this paper, we report a novel dry method of surface modification of SU-8 which is compatible with standard microfabrication techniques. The surface obtained by spin coating SU-8 (2002) on silicon wafer was modified by grafting amine groups using pyrolytic dissociation of ammonia in a hotwire CVD setup. To demonstrate the presence of amine groups on modified SU-8 surface, the surface characteristic after modification was assessed using Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy. The change in SU-8 surface morphology before and after surface modification was investigated using atomic force microscopy. To show the utility of this process for application in Bio-MEMS, SU-8 microcantilevers were fabricated and subjected to the same surface modification protocol. Following this, the cantilevers were incubated first in a suspension of human immunoglobulin (HIgG) and then in FITC tagged goat anti-human IgG in order to demonstrate the utility of the surface modification performed. The efficacy of the process was assessed by observing the cantilevers under a fluorescence microscope.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:41:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:41:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Biosensors and Bioelectronics 22(11), 2429-2435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0956-5663</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.bios.2006.08.045</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1217</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1217</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>