<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16832</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:07:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Three-phase three-level one-cycle controlled bidirectional ac-dc neutral-point-clamped converter without having voltage sensors</dc:title><dc:creator>GHODKE, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>FREQUENCY INTEGRATION CONTROL</dc:subject><dc:subject>POWER-FACTOR CORRECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MULTILEVEL CONVERTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PWM RECTIFIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>INVERTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>VECTOR</dc:subject><dc:description>A three-phase three-level bidirectional ac-dc neutral-point-clamped converter (3 L-NPC) based on one-cycle control (OCC) is proposed in this study. It ensures that the 3 L-NPC converter operates stably during inverting mode of operation. A neutral point potential regulator is also presented which adds a dc offset to the three-phase modulating signals to nullify the deviation in the neutral point potential. First, a one-cycle controlled (OCC) 3 L-NPC converter which requires the sensing of instantaneous phase voltages of the utility is presented. Subsequently, a modified version of the OCC-based 3 L-NPC converter which does not requires sensing of the instantaneous phase voltages is proposed. The modified OCC-based 3 L-NPC estimates instantaneous phase voltages of the source from the pulse width modulation (PWM) switching sequence of the converter. The viability of the schemes is confirmed through a detailed simulation and experimental studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY-IET</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:07:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:07:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IET POWER ELECTRONICS, 7(8)2161-2172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1755-4535</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1755-4543</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1049/iet-pel.2013.0788</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16832</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>