<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9564</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Two-stage component test plans for testing the reliability of a series system</dc:title><dc:creator>VELLAISAMY, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>series system</dc:subject><dc:subject>reliability test plans</dc:subject><dc:subject>exponential lifetimes</dc:subject><dc:subject>two-stage component test plans</dc:subject><dc:subject>maximum expected cost</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization problems</dc:subject><dc:subject>feasible solutions</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>prior information</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithm</dc:subject><dc:description>A system reliability is often evaluated by individual tests of components that constitute the system. These component test plans have advantages over complete system based tests in terms of time and cost. In this paper, we consider the series system with 11 components, where the lifetime of the i-th component follows exponential distribution with parameter lambda(i). Assuming test costs for the components are different, we develop an efficient algorithm to design a two-stage component test plan that satisfies the usual probability requirements on the system reliability and in addition minimizes the maximum expected cost.: For the case of prior information in the form of upper bounds on lambda(i)'s, we use the genetic algorithm to solve the associated optimization problems which are otherwise difficult to solve using mathematical programming techniques. The two-stage component test plans are cost effective compared to single-stage plans developed by Rajgopal and Mazumdar. We demonstrate through several numerical examples that our approach has the potential to reduce the overall testing costs significantly. (C) 2002 John Wiley Sons, Inc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:01:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:01:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NAVAL RESEARCH LOGISTICS, 49(1), 95-116</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0894-069X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/nav.1051</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9564</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9564</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>