<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16822</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T15:02:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Embelin - a drug of antiquity: shifting the paradigm towards modern medicine</dc:title><dc:creator>POOJARI, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>embelin</dc:subject><dc:subject>ethnomedicinal uses</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular targets</dc:subject><dc:subject>pharmacotherapeutics</dc:subject><dc:subject>vidanga</dc:subject><dc:subject>X-LINKED INHIBITOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITROSODIETHYLAMINE/PHENOBARBITAL-INDUCED-HEPATOCARCINOGENESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PEG-DERIVATIZED EMBELIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BREAST-CANCER CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NF-KAPPA-B</dc:subject><dc:subject>APOPTOSIS PROTEIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>MITOCHONDRIAL PATHWAY</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIPID-PEROXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WISTAR RATS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:description>Introduction: Embelia ribes or Embelia tsjeriam-cottam, more commonly known as vidanga, is a type of ayurvedic medicine that has been used to treat various diseases for a number of years. Bright orange embelin-rich fruits have been well established as ethnomedicinals, for a number of years with their pharmacological actions attributed to their hydroxybenzoquinone active constituent. Embelin has become known specifically for its antihelminthic and contraceptive use. Areas covered: This drug evaluation provides a historical summary of embelin along with its therapeutic use, phytochemistry and toxicology. Embelin's pharmacotherapeutical properties are also discussed along with its molecular targets. It is hoped that this article will help to draw the attention of researchers and biopharmaceutical companies to the untapped potential in bioprospection for the development of new drugs. Expert opinion: Embelin is the only known non-peptide small-molecule X-linked inhibitor of the apoptosis protein (XIAP) - an anti-apoptotic protein considered a promising cancer therapeutic target. Embelin acts as an NF-kappa B blocker and potential suppressor of tumorigenesis. It also exhibits potent cytotoxic, antioxidant and cancer chemopreventive effects. Given the potential uses of embelin, it is recommended that further investigations take place to properly explore its pharmacological and clinical effects.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INFORMA HEALTHCARE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:02:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T15:02:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERT OPINION ON INVESTIGATIONAL DRUGS, 23(3)427-444</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1354-3784</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1744-7658</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1517/13543784.2014.867016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16822</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>