<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15799</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:35:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Codes Against Online Adversaries: Large Alphabets</dc:title><dc:creator>DEY, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAGGI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LANGBERG, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Arbitrarily varying channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>channel coding</dc:subject><dc:subject>jamming</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMMUNICATION</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we consider the communication of information in the presence of an online adversarial jammer. In the setting under study, a sender wishes to communicate a message to a receiver by transmitting a codeword x = (x(1), ... , x(n)) symbol-by-symbol over a communication channel. The adversarial jammer can view the transmitted symbols x(i) one at a time and can change up to a p-fraction of them. However, for each symbol x(i), the jammer's decision on whether to corrupt it or not (and on how to change it) must depend only on x(j) for j &lt;= i. This is in contrast to the "classical" adversarial jammer which may base its decisions on its complete knowledge of x. More generally, for a delay parameter delta is an element of (0, 1), we study the scenario in which the jammer's decision on the corruption of x(i) must depend solely on x(j) for j &lt;= i - delta n. In this study, the transmitted symbols are assumed to be over a sufficiently large field F. The sender and receiver do not share resources such as common randomness (though the sender is allowed to use stochastic encoding). We present a tight characterization of the amount of information one can transmit in both the 0-delay and, more generally, the delta-delay online setting. We show that for 0-delay adversaries, the achievable rate asymptotically equals that of the classical adversarial model. For positive values of delta, we consider two types of jamming: additive and overwrite. We also extend our results to a jam-or-listen online model, where the online adversary can either jam a symbol or eavesdrop on it. We present computationally efficient achievability schemes even against computationally unrestricted jammers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:35:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:35:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON INFORMATION THEORY, 59(6)3304-3316</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIT.2013.2245717</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15799</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>