<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14160</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:40:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>High strain rate mechanical behavior of epoxy under compressive loading: Experimental and modeling studies</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANKAR, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAVALA, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVIKUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTHNIS, JR</dc:creator><dc:creator>ARYA, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>HOPKINSON PRESSURE BAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESS-STRAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYUREA</dc:subject><dc:subject>TENSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:subject>TESTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYETHYLENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>High strain rate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Epoxy LY 556</dc:subject><dc:subject>Split Hopkinson Pressure Bar</dc:subject><dc:subject>Compressive properties</dc:subject><dc:description>Investigations on high strain rate behavior of epoxy LY 556 under compressive loading are presented. Compressive Split Hopkinson Pressure Bar (SHPB) apparatus was used for the experimental investigations. The studies are presented in the strain rate range of 683-1890 per second. It was generally observed that the compressive strength is enhanced at high strain rate loading compared with that at quasi-static loading. During SHPB testing of the specimens, it was observed that the peak force obtained from the strain gauge mounted on the transmitter bar is lower than the peak force obtained from the strain gauge mounted on the incident bar. Further, an analytical method is presented based on variable rate power law for the prediction of compressive strength at high strain rate loading for epoxy LY 556. Using the analytical method, high strain rate compressive stress-strain behavior is presented up to strain rate of 10,000 per second. (C) 2010 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:40:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:40:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING,528(3)846-854</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2010.10.099</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14160</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>