<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1547</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electron field emission from carbon films grown from pyrolysis of kerosene</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANDO, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHAO, XL</dc:creator><dc:subject>diamond</dc:subject><dc:subject>emitters</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>affinity</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>fibers</dc:subject><dc:subject>area</dc:subject><dc:subject>amorphous carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>field emission</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>kerosene</dc:subject><dc:description>Kerosene - the cheapest petroleum product, has now been found to produce amorphous carbon having the property of electron field emission at a pressure 1 Torr. The process of synthesis involves simple pyrolysis of kerosene vapour at 800-1000 degreesC in argon atmosphere. Clay tiles and alumina pellets having nanopores are used as substrates so that the pyrolysis is achieved within the pores resulting in conducting carbon nanochannels across the substrates. Kerosene-pyrolyzed carbon deposited at 800 degreesC for 2 h on a clay tile was able to yield an emission current of 1 muA/cm(2) at a low electric field of 1.4 V/mum, whereas that deposited at 1000 degreesC for 3 h on an alumina pellet yielded 26 muA/cm(2) at an applied held of 5 V/mum. Field emission property of kerosene-pyrolyzed carbon has been discussed on the basis of XRD, SEM and Raman spectra analysis. The evidence of electron emission from this extremely cheap material at such a high pressure and low potential, and without any sophistication, makes it a promising candidate for further investigation for a prototype display device application. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science B.V. Ah rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:52:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:52:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DIAMOND AND RELATED MATERIALS,10,883-888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-9635</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0925-9635(00)00379-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14759</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1547</dc:identifier><dc:source>11th European Conference on Diamond, Diamond-like Materials, Carbon Nanotubes, Nitrides and Silicon Carbide (Diamond 2000),OPORTO, PORTUGAL,SEP 03-08, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>