<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15834</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:53:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assessment of portable traveling pluviator to prepare reconstituted sand specimens</dc:title><dc:creator>DAVE, TN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASAKA, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>portable traveling pluviator</dc:subject><dc:subject>deposition intensity</dc:subject><dc:subject>height of fall</dc:subject><dc:subject>sand bed uniformity</dc:subject><dc:subject>APPARATUS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TESTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR</dc:subject><dc:description>Air pluviation method is widely adopted for preparation of large, uniform and repeatable sand beds of desired densities for laboratory studies to simulate in-situ conditions and obtain test results which are highly reliable. This paper presents details of a portable traveling pluviator recently developed for model sand bed preparation. The pluviator essentially consisted of a hopper, orifice plates for varying deposition intensity, combination of flexible and rigid tubes for smooth travel of material, and a set of diffuser sieves to obtain uniformity of pluviated sand bed. It was observed that sand beds of lower relative density can be achieved by controlling height of fall, whereas, denser sand beds could be obtained by controlling deposition intensity. Uniformity of pluviated sand beds was evaluated using cone penetration test and at lower relative densities minor variation in density was observed with depth. With increase in relative density of sand bed higher repeatability of uniform pluviation was achieved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TECHNO-PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:53:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:53:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOMECHANICS AND ENGINEERING, 4(2)79-90</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15834</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>