<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1572</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>A reappraisal of the coastal Panvel flexure, Deccan Traps, as a listric-fault-controlled reverse drag structure</dc:title><dc:creator>SHETH, HC</dc:creator><dc:subject>coastal panvel flexure</dc:subject><dc:subject>deccan traps</dc:subject><dc:subject>listric faulting</dc:subject><dc:subject>monoclinal flexure</dc:subject><dc:description>The Panvel monoclinal flexure of the Deccan Traps flood basalt province, along the rifted west coast of India, is neither a monocline formed due to simple downbending of the lava pile (e.g., due to sag), nor due to compressional folding, nor merely an extensional fault structure as previously proposed, but is interpreted here as a reverse drag structure on an east-dipping listric master fault that should lie offshore Bombay, with numerous, subsidiary, antithetic (west-dipping) and sympathetic (east-dipping) faults. The proposed model satisfactorily explains a wide range of observations such as the systematic westerly increase in dip of the basalts, their occurrence at shallow levels on the continental shelf, syn-volcanic subsidence and sedimentation, and oil reserves of the shelf. Innumerable graben systems of the continental interiors in the world are indeed characterized by listric faults and reverse drag structures, and the reverse drag model appears highly applicable to most flood basalt provinces with coastal flexures and seaward-dipping reflector sequences at rifted continental margins, namely Karoo, Parana, East Greenland, West Greenland, and Afar.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-25T09:49:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:02:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-25T09:49:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:02:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Tectonophysics  294(1-2), 143-149</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-1951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0040-1951(98)00148-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1572</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1572</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>