<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14843</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T11:56:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analytical and experimental studies on mechanical behavior of composites under high strain rate compressive loading</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVIKUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>POTHNIS, JR</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>AKELLA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:subject>HOPKINSON PRESSURE BAR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIBER-REINFORCED COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMER-MATRIX COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE/EPOXY COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON/EPOXY COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECIMEN GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRIC COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RADIAL CONSTRAINT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ESTER COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>RATE RESPONSE</dc:subject><dc:description>An analytical method is presented for the prediction of compressive strength at high strain rate loading for composites. The method is based on variable rate power law. Using this analytical method, high strain rate compressive stress-strain behavior is presented up to strain rate of 5000 s (1) starting with the experimentally determined compressive strength values at relatively lower strain rates. Experimental results were generated in the strain rate range of 472-1957 s (1) for a typical woven fabric E-glass/epoxy laminated composite along all the three principal directions. The laminated composite was made using resin film infusion technique. The experimental studies were carried out using compressive split Hopkinson pressure bar apparatus. It was generally observed that the compressive strength is enhanced at high strain rate loading compared with that at quasi-static loading. Also, compressive strength increased with increasing strain rate in the range of parameters considered. Analytically predicted results are compared with the experimental results up to strain rate of 1957 s (1). (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T11:56:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T11:56:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS &amp; DESIGN, 44246-255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.matdes.2012.07.040</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14843</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>