<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1407</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-12T05:06:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>On the coverage process of a moving point target in a Non-uniform dynamic sensor field</dc:title><dc:creator>MANOHAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANJUNATH, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>non-uniform sensor density</dc:subject><dc:subject>k-coverage</dc:subject><dc:subject>path coverage</dc:subject><dc:subject>markov-boolean model</dc:subject><dc:subject>target tracking</dc:subject><dc:description>We analyze the statistical properties of the k-coverage of a point-target moving in a straight line in a non-uniform dynamic sensor field. Sensor locations form a spatial point process. The environmental variation is captured by making the sensor locations form a non homogeneous spatial Poisson process with a fixed, spatially varying density function. The sensing areas of the sensors are circles of i.i.d. radii. The availability of each node is modeled by an independent, {0, 1}-valued, continuous time Markov chain. This gives a Markov-non homogeneous Poisson-Boolean model for which we perform a coverage analysis. We first obtain k-coverage of the target at an arbitrary time instant. We then obtain k-coverage statistics of the target during the time interval [0, T]. We also provide an asymptotically tight, closed form approximation for the duration for which the target is not k-covered in [0, T]. Numerical results illustrate the analysis. The environmental variation can also be captured by modeling the density function as a spatial random process resulting in the point process being a two-dimensional Cox process. For this model, we discuss issues in the coverage analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T04:22:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T04:22:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE JOURNAL ON SELECTED AREAS IN COMMUNICATIONS,27(7)1245-1255</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0733-8716</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSAC.2009.090920</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14583</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1407</dc:identifier><dc:source>WiOpt Conference 2008,Berlin, GERMANY,</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>