<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2637</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>On preliminaries of 3D solid reconstruction using auxiliary views</dc:title><dc:creator>MISHRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAXENA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>2d orthographic views</dc:subject><dc:subject>objects</dc:subject><dc:subject>projections</dc:subject><dc:subject>extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>drawings</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper is proposed a method to reconstruct a solid from given two or three orthographic views along with any number of primary auxiliary views based on the combination of wire-frame and volumetric approaches. None of the existing works in automatic reconstruction of solids from two dimensional orthographic views have addressed auxiliary views in detail. Polyhedral approximation of cylindrical, conical, toroidal and spherical surfaces is considered. The algorithm presented, entails the constriction of the basic wire-frame from given standard views using the wire-frame approach. The projections in the auxiliary views on the basic orthographic views are swept along the projection lines to form the primitives. These primitives are glued to the basic wire-frame to construct the final solid. Numerous examples are presented in this paper to demonstrate the versatility of the proposed method which can handle partial standard and auxiliary views as well.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T14:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T14:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the ASME International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference 2005, Vol 3, Pts A and B,69-77</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7918-4740-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2637</dc:identifier><dc:source>ASME International Design Engineering Technical Conference/Computers and Information in Engineering Conference,Long Beach, CA,SEP 24-28, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>