<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6015</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Chemical synthesis of optical grade ceramic precursors: A spectrophotometric approach for analysis</dc:title><dc:creator>HARIDAS, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOYAL, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>chelated aluminum alkoxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>sols</dc:subject><dc:description>Extremely controlled hydrolysis of a rapidly water-absorbing alkoxide was performed so as to achieve a gel of high optical transmittance. An aluminium sec-butoxide precursor was structurally modified using ethyl acetoacetate in varying stoichiometric ratios. The sol-gel synthesis of the chelated alkoxide was conducted under closely monitored conditions of humidity, temperature and ultrasonic power and the hydrolysing water was added at extremely slow rates using callibrated micropipettes. Molecular level homogeneity was ensured by adopting an intense, contact mode probe type ultrasonication of the chelated alkoxide in presence of excess alcohol, until the alumina sol sonogelled on the addition of a stoichiometric amount of water. The sonogels were seen to possess an extremely high optical transmittance as a result of the novel processing and synthesis technique proposed and developed by us. Uv-visible spectrophotometric analysis of the sonogelling sol at every water addition was performed and a gel of over 95% transmittance could be obtained at a chelate ratio of 1:2, with 15 ml isopropyl alcohol, at a water addition rate of 0.4 ml h(-1) g(-1) of alkoxide, under an ultrasonic power of 90 watts. (C) 1998 Elsevier Science Limited and Techna S.r.l. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T22:29:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T22:29:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CERAMICS INTERNATIONAL, 24(6), 415-420</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0272-8842</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0272-8842(97)00011-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6015</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6015</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>