<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15424</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:23:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Fortran 90 Hartree-Fock program for one-dimensional periodic pi-conjugated systems using Pariser-Parr-Pople model</dc:title><dc:creator>KONDAYYA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKLA, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Hartree-Fock method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-consistent field approach P-P-P model</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hamiltonian</dc:subject><dc:subject>Periodic boundary conditions</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHENYL-SUBSTITUTED POLYACETYLENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHENE NANORIBBONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLUSTER APPROACH</dc:subject><dc:subject>EDGE STATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ABSORPTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLET</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLIDS</dc:subject><dc:description>Pariser-Parr-Pople (P-P-P) model Hamiltonian is employed frequently to study the electronic structure and optical properties of pi-conjugated systems. In this paper we describe a Fortran 90 computer program which uses the P-P-P model Hamiltonian to solve the Hartree-Fock (HF) equation for infinitely long, one-dimensional, periodic, pi-electron systems. The code is capable of computing the band structure, as also the linear optical absorption spectrum, by using the tight-binding and the HF methods. Furthermore, using our program the user can solve the HF equation in the presence of a finite external electric field, thereby, allowing the simulation of gated systems. We apply our code to compute various properties of polymers such as trans-polyacetylene, poly-para-phenylene, and armchair and zigzag graphene nanoribbons, in the infinite length limit. Program summary Program title: ppp_bulk.x Catalogue identifier: AEKW_v1_0 Program summary URL: http://cpc.cs.qub.ac.uk/summaries/AEKW_v1_0.html Program obtainable from: CPC Program Library, Queen's University, Belfast, N. Ireland Licensing provisions: Standard CPC licence, http://cpc.cs.qub.ac.uk/licence/licence.html No. of lines in distributed program, including test data, etc.: 87 464 No. of bytes in distributed program, including test data, etc.: 2 046 933 Distribution format: tar.gz Programming language: Fortran 90 Computer: PCs and workstations Operating system: Linux, Code was developed and tested on various recent versions of 64-bit Fedora including Fedora 14 (kernel version 2.6.35.12-90). Classification: 7.3 External routines: This program needs to link with LAPACK/BLAS libraries compiled with the same compiler as the program. For the Intel Fortran Compiler we used the ACML library version 4.4.0, while for the gfortran compiler we used the libraries supplied with the Fedora distribution. Nature of problem: The electronic structure of one-dimensional periodic pi-conjugated systems is an intense area of research at present because of the tremendous interest in the physics of conjugated polymers and graphene nanoribbons. The computer program described in this paper provides an efficient way of solving the Hartree-Fock equations for such systems within the P-P-P model. In addition to the Bloch orbitals, band structure, and the density of states, the program can also compute quantities such as the linear absorption spectrum, and the electro-absorption spectrum of these systems. Solution method: For a one-dimensional periodic pi-conjugated system lying in the xy-plane, the single-particle Bloch orbitals are expressed as linear combinations of p(z)-orbitals of individual atoms. Then using various parameters defining the P-P-P Hamiltonian, the Hartree-Fock equations are set up as a matrix eigenvalue problem in the k-space. Thereby, its solutions are obtained in a self-consistent manner, using the iterative diagonalizing technique at several k points. The band structure and the corresponding Bloch orbitals thus obtained are used to perform a variety of calculations such as the density of states, linear optical absorption spectrum, electro-absorption spectrum. etc. Running time: Most of the examples provided take only a few seconds to run. For a large system, however, depending on the system size, the run time may be a few minutes to a few hours. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:23:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:23:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTER PHYSICS COMMUNICATIONS, 183(3)677-689</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cpc.2011.11.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15424</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>