<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15334</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:27:05Z</datestamp><dc:title>Selective recognition of fluoride and acetate by a newly designed ruthenium framework: experimental and theoretical investigations</dc:title><dc:creator>KUNDU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, AD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>PURANIK, VG</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>BIPYRIDYL RECEPTOR MOLECULES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANION-SENSING PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPRAMOLECULAR SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION-ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION-METAL</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIOCYANIC ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>AB-INITIO</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING</dc:subject><dc:description>An effective anion sensor, [Ru-II(bpy)(2)(H2L-)](+) (1(+)), based on a redox and photoactive {Ru-II(bpy)(2)} moiety and a new ligand (H3L = 5-(1H-benzo[d]imidazol-2-yl)-1H-imidazole-4-carboxylic acid), has been developed for selective recognition of fluoride (F-) and acetate (OAc-) ions. Crystal structures of the free ligand, H3L and [1](ClO4) reveal the existence of strong intramolecular and intermolecular hydrogen bonding interactions. The structure of [1](ClO4) shows that the benzimidazole N-H of H2L- is hydrogen bonded with the pendant carboxylate oxygen while the imidazole N-H remains free for possible hydrogen bonding interaction with the anions. The potential anion sensing features of 1(+) have been studied by different experimental and theoretical (DFT) investigations using a wide variety of anions, such as F-, Cl-, Br-, I-, HSO4-, H2PO4-, OAc- and SCN-. Cyclic voltammetry and differential pulse voltammetry established that 1(+) is an excellent electrochemical sensor for the selective recognition kof F- and OAc- anions. 1(+) is also found to be a selective colorimetric sensor for F- or OAc- anions where the MLCT band of the receptor at 498 nm is red shifted to 538 nm in the presence of one equivalent of F- or OAc- with a distinct change in colour from reddish-orange to pink. The binding constant between 1(+) and F- or OAc- has been determined to be logK = 7.61 or 7.88, respectively, based on spectrophotometric titration in CH3CN. The quenching of the emission band of 1(+) at 716 nm (lambda(ex) = 440 nm, Phi = 0.01 at 298 K in CH3CN) in the presence of one equivalent of F- or OAc-, as well as two distinct lifetimes of the quenched and unquenched forms of the receptor 1(+), makes it also a suitable fluorescence-based sensor. All the above experiments, in combination with H-1 NMR, suggest the formation of a 1 : 1 adduct between the receptor (1(+)) and the anion (F- or OAc-). The formation of 1 : 1 adduct {[1(+).F-] or [1(+).OAc-]} has been further evidenced by in situ ESI-MS(+) in CH3CN. Though the receptor, 1(+), is comprised of two N-H protons associated with the coordinated H2L- ligand, only the free imidazole N-H proton participates in the hydrogen bonding interactions with the incoming anions, while the intramolecularly hydrogen bonded benzimidazole N-H proton remains intact as evidenced by the crystal structure of the final product (1). The hydrogen bond mediated anion sensing mechanism, over the direct deprotonation pathway, in 1(+) has been further justified by a DFT study and subsequent NBO analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:27:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:27:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 41(15)4484-4496</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c2dt12126c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15334</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>