<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1582</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microstructural studies on phase evolution sequence in rapidly solidified Zr3Al based binary and ternary alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>TEWARI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>ageing</dc:subject><dc:subject>amorphous state</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>phase separation</dc:subject><dc:description>Transformation sequences in the alloys Zr3Al, Zr3Al–3Nb and Zr3Al–10Nb are described and rationalized in terms of some basic tendencies such as phase separation and chemical ordering in the β phase and displacive omega and β→α (h.c.p.) transformations. These alloys were melt-spun and aged at different temperatures to study the evolution of different phases. The rapidly solidified Zr3Al alloy showed the presence of an amorphous phase or of a spinodally decomposed microstructure depending upon the severity of quenching, whereas the microstructure of the Zr3Al–3Nb and the Zr3Al–10Nb alloys exhibited a distribution of cuboidal particles (D88 phase) in the β matrix. Ageing of these alloys showed the formation of several metastable phases prior to the formation of equilibrium phase. The transformation sequence was found to involve a gradual filling of the open structure into a close packed configuration without reconstruction of the lattice.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-30T07:05:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:04:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-30T07:05:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:04:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:04:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Materials Science and Engineering: A 304-306(1-2), 548-554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0921-5093(00)01513-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1582</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1582</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>