<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9097</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electronic structure and magnetism in half-Heusler compounds</dc:title><dc:creator>NANDA, BRK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DASGUPTA, I</dc:creator><dc:subject>thermoelectric-materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>band-gap</dc:subject><dc:subject>phases</dc:subject><dc:subject>ni</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>explicit</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal</dc:subject><dc:subject>pure</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper we have applied the full-potential linearized muffin tin orbital method and the tight-binding linearized muffin tin orbital method to investigate in detail the electronic structure and magnetism of a series of half-Heusler compounds XMZ with X = Fe, Co, Ni, M = Ti, V, Nb, Zr, Cr, Mo, Mn and Z = Sb, Sn. Our detailed analysis of the electronic structure using various indicators of chemical bonding suggests that covalent hybridization of the higher-valent transition element X with the lower-valent transition element M is the key interaction responsible for the formation of the d-d gap in these systems. However, the presence of the sp-valent element is crucial to provide stability to these systems. The influence of the relative ordering of the atoms in the unit cell on the d-d gap is also investigated. We have also studied in detail some of these systems with more than 18 valence electrons which exhibit novel magnetic properties, namely half-metallic ferro- and ferrimagnetism. We show that the d-d gap in the paramagnetic state, the relatively large X-Sb hybridization and the large exchange splitting of the M atoms are responsible for the half-metallic property of some of these systems.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:13:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:13:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 15(43), 7307-7323</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/15/43/014</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9097</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9097</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>