<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14941</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:55:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Influence of Fe doping on the structural, optical and acetone sensing properties of sprayed ZnO thin films</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAJAPATI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHAY, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Semiconductors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>Optical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS SENSOR APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXYGEN VACANCIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPARENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATHODOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GROWTH</dc:subject><dc:description>The ZnO thin films (undoped and Fe-doped) deposited by chemical spray pyrolysis technique have been analyzed by X-ray powder diffraction (XRD), atomic force microscopy (AFM) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). Results show that all the films possess hexagonal wurtzite structure of zinc oxide having crystallite sizes in the range 15-36 nm. On 1 at% Fe doping, the surface roughness of the film increases which favors the adsorption of atmospheric oxygen on the film surface and thereby increase in the gas response. Optical studies reveal that the band gap decreases due to creation of some defect. energy states below the conduction band edge, arising out of the lattice disorder in the doped films. The refractive index of the films decreases on Fe doping and follows the Cauchy relation of normal dispersion. Among all the films examined, the 1 at% Fe-doped film exhibits the maximum response (similar to 72%) at 300 degrees C for 100 ppm concentration of acetone in air. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:55:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:55:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS RESEARCH BULLETIN, 48(7)2687-2695</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2013.03.026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14941</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>