<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15228</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T16:37:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic Recrystallization during Hot Deformation of 304 Austenitic Stainless Steel</dc:title><dc:creator>MARCHATTIWAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRAVARTTY, JK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KASHYAP, BP</dc:creator><dc:subject>austenitic Stainless Steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>compression test</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic recrystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>recrystallization kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROCESSING MAPS</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>NUCLEATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>NICKEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER</dc:subject><dc:description>The kinetics of dynamic recrystallization (DRX) during hot compression of 304 austenitic stainless steel was studied over the temperature range of 900-1200 A degrees C and strain rate range of 0.002-0.1 s(-1). The initiation and evolution of DRX were investigated using the process variables derived from flow curves. By the regression analysis for conventional hyperbolic sine equation, the activation energy for DRX was determined as Q = 475 kJ mol(-1). The temperature and strain rate domain where DRX occurred were identified from the strain rate sensitivity contour map. The critical stress (and strain) for the initiation of DRX was determined from the inflection point on the work hardening rate (theta = d sigma/d epsilon) versus flow stress (sigma) curve. The saturation stress of the dynamic recovery (DRV) curve was calculated from the theta-sigma plot at the same condition at which DRX occurred. Progress of fraction recrystallization was determined from the difference between the generated DRV curve and the experimental DRX curve. In addition, the microstructural evolution at different strain levels during DRX was characterized and compared with the calculated fraction recrystallization.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:37:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T16:37:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS ENGINEERING AND PERFORMANCE, 22(8)2168-2175</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11665-013-0496-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15228</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>