<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14211</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T08:43:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Superhydrophobic transparent films from silica powder: Comparison of fabrication methods</dc:title><dc:creator>LIU, LD</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIN, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIKEKAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHEN, PH</dc:creator><dc:subject>TITANIUM-DIOXIDE FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASSEMBLED MONOLAYERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLASS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARRANGEMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOFIBERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPHERES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Self-cleaning surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>Superhydrophobicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transmissivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sol-gel deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>Silica</dc:subject><dc:subject>Polydimethylsiloxane</dc:subject><dc:description>The lotus leaf is known for its self-clean, superhydrophobic surface, which displays a hierarchical structure covered with a thin wax-like material. In this study, three fabrication techniques, using silicon dioxide particles to create surface roughness followed by a surface modification with a film of polydimethylsiloxane, were applied on a transparent glass substrate. The fabrication techniques differed mainly on the deposition of silicon dioxide particles, which included organic, inorganic, and physical methods. Each technique was used to coat three samples of varying particle load. The surface of each sample was evaluated with contact angle goniometer and optical spectrometer. Results confirmed the inverse relationships between contact angle and optical transmissivity independent of fabrication techniques. Microstructural morphologies also suggested the advantage of physical deposition over chemical methods. In summary, the direct sintering method proved outstanding for its contact angle vs transmissivity efficiency, and capable of generating a contact angle as high as 174 degrees. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T08:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>THIN SOLID FILMS,519(19)6224-6229</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6090</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2011.03.129</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14211</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>