<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-312</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Minimum probability of error demodulation for uplink MC-CDMA</dc:title><dc:creator>DAYAL, PM</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHANTA, ANIL</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>ofdm modulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>code division multiple access</dc:subject><dc:subject>demodulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>diversity reception</dc:subject><dc:subject>error statistics</dc:subject><dc:subject>intersymbol interference</dc:subject><dc:subject>least mean squares methods</dc:subject><dc:description>Multi-Carrier Code Division Multiple Access (MC-CDMA) is an attractive choice for high speed wireless communication as it mitigates the problem of Intersymbol Interference (I S) inherent in Code Division Multiple Access (CDMA) and also exploits frequency diversity unlike Orthogonal Frequency Division MultipIexing (OFDM). The data stream in MC-CDMA is spread using a user specific spreading sequence in the frequency domain and thus, every chip travels on a different sub-camer. At the receiver, the different sub-carriers have to be combined properly to form the decision variable. Minimum Mean Square Error (MMSE) detector is a popular choice for this, but as it tries to minimize the Mean Square Error (MSE) and not the Bit Error Rate (BER), the BER it attains is not optimum. In this paper, we propose a Minimum Probability of Error (MPOE) based linear multiuser detector for uplink MC-CDMA, which tries to minimize the probability of error, by exploiting the probability density function (pdf) of the filter’s output. Theoretical and simulation results are presented for the MPOE detector and it can be seen that the MPOE detector outperforms the MMSE detector in terms of BER and Near Far Resistance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-12T04:50:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:31:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-12T04:50:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T09:31:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on Signal Processing and Communications, Bangalore, India, 11-14 December 2004, 428-433</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-8674-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/312</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/312</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>