<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18278</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:41:39Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analytical Modeling of Chip Geometry in High-Speed Ball-End Milling on Inclined Inconel-718 Workpieces</dc:title><dc:creator>SONAWANE, HA</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>CUTTING FORCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INCLINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PREDICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ball-end milling</dc:subject><dc:subject>chip geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear angle</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inconel-718</dc:subject><dc:description>Most often contoured surfaces inclined at several inclinations are generated using ball-end milling of aerospace and automobile components. It is understood that the chip morphology and the corresponding cutting mechanisms change with a change in the tool-workpiece interactions on inclined surfaces. Analytical predictive models to accurately evaluate the undeformed and deformed geometries of chip in ball-end milling are not available. Therefore, this work presents development of analytical models to predict the cutting tool-workpiece interaction as the workpiece inclination changes, in terms of undeformed and deformed chip cross sections. The models further evaluate instantaneous shear angle along any cross section of the tool-work interaction on a ball-end cutter in a milling operation. The models illustrate evaluation of a chip segment and mechanism of its formation in ball-end milling on an inclined work surface. It is observed that the chip dimensions, except deformed chip thickness, increase with an increase in the workpiece inclination angle. Also, a higher workpiece inclination results into an easy flow of the deformed chip over the cutting tool flank, which leads to a higher shear angle during the cut. The predictive chip geometry models corroborate 90% to the experimental results obtained at various workpiece inclinations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASME</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:41:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:41:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MANUFACTURING SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING-TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASME, 137(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1087-1357</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1528-8935</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/1.4028635</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18278</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>