<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-917</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-14T09:57:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Competition between magnetism and superconductivity in tmni2b2c observed by muon-spin rotation</dc:title><dc:creator>COOKE, DW</dc:creator><dc:creator>SMITH, JL</dc:creator><dc:creator>BLUNDELL, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOW, KH</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATTENDEN, PA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRATT, FL</dc:creator><dc:creator>COX, SFJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BROWN, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MORROBELSOSA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>LICHTI, RL</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, LC</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAGARAJAN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSAIN, Z</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAZUMDAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>GODART, C</dc:creator><dc:description>We report muon-spin-rotation measurements of the internal field in the rare-earth nickel boride carbide superconductor TmNi2B2C from 100 mK up to well above the superconducting transition temperature (T-c=9.5 K). An oscillatory muon response indicates that the muon is affected by a quasistatic local field that follows a T-1 dependence over a wide temperature range and without interruption at the superconducting transition. The corresponding relaxation rate remains constant in the normal state, but begins to rise very sharply with decreasing temperature below T-c scaling approximately with the local field down to its maximum at 2.5 K. The quasistatic internal field may be attributed to a spiral structure or dow three-dimensional correlations of the Tm moments. Decoupling experiments reveal a dynamic depolarization mechanism which may tentatively be ascribed to fast two-dimensional correlations of the Ni moments, slowed by the onset of superconductivity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMERICAN PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-11T09:31:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:08:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-11T09:31:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:08:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Note</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B,52(6)R3864-R3867</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0163-1829</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13444</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/917</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>