<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10794</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enhanced granulation by natural ionic polymer additives in UASB reactor treating low-strength wastewater</dc:title><dc:creator>TIWARI, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>HARENDRANATH, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>sludge blanket reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>granules</dc:subject><dc:subject>start</dc:subject><dc:subject>uasb reactor</dc:subject><dc:subject>low-strength wastewater</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhanced granulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sapindus trifoliata</dc:subject><dc:subject>chitosan</dc:subject><dc:subject>cationic polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>anionic polymer</dc:subject><dc:subject>water-absorbing polymer</dc:subject><dc:description>Effect of natural ionic polymer additives on granulation in lab-scale UASB reactors treating low-strength synthetic wastewater (COD 750-850 mg/L) was examined. The organic loading rate was 1.477 +/- 0.118 kg COD/m(3)/day. Under identical conditions four similar reactors were operated in parallel with the following additives: control with no additive, anionic part of Reetha (Sapindus trifoliata) extract, cationic part of Reetha extract, and Chitosan. By the end of the study period, Chitosan as an additive produced largest granules with mean size of 0.15 mm closely followed by the cationic fraction of the Reetha extract with mean size of 0.144 mm, and anionic fractions of the Reetha extract with 0.139 mm. Control reactor with no additives had the smallest size granules with mean size of 0.128 mm. The fraction of granules in the sludge bed of size &gt; 0.1 mm showed similar trend. The largest granule size observed in the reactors with additives was 4-5 mm as compared to 2 mm in the control reactor. Cationic polymers were more effective additives for enhancing sludge granulation. Exo-cellular protein, lipid, sugar and total polymer increased with granulation in the reactors. A COD removal efficiency of 95-98% was achieved in all the reactors. (c) 2005</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T06:51:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T06:51:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESEARCH, 39(16), 3801-3810</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0043-1354</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2005.07.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10794</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10794</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>