<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14072</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:45:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Centrifuge model study on low permeable slope reinforced by hybrid geosynthetics</dc:title><dc:creator>RAISINGHANI, DV</dc:creator><dc:creator>VISWANADHAM, BVS</dc:creator><dc:subject>GEOTEXTILE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRAINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOCOMPOSITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FAILURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TESTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>WALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geosynthetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Low permeable soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reinforced slopes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hybrid Geosynthetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Seepage</dc:subject><dc:subject>Centrifuge modeling</dc:subject><dc:description>The objective of this paper is to study the performance of hybrid geosynthetic reinforced slopes, with permeable geosynthetic as one of its components, for low permeable backfill slopes subjected to seepage. Four centrifuge tests have been performed to study the behavior of hybrid geosynthetic reinforced slopes subjected to seepage, keeping the model slope height and vertical spacing of geosynthetic reinforcement layers constant. Centrifuge model tests were performed on 2V:1H slopes at 30 gravities. One unreinforced, one model geogrid reinforced and two hybrid geosynthetic reinforced slope models with varying number of hybrid geosynthetic layers were tested. The effect of raising ground water table was simulated by using a seepage flow simulator during the flight. Surface movements and pore water pressure profiles for the slope models were monitored using displacement transducers and pore pressure transducers during centrifuge tests. Markers glued on to geosynthetic layers were digitized to arrive at displacement vectors at the onset of raising ground water table. Further, strain distribution along the geosynthetic reinforcement layers and reinforcement peak strain distribution have been determined using digital image analysis technique. The discharge for the performed model tests is determined by performing seepage analysis. It was confirmed by the centrifuge tests that the hybrid geosynthetics increases the stability of low permeable slope subjected to water table rise. The hybrid geosynthetic layers in the bottom half of the slope height play a major role in the dissipation of pore water pressure. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:45:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:45:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GEOTEXTILES AND GEOMEMBRANES,29(6)567-580</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0266-1144</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geotexmem.2011.07.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14072</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>