<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18258</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:31:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of Three Design Architectures for Quantum Dot Infrared Photodetectors: InGaAs-Capped Dots, Dots-in-a-Well, and Submonolayer Quantum Dots</dc:title><dc:creator>GHADI, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SENGUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHETTY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANOHAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALGARKASHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENDYALA, NB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAJAPATI, SL</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>THICKNESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Infrared detectors</dc:subject><dc:subject>photodetectors</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>quantum dots</dc:subject><dc:description>In this letter, we compare three design architectures for quantum dot infrared photodetectors-InGaAs-capped InAs dots, InAs dot-in-a-well (DWELL), and InAs submonolayer (SML) heterostructures-in terms of optical and spectral behavior. The photoluminescence (PL) intensity measured of the SML sample at 8 K was 20 times stronger than that of the other samples, and its full-width at half-maximum value broader than the rest. Activation energy was calculated using temperature-dependent PL and dark current measurements, which showed the same trend. Peak spectral responses for the InGaAs-capped InAs dot and DWELL samples were observed at 4.1 and 7.3 mu m and at 4.1 and 8.5 mu m, respectively; however, only a single transition was observed for the SML sample because of the absence of a wetting layer. Spectral response of DWELL sample exhibited bias tunability at 87 K, and the SML sample exhibited high temperature of operation till 110 K. One order increment in responsivity was observed in the SML sample compared to others. The peak detectivity of InGaAs-capped InAs dot, DWELL, and SML samples was 4.1 x 10(9), 4.99 x 10(9), and 3.89 x 10(9) Jones, respectively, at 87 K.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:31:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:31:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON NANOTECHNOLOGY, 14(4)603-607</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1536-125X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1941-0085</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TNANO.2015.2432044</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18258</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>