<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-706</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-27T04:55:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>A multiple model approach for predictive control of nonlinear hybrid systems</dc:title><dc:creator>NANDOLA, NARESH N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARTIYA, SHARAD</dc:creator><dc:subject>nonlinear systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>bayesian networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>computational efficiency</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonlinear programming</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents modeling and control of nonlinear hybrid systems using multiple linearized models. Each linearized model is a local representation of all locations of the hybrid system. These models are then combined using Bayes theorem to describe the nonlinear hybrid system. The multiple models, which consist of continuous as well as discrete variables, are used for synthesis of a model predictive control (MPC) law. The discrete-time equivalent of the model predicts the hybrid system behavior over the prediction horizon. The MPC formulation takes on a similar form as that used for control of a continuous variable system. Although implementation of the control law requires solution of an online mixed integer nonlinear program, the optimization problem has a fixed structure with certain computational advantages. We demonstrate performance and computational efficiency of the modeling and control scheme using simulations on a benchmark three-spherical tank system and a hydraulic process plant.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-18T09:13:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:14:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-18T09:13:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T17:14:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Process Control 18(2), 131-148</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0959-1524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jprocont.2007.07.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/706</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/706</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>