<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14485</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:10:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Real-time observation of ultrafast Rabi oscillations between excitons and plasmons in metal nanostructures with J-aggregates</dc:title><dc:creator>VASA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>POMRAENKE, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAMMERS, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAIURI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANZONI, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>CERULLO, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIENAU, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE QUANTUM-DOT</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROCAVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTICS</dc:subject><dc:description>Surface plasmon polaritons (SPPs), optical excitations at the interface between a metal and a dielectric, carry significant potential for guiding and manipulating light on the nanoscale(1-3). However, their weak optical nonlinearities hinder active device fabrication, for example, for all-optical switching(4-7) or information processing(8,9). Recently, strong optical dipole coupling has been demonstrated between SPPs and nonlinear quantum emitters with normal mode splittings of up to 700 meV (refs 10-15). The predicted ultrafast energy transfer between quantum emitters and SPP fields could be a crucial microscopic mechanism for switching light by light on the nanoscale. Here, we present the first real-time observation of ultrafast Rabi oscillations in a J-aggregate/metal nanostructure, indicating coherent energy transfer between excitonic quantum emitters and SPP fields. We demonstrate coherent manipulation of the coupling energy by controlling the exciton density on a 10 fs timescale, which represents a step towards coherent, all-optical ultrafast plasmonic circuits and devices.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:10:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:10:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURE PHOTONICS, 7(2)128-132</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/NPHOTON.2012.340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14485</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>