<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9449</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mechanism-based protein design: Attempted "nucleation-condensation" approach to a possible minimal helix-bundle protein</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHANRAJA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHANASEKARAN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNDU, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>DURANI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>de-novo design</dc:subject><dc:subject>beta-turns</dc:subject><dc:subject>biological macromolecules</dc:subject><dc:subject>circular-dichroism</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-states</dc:subject><dc:subject>aqueous-solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>hairpin peptide</dc:subject><dc:subject>conformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>trifluoroethanol</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:subject>de novo design</dc:subject><dc:subject>beta-turn</dc:subject><dc:subject>d-chiral residue</dc:subject><dc:subject>folding nucleation</dc:subject><dc:subject>helix bundle</dc:subject><dc:subject>tertiary structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>conformation energy calculation</dc:subject><dc:description>In an intended mechanism-based de novo approach, a 22-mer peptide was so designed as to make it both a stereochemically nucleatable and hydrophobically condensable minimal globular protein. Framework-like nucleation of a triple-helix bundle was targeted by employing as folding nucleators composite beta-turns that could both nucleate helices and place them in close juxtaposition for possible interhelical interaction. To promote the targeted triple-helix bundle to condense as a globular protein, an amphipathic sequence pattern was adopted for possible hydrophobic interhelical interaction. A predominantly helicogenic 22-mer amphipathic peptide was thus designed, punctuating it with composite type II'-III and type II-Asx type beta-turns as the helix nucleators cum chain reversal elements. The peptide made by solid-phase synthesis was shown by NMR and CD to be a nascent and distorted triple-helix bundle in a trifluoroethanol (TFE)-water mixture, but more or less a random coil in water. A fold nucleation effect is evident in the TFE-water mixture, but apparently the hydrophobic effect cannot sustain the peptide conformational order in water. A lack of synergy between folding nucleation and hydrophobic condensation of the peptide is possible. Indeed, a mismatch between the sequential H, P pattern of the peptide and its nascent-type globular fold in a TFE-water mixture is evident based on a simulated annealing study guided by NMR. (C) 2003 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T08:56:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T08:56:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOPOLYMERS, 70(3), 355-363</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-3525</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/bip.10465</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9449</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9449</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>