<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15822</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:47:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic Stability and Liquefaction Analysis of Tailings Dam</dc:title><dc:creator>DEBARGHYA, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEEPANKAR, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>Tailings dam</dc:subject><dc:subject>displacement</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability of slope</dc:subject><dc:subject>liquefaction potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>AMPLIFICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOILS</dc:subject><dc:description>Proper analysis for safe design of tailings earthen dam is necessary under static loading and more so under earthquake conditions to reduce damages of important geotechnical structure. This paper presents both static and seismic analyses of a typical section of tailings earthen dam constructed by downstream method and located at a site in eastern part India to store non-radioactive nuclear waste material. The entire analysis is performed using geotechnical softwares FLAC(3D) and TALREN 4. Results are obtained for various possible conditions of the reservoir to investigate the stability under both static and seismic loading condition using 1989 Loma Prieta earthquake acceleration-time history. FLAC(3D) analyses indicate the critical maximum displacement at crest of the proposed tailings dam section is 5.5 cm under the static loading but it increases to about 16.24 cm under seismic loading. The slope stability analyses provide the minimum value of factor of safety for seismic loading as 1.5 as compared to 2.31 for static loading. Amplification of base seismic acceleration is also observed. The liquefaction potential analysis in FLAC(3D) indicates considerable loss of shear strength in the tailings portion of the proposed earthen dam section with significantly high values of pore pressure ratio.</dc:description><dc:publisher>DISASTER ADVANCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:47:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:47:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DISASTER ADVANCES, 5(3)15-25</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15822</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>