<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-682</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Simulation of three dimensional circulation flow field for groundwater pollution remediation</dc:title><dc:creator>KIRUBAHARAN C, SAMUEL</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>ULF MOHRLOK</dc:creator><dc:subject>groundwater circulation well</dc:subject><dc:subject>groundwater remediation</dc:subject><dc:subject>solute transport</dc:subject><dc:subject>numerical simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>The contamination of groundwater by Dense Non-Aqueous Phase Liquids (DNAPL) such as TCE, PCE etc., is a significant problem in all industrial countries. Until recently pump-and-treat method was the widely adopted remediation technique. Owing to the high operation costs involved, efforts were made in the past decade to find innovative in situ remediation techniques such as Groundwater Circulation Well (GCW). In this technique vertical circulation flow is artificially induced around wells with at least two screen sections. As the flow phenomena surrounding a GCW in a heterogeneous aquifer is very complex, the characterization of transport is very difficult. This paper presents the simulation and analysis of experimental tracer transport in a three-dimensional (3D) flow field induced by a GCW in an artificial aquifer at the research facility for groundwater remediation VEGAS at University of Stuttgart, Germany. The circulation flow field within a heterogeneous aquifer was investigated by a partial tracer injection tracing a certain stream tube of the flow field. A numerical model has been built-up and simulation has been carried out for flow and transport processes. Experimental and simulated breakthrough curves were compared and the influence of aquifer heterogeneity and dispersivity on the transport has been evaluated. The present study gives further insight into the remediation by GCW.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IACMAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:09:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:29:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-17T12:09:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:29:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 12th IACMAG: Geomechanics in the Emerging Social &amp; Technological Age, Goa, India, 1-6 October 2008, 2551-2558</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/682</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>