<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15018</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:35:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Study of the preparation, properties and kinetics of anion release in drug intercalated magnetic nanohybrids</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDA, HS</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Layered compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnetic materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>Intercalation reactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>LAYERED DOUBLE HYDROXIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERPARAMAGNETIC NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUSTAINED-RELEASE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CLAYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIVO</dc:subject><dc:description>We report a new magnetic nanohybrid material to make layered double hydroxides (LDHs) as a targeted drug carrier. The magnetite prepared using a modified conventional coprecipitation technique was embedded in to the fluvastatin intercalated hydrophobic anionic clay through one step process. XRD analysis shows a decrease in lattice parameter of magnetite which is due to generation of stress by the LDHs. Filtered HRTEM image indicates that the magnetic nanohybrid consists of well-defined composite structure and the diameter is around 13 nm. Further, it is shown through magnetisation and ESR study that the exchange interaction between magnetite and drug intercalated LDHs layers shifted the T-B of Fe3O4 in magnetic nanohybrid to lower temperatures. In vitro release study of nanohybrid particles at pH 7.4 in PBS and at 37 degrees C show a faster release for magnetic nanohybrids. The mechanism is probably due to combined effect of interparticle and heterogeneous diffusion via anionic exchange. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:35:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:35:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS RESEARCH BULLETIN, 47(3)571-579</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2011.12.041</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15018</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>