<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15928</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:17:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>BaV3O8: A possible Majumdar-Ghosh system with S=1/2</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTY, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>GIPPIUS, AA</dc:creator><dc:creator>TKACHEV, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTTGEN, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRAETSCHMER, W</dc:creator><dc:subject>HEISENBERG-ANTIFERROMAGNET</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-SUSCEPTIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERCONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FRUSTRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>VANADATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>STATE</dc:subject><dc:description>BaV3O8 contains magnetic V4+(S = 1/2) ions and also nonmagnetic V5+(S = 0) ions. The V4+ ions are arranged in a coupled Majumdar-Ghosh chainlike network. A Curie-Weiss fit of our magnetic susceptibility.(T) data in the temperature region of 80-300 K yields a Curie constant C = 0.39 cm(3)K/mole V4+ and an antiferromagnetic Weiss temperature theta = -26 K. The chi(T) curve shows a broad maximum at T similar or equal to 25 K indicative of short-range order (SRO) and an anomaly corresponding to long-range order (LRO) at T-N similar to 6K. The value of the "frustration parameter" (f = vertical bar theta/T-N vertical bar similar to 5) suggests that the system is moderately frustrated. Above the LRO temperature, the experimental magnetic susceptibility data match well with the coupled Majumdar-Ghosh (or J(nn) -J(nnn) Heisenberg) chain model with the ratio of the nnn (next-nearest neighbor) to nn (nearest neighbor) magnetic coupling alpha = 2 and J(nnn)/k(B) = 40 K. In a mean-field approach when considering the interchain interactions, we obtain the total interchain coupling to be about 16 K. The LRO anomaly at T-N is also observed in the specific heat CP(T) data and is not sensitive to an applied magnetic field up to 90 kOe. A 51V NMR signal corresponding to the nonmagnetic vanadium was observed. Anomalies at 6 K were observed in the variation with temperature of the 51V NMR linewidth and the spin-lattice relaxation rate 1/T-1 indicating that they are sensitive to the LRO onset and fluctuations at themagnetic V sites. The existence of two components (one short and another long) is observed in the spin-spin relaxation rate 1/T-2 data in the vicinity of TN. The shorter component seems to be intimately connected with the magnetically ordered state. We suggest that both magnetically ordered and nonlong-range-ordered (non-LRO) regions coexist in this compound below the long-range-ordering temperature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:17:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:17:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 88(1)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.88.014433</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15928</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>