<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18149</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:20:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Passive blood plasma separation at the microscale: a review of design principles and microdevices</dc:title><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, YVBV</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHAKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>RED-CELL DISTRIBUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WHOLE HUMAN BLOOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRIVEN MICROFLUIDIC DEVICE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ON-A-CHIP</dc:subject><dc:subject>CROSS-FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>FREE LAYER</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROVASCULAR BIFURCATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>APPARENT VISCOSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAPID SEPARATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROCHANNEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrodynamic</dc:subject><dc:subject>geometrical effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>bio-physical effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>sedimentation</dc:subject><dc:subject>microfiltration</dc:subject><dc:subject>microfluidics</dc:subject><dc:description>Blood plasma separation is vital in the field of diagnostics and health care. Due to the inherent advantages obtained in the transition to microscale, the recent trend in these fields is a rapid shift towards the miniaturization of complex macro processes. Plasma separation in microdevices is one such process which has received extensive attention from researchers globally. Blood plasma separation techniques based on microfluidic platforms can be broadly classified into two categories. While active techniques utilize external force fields for separation, the passive techniques are dependent on biophysical effects, cell behavior, hydrodynamic forces and channel geometry for blood plasma separation. In general, passive separation methods are favored in comparison to active methods because they tend to avoid design complexities and are relatively easy to integrate with biosensors; additionally they are cost effective. Here we review passive separation techniques demonstrating separation and blood behavior at microscale. We present an extensive review of relevant biophysical laws, along with experimental details of various passive separation techniques and devices exploiting these physical effects. The relative performances, and the advantages and disadvantages of microdevices discussed in the literature, are compared and future challenges are brought about.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:20:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:20:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MICROMECHANICS AND MICROENGINEERING, 25(8)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-1317</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1361-6439</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0960-1317/25/8/083001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18149</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>