<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13841</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-08T18:44:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermodynamic studies on the interaction of folic acid with bovine serum albumin</dc:title><dc:creator>JHA, NS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>THYMIDYLATE SYNTHASE INHIBITORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRUG-BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROTEINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Bovine serum albumin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Folic acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>Isothermal titration calorimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>Binding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Thermodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:description>Binding of the vitamin folic acid with bovine serum albumin (BSA) has been studied using isothermal titration calorimetry (ITC) in combination with fluorescence and circular dichroism spectroscopies. The thermodynamic parameters of binding have been evaluated as a function of temperature, ionic strength, in the presence of nonionic surfactants triton X-100, tetrabutylammonium bromide, and sucrose. The values of the van't Hoff enthalpy calculated from the temperature dependence of the binding constant agree with the calorimetric enthalpies indicating that the binding of folic acid to the BSA is a two state process without involving intermediates. These observations are supported by the intrinsic fluorescence and circular dichroism spectroscopic measurements. With increase in the ionic strength, reduction in the binding affinity of folic acid to BSA is observed suggesting predominance of electrostatic interactions in the binding. The contribution of hydrophobic interactions in the binding is also demonstrated by decrease in the binding affinity in the presence of tetrabutylammonium bromide (TBAB). The value of binding affinity in the presence of sucrose indicates that hydrogen bonding also plays a significant contribution in the complexation process. The calorimetric and spectroscopic results provide quantitative information on the binding of folic acid to BSA and suggest that the binding is dominated by electrostatic interactions with contribution from hydrogen bonding. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-02-08T18:44:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-02-08T18:44:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL THERMODYNAMICS,43(5)814-821</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9614</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jct.2010.12.024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13841</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>