<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3776</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cracking in Drying Colloidal Films of Flocculated Dispersions</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, KB</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHOSALE, LR</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIRUMKUDULU, MS</dc:creator><dc:subject>latex films</dc:subject><dc:subject>suspensions</dc:subject><dc:subject>stresses</dc:subject><dc:subject>rheology</dc:subject><dc:subject>alumina</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear</dc:subject><dc:description>Understanding the mechanism of cracking during the drying of aqueous colloidal dispersions is important to preventing film failure. While most of the reported work has dealt with stable aqueous dispersions, a few studies have focused on flocculated systems. The latter especially assumes importance because the role of particle packing in the mechanism of cracking is not completely understood. In this work, we study the cracking of colloidal films cast from flocculated aqueous dispersions of alpha-alumina. Here, the extent of flocculation is controlled by varying the pH of the dispersion and characterized in terms of the final packing volume fraction of the dried film. The influence of varying the close-packed volume fraction on the critical cracking thickness and critical cracking stress is measured. The measurements are compared with the model predictions based on Griffith's energy balance, and good agreement is found between theory and experiments, suggesting that the model is universal and applies equally well to stable as well as flocculated systems.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T21:31:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T21:31:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LANGMUIR, 25(8), 4284-4287</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0743-7463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/la804331c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3776</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3776</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>