<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9752</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effects of alternative carbon sources on biological transformation of nitrophenols</dc:title><dc:creator>KARIM, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>n-substituted aromatics</dc:subject><dc:subject>granular sludge</dc:subject><dc:subject>uasb reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>denitrification</dc:subject><dc:subject>toxicity</dc:subject><dc:subject>biotransformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>mineralization</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>consortium</dc:subject><dc:subject>acetate</dc:subject><dc:subject>aminophenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>glucose</dc:subject><dc:subject>methanol</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrate</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrophenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>uasb</dc:subject><dc:description>The removal of nitrophenols under denitrifying conditions was studied in bench-scale upflow anaerobic sludge blanket (UASB) reactors (R1, R2, R3 and R4) using three different carbon sources. Initially acetate was used as carbon source (substrate) in all the four reactors followed by glucose and methanol. Reactor R1 was kept as control and R2, R3, R4 were fed with 30 mg/l concentration of 2-nitrophenol (2-NP), 4-nitrophenol (4-NP), and 2,4-dinitrophenol (2,4-DNP), respectively. Throughout the study the hydraulic retention time (HRT) and COD/NO3--N ratio were kept as 24 h and 10, respectively. 2-Aminophenol (2-AP), 4-aminophenol (4-AP) and 2-amino, 4-nitrophenol (2-A, 4-NP) were found as the major intermediate metabolites of 2-NP, 4-NP and 2, 4-DNP degradation, respectively. Methanol was found to be a better carbon source for 4-NP and 2,4-DNP degradation as compared to acetate and glucose, while 2-NP degradation was not influenced much by the change of substrate. Nitrate nitrogen removal was always more than 99%. COD removal efficiency of the nitrophenol fed reactors varied from 85.7% to 97.7%. The oxidation-reduction potential (ORP) inside the reactors dropped, up to -300 mv, with glucose as carbon source. As the reactors were switched over to methanol, ORP increased to -190 mv. The granular sludge developed inside the reactors was light brown in colour when acetate and glucose were used as substrate, which turned dark brown to black at the end of methanol run. Biomass yield in terms of volatile suspended solids was observed as 0.15, 0.089 and 0.14 g per gram of COD removal for acetate, glucose and methanol, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T04:58:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T04:58:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIODEGRADATION, 13(5), 353-360</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0923-9820</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1022364616575</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9752</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9752</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>