<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1487</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Properties of CMR composites</dc:title><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>low-field magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>room-temperature magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>ca-mn-o</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanosized la0.7sr0.3mno3/pr0.5sr0.5mno3 composites</dc:subject><dc:subject>colossal magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>enhanced magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>giant magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>manganese oxides</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>manganites</dc:subject><dc:subject>colossal magnetoresistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>composites</dc:subject><dc:description>Colossal magnetoresistance (CMR) composites form an interesting field of study. The intrinsic CMR, governed by the intragrain transport of the conduction electrons through the double exchange, limits its application owing to the high field requirement and generally low transition temperatures. Extrinsic CMR, a function of the intergrain transport between ferromagnetic (FM) particles, plays a crucial role in enhancing low field magnetoresistance (LFMR) or increasing room temperature magnetoresistance. Since extrinsic CMR is a grain boundary controlled phenomena, magnetically dirty grain boundaries in the virgin state of the sample help in achieving a high LFMR or increase the field sensitivity. In this article, we give the properties of different composites of magnetoresistive LCMO or LSMO where the second component is (a) an insulating phase, (b) a conducting phase, (c) a nonmagnetic phase and (d) a magnetic phase. We present here some of our recent work on CMR composites where the CMR phase is chosen as LCMO and SiO2, ZnO, ZrO2 and SiCN have been used as the different second phase of the composites. We summarise some of the salient features of the results.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T15:02:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T15:02:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INDIAN ACADEMY OF SCIENCES-CHEMICAL SCIENCES,115,587-606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4134</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14925</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1487</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Emerging Directions in Chemical Sciences,BANGALORE, INDIA,NOV 25-28, 2003</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>