<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1465</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Scattering and absorption properties of multiply coated magnetic nanoparticles</dc:title><dc:creator>PURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>permeability</dc:subject><dc:subject>permittivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>coated nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>maxwell-garnett theory</dc:subject><dc:description>The optical properties of a material are characterized by its electric and magnetic susceptibilities. Finding analytical expressions for those quantities for a nanoparticle of arbitrary shape is generally a formidable task. A great deal of insight in to the basic phenomena can be obtained by studying analytically solvable cases, for nanoparticles of ellipsoidal and spherical shapes. We present here our study on the scattering and absorptive properties of multiply coated magnetic spherical and elliptical nanoparticles as functions of frequency of an incident electromagnetic radiation. We will present our results based on the analytical expressions for the dielectric and magnetic susceptibilities derived for such multiply coated nanoparticles. To our knowledge, the latter results are new. We will also present our results based on Maxwell-Garnett theory for a material having uniform distribution of mono dispersed multiply coated nanoparticles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T08:14:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T08:14:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY,9(9)5177-5182</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1533-4880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jnn.2009.1147</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1465</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Nanoscience and Technology,Chennai, INDIA,FEB 27-29, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>