<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12494</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic asset management with risk-sensitive criterion and non-negative factor constraints: a differential game approach</dc:title><dc:creator>BAGCHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, KS</dc:creator><dc:subject>oblique reflection</dc:subject><dc:subject>equations</dc:subject><dc:subject>domains</dc:subject><dc:subject>risk-sensitive control</dc:subject><dc:subject>portfolio optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>reflecting diffusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>skorohod problem</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we study continuous time portfolio optimization problem where individual securities are directly affected by economic factors. We consider the risk-sensitive criterion function as is familiar in the robust control literature. This is the natural setting for studying the infinite horizon case of the control problem arising in portfolio optimization. Our result extends earlier works by imposing explicitly the non-negativity constraint on the economic factors. This is achieved by using reflected diffusions. The risk-sensitive control problem with reflected diffusion is then converted into a stochastic differential game. The lower value of this game leads immediately to the desired optimal strategy. Also we prove the existence of unique strong solution to reflected diffusions with bounded measurable drift coefficient which is the first result of its kind for higher dimensional reflected diffusions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T22:54:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T22:54:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STOCHASTICS-AN INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PROBABILITY AND STOCHASTIC PROCESSES, 81(5), 503-530</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1744-2508</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17442500902774917</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12494</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12494</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>