<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15755</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:13:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>A nanoparticulate injectable hydrogel as a tissue engineering scaffold for multiple growth factor delivery for bone regeneration</dc:title><dc:creator>DYONDI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>WEBSTER, TJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>bone tissue engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>bone morphogenetic protein 7 (BMP7)</dc:subject><dc:subject>basic fibroblast growth factor (bFGF)</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogel</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>osteoblasts</dc:subject><dc:subject>MESENCHYMAL STEM-CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIFFERENTIATION IN-VITRO</dc:subject><dc:subject>GELLAN GUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>OSTEOBLAST DIFFERENTIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MORPHOGENETIC PROTEINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHONDROGENESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MINERALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROLIFERATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:description>Gellan xanthan gels have been shown to be excellent carriers for growth factors and as matrices for several tissue engineering applications. Gellan xanthan gels along with chitosan nanoparticles of 297 +/- 61 nm diameter, basic fibroblast growth factor (bFGF), and bone morphogenetic protein 7 (BMP7) were employed in a dual growth factor delivery system to promote the differentiation of human fetal osteoblasts. An injectable system with ionic and temperature gelation was optimized and characterized. The nanoparticle loaded gels showed significantly improved cell proliferation and differentiation due to the sustained release of growth factors. A differentiation marker study was conducted, analyzed, and compared to understand the effect of single vs dual growth factors and free vs encapsulated growth factors. Dual growth factor loaded gels showed a higher alkaline phosphatase and calcium deposition compared to single growth factor loaded gels. The results suggest that encapsulation and stabilization of growth factors within nanoparticles and gels are promising for bone regeneration. Gellan xanthan gels also showed antibacterial effects against Pseudomonas aeruginosa, Staphylococcus aureus, and Staphylococcus epidermidis, the common pathogens in implant failure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>DOVE MEDICAL PRESS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:13:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:13:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF NANOMEDICINE, 847-59</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.2147/IJN.S37953</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15755</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>