<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4980</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel finite-element-numerical-integration model for composite laminates supported on opposite edges</dc:title><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>PENLHARI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, YM</dc:creator><dc:subject>order refined theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>sandwich plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>hybrid-stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>free-vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin</dc:subject><dc:subject>plane-strain</dc:subject><dc:subject>partial discretization</dc:subject><dc:subject>laminate</dc:subject><dc:subject>boundary value problem</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>numerical integration method</dc:subject><dc:description>An attempt is made here to devise a new methodology for an integrated stress analysis of laminated composite plates wherein both in-plane and transverse stresses are evaluated simultaneously. The method is based on the governing three-dimensional (3D) partial differential equations (PDEs) of elasticity. A systematic procedure is developed for a case when one of the two in-plane dimensions of the laminate is considered infinitely long (y direction) with no changes in loadin and boundary conditions in that direction. The laminate could then be considered in a two-dimensional (2D) state of plane strain in x-z plane. It is here that the governing 2D PDEs are transformed into a coupled system of first-order ordinary differential equations (ODEs) in transverse z direction by introducing partial discretization in the finite inplane direction x. The mathematical model thus reduces to solution of a boundary value problem (BVP) in the transverse z direction in ODEs. This BVP is then transformed into a set of initial value problems (IVPs) so as to use the available efficient and effective numerical integrators for them. Through thickness displacement and stress fields at the finite element discrete nodes are observed to be in excellent agreement with the elasticity solution. A few new results for cross-ply laminates under clamped support conditions are also presented for future reference and also to show the generality of the formulation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASME-AMER SOC MECHANICAL ENG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T16:24:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T16:24:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED MECHANICS-TRANSACTIONS OF THE ASME, 74(6), 1114-1124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-8936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1115/1.2722770</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4980</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4980</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>