<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1453</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-14T13:45:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experience with UASB reactor start-up under different operating conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>GHANGREKAR, MM</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASOLEKAR, SR</dc:creator><dc:creator>RANGANATHAN, KR</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, SG</dc:creator><dc:subject>sludge</dc:subject><dc:subject>hrt</dc:subject><dc:subject>integrity coefficient</dc:subject><dc:subject>olr</dc:subject><dc:subject>slr</dc:subject><dc:subject>sludge granules</dc:subject><dc:subject>start-up</dc:subject><dc:subject>uasb</dc:subject><dc:description>Four laboratory upflow anaerobic sludge blanket (UASB) reactors were operated at different operating parameters viz., hydraulic retention time (HRT), upflow velocity, organic concentration, and Ca2+ concentration in the wastewater. These operating parameters gave different values of organic loading rates (OLRs) and sludge loading rates (SLRs). The reactor performance during start-up was evaluated at different values of the above listed parameters. Also, the effects of these parameters on the granule characteristics were investigated. It was observed that COD removal efficiency at steady state was profoundly influenced by SLR. The reactor started with SLR of 0.6 kgCOD/kgVSS.d could result in about 50% COD removal at steady state. The reactor performance could not improve even after three months of operation. Up to 0.3 kgCOD/kgVSS.d the reactor performance was good with more than 90% COD removal at steady state. The OLR and SLR also determine time required for the reactor to achieve steady state. Different operating conditions also have the bearing on the strength of the granules cultivated. The methanogenic activity measured on acetate for each reactor was observed between 0.259 and 0.909 kg CH4 COD/kgVSS.d. The sludge production in all the reactors was between 0.087 and 0.13 kgVSS/kgCOD(in). The mathematical model was developed in order to predict sludge production. Copyright (C) 1996 IAWQ.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T18:11:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T18:11:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>1996</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY,34(5-6)421-428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0273-1223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0273-1223(96)00674-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1453</dc:identifier><dc:source>18th Biennial Conference of the International-Association-on-Water-Quality,SINGAPORE, SINGAPORE,JUN 23-28, 1996</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>