<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15166</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:34:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of variation in axial spacing and rotor speed combinations on the performance of a high aspect ratio contra-rotating axial fan stage</dc:title><dc:creator>MISTRY, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRADEEP, AM</dc:creator><dc:subject>Axial fans</dc:subject><dc:subject>compressor performance</dc:subject><dc:subject>turbomachinery aerodynamics</dc:subject><dc:description>This article reports a parametric study on the performance of a high aspect ratio, low speed contra-rotating fan stage. Parameters namely speed ratios of the two rotors and axial spacing between the rotors that play a significant role on the overall performance of the contra-rotating fan stage were evaluated. The rotors have a low hub-tip ratio of 0.35 and chord of 45mm. The two rotors were designed to develop a pressure rise of 1100Pa and 900Pa, respectively, when operating at 2400r/min and developing a mass flow rate of 6kg/s. In order to evaluate the performance of the designed rotors, measurements of total pressure at the entry of rotor-1, between the rotors and the exit of rotor-2 were taken using total pressure probe rake, 4-hole probe and a Kiel probe rake. The experiments were conducted for different speed combinations of rotor-1 and rotor-2. All these speed combinations were studied separately for different axial spacing. The performance plots revealed the existence of two stall limits namely, partial stall and full stall. For lower throttle positions, rotor-2 was observed to stall. Further lowering the mass flow rate; reduces the pressure rise capacity of the stage due to stalling of rotor-1 as well as rotor-2. For the design speed operation of rotor-1 in combination with an off-design speed of rotor-2, the flow parameters change significantly. A higher rotational speed of rotor-2 generates a stronger suction effect leading to an overall improvement in the performance of the whole stage. The effect of variation in the axial spacing between the rotors was also studied. The strongest suction effect between the rotors was observed at an axial spacing of 0.9 chord.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:34:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF THE INSTITUTION OF MECHANICAL ENGINEERS PART A-JOURNAL OF POWER AND ENERGY, 227(2)138-146</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/0957650912467453</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15166</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>