<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14804</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:58:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Co-existence of magnetocaloric effect and magnetoresistance in Co substituted La0.67Sr0.33MnO3 at room temperature</dc:title><dc:creator>RESHMI, CP</dc:creator><dc:creator>PILLAI, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VASUNDHARA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJI, GR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:creator>VARMA, MR</dc:creator><dc:subject>MAGNETIC ENTROPY CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLOSSAL MAGNETORESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>300 K</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-SEPARATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MANGANITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:description>Magnetization (M), Magnetocaloric effect (MCE), and Magnetoresistance (MR) in Co substituted La0.67Sr0.33Mn1-xCoxO3 (x = 0.03, 0.05, and 0.1) samples have been investigated. All the studied samples were crystallized into a single phase rhombohedral structure with R (3) over barc space group. The Curie temperature (T-C) is found to decrease with the increase of Co content and for the composition x = 0.1, a cluster glass-like nature is observed. Temperature variation of magnetic entropy change (Delta S-M) shows a positive peak at TC for the composition x = 0.1 with Delta S-M = 3.1 J/kg K and relative cooling power, RCP = 155 J/kg at a magnetic field of 50 kOe. Again, the critical analysis of the paramagnetic to ferromagnetic transition and the scaling behaviour of field dependence of MCE for x = 0.1 composition is also reported. Furthermore, the temperature dependence of electrical resistivity under the magnetic fields up to 50 kOe is reported along with the values of 20% enhancement in MR at room temperature for the Co substituted samples. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:58:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:58:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS, 114(3)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4813515</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14804</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>