<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16318</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:07:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Accelerating rare events while overcoming the low-barrier problem using a temperature program</dc:title><dc:creator>DIVI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>CLUSTER-EXPANSION MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INFREQUENT EVENTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIFFUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AG</dc:subject><dc:subject>CU</dc:subject><dc:description>We present a hierarchical coarse-grained simulation technique called the temperature programmed molecular dynamics (TPMD) method for accelerating molecular dynamics (MD) simulations of rare events. The method is targeted towards materials where a system visits many times a collection of energy basins in the potential energy surface, called a superbasin, via low-barrier moves before escaping to a new superbasin via a high-barrier move. The superbasin escape events are rare at the MD time scales. The low-barrier moves become accessible to MD by employing a temperature program, i.e., the MD temperature changes during the simulation. Once a superbasin is detected, transitions within the superbasin are ignored, in effect causing coarse-graining of basins. The temperature program enables the system to escape from the superbasin with reduced computational cost thereby overcoming the "low-barrier" problem. The main advantage of our approach is that the superbasin-to-superbasin transitions are accurately obtained at the original temperature with a reasonable computational cost. We study surface diffusion in Ag/Ag(001) system and demonstrate the ability of the TPMD method to span a wide-range of timescales. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:07:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:07:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL PHYSICS, 140(18)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9606</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-7690</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4875476</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16318</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>