<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9172</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Piezo actuator placement and sizing for good control effectiveness and minimal change in original system dynamics</dc:title><dc:creator>DHURI, KD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHU, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>active vibration control</dc:subject><dc:subject>piezoelectric actuators</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>beam</dc:subject><dc:subject>controllability</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:description>Piezoelectric actuators are commonly considered for active vibration control of smart structures. The placement and sizing of the actuators are normally decided based on control effectiveness. A piezo actuator affects the host structure's mass and stiffness properties and thus alters the original system, which would have been designed to have a certain natural frequency spectrum in relation to the disturbance excitation. For a rotating structure, the mass of the actuator additionally contributes to the centrifugal stiffening effect. In the event of failure of the active system, natural frequencies of the structure with piezos ( now rendered passive) become significant. Considering the example of a stationary and rotating beam-like structure, it is attempted to identify the piezo actuator sizing and location that possess significant control effectiveness yet cause minimal change in the system dynamics.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T23:25:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T23:25:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SMART MATERIALS &amp; STRUCTURES, 15(6), 1661-1672</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0964-1726</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0964-1726/15/6/019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9172</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>