<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6662</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Identification and characterization of membrane-associated polypeptides in Torpedo nicotinic acetylcholine receptor-rich membranes by hydrophobic photolabeling</dc:title><dc:creator>BLANTON, MP</dc:creator><dc:creator>LALA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>COHEN, JB</dc:creator><dc:subject>gated chloride channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>amino-acid-sequence</dc:subject><dc:subject>mitochondrial porin</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric organ</dc:subject><dc:subject>postsynaptic membranes</dc:subject><dc:subject>skeletal-muscle</dc:subject><dc:subject>agrin receptor</dc:subject><dc:subject>ion-channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>purification</dc:subject><dc:subject>[h-3]diazofluorene</dc:subject><dc:subject>nicotinic acetylcholine receptor</dc:subject><dc:subject>(na++k+)-atpase</dc:subject><dc:subject>voltage-dependent anion channel</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoaffinity</dc:subject><dc:description>To identify membrane-associated polypeptides present in Torpedo nicotinic acetylcholine receptor (AChR)-rich membranes, we used hydrophobic photolabeling with [H-3]diazofluorene ([H-3]DAF) and 1-azidopyrene (1-AP) to tag the membrane proteins which were then identified by amino-terminal sequence analysis of labeled fragments isolated from proteolytic digests by sodium dodecyl sulfate-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis followed by reverse-phase high-performance liquid chromatography. In addition to AChR subunits, identified polypeptides include the 95 kDa alpha -subunit of the (Na++K+)-ATPase, the 89 kDa voltage-gated chloride channel (CLC-0), the 105 kDa SITS-binding protein, and 32 and 34 kDa polypeptides identified as Torpedo homologues of the mitochondrial membrane ATP/ADP carrier protein and the voltage-dependent anion channel (VDAC), respectively. Further, individual amino acids that reacted with [H-3]DAF and therefore likely to be in contact with lipid were identified in the transmembrane segment M3 of the alpha -subunit of the (Na++K+)-ATPase and in a putative transmembrane beta -strand in VDAC. Collectively these results demonstrate that [H-3]DAF/1-AP photolabeling provides an effective method for tagging the membrane-associated segments of polypeptides in a way that makes it easy to isolate the labeled polypeptide or polypeptide fragments by fluorescence and then to identify amino acids at the lipid-protein interface by H-3 release. (C) 2001  .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T06:30:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T06:30:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHIMICA ET BIOPHYSICA ACTA-BIOMEMBRANES, 1512(2), 215-224</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0005-2736</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0005-2736(01)00321-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6662</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6662</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>