<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17604</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:22:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thermodynamic insights into drug-surfactant interactions: Study of the interactions of naporxen, diclofenac sodium, neomycin, and lincomycin with hexadecytrimethylammonium bromide by using isothermal titration calorimetry</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHARY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>TALELE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>KISHORE, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>PHARMACOLOGICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICELLAR SOLUTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NAPROXEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>INHIBITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>AGGREGATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEQUALINIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCATTERING</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELIVERY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHLORIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDING</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug delivery</dc:subject><dc:subject>Micelles</dc:subject><dc:subject>Drug-partitioning</dc:subject><dc:subject>Isothermal titration calorimetry, Cationic surfactant</dc:subject><dc:description>The success of drug delivery depends on the efficiency of the route of administration, which in turn relies on properties of the drug and its transport vehicle. A quantitative knowledge of association of drugs with transport vehicles is lacking when the latter are in the category of self assembled structures. The work reported in this manuscript addresses the mechanism of partitioning of naproxen, diclofenac sodium, neomycin and lincomycin in the micelles of hexadecytrimethylammonium bromide and that is quantitatively based on the measurement of thermodynamic parameters of interactions by using isothermal titration calorimetry. The addressed mechanism of partitioning is based on the identification of the type of interactions of these drugs with the surfactant micelles and monomers, along with the effect of the former on the micellization properties of the surfactant. The conclusions are based on the interpretation of the values of partitioning constant, standard molar enthalpy change, standard molar entropy change and the stoichiometry of the interaction. The results of this study have implications for deriving guidelines for the target oriented synthesis of new drugs that are to be used for effective delivery via micellar media. (c) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:22:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:22:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COLLOIDS AND SURFACES B-BIOINTERFACES, 132,313-321</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0927-7765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4367</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfb.2015.05.031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17604</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>