<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6231</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic rotational displacement of gravity walls by pseudo-dynamic method: Passive case</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIMBALKAR, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>retaining walls</dc:subject><dc:subject>rigid walls</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquakes</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressures</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquakes</dc:subject><dc:subject>retaining wall</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>time dependence</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil-wall interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>design parameters</dc:subject><dc:description>Prediction of the seismic rotational displacements of retaining wall under passive condition is an important aspect of design in earthquake prone region. In this paper, the pseudo-dynamic method is used to compute the rotational displacements of rigid retaining wall supporting cohesionless backfill under seismic loading for the passive earth pressure condition. The proposed method considers time, phase difference and effect of amplification in shear and primary waves propagating through both the backfill and the retaining wall. The influence of ground motion characteristics on rotational displacement of the wall is evaluated. Also the effects of variation of parameters like wall friction angle, soil friction angle, amplification factor, shear wave velocity, primary wave velocity, period of lateral shaking, horizontal and vertical seismic accelerations on the rotational displacements are studied. The rotational displacement of the wall increases substantially with increase in amplification of both shear and primary waves, time of input motion, period of lateral shaking and decreases with increase in soil friction angle, wall friction angle. The rotational displacements of the wall also increase when the effect of wall inertia is taken into account. Results are provided in graphical form. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-22T12:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-22T12:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SOIL DYNAMICS AND EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING, 27(3), 242-249</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0267-7261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.soildyn.2006.06.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6231</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>