<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-415</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis and design of superjunction power MOSFET: CoolMOS™ for improved on resistance and breakdown voltage using theory of novel voltage sustaining layer</dc:title><dc:creator>KONDEKAR, PN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, MB</dc:creator><dc:creator>PARIKH, CD</dc:creator><dc:subject>power mosfet</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor device breakdown</dc:subject><dc:subject>semiconductor device models</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we have observed that the drift layer of conventional power device can be modified to SJ-drift layer for improvement in the breakdown voltage (BV). Doping level of SJ-drift layer increased by one order of magnitude gives at least 5 times improvement in on resistance Ron, without reducing the BV. Further increase in the BV is possible by increasing the thickness of the SJ-drift layer where we observed the proportional increase in Ron. Theory of novel voltage sustaining layer (SJ-theory) recently published is used for the first time to analyze and design CoolMOS structure. We observed that for a fixed cell-pitch, increasing the height of drift layer proportionately increases the BV. The rate of increasing BV is higher for smaller cell-pitch. The Ron also increases proportionally. For a fixed geometry increasing doping level by one order of magnitude reduces the BV and the rate of reduction of this BV is dependent on the cell-pitch.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-19T10:51:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T00:05:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-19T10:51:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T00:05:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 23rd International Conference on Microelectronics (V 1), Nis, Yugoslavia, 12-15 May 2002, 209-212</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-7235-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/MIEL.2002.1003176</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/415</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/415</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>