<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3815</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electronic and vibrational spectroscopic investigation of phenylacetylene - Amine complexes. Evidence for the diversity in the intermolecular structures</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, PC</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:subject>supersonic jets</dc:subject><dc:subject>clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>ammonia</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenol</dc:subject><dc:description>Shifts in the electronic transitions for the complexes of phenylacetylene with ammonia, methylamine, and triethylamine clearly indicate the variation in the intermolecular structures of the three complexes. The infrared spectrum of phenylacetylene in the, acetylenic C-H stretching region shows Fermi resonance bands, which act as a sensitive tool to probe the intermolecular structures. The IR-UV double resonance spectra of the three complexes are disparate and signify the formation of distinct structures. The formation of C-H center dot center dot center dot N hydrogen-bonded complex with ammonia and two distinct types of c complexes with methylamine and triethylamine can be inferred from the analysis of electronic and vibrational spectra in combination with ab initio calculations. These complexes clearly point out the fact that marginal changes in the interacting partner can significantly alter the intermolecular structure.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T00:55:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T00:55:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 112(19), 4426-4431</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp800064b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3815</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3815</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>