<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1083</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Real-time wave forecasting using genetic programming</dc:title><dc:creator>GAUR, SURABHI</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEO, MC</dc:creator><dc:subject>integer programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>computer networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>forecasting</dc:subject><dc:description>The forecasting of ocean waves on real-time or online basis is necessary while carrying out any operational activity in the ocean. In order to obtain forecasts that are station-specific a time-series-based approach like stochastic modeling or artificial neural network was attempted by some investigators in the past. This paper presents an application of a relatively new soft computing tool called genetic programming for this purpose. Genetic programming is an extension of genetic algorithm and it is suited to explore dependency between input and output data sets. The wave rider buoy measurements available at two locations in the Gulf of Mexico are analyzed. The forecasts of significant wave heights are made over lead times of 3, 6, 12 and 24 h. The sample size belonged to a period of 15 years and it included an extensive testing period of 5 years. The forecasts made by the approach of genetic programming indicated that it can be regarded as a promising tool for future applications to ocean predictions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-23T09:44:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:17:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-23T09:44:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T20:17:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Ocean Engineering 35(11-12), 1166-1172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-8018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.oceaneng.2008.04.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1083</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1083</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>