<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7453</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Prediction of vapor-liquid equilibria of binary systems using PRSV equation of state and Wong-Sandler mixing rules</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>TARAPHDAR, T</dc:creator><dc:subject>gibbs energy models</dc:subject><dc:subject>cubic equations</dc:subject><dc:subject>nonideal mixtures</dc:subject><dc:subject>excess properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>application</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>cubic equation of state</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixing rules</dc:subject><dc:subject>excess functions</dc:subject><dc:description>The Peng-Robinson equation of state modified by Stryjek and Vera (1986) has been used with Wong-Sandler mixing rules (1992) to predict vapor-liquid equilibria of forty-three binary mixtures involving organic alcohols, esters, ketones, amines, etc. The Wong-Sandler mixing rules are theoretically correct in the sense that they reproduce quadratic composition dependence of the second virial coefficient. However, recent studies indicate that the basic premises of these rules break down for highly asymmetric systems and at high pressures. The systems studied have low to moderate asymmetry. II has been observed that the non random two liquid (NRTL) model provides a good representation of GE models and the results obtained from optimization compare well with those reported in DECHEMA data series in spite of the asymmetry inherent to these systems. The results obtained from this study can be used directly to predict vapor-liquid equilibria involving such systems. (C) 1998 Elsevier Science S.A. .</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-28T17:03:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-28T17:03:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING JOURNAL, 70(1), 15-24</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1385-8947</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1385-8947(98)00063-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7453</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7453</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>