<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15794</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:33:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>As-75 NMR local probe study of magnetism in (Eu1-xKx)Fe2As2</dc:title><dc:creator>DEY, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHUNTIA, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJAN, AV</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANUPAM</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSAIN, Z</dc:creator><dc:subject>SPIN-LATTICE RELAXATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPERCONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:description>As-75 NMR measurements were performed as a function of temperature and doping in Eu1-xKxFe2As2 (x = 0.5, 0.7) samples. The large Eu2+ moments and their fluctuations are found to dominate the As-75 NMR properties. The As-75 nuclei close to the Eu2+ moments likely have a very short spin-spin relaxation time (T-2) and are wiped out of our measurement window. The As-75 nuclei relatively far from Eu2+ moments are probed in this study. Increasing the Eu content progressively decreases the signal intensity with no signal found for the full-Eu sample (x = 0). The large As-75 NMR linewidth arises from an inhomogeneous magnetic environment around them. The spin lattice relaxation rate (1/T-1) for x = 0.5 and 0.7 samples is nearly independent of temperature above 100 K and results from a dipolar coupling to paramagnetic fluctuations of the Eu2+ moments. The behavior of 1/T-1 at lower temperatures has contributions from the antiferromagnetic fluctuations of the Eu2+ moments as also the fluctuations intrinsic to the FeAs planes and from superconductivity.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:33:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:33:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EUROPEAN PHYSICAL JOURNAL B, 86(11)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1434-6028</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1434-6036</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjb/e2013-40483-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15794</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>