<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16178</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T06:25:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparing Reactivation Behavior of TIG and Laser Beam Welded Alloy 690</dc:title><dc:creator>ABRAHAM, GJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHAMBROO, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAIN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:subject>corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>nickel base alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>welding</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRESS-CORROSION CRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>AUSTENITIC STAINLESS-STEELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ND-YAG LASER</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTERGRANULAR CORROSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHROMIUM DEPLETION</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TREATMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUSCEPTIBILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:description>The nickel base Alloy 690 was subjected to simulated autogenous welding treatment employing two different techniques, laser beam welding (LBW) and tungsten inert gas (TIG) welding. The resultant weld fusion zone (WFZ) and heat-affected zone (HAZ) were compared by studying the reactivation behavior. The chromium depletion effect was assessed by measuring the degree of sensitization (DOS) from the electrochemical potentiodynamic reactivation (EPR) test. A double-loop EPR test for Alloy 690 was employed to measure the DOS at different regions of weldments by masking the remaining regions. The results clearly demonstrated that Alloy 690 showed no sensitization in the parent material and the WFZ region of both TIG and laser weldments. However, it exhibited reactivation in the HAZ region of both the weldments. The DOS values measured for Alloy 690 were very low for all the regions of the LBW weldment as compared to that in the TIG weldment. The HAZ region of the LBW weldment showed the highest DOS value in any region of the weldment but even this value was quite low indicating absence of sensitization in LBW weldment. The attack along the grain boundaries for the weldments after EPR experiments were studied using optical and scanning electron microscopy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T06:25:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T06:25:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS ENGINEERING AND PERFORMANCE, 22(2)427-432</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11665-012-0249-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16178</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>