<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9094</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electron spin resonance and thermoluminescence studies in CaSO4: Dy,Ag phosphor</dc:title><dc:creator>DHABEKAR, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENON, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATT, BC</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAKSHMANAN, AR</dc:creator><dc:subject>single-crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>luminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>photoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>centers</dc:subject><dc:description>The defect centres formed in the thermoluminescence (TL) phosphor CaSO4: Dy,Ag are studied using the technique of electron spin resonance (ESR). The Ag co-doped phosphor exhibits three glow peaks around 130 degrees C, 220 degrees C and 375 degrees C, in contrast to the two glow peaks observed in the CaSO4: Dy phosphor at 130 degrees C and 220 degrees C, at gamma ray dose of 1 Gy when the TL measurements were carried out in the spectral region 300-650 nm. ESR studies show that the additional peak at 375 degrees C correlates with a Ag2+ centre formed owing to gamma-irradiation and observable below -170 degrees C. The Ag2+ centre is characterized by an axial g-tensor with principal values g(parallel to) = 2.38 and g(perpendicular to) = 2.41. ESR studies further indicate that the precursor to a centre observable at low temperature (-170 degrees C) appears to act as the recombination centre for the TL peak at 375 degrees C; this radical is characterized by the g-values g(parallel to) = 2.0023 and g(perpendicular to) = 2.0038 and is assigned to the SO3- radical. It is observed that there is more incorporation of Ag in the CaSO4: Dy system as compared with that in the pure CaSO4 system. The variation of Ag2+ ESR intensity with Ag concentration as well as with dose in the range 0.3 - 120 kGy is studied. The Ag2+ ESR signal and TL saturate at 2 x 10(4) Gy, but the intensity of the SO3- radical continues to increase up to the studied dose of 1.2 x 10(5) Gy. The intensity of the SO3- radical decreases with Ag concentration in CaSO4: Dy,Ag, in agreement with the TL model proposed in this work.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:01:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T17:01:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS D-APPLIED PHYSICS, 38(18), 3376-3381</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-3727</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0022-3727/38/18/008</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9094</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9094</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>