<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14672</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:22:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Solidification behaviour and mechanical properties of ductile iron castings with varying thickness</dc:title><dc:creator>SHINDE, VD</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>Thin wall casting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ductile iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>Solidification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inoculation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Microstructure</dc:subject><dc:description>Achieving the desired mechanical properties in thin wall ductile iron castings poured in industrial production foundries is a challenge. In this work, the effect of copper addition (up to 0.74%) and melt processing (Ba based stream inoculation) on the matrix structure, mechanical properties and fracture behaviour of ductile iron castings with varying section thickness (4-16 mm) were investigated in a regular jobbing foundry. It was possible to obtain 80% pearlitic structure without carbides in 4 mm sections, giving a tensile strength of 658 MPa with 2.5% ductility and 264 Brinell hardness. The solidification behaviour represented by the cooling curves helped in checking the effectiveness of the melt treatment by observing the amount of undercooling. Fractography studies of tensile specimens showed the change in fracture mechanisms due to increase in copper content on fracture paths. The increased amount of pearlite in the matrix exhibited brittle fracture with river pattern.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MANEY PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:22:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:22:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF CAST METALS RESEARCH, 25(6)364-373</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1179/1743133612Y.0000000024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14672</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>