<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6578</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>EPR, X-RAY, AND MAGNETIZATION STUDIES OF METASTABLE ALLOYS TI2FE, AL40CU10MN25GE25 AND AL65CU20FE15 AS PREPARED BY MECHANICAL ALLOYING</dc:title><dc:creator>MISRA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAHRIZI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATRAMANI, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>mn-si alloy</dc:subject><dc:subject>quasi-crystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>al</dc:subject><dc:subject>quasicrystals</dc:subject><dc:subject>phases</dc:subject><dc:description>Mechanical alloying (MA) technique has been used to synthesize metastable alloys with nominal compositions Ti,Fe (MA for 1, 5, and 26 h), Al65Cu20Fe15 (MA for 26 and 34 h) and Al40Cu10Mn25Ge25 (MA for 42 h). These have been studied by EPR, X-ray diffraction, differential thermal analysis (Ti2Fe only), and magnetization (Ti2Fe only) techniques. X-ray diffraction provided information on transformation to metastable phases, while the EPR spectra gave insight into inequivalent paramagnetic transition metal sites in the alloys and the temperature variation of magnetic ordering of the samples. Magnetization data on Ti2Fe system has been interpreted in terms of phase separations within the amorphous phase. It is concluded that MA process significantly influences the magnetic properties of the samples, wherein the duration of MA process plays an important role. The EPR and magnetization data indicate that the disorder of paramagnetic ions within the samples increases with increasing temperature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-25T00:33:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-25T00:33:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS, 150(3), 430-436</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-8853</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0304-8853(95)00529-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6578</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6578</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>