<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16539</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:32:28Z</datestamp><dc:title>Viscosity Radius of Polymers in Dilute Solutions: Universal Behavior from DNA Rheology and Brownian Dynamics Simulations</dc:title><dc:creator>PAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>AHIRWAL, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>NGUYEN, DA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIDHAR, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNTHAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRAKASH, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>EXCLUDED-VOLUME INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUCTUATING HYDRODYNAMIC INTERACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MONTE-CARLO</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPANSION FACTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROUSE CHAINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEAR-FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>VISCOMETRIC FUNCTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTRINSIC-VISCOSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-PARAMETER THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINEAR-CHAINS</dc:subject><dc:description>The swelling of the viscosity radius, alpha(eta), and the universal viscosity ratio, U-nR, have been determined experimentally for linear DNA molecules in dilute solutions with excess salt, and numerically by Brownian dynamics simulations, as a function of the solvent quality. In the latter instance, asymptotic parameter free predictions have been obtained by extrapolating simulation data for finite chains to the long chain limit. Experiments and simulations show a universal crossover for alpha(eta) and U-eta R from theta to good solvents in line with earlier observations on synthetic polymersolvent systems. The significant difference between the swelling of the dynamic viscosity radius from the observed swelling of the static radius of gyration is shown to arise from the presence of hydrodynamic interactions in the nondraining limit. Simulated values of alpha(eta) and U-eta R are in good agreement with experimental measurements in synthetic polymer solutions reported previously and with the measurements in linear DNA solutions reported here.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:32:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:32:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MACROMOLECULES, 47(21)7548-7560</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0024-9297</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-5835</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ma500960f</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16539</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>