<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9720</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-21T02:24:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>A statistical analysis of particulate data sets for Jawaharlal Nehru Port and surrounding harbour region in India</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>air-pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>children</dc:subject><dc:subject>ambient air quality</dc:subject><dc:subject>meteorology</dc:subject><dc:subject>pm10</dc:subject><dc:subject>statistical analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>port</dc:subject><dc:subject>tsp</dc:subject><dc:description>The concentrations of total suspended particulate matter (TSP) and particulate matter less than 10 microns (PM10) were measured at various locations in a Jawaharlal Nehru port and surrounding harbour region. Meteorological data was also collected to establish the correlation with air pollutant concentration. The results are analysed from the standpoint of monthly and seasonal variations, annual trends as well as meteorological effects. The monthly mean concentration of TSP was in the range of 88.2 to 199.3 mug m(-3). The maximum and minimum-recorded value of PM10 was 135.8 and 20.3 mug m(-3), respectively. The annual average concentration of PM10 was 66.1 mug m-3. There are clear associations between TSP and PM10 data set at all the measured three sites with a correlation coefficient of 0.89, 0.69 and 0.81, respectively. PM10 data appears to be a constant fraction of the TSP data throughout the year, indicating common influences of meteorology and sources. Particle size analysis showed PM10 to be 47% of the total TSP concentration, which is lower than reported for industrial area and traffic junctions in Mumbai. Anthropogenic sources contribute significantly to the PM10 fraction in an industrial region, while contributions from natural sources are more in a port and harbour area. Statistical analysis of air quality data shows that TSP is strongly correlated with wind speed but weakly correlated with temperature. There appears to be a simple inverse relationship between TSP and wind speed data, indicating the dilution and transport by winds.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T03:11:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T03:11:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING AND ASSESSMENT, 95(1-3), 295-309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-6369</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/B:EMAS.0000029910.17854.c4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9720</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9720</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>