<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15490</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:56:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Extramedullary versus intramedullary tibial cutting guides in megaprosthetic total knee replacement</dc:title><dc:creator>KARADE, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>Megaprosthetic knee replacement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cutting guide</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tibial component</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tibial cut</dc:subject><dc:subject>Statistical analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARTHROPLASTY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALIGNMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPONENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACCURACY</dc:subject><dc:description>Background: In a standard total knee replacement, tibial component alignment is a key factor for the long term success of the surgery. The purpose of this study is to compare the accuracy of extramedullary and intramedullary tibial cutting guides used in indigenous and imported implants respectively, in positioning of the tibial components in megaprosthetic knee replacements. Methods: A comparative study of the accuracy of extramedullary and intramedullary tibial cutting guides was carried out in 92 megaprosthetic knee replacements for distal femoral tumors. For the proximal tibia cut for tibial component placement, an extramedullary guide was used in 65 patients and an intramedullary guide was used in 27 patients. Tibial component alignment angles were measured in postoperative X-rays with the help of CAD software. Results: There was more varus placement in coronal plane with extramedullary cutting guide (-1.18 +/- 2.4 degrees) than the intramedullary guide (-0.34 +/- 2.31 degrees) but this did not reach statistical significance. The goal of 90 +/- 2 degrees alignment of tibial component was achieved in 54% of patients in the extramedullary group versus 67% in the intramedullary group. In terms of sagittal plane alignment, extramedullary guide showed less accurate results (2.09 +/- 2.4 degrees) than intramedullary guide (0.50 +/- 3.80 degrees) for tibial component alignment, though 78% of patients were aligned within the goal of 0-5 degrees of tibial slope angle in extramedullary group versus 63% in intramedullary group. The mean error in the measurements due to rotation of the knee during taking the X-rays was less than 0.1 degrees and distribution of the X-rays with the rotation of knee was similar in both the groups. Conclusions: Overall, in megaprosthetic knee replacement intramedullary guides gave more accurate results in sagittal plane and exhibited similar variability as of extramedullary guides in coronal plane.</dc:description><dc:publisher>BIOMED CENTRAL LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:56:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:56:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ORTHOPAEDIC SURGERY AND RESEARCH, 7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1749-799X-7-33</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15490</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>