<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4512</identifier><datestamp>2012-03-12T05:11:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Anomalous magnetic properties of Sr(2)YRuO(6)</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>TOMY, CV</dc:creator><dc:subject>weak ferromagnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>superconductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal</dc:subject><dc:subject>sr</dc:subject><dc:description>Anomalous magnetic properties of the double perovskite ruthenate compound Sr(2)YRuO(6) are reported here. Magnetization measurements as a function of temperature in low magnetic fields show clear evidence for two components of magnetic order (T(M1)similar to 32 K and T(M2)similar to 27 K) aligned opposite to each other with respect to the magnetic-field direction even though only Ru(5+) moments can order magnetically in this compound. The second component of the magnetic order at T(M2)similar to 27 K results only in a magnetization reversal, and not in the negative magnetization when the magnetization is measured in the field-cooled (FC) mode. Isothermal magnetization (M-H) measurements show hysteresis with maximum coercivity (H(c)) and remnant magnetization (M(r)) at T similar to 27 K, corroborating the presence of the two oppositely aligned magnetic moments, each with a ferromagnetic component. The two components of magnetic ordering are further confirmed by the double peak structure in the heat-capacity measurements. These anomalous properties have significance to some of the earlier results obtained for the Cu-substituted superconducting Sr(2)YRu(1-x)Cu(x)O(6) compounds.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-16T19:31:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-16T19:31:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 78(2), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.78.024432</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4512</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4512</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>