<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17722</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T14:25:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Activation of visible up-conversion luminescence in transparent and conducting ZnO:Er:Yb films by laser annealing</dc:title><dc:creator>LLUSCA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>LOPEZ-VIDRIER, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAUZURICA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SANCHEZ-ANIORTE, MI</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANTONY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOLPECERES, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>HERNANDEZ, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>GARRIDO, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BERTOMEU, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>ZNO THIN-FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GLASS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Up-conversion</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZnO:Er:Yb</dc:subject><dc:subject>Laser annealing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Transparent conducting oxides</dc:subject><dc:description>Transparent and conducting ZnO:Er:Yb thin films with visible up-conversion (660-nm emission under 980-nm excitation) were fabricated by RF magnetron sputtering. The as-deposited films were found to be transparent and conducting and the activation of the Er ions in these films to produce up-conversion luminescence was achieved by different post-deposition annealing treatments in air, vacuum or by laser annealing using a Nd:YVO4 laser. The structural, electrical and optical properties and the up-conversion efficiency of these films were found to be strongly influenced by the annealing method, and a detailed study is reported in this paper. It has been demonstrated that, although the air annealing was the most efficient in terms of up-conversion, laser annealing was the only method capable of activating Er ions while preserving the electrical conductivity of the doped films. It has been shown that a minimum energy was needed in laser annealing to optically activate the rare earth ions in the ZnO host material to produce up-conversion. Up-converting and transparent conducting ZnO:Er:Yb films with an electrical resistivity of 5 x 10(-2) cm and transparency 80% in the visible wavelength range has been achieved by laser annealing. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:25:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T14:25:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF LUMINESCENCE, 167,101-105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-2313</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-7883</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jlumin.2015.06.017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17722</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>