<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12248</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>CHROMIUM CONTAMINATION FROM CHROMITE MINE</dc:title><dc:creator>GODGUL, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHU, KC</dc:creator><dc:subject>chromium</dc:subject><dc:subject>geogenic</dc:subject><dc:subject>pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>sukinda</dc:subject><dc:description>Among the dominant species of chromium, the trivalent form widely occurs in nature in chromite ores or in silicate minerals and is extremely immobile. The higher oxidation state Cr(VI), is, however, rarely found in nature, is more mobile, and several times more toxic than Cr(III). Cr(VI) occurs in chromates and dichromates manufactured from chromite ores. The hexavalent state is stable in an oxidizing alkaline environment, whereas the trivalent state is stable in a reducing acidic environment. Serpentinization and Mg release during deuteric alteration of ultramafic rocks create alkaline pore water and lateritization is an intensive oxidation process. Chromite ore bodies in oxidized serpentinite therefore may generate hexavalent chromium from the inert chromites and cause hazardous chromium pollution of the water. With this end in view, a combined field and laboratory study has been made on chromite-bearing oxidized serpentinite rocks of Sukinda in Orissa, India. Laboratory leaching studies on mine overburden samples, chemical analyses of streamwater, and hydrolysate incrustation on detrital grains taken from stream beds have indicated the possibility of chromium mobilization from the chromite ores into the waterbodies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T08:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T08:10:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL GEOLOGY, 25(4), 251-257</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0177-5146</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12248</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>