<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10223</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Corrosion studies of organiedithiol/monothiol derived self assembled monolayer on copper substrate towards corrosion protection in 0.5 M NaCl</dc:title><dc:creator>PATHAK, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>YEGNARAMAN, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>MATHIYRASU, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAJI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>aqueous environments</dc:subject><dc:subject>anodic-dissolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-alkanethiols</dc:subject><dc:subject>schiff-base</dc:subject><dc:subject>chloride</dc:subject><dc:subject>surfaces</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>iron</dc:subject><dc:subject>self assembled monolayer (sam)</dc:subject><dc:subject>corrosion resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>dithiol</dc:subject><dc:subject>copper</dc:subject><dc:description>The corrosion resistance of 1-decanthiol (DT), 1,9-nonanedithiol (NDT) and 1,4-benzendimethanethiol (BDMT) sell assembled monolayer (SAM) covered copper were investigated using several electrochemical methods including polarization studies and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) in aqueous 0.5 M NaCl solution. The SAM covered surface was characterized by Fourier transform infrared reflectance spectroscopy (FTIR), atomic force microscopy (AFM) and cyclic voltammetry. The inhibition efficiency (IE) of the SAM/copper was investigated by varying; concentration of thiol in solution used for self assembly, assembly period for the formation of SAM and effect of solvents (DMF, toluene, ethanol and acetonitrile) for preparing the thiol solution. The inhibition efficiency of the different thiol compounds under similar experimental conditions for copper corrosion was found to be in the following order: NDT &gt; DT &gt; BMDT. The concentration of thiol and self assembly period affect the quality significantly. At the higher concentration, the self assembled monolayer was formed immediately after the solution was introduced to a substrate. There was only a marginal effect of using different solvent for dissolving the thiols on the inhibition efficiency (113). FTIR and AFM confirm the self assembling of thiols on copper surface.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T04:18:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T04:18:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL TECHNOLOGY, 14(1), 5-15</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0971-457X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10223</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10223</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>