<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9112</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>First-principles calculations of the electronic structure and phase stability of Ni-Mo alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>ARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, GP</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATNI, MJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>coherent potential approximation</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:description>Self-consistent local density electronic structure calculations have been carried out on various fee-based ground-state ordered superstructures of Ni1-xMox alloys spanning the entire concentration range. Using the tight-binding linear muffin-tin orbital (TB-LMTO) method, we have calculated the volume-dependent total ground-state energies, and hence the different equilibrium cohesive properties, as functions of the Mo concentration. Following the 'transferability prescription' of Andersen and co-workers, we have estimated the potential parameters of the constituent atoms as embedded in the alloy and compared these with the corresponding charge-self-consistent parameters for the intermetallic compounds. The ground-state stability profile has been obtained for the first time for this family of Ni-Mo compounds. Moreover, we have tested the applicability of the cluster expansion method (CEM) for parametrizing the cohesive energies to estimate the volume-dependent effective cluster interactions (ECIs) under the octahedron-tetrahedron cluster approximation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T18:22:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T18:22:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICS-CONDENSED MATTER, 10(38), 8459-8475</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0953-8984</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/10/38/007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9112</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9112</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>