<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16981</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:24:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>Droplet combustion studies of hydrocarbon-monopropellant blends</dc:title><dc:creator>AMBEKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHALLA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RADHAKRISHNA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Isopropyl nitrate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Blend</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dibutyl sebacate</dc:subject><dc:subject>Droplet combustion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Micro-explosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>INITIAL DIAMETER</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONVECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DECOMPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENVIRONMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FUELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVAPORATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPHERES</dc:subject><dc:subject>WIRES</dc:subject><dc:description>An experimental investigation was conducted to characterize the monopropellant droplet combustion of pure and blended isopropyl nitrate (IPN), suspended on quartz fibers in a quiescent atmosphere. The blends were prepared by mixing varying percentages by weight of IPN with less viscous n-heptane, as well as highly viscous desensitizer dibutyl sebacate (DBS). Ignition was achieved by using a heated 60 mu m Nichrome wire. The dependence of the burning rate constant of pure IPN on initial droplet diameter was investigated in the droplet size range of 0.79-1.97 mm. The blended IPN studies were carried out with initial droplet diameters of 2 and 1.5 mm for IPN-n-heptane and IPN-DBS blends respectively, to characterize the effect of gravimetric composition. The experiments revealed a strong dependence of IPN burning rate on droplet size. The IPN-DBS blends were characterized by severe micro-explosions, further atomizing the droplet, governed by the preferential evaporation of IPN over DBS. However, micro-explosions were conspicuously absent in case of IPN-n-heptane blends due to simultaneous gasification of both components. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:24:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:24:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FUEL, 115697-705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-2361</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-7153</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2013.07.056</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16981</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>