<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5058</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Forced simulation: A technique for automating component reuse in embedded systems</dc:title><dc:creator>ROOP, PS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOWMYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMESH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>implementation</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite</dc:subject><dc:subject>component reuse</dc:subject><dc:subject>embedded systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>forced simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>interface generation</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation relation</dc:subject><dc:subject>verification</dc:subject><dc:description>Component reuse techniques have been a recent focus of research because they are seen as the next-generation techniques to handle increasing system complexities. However, there are several unresolved issues to be addressed and prominent among them is the issue of component matching. As the number of reusable components in a component database grows, the task of manually matching a component to the user requirements becomes infeasible. Automating this matching can help in rapid system prototyping, improving quality and reducing cost. In addition, if the matching algorithm is sound, this approach can also reduce precious validation effort. In this article, we propose an algorithm for automatic matching of a design function to a device from a component database. The distinguishing feature of the algorithm is that when successful, it generates an interface that can automatically adapt the device to behave as the function. The algorithm is based on a new simulation relation called forced simulation that is shown to be a necessary and sufficient condition for component matching to be possible for a given pair of function and device. We demonstrate the application of the algorithm by reusing on some programmable components of the Intel family.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASSOC COMPUTING MACHINERY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T20:39:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T20:39:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACM TRANSACTIONS ON DESIGN AUTOMATION OF ELECTRONIC SYSTEMS, 6(4), 602-628</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1084-4309</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/502175.502185</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5058</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5058</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>