<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17799</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:49:30Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fuzzy inference systems for prospectivity modeling of mineral systems and a case-study for prospectivity mapping of surficial Uranium in Yeelirrie Area, Western Australia</dc:title><dc:creator>PORWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARY, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>GONZALEZ-ALVAREZ, I</dc:creator><dc:creator>KREUZER, O</dc:creator><dc:subject>GOLD DEPOSITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXPLORATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRANITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fuzzy inference systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mineral prospectivity modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>Expert systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mineral systems approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>Surficial uranium</dc:subject><dc:subject>Yeelirrie</dc:subject><dc:subject>Western Australia</dc:subject><dc:description>A Mamdani-type fuzzy inference system for prospectivity modeling of mineral systems is described. The system is a type of knowledge-driven symbolic artificial intelligence that is transparent, intuitive and is easy to construct by geologists because they are built in natural language and use linguistic values. No examples are used for training the system and expert-opinions are incorporated indirectly in terms of objective mathematical functions, which reduce the possibility of over-emphasizing the known deposits usually used as training data. The cognitive reasoning of the exploration geologist is captured in explicit if then type of statements written in natural language using linguistic values. Conditional dependencies in the exploration data sets are managed through the use of fuzzy operators. A case study for surficial uranium prospectivity modeling in the Yeelirrie area, Western Australia, is used to demonstrate the approach. In the output prospectivity map, the SE-NW trending Yeelirrie and E-W trending Hinkler's Well palaeochannels show high prospectivity, while other channels show very low prospectivity ranges. The known surficial uranium deposits fall in high prospectivity areas, although minor showings and anomalies in the southern partof the study area fall in low prospectivity areas. A comparison of the prospectivity model with the radiometric image shows that several channels showing high surface uranium concentrations in the NW and NE quadrants may not be prospective. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:49:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:49:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ORE GEOLOGY REVIEWS, 71(SI)839-852</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0169-1368</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-7360</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2014.10.016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17799</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>