<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-49</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:56:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fractionated crystallization in PA6/ABS blends: Influence of a reactive compatibilizer and multiwall carbon nanotubes</dc:title><dc:creator>BOSE, SURYASARATHI</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, ARUP R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KODGIRE, PRAVIN V</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, ASHOK</dc:creator><dc:subject>carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>scanning electron microscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>x-ray scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>supercooling</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystallization</dc:subject><dc:description>The 20/80 blends of polyamide 6 (PA6) and acrylonitrile–butadiene–styrene copolymer (ABS) in the presence of styrene–maleic anhydride copolymer (SMA) and multiwall carbon nanotubes (MWNT) were prepared using melt-mixing technique. Crystallization behavior of the PA6 phase in the blends was studied using DSC, WAXD and SAXS techniques. Blends' morphology was characterized by SEM. We observed fractionated crystallization of PA6 phase in 20/80 PA6/ABS blends. It was also observed that the phenomenon of fractionated crystallization was influenced by the presence of both SMA and MWNT. Blends' morphology revealed the presence of wide domain size distribution of PA6 droplets in the amorphous ABS matrix. On incorporation of either SMA or SMA modified MWNT, the average domain size of PA6 droplets was found to be finer up to 1 wt% SMA modified MWNT. Encapsulation of SMA copolymer layer on the MWNT surface was also evident from SEM micrographs. SAXS analysis revealed the formation of multiple lamellae stacking of PA6 phase in the presence or absence of SMA and MWNT in 20/80 PA6/ABS blends. This was attributed to the formation of less perfect crystallites formed during the cooling of melt at higher degree of supercooling.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2007-02-26T16:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:38:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007-02-26T16:48:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:38:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:56:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Polymer 48(1), 356-362</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3861</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.polymer.2006.11.019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/49</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/49</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>