<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11776</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Paramagnetic ruthenium-biimidazole derivatives [(acac)2Ru(III)(LH(n))](m), n/m=2/+, 1/0, 0/-. Synthesis, structures, solution properties and anion receptor features in solution state</dc:title><dc:creator>KUNDU, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOBIN, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>nuclear magnetic resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>mixed-valence states</dc:subject><dc:subject>bridging ligand</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal-complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>molecular recognition</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystal-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>redox properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>supramolecular systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>diruthenium complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>osmium complexes</dc:subject><dc:description>The paramagnetic ruthenium-biimidazole complexes [(acac)(2)Ru(III)(LH(-))] (1 = red-brown), [(acac)(2)Ru(III)(LH(2))](ClO(4)) (2 = pink) and Bu(4)N[(acac)(2)Ru(III)(L(2-))] (3 = greenish yellow) comprising of monodeprotonated, neutral and bideprotonated states of the coordinated biimidazole ligand (LH(n), n = 1, 2, 0), respectively, have been isolated (acac-= acetylacetonate). Single-crystal X-ray diffraction of 1 reveals that the asymmetric unit consists of three independent molecules: A-C, where molecule A corresponds to complex 1 and the other two molecules B and C co-exist as a hydrogen bonded dimeric unit perhaps between the cationic 2(+) and anionic 3(-). The packing diagram further reveals that the molecule A in the crystal of 1 also forms a hydrogen bonded dimer with the neighbouring another unit of molecule A. The formation of [(acac)(2)Ru(III)(LH(2))](ClO(4)) (2) has also been authenticated independently by its single-crystal X-ray structure. The packing diagram of 2 shows multiple hydrogen bonds between the N-H protons of coordinated LH(2) and the counter ClO(4)(-). Paramagnetic complexes show (1)H NMR spectra over a wide range of chemical shift, delta (ppm), + 10 to-35 in CDCl(3). One-electron paramagnetic 1-3 (mu/B. M. similar to 1.9) exhibit distinct rhombic-EPR spectra with relatively large g anisotropic factors: &lt; g &gt; 2.136-2.156 and Dg 0.65-0.77, typical for distorted octahedral ruthenium(III) complexes. The complexes 1-3 are inter-convertible as a function of pH. The pK(a1) and pK(a2) of 6.8 and 11, respectively, for 2 are estimated by monitoring the pH dependent spectral changes. The Ru(III)-Ru(IV) couple near 1.25 V vs. SCE remains almost invariant in 1-3 whereas the corresponding Ru(III)-Ru(II) couple varies appreciably in the range of-0.52 to-0.85 V vs. SCE based on the protonated-deprotonated states of the coordinated biimidazole ligand. Compounds 1-3 exhibit one weak ligand to metal charge transfer (LMCT) transition near 500 nm and intense intraligand transitions in the higher energy UV region. The spectrophotometric titrations of 2 with the TBA (TBA = tetrabutylammonium) salts of a wide variety of anions, F(-), Cl(-), Br(-), I(-), HSO(4)(-), OAc(-), H(2)PO(4)(-) in CH(3)CN reveal that the possible hydrogen bonds between the N-H protons of LH(2) in 2 and Cl-or Br(-) or I(-) or HSO(4)(-) or H(2)PO(4)(-) anion are rather weak or negligible. However, in presence of excess H(2)PO(4)(-)anion, the molar ratio of 2 to H(2)PO(4)(-) being 1 : 4, simple liberation of one N-H proton of the coordinated LH(2) in 2 has been taken place which in effect yields 1 and H(3)PO(4). On the contrary, the spectrophotometric titrations of 1 : 1 molar solution of 2 and OAc(-) or F(-) anion suggest the initial formation of hydrogen bonds between the N-H protons of LH(2) in 2 and the anion with the calculated log K value of 5.92 or 4.7, respectively, which eventually leads to the transfer of one of the N-H protons of LH(2) in 2 to the anion, resulting in 1 and HOAc or HF. On addition of excess OAc(-) to the above solution of 1 (moar ratio of OAc(-) to 1, 4 : 1), further hydrogen bonding between the N-H proton of LH(-) in 1 and OAc(-) occurs but without the abstraction of the N-H proton of LH(-) . However, excess Fanion concentration (molar ratio of anion to 1, 5 : 1) facilitates the removal of the remaining N-H proton of LH(-) in 1 which in turn yields 3 incorporating the bideprotonated form L(2-).</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T15:41:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T15:41:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, 39(17), 4232-4242</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b919036h</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11776</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11776</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>