<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2520</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Weighted aggregation scheme with lifetime-accuracy tradeoff in wireless sensor network</dc:title><dc:creator>JAGYASI, BG</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEY, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>distributed detection</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiple sensors</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider design of wireless sensor network for event detection application. An MMSE based q-bit weighted aggregation scheme (q-WAS) is proposed in which each node transmits q bits to its parent in every session. The observation of each sensor is assumed to be one bit. The simulation results sow that 1-WAS achieves better accuracy than a previously proposed one bit aggregation scheme while offering almost same lifetime. With increasing q, the accuracy of q-WAS approaches that of the infinite precision aggregation scheme. Moreover the lifetime for q-WAS is significantly higher than infinite precision aggregation scheme. For a 100 node sensor network, the simulation results show that 3-WAS achieves a near optimum accuracy. The lifetime of the q-WAS is approximately 1/q-th of the lifetime of the one bit aggregation schemes. Hence this class of aggregation schemes offers a trade-off between accuracy and lifetime.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T09:35:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T09:35:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>Fourth International Conference on Intelligent Sensing and Information Processsing, Proceedings,31-36</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-0611-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15970</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2520</dc:identifier><dc:source>4th International Conference on Intelligent Sensing and Information Processing,Bangalore, INDIA,DEC 15-18, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>