<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18130</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:09:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of pre-annealing strains on annealing texture developments in commercially pure (CP) titanium</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SABAT, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISHRA, SC</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHANTY, UK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUWAS, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>RECRYSTALLIZATION TEXTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARB PROCESS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IF-STEEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEET</dc:subject><dc:subject>cross-rolling</dc:subject><dc:subject>recrystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>cp-titanium</dc:subject><dc:subject>annealing texture</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARB processing</dc:subject><dc:description>Hexagonal commercially pure titanium (cp-titanium) plates were subjected to unidirectional-rolling (rolling), accumulative roll-bonding (ARB) and cross-rolling in a laboratory rolling mill. Rolling and cross-rolling were carried out to impart 90% reduction in thickness and ARB processing was performed for six passes. The deformed plates were then subjected to annealing at 600 degrees C for a large range of soaking time starting from 0.17min (10s) to 30min. It was observed that the samples were fully recrystallized after 5min of annealing, irrespective of the rolling processes employed in this study. Also, the samples were seen to develop almost similar texture when annealing was carried out beyond 5min of annealing time. However, before annealing, the texture development was seen to be different in the respective samples subjected to different rolling processes. The initial [GRAPHICS] texture present in the deformed structure got strengthened during annealing of the samples under investigation. It was also observed that the texture development was insignificant in ARB-processed samples after annealing.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:09:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:09:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHILOSOPHICAL MAGAZINE, 95(10)1105-1124</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1478-6435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1478-6443</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/14786435.2015.1020905</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18130</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>