<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1042</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:55:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Real-time wave forecasts off the western Indian coast</dc:title><dc:creator>JAIN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>DEO, MC</dc:creator><dc:subject>neural networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>regression analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>water waves</dc:subject><dc:subject>statistical methods</dc:subject><dc:description>The wave observations at three locations off the west coast of India have been analyzed using artificial neural network (ANN) to obtain forecasts of significant wave heights at intervals of 3, 6, 12 and 24 h. The most appropriate training method requiring an input of four observations spread over previous 24 h has been selected after considerable trials. Further, the networks are trained after filling in the missing information. Larger gaps in data are filled in using spatial mapping involving observations at nearby locations, while relatively smaller gaps are accounted for by the statistical technique of multiple regressions in temporal mode. It is found that by doing so the long-interval forecasting is tremendously improved, with corresponding accuracy levels becoming close to those of the short-interval forecasts. If the amount of gaps is restricted to around 2% per year or so it is possible to obtain 12 h ahead forecasts with 0.08 m accuracy on an average and 24 h ahead forecast with a mean accuracy of 0.13 m. However, in harsher environments the prediction accuracy can change.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-20T06:00:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:57:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-20T06:00:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T19:57:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:07:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:55:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Applied Ocean Research 29(1-2), 72-79</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0141-1187</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apor.2007.05.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1042</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1042</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>