<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15825</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T14:48:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Quantum-confined stark effect in localized luminescent centers within InGaN/GaN quantum-well based light emitting diodes</dc:title><dc:creator>DE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAYEK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KADIR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOWDHURY, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>MOLECULAR-BEAM EPITAXY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPONTANEOUS POLARIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITON LOCALIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMISSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLUE</dc:subject><dc:description>The nature of the polarization-field in disorder induced nanoscale potential fluctuations (radiative traps) within (In,Ga)N based quantum-well (QW) heterostructures remains ambiguous. Spectrally resolved photoluminescence microscopy has been utilized to probe the local polarization field by monitoring the extent of quantum-confined Stark effect (QCSE) in radiative trap centers spontaneously formed within an (In, Ga) N QW based light emitting diode. Interestingly, two distinct categories of nanoscale radiative domains, which arise from indium compositional and interface-morphology related fluctuations of the active layers, are found to have very different degree of built-in polarization fields. Screening of QCSE in indium-rich emission centers results in blue-shift of transition energies by up to 400meV, significantly higher than that reported previously for group III-nitride based semiconductor heterostructures. A lack of correlation between the extent of QCSE and local indium mole-fractions suggests that size, shape, and strain of individual localization centers play a crucial role in modulating the local polarization field. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4754079]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:48:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T14:48:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS, 101(12)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-6951</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1077-3118</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4754079</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15825</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>