<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7818</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Bifurcation analysis for onset and cessation of surge in axial flow compressors</dc:title><dc:creator>AGARWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>ANANTHKRISHNAN, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>rotating stall</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:description>Surge is a limit cycle oscillation in the pressure rise acid mass flow across an axial flow compressor. The generation of surge oscillations in axial flow compressors is investigated by a bifurcation analysis of the Moore-Greitzer model. The work reported in this paper is an extension of previous work by McCaughan which distinguished between deep surge and classic surge. In the present study, both deep surge and classic surge limit cycles are computed by using a continuation algorithm. The bifurcation mechanisms for the onset and termination of deep surge and classic surge: oscillations are discovered. It is found that the generation of deep surge is independent of the presence of classic surge. Classic surge limit cycles originate at a Hopf bifurcation and are found to terminate at a saddle loop. The occurrence of stable classic surge oscillations depends on the relative locations of the Hopf bifurcation point and the saddle loop. By modeling the effect of rotational disturbances at the compressor inlet as a perturbation to the compressor characteristic, it is shown that the rotational disturbance introduced by preswirl, inlet guide vanes, or air injection, can be used to manipulate the location of the bifurcation points so as to avoid stable classic surge.</dc:description><dc:publisher>FREUND PUBLISHING HOUSE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T20:15:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T20:15:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF TURBO &amp; JET-ENGINES, 17(3), 207-217</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0334-0082</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7818</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7818</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>