<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9231</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of winding disk in transformer under action of axial electromagnetic forces by Green's function approach</dc:title><dc:creator>BAKSHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>beams</dc:subject><dc:subject>axial electromagnetic force</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method (fem)</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic vector potential</dc:subject><dc:subject>axial displacement</dc:subject><dc:subject>green's function</dc:subject><dc:description>Dynamic axial displacement of high voltage (HV) winding disk of a power transformer has been calculated by Green's function approach, when time varying axial electromagnetic forces corresponding to worst case of short circuit condition, are applied. An elaborate analysis of the axial electromagnetic forces and corresponding axial displacement of a top-end disk of HV winding is carried out. Under the action of these time varying forces, the winding moves in the axial direction as a function of time between radially placed insulation spacers. Between the spacer supports the winding sections can be considered as clamped-clamped (C-C) beams. Static Green's function of such a beam structure is determined first, and convolving it with axial electromagnetic force determines the axial displacement (bending) at any point on the beam for the purpose of verification of the methodology. Dynamic Green's function of the same winding sector is subsequently derived, which is used to obtain displacement of the winding section by convolving it with an applied time varying axial electromagnetic force. The results are verified with commercial FEM software.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOS PRESS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:26:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T03:26:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF APPLIED ELECTROMAGNETICS AND MECHANICS, 34(4), 237-247</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1383-5416</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3233/JAE-2010-1314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9231</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9231</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>