<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16401</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:49:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Improved electrode fabrication method to enhance performance and stability of MoS2-based lithium-ion battery anode</dc:title><dc:creator>SEN, UK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>CMC binder</dc:subject><dc:subject>Electrode fabrication</dc:subject><dc:subject>High power density anode</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gas phase synthesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lithium-ion battery</dc:subject><dc:subject>MoS2</dc:subject><dc:subject>INORGANIC FULLERENES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEGATIVE-ELECTRODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CARBON NANOTUBES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-FE2O3</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TEMPERATURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATHODE</dc:subject><dc:description>Choice of binder and the electrode-making process play a pivotal role in the electrochemical performance of MoS2, when used as lithium-ion battery anode. In this work, MoS2 nanorods are prepared by gas phase synthesis method using molybdenum trioxide (MoO3) nanobelts and sulfur as starting materials. It has been observed that by tuning the reaction conditions, morphology and yield of the final product can be controlled. Carboxymethyl cellulose (CMC) is used as binder to fabricate the MoS2 electrode, and its electrochemical performance is tested against Li/Li+. The performance of electrode can be further improved by incorporating heat treatment to the active material and conductive carbon mixture prior to electrode fabrication. The electrochemical data shows that the optimum temperature for heat treatment is 700 A degrees C. In the current report, we would like to elucidate a detailed study based on electrode fabrication process and their impact on the electrochemical performance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF SOLID STATE ELECTROCHEMISTRY, 18(10)2701-2708</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1432-8488</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1433-0768</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10008-014-2518-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16401</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>