<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17067</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T18:07:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Coupled Electromagnetic-Structural Analysis of the Spiraling Phenomenon in a Helical Winding of a Power Transformer</dc:title><dc:creator>BAKSHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Finite-element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>helical winding</dc:subject><dc:subject>spiraling</dc:subject><dc:subject>torsional forces</dc:subject><dc:subject>transformers</dc:subject><dc:description>Spiraling of conductors in a helical winding of a transformer may lead to a catastrophic failure under the action of torsional short-circuit electromagnetic forces. Torsional forces are produced by the interaction of the axial component of the short-circuit current and the radial component of the leakage magnetic flux density. In this paper, 3-D magnetostatic analysis has been performed to determine the leakage magnetic-field distribution in a 130-MVA power transformer. Torsional electromagnetic forces are calculated from the analysis to determine circumferential displacements of conductors of its low-voltage helical winding. Furthermore, mechanical stress components are computed and a factor of safety is defined, which gives an indication as to whether the winding conductors are in the elastic or plastic zone. The numerical results thus obtained by the finite-element method are verified using the first principles from mechanics. The effect of looseness in the inner support structure on the von-Mises equivalent stress and, hence, on the factor of safety has been studied.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:07:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T18:07:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON POWER DELIVERY, 29(1)235-240</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-8977</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1937-4208</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TPWRD.2013.2276047</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17067</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>