<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14684</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T08:28:47Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kutta-Joukowsky theorem in viscous and unsteady flow</dc:title><dc:creator>SHARMA, SD</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESHPANDE, PJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>LOW REYNOLDS-NUMBERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LOW-ASPECT-RATIO</dc:subject><dc:subject>CORRUGATED AIRFOIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATE WINGS</dc:subject><dc:subject>AERODYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIFT</dc:subject><dc:subject>CIRCULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRAG</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR</dc:subject><dc:description>Nominally two-dimensional air flow over a thin flat plate at low Reynolds number is investigated. The primary objective is to experimentally determine with good accuracy the small magnitude lift force, generated by the plate at various angles of attack, by means of application of the Kutta-Joukowsky theorem where circulation is obtained from the line integral of velocity around the flat plate using non-invasive laser doppler velocimeter. Specific focus is on assessing applicability of the Kutta-Joukowsky theorem, originally theorized for inviscid and steady flow, in the post-stall region. At high angles of attack, due to severe flow separation from both the edges of the flat plate and occurrence of periodic vortex shedding, wake flow is found to be highly viscous, turbulent and unsteady. Nevertheless, the results show a remarkably good agreement with previous investigations in both the linear range and the non-linear range of the lift curve without any correction applied to the data. The line integral of velocity along the rectangular loop enclosing the flat plate shows that the vertical components, albeit smaller in magnitude, possess the same sign and hence are additive in contribution to the circulation, whereas the horizontal components possess opposite signs and hence are subtractive in their contribution to the circulation. The paper presents some interesting and hitherto undisclosed features of flow field around the flat plate.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:28:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T08:28:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTS IN FLUIDS, 52(6)1581-1591</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00348-012-1276-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14684</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>