<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18314</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:59:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Impulse Force Balance for Ultrashort Duration Hypersonic Test Facilities</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MENEZES, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>IRIMPAN, KJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>HOSSEINI, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>SYSTEM</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the measurement of side force, pitching, and yawing moments on a model, using an accelerometer force balance, in a short duration hypersonic shock tunnel. The test model is a blunt-nosed, flapped delta wing, mounted on a support sting through a force balance. The flexible rubber bushes constituting the balance allow the model to float freely on the sting during the test. The accelerometers were located in the model to record accelerations in the directions of interest. The model was tested in shock tunnel at Mach 8 at different angles of incidence with the free stream. Dynamic calibration of the test assembly was carried out for the acquisition of impulse response functions for the above components of force and moments, using an impulse hammer. The convolution technique was applied to derive the impulse response functions. The accelerometer outputs from the model in the hypersonic free stream were processed using the respective impulse response functions to derive the unknown aerodynamic force and moments. The newly adopted convolution technique has been found very effective for data reduction from accelerometer force balances developed for shock tunnel applications.</dc:description><dc:publisher>HINDAWI PUBLISHING CORPORATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:59:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:59:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SHOCK AND VIBRATION</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1070-9622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1875-9203</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2015/803253</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18314</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>