<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1306</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Distributed boundary estimation using sensor networks</dc:title><dc:creator>DUTTAGUPTA, SUBHASRI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAMRITHAM, KRITHI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMANATHAN, PARMESH</dc:creator><dc:subject>regression analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>wireless sensor networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>cluster analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>data acquisition</dc:subject><dc:description>We examine the problem of determining boundaries occurring in natural phenomena using sensor networks. Sensor nodes remotely collect data about various points on the boundary. From this data, we estimate the boundary along with the confidence intervals using a regression relationship among sensor locations and the distances to the boundary. The confidence intervals are guaranteed to be narrower than a specified maximum width. Our distributed boundary estimation strategy uses a hierarchical structure of clusters of sensor nodes and requires 20-50% less messages as compared to a centralized scheme. The computed intervals show desired coverage of the true boundary points. Further, motivated by the practical need to estimate the boundary with a minimum number of sensors, we develop an adaptive approach for turning sensors on and off. The number of ON sensors in this scheme is only about 15% more than what a practical Oracle needs, to evaluate the boundary and confidence intervals around it. Our algorithms are also evaluated using data from real sensors on a testbed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:37:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:51:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-05-08T02:37:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:51:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the IEEE International Conference on Mobile Adhoc and Sensor Systems, Vancouver, Canada, October 2006 , 316-325</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0507-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/MOBHOC.2006.278571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1306</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1306</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>