<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-612</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:53:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Manufacture of gem quality diamonds: a review</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHARY, DEVASHISH</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JAYESH</dc:creator><dc:subject>crystal growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthesis (chemical)</dc:subject><dc:subject>thermodynamics</dc:subject><dc:description>Gem quality diamonds have been grown using high temperature, high pressure processes like the solvent catalyst method and the temperature gradient method. This review with 64 references focuses on the thermodynamics, kinetics of the growth processes and the apparatus used to grow diamonds. Gem quality diamonds can be synthesized by the high pressure, high temperature process, either by the solvent catalyst method or the reconstitution technique. The Hall belt apparatus and the toroid anvil are the commonly used equipment to generate high pressures. In the high pressure, high temperature processes a catalyst is essential for synthesis. The commonly used catalysts are Fe, Co and Ni whereas recently hydroxides and carbonates have also been used to synthesize diamond. Surface chemistry plays an important role in determining the quality of the crystal. If the carbon flux to the nucleating diamond exceeds a certain limit, graphite nucleates instead of diamond. Temperature, pressure and impurities like nitrogen and boron also affect the quality and growth rates of the synthesized diamond. High growth rates have also been observed if substantial amount of paramagnetic nitrogen is dispersed in the reaction bath. Recent developments of growing diamond by chemical vapour deposition techniques like microwave plasma and hot filament technique have been reviewed. Non-destructive, optical methods to characterize diamonds have been briefly described.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-02-13T15:00:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:37:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-02-13T15:00:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T16:37:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:53:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Ceramics International 26(1), 73-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0272-8842</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0272-8842(99)00022-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/612</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/612</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>