<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11612</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>FTSZ INHIBITION: A PROMISING APPROACH FOR ANTI-STAPHYLOCOCCAL THERAPY</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>cell-division protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistant staphylococcus-aureus</dc:subject><dc:subject>penicillin-binding proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacillus-subtilis</dc:subject><dc:subject>escherichia-coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>assembly dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>peptide inhibitors</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>antibacterial activity</dc:subject><dc:subject>bacterial cytokinesis</dc:subject><dc:description>Staphylococcus causes a large number of animal and human diseases and has been considered as a major health concern. With the emergence of resistant strains of staphylococcus, like methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus and vancomycin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus, the search for novel antibacterial targets has intensified. FtsZ, a bacterial cytoskeleton protein, is involved in cell division. FtsZ assembles into protofilaments in a GTP-dependent manner, and forms a dynamic Z-ring at the mid-cell position. The assembly dynamics of FtsZ in the Z-ring are regulated by the combined actions of several FtsZ-associated proteins. Furthermore, the interaction of FtsZ with accessory proteins is essential for their recruitment to the Z-ring. A disruption of this interaction perturbs the Z-ring formation. FtsZ inhibitors like PC-190723 have been suggested to inhibit the Staphylococcus cell division by perturbing the assembly and stabitity of FtsZ polymers. In this review, we discuss the assembly dynamics of Z-ring and its role in cell division. In addition, we highlight recent advances suggesting the potential of FtsZ as a drug target for antistaphylococcal therapy.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PROUS SCIENCE, SA-THOMSON REUTERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T09:09:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T09:09:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DRUG NEWS &amp; PERSPECTIVES, 23(5), 295-304</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0214-0934</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1358/dnp.2010.23.5.1429489</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11612</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11612</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>