<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12790</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:52:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>In vitro evaluation of in situ gels as short term vitreous substitutes</dc:title><dc:creator>SURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>rheological properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>intraocular-pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>pseudomonas-elodea</dc:subject><dc:subject>delivery-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>hyaluronic-acid</dc:subject><dc:subject>gellan gum</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicone</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocompatibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>biodegradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>implants</dc:subject><dc:subject>gellan</dc:subject><dc:subject>in situ gel</dc:subject><dc:subject>ocular biomaterial</dc:subject><dc:subject>vitreous</dc:subject><dc:description>Dysfunction of the vitreous humor, present in the posterior cavity of the eye, leads to its detachment from the retina and vision loss. In this study, biopolymers were evaluated as in situ gels for short term vitreous substitution. Biophysical characterization revealed that the viscosity of the vitreous was &gt; 4000 cP at a shear rate of 0.15/s and it formed a gel with elastic modulus G' greater than the viscous modulus G". Biopolymers of gellan and hyaluronic acid (8:2 w/w, 1% concentration) were low viscosity liquids at 37 degrees C and gelation was triggered both by the addition of 0.18 mM CaCl2 as well as. ocular temperature, thus making them feasible as in situ gels. Gelation was confirmed by viscoelastic moduli where G' was greater than G", similar to the vitreous and unlike that of silicone oil, a common vitreous substitute. The gels had a viscosity &gt; 5000 cP at a shear rate of 0.512/s, excellent light transmittance and absence of syneresis. Contact angle studies with water and simulated ocular fluids showed that gellan hyaluromc acid gels had similar wetting properties to that of vitreous with contact angles of 27 degrees +/- 1 degrees, 36.7 degrees +/- 1.6 degrees, and 33.7 degrees +/- 0.5 degrees for water, simulated tear fluid, and simulated aqueous humor, respectively. The results of this study suggest that biopolymers of gellan and hylauronic acid are suitable as in situ gels, have biophysical properties similar to that of the vitreous, and may be promising as alternatives to silicone oil as short-term vitreous substitutes. (c) 2006 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-LISS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-09-01T13:25:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-09-01T13:25:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:52:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOMEDICAL MATERIALS RESEARCH PART A, 79A(3), 650-664</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1549-3296</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/jbm.a.30917</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12790</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12790</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>