<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10305</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:27Z</datestamp><dc:title>Seismic uplift capacity of inclined strip anchors</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUBBA RAO, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>sand</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>soils</dc:subject><dc:subject>seismic uplift capacity factors</dc:subject><dc:subject>inclined strip anchors</dc:subject><dc:subject>limit equilibrium</dc:subject><dc:subject>pseudostatic</dc:subject><dc:subject>c-phi soil</dc:subject><dc:description>Uplift capacities of inclined strip anchors in soil with a horizontal ground surface are obtained under seismic conditions. Limit equilibrium approaches with a logarithm-spiral failure surface and pseudostatic seismic forces are adopted in the analysis. The results are presented in the form of seismic uplift capacity factors as functions of anchor inclination, embedment ratio, angle of internal friction of the soil, and horizontal and vertical seismic acceleration coefficients. The uplift capacity factors are worked out separately for cohesion, surcharge, and density components. Use of the principle of superposition for calculating anchor uplift capacity is validated. The vertical seismic acceleration coefficient always reduces the uplift capacity, whereas the horizontal seismic acceleration coefficient reduces the uplift capacity in most cases. The roles of anchor embedment ratio, soil friction angle, and anchor inclination in determination of the seismic uplift capacity are also discussed. Comparisons of the proposed method with available theories in the seismic case are also presented. The present study gives the minimum seismic uplift capacity factors compared with the existing theory.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL RESEARCH COUNCIL CANADA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:26:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T09:26:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CANADIAN GEOTECHNICAL JOURNAL, 42(1), 263-271</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0008-3674</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1139/t04-074</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10305</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10305</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>