<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2015</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Novel high-Q torsion microresonator</dc:title><dc:creator>APTE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAWARIKAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>AJISHNA, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHOO, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>decoupled resonator</dc:subject><dc:subject>mems</dc:subject><dc:subject>torsion resonator</dc:subject><dc:subject>doubly-supported</dc:subject><dc:subject>high q-factor</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we propose a resonator structure with a high Q factor, which has the potential to replace the Quartz crystal. In order to achieve a higher Q, complete decoupling of the resonating structure from the supporting ends is desired. One of the ways of achieving this is to distribute the stress uniformly throughout the support beam rather than their being concentrated at the fixed ends. This suggests a resonating mass supported by torsion wires. Here, three resonating structures are connected in a serial fashion. The outer two resonators act as interfaces to the external oscillator circuit, while the centre one is fully decoupled. The losses at the end of torsion wires are thus kept to lowest value. The other losses, namely damping and internal friction losses, are kept to a minimum by providing vacuum and using high quality material for the torsion wire. Modal analysis and static stress analysis were done on the structures and results clearly show the fundamental torsion mode of vibration and extremely small stresses at the fixed ends of the torsion wire.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOC OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T01:22:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T01:22:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MEMS/MOEMS Components and Their Applications II,5717,211-218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-8194-5691-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0277-786X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.590016</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15293</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2015</dc:identifier><dc:source>Conference on MEMS/MOEMS Components and Their Applications II,San Jose, CA,JAN 24-25, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>