<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1687</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intelligent design environment - a knowledge-based simulations approach for sheet-metal forming</dc:title><dc:creator>PALANI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>WAGONER, RH</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMHAN, K</dc:creator><dc:description>Intelligent Design Environment (IDE) is a knowledge based expert system which provides a method of integration, automation and optimization in sheet metal forming. IDE integrates knowledge based systems, Finite Element Analysis and Geometric Modellors in Artificial Intelligence framework called Blackboard Architecture. IDE uses heuristic knowledge to automatically invoke appropriate finite element analysis codes, choose key design parameters and manage communication and interaction between the diverse technologies. The input to IDE is the geometry of the sheet metal component and the constraints on material and process parameters. The output of IDE is a set of optimized die geometry, material and process parameters for successful forming of the component. IDE has been tested on an automotive panel, and the results were found to be comparable to that obtained in experimental studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA LAUSANNE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-22T08:39:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-22T08:39:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF MATERIALS PROCESSING TECHNOLOGY,45,703-708</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0924-0136</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0924-0136(94)90421-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14856</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1687</dc:identifier><dc:source>5th International Conference on Metal Forming: Metal Forming 94,BIRMINGHAM, ENGLAND,SEP 13-15, 1994</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>