<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4123</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:57Z</datestamp><dc:title>Theoretical determination of standard oxidation and reduction potentials of chlorophyll-a in acetonitrile</dc:title><dc:creator>PANDEY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>molecular-dynamics simulations</dc:subject><dc:subject>free-energy</dc:subject><dc:subject>plastocyanin</dc:subject><dc:subject>proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>geometry</dc:subject><dc:subject>model</dc:subject><dc:description>QM/MM calculations were performed on ethyl chlorophyllide-a and its radical cation and anion, by using the density functional (DF) B3LYP method to determine the molecular characteristics, and a molecular mechanics (MM) method to simulate the solvating medium. The presence of the solvent was accounted for during the optimization of the geometry of the 85-atom chlorophyll-a system by using an ONIOM methodology. A total of 24 solvent molecules were explicitly considered during the optimization process, and these were treated by the universal force field (UFF) method. Initially, the split-valence 3-21G basis set was used for optimizing the geometry of the 85-atom species, neutral, cation and anion. Electronic energies were then determined for the optimized species by making use of the polarized 6-31G(d) basis set. The ionization energy calculated (6.0 eV) is in very good agreement with the observed one (6.1 eV). The MM+ force field was used to investigate the dynamics of the acetonitrile molecules around the neutral species as well as the radical ions of chlorophyll. The required atomic charges on all the atoms were obtained from calculations on all involved molecules at the DFT/6-31G(d) level. Randomly sampled configurations were used to determine the first solvation layer contribution to the free energy of solvation of various species. A truncated 46-atorn model of ethyl chlorophyllide-a was used to evaluate the thermal energies of neutral chlorophyll molecule relative to its two radical ions in the gas phase. Born energy, Onsager energy, and the Debye-Huckel energy of the chlorophyll-solvent aggregate were added as perturbative corrections to the free energy of solvation that was initially obtained through molecular dynamics method for the same complex. These calculations yield the oxidation potential as 0.75 &amp;PLUSMN; 0.32 V and the reduction potential -1.18 &amp;PLUSMN; 0.31 V at 298.15 K. The calculated values are in good agreement with the experimental midpoint potentials of +0.76 and -1.04 V, respectively.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T02:07:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T02:07:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY B, 109(18), 9066-9072</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-6106</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp0446478</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4123</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4123</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>