<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2256</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Pullout response study for cellular reinforcement</dc:title><dc:creator>KHEDKAR, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANDAL, JN</dc:creator><dc:subject>out tests</dc:subject><dc:subject>theoretical-model</dc:subject><dc:subject>sand</dc:subject><dc:subject>soil</dc:subject><dc:description>Various forms of reinforcing elements have been used for construction of reinforced soil retaining wall i.e., sheets, grids, meshes, strips, bars, rods etc. In ultimate limit state design, considering the internal stability analysis, the reinforced soil wall may fail in tension/rupture or pullout type of failure. Pullout tests results are commonly used to predict actual field pullout performance of reinforcements. Various authors have studied different kinds of shapes and sizes of reinforcements for pullout test, but much attention has not been given to conduct pullout test with cellular reinforcement like geocell. Though Soil reinforcement using of cellular reinforcement (geocell) has been utilized successfully in many other areas of geotechnical engineering, there is still need to study the probable use of cellular reinforcement in reinforced soil retaining wall. In the present paper, cellular type geometry of reinforcement is proposed for reinforced soil applications. Pullout analysis of such reinforcement is performed. Also, the pullout test conditions are simulated in finite element method, with the help of readymade software, Plaxis-V8 and the outputs are visualized. The results are found supportive to the assumptions made in the analysis.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T03:21:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T03:21:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NEW HORIZONS IN EARTH REINFORCEMENT,293-298</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-415-45775-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2256</dc:identifier><dc:source>5th International Symposium on Earth Reinforcement (IS Kyushu 07),Fukuoka, JAPAN,NOV 14-16, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>