<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10820</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>EXPERIMENTAL AND FINITE-ELEMENT STUDIES ON MODE-I AND MIXED-MODE (I AND II) STABLE CRACK-GROWTH .1. EXPERIMENTAL</dc:title><dc:creator>MAHANTY, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>stress-strain field</dc:subject><dc:subject>brittle-fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>ductile fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>tip deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>initiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>extension</dc:subject><dc:subject>criteria</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanics</dc:subject><dc:subject>behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>shear</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental results on mode I and mixed mode stable crack growth under static loadings through an aluminium alloy (D16AT) are presented. The compact tension type of geometry was employed for both the sets of tests. Data pertaining to load-deflection diagrams, crack opening displacements, crack front geometry, etc., are included. There is a greater spurt of crack growth at the initiation stage in a mixed mode than in mode I. The crack opening angle (COA) remained nearly constant during the whole stable growth. There is a substantial tunneling, the extent of which increases as the extension progresses in both mode I and mixed mode. The tunneling reduces as the ratio a(0)/W increases. Because of this tunneling, the COD at a point finite distance behind the crack tip and on the specimen surface is much more than expected. At the maximum load the tunneling is 2 to 3.5 mm in the case of mode I. The crack extends intially almost along a straight line at an angle with the initial crack in a mixed mode. The maximum to initiation load ratio varied in the range 1.50 to 1.75 for the whole range of tests.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:31:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-24T08:31:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>1990</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENGINEERING FRACTURE MECHANICS, 37(6), 1237-1250</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0013-7944</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0013-7944(90)90065-O</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10820</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10820</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>