<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16350</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T11:23:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ensemble prediction of regional droughts using climate inputs and the SVM-copula approach</dc:title><dc:creator>GANGULI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, MJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>drought prediction</dc:subject><dc:subject>copulas</dc:subject><dc:subject>support vector regression</dc:subject><dc:subject>climate teleconnection</dc:subject><dc:subject>ensembles</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPPORT VECTOR MACHINES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEURAL-NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOIL-MOISTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDIAN-OCEAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAINFALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDEX</dc:subject><dc:subject>MONSOON</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIPOLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMPACT</dc:subject><dc:description>In this study, the climate teleconnections with meteorological droughts are analysed and used to develop ensemble drought prediction models using a support vector machine (SVM)-copula approach over Western Rajasthan (India). The meteorological droughts are identified using the Standardized Precipitation Index (SPI). In the analysis of large-scale climate forcing represented by climate indices such as El Nino Southern Oscillation, Indian Ocean Dipole Mode and Atlantic Multidecadal Oscillation on regional droughts, it is found that regional droughts exhibits interannual as well as interdecadal variability. On the basis of potential teleconnections between regional droughts and climate indices, SPI-based drought forecasting models are developed with up to 3months' lead time. As traditional statistical forecast models are unable to capture nonlinearity and nonstationarity associated with drought forecasts, a machine learning technique, namely, support vector regression (SVR), is adopted to forecast the drought index, and the copula method is used to model the joint distribution of observed and predicted drought index. The copula-based conditional distribution of an observed drought index conditioned on predicted drought index is utilized to simulate ensembles of drought forecasts. Two variants of drought forecast models are developed, namely a single model for all the periods in a year and separate models for each of the four seasons in a year. The performance of developed models is validated for predicting drought time series for 10 years' data. Improvement in ensemble prediction of drought indices is observed for combined seasonal model over the single model without seasonal partitions. The results show that the proposed SVM-copula approach improves the drought prediction capability and provides estimation of uncertainty associated with drought predictions. Copyright (C) 2013 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:23:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T11:23:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HYDROLOGICAL PROCESSES, 28(19)4989-5009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-6087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1099-1085</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/hyp.9966</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16350</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>