<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4126</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:58Z</datestamp><dc:title>Theoretical investigation of in-plane hydrogen-bonded complexes of ammonia with partially substituted fluorobenzenes</dc:title><dc:creator>SINGH, PC</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATWARI, GN</dc:creator><dc:subject>center-dot-o</dc:subject><dc:subject>ab-initio</dc:subject><dc:subject>intermolecular interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>1,2,4,5-tetrafluorobenzene clusters</dc:subject><dc:subject>hexafluorobenzene interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>infrared-spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>pi-systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>fluorine</dc:subject><dc:subject>methanol</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:description>Systematic investigation of in-plane hydrogen-bonded complexes of ammonia with partially substituted fluorobenzenes has revealed that fluorobenzene, difluorobenzene, and trifluorobenzene favor formation of cyclic complexes with a C-H center dot center dot center dot N-H center dot center dot center dot F-C binding motif. On the other hand, tetrafluorobenzene and pentafluorobenzene favor formation of linear C-H center dot center dot center dot N hydrogen-bonded complexes. The complete absence of exclusively linear N-H center dot center dot center dot F hydrogen-bonded complexes for the entire series indicates that C-F bond in fluorobenzenes is a reluctant hydrogen-bond acceptor. However, fluorine does hydrogen bond when cooperatively stabilized with C-H center dot center dot center dot N hydrogen bonds for the lower fluoro analogues. The propensity of fluorobenzenes to adapt to the C-H center dot center dot center dot N-H center dot center dot center dot F-C binding motif decreases with the progressive fluorination of the benzene ring and disappears completely when benzene ring is substituted with five or more fluorine atoms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T02:18:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T02:18:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 111(14), 2772-2777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp0690087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4126</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>