<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2137</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Surface reconstruction from contour lines or LIDAR elevations by least squared-error approximation using Tensor-Product Cubic B-splines</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJI, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>interpolation</dc:subject><dc:description>We consider, in this paper, the problem of reconstructing the surface from contour lines of a topographic map. We reconstruct the surface by approximating the elevations, as specified by the contour lines, by tensor-product cubic B-splines using the least squared-error criterion. The resulting surface is both accurate and smooth and is free from the terracing artifacts that occur when thin-plate splines are used to reconstruct the surface. The approximating surface, S(x,y), is a linear combination of tensor-product cubic B-splines. We denote the second-order partial derivatives of S by S(xx), S(xy) and S(yy). Let h(k) be the elevations at. the points (x(k),y(k)) on the contours. S is found by minimising the sum of the squared-errors {S(x(k),y(k))-h(k)}(2) and the quantity integral integral S(xx)(2)(x, y) + 2S(xy)(2)(x, y) + S(yy)(2) (x, y) dydx, the latter weighted by a constant lambda. Thus, the coefficients of a small number of tensor-product cubic B-splines define the reconstructed surface. Also, since tensor-product cubic B-splines are non-zero only for four knot-intervals in the x-direction and y-direction, the elevation at any point can be found in constant time and a grid DEM can be generated from the coefficients of the B-splines in time linear in the size of the grid.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-24T08:59:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-24T08:59:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ADVANCES IN 3D GEOINFORMATION SYSTEMS,213-227</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-3-540-72134-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1863-2246</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-540-72135-2_13</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15370</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2137</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Workshop on 3D Geo-Information,Delf, NETHERLANDS,DEC 12-14, 2007</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>