<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15216</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T15:59:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>Palynology, palaeoecology and palaeodepositional environment of Eocene lignites and associated sediments from Matanomadh mine, Kutch Basin, western India</dc:title><dc:creator>MATHEWS, RP</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, SM</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUTTA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Palynomorphs</dc:subject><dc:subject>Eocene lignites</dc:subject><dc:subject>Matanomadh</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kutch Basin</dc:subject><dc:subject>Gujarat</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHYLOGENY</dc:subject><dc:description>Extensive Cenozoic lignite-bearing sediments in the western part of Kutch, western India provide a unique opportunity to study the floral diversity at a crucial time of early Eocene Climatic Optimum (EECO). Rock samples representing a lignite-bearing sequence from the open cast mine at Matanomadh, Gujarat, western India were collected to study the palynofloral composition and to interpret the palaeoclimate and environment of deposition. The sequence mainly composed of lignites, shales and calcareous mudstones yielded rich assemblage consists of pteridophytic spores (7 genera, 10 species), angiosperm pollens (20 genera, 26 species), fungal remains (14 genera, 16 species) and dinoflagellate cysts. The palynofloral assemblage is marked with dominance of angiospermic pollen, particularly those having affinity with the family Arecaceae. Occurrence of fungal remains in high abundance is also noticed. Based on palynomorph contents, the studied sequence is divisible into two palynozones. It is inferred that lower part of the sequences was deposited in a near-shore environment with intermittent marine incursions whereas the depositional regime of upper part was shallow marine. The climate is found to be tropical-subtropical, humid with heavy precipitation during the deposition of Matanomadh lignite-bearing sequence.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:59:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T15:59:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 82(3)236-248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12594-013-0146-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15216</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>