<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1898</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fast on-line/off-line algorithms for optimal reinforcement of a network and its connections with principal partition</dc:title><dc:creator>PATKAR, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAN, H</dc:creator><dc:subject>lattice</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymatroids</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:description>The problem of computing the strength and performing optimal reinforcement for an edge-weighted graph G(V, E, w) is well-studied [1,2,3,6,7,9]. In this paper, we present fast (sequential linear time and parallel logarithmic time) on-line algorithms for optimally reinforcing the graph when the reinforcement material is available continuosly online. These are first on-line algortithms for this problem. Although we invest some time in preprocessing the graph before the start of our algorithms, it is also shown that the output of our on-line algorithms is as good as that of the off-line algorithms, making our algorithms viable alternatives to the fastest off-line algorithms in situtations when a sequence of more than O(/V/) reinforcement problems need to be solved. In such a situation the time taken for preprocessing the graph is less that the time taken for all the invocations of the fastest off-line algorithms. Thus our algorithms are also efficient in the general sense. The key idea is to make use of the theory of Principal Partition of a Graph. Our results can be easily generalized to the general setting of principal partition of nondecreasing submodular functions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T13:34:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T13:34:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>FST TCS 2000: FOUNDATIONS OF SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY AND THEORETICAL COMPUTER SCIENCE, PROCEEDINGS,1974,94-105</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>3-540-41413-4</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15142</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1898</dc:identifier><dc:source>20th Conference on Foundations of Software Technology and Theoretical Computer Science,NEW DELHI, INDIA,DEC 13-15, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>