<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1655</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:51:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Degradation of azo dyes by sequential Fenton's oxidation and aerobic biological treatment</dc:title><dc:creator>TANTAK, NILESH P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, SANJEEV</dc:creator><dc:subject>azo dyes</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>sequence</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic amines</dc:subject><dc:description>A two stage sequential Fenton's oxidation followed by aerobic biological treatment train was used to achieve decolorization and to enhance mineralization of azo dyes, viz. Reactive Black 5 (RB5), Reactive Blue 13 (RB13), and Acid Orange 7 (AO7). In the first stage, Fenton's oxidation process was used while in the second stage aerobic sequential batch reactors (SBRs) were used as biological process. Study was done to evaluate effect of pH on Fenton's oxidation process. Results reveal that pH 3 was optimum pH for achieving decolorization and dearomatization of dyes by Fenton's process. Degradation of dye was assessed by COD reduction and reduction in aromatic amines (naphthalene chromophores) which was measured by reduction in absorbance at 200 nm. More than 95% of color was removed with Fenton's oxidation process in all dyes. In overall treatment train 81.95, 85.57, and 77.83% of COD reduction was achieved in RB5, RB13, and AO7 dyes, respectively. In the Fenton's oxidation process 56, 24.5, and 80% reduction in naphthalene group was observed in RB5, RB13, and AO7, respectively, which further increased to 81.34, 68.73, and 92% after aerobic treatment. Fenton's oxidation process followed by aerobic SBRs treatment sequence seems to be viable method for achieving significant degradation of azo dye.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-19T08:45:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:33:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-19T08:45:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T15:33:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:05:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:51:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Hazardous Materials 136(3), 698-705</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-3894</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.jhazmat.2005.12.049</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1655</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1655</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>