<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7076</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-20T03:07:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>The influence of aluminium sources on the acidic behaviour as well as on the catalytic activity of mesoporous H-AlMCM-41 molecular sieves</dc:title><dc:creator>SAKTHIVEL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAPURKAR, SE</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, NM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULSHRESHTHA, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>tertiary butylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>aromatic-hydrocarbons</dc:subject><dc:subject>t-butylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>mcm-41</dc:subject><dc:subject>phenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>zeolites</dc:subject><dc:subject>alkylation</dc:subject><dc:subject>al-mcm-41</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability</dc:subject><dc:subject>strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>mesoporous materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>aluminium sources</dc:subject><dc:subject>butylation of phenol</dc:subject><dc:subject>almcm-41</dc:subject><dc:description>A series of mesoporous molecular sieves (AIMCM-41) were synthesized with varying silicon-to-aluminium ratios and using three different aluminium sources, viz., sodium aluminate, aluminium isopropoxide and aluminium. sulphate. The samples were characterized systematically using XRD, TG-DTA, BET surface area, and ICP-AES. In addition, the extent of framework substitution as well as the nature of acid sites was deduced employing Al-27 MAS-NMR, pyridine FT-IR, and NH3-TPD methods. These studies indicate that in case of samples prepared with sodium aluminate, most of the aluminium existed in tetrahedral positions even after calcination. Also, such samples posses moderate-to-strong (Bronsted) acid sites along with small amounts of structural as well as non-framework Lewis acid sites. The density of non-framework acid sites depended upon the source of aluminium following a trend in the order of sodium aluminate &lt; aluminium sulphate &lt; aluminium isopropoxide. Among the various catalysts investigated, those having a silicon-to-aluminium ratio of around 60 irrespective of aluminum sources exhibited highest conversion and good selectivity for vapour phase tertiary-butylation of phenol. This characteristic is attributed to the presence of larger number of moderate-to-strong acid sites and a smaller number of Lewis acid sites. (C) 2003</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T01:35:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T01:35:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROPOROUS AND MESOPOROUS MATERIALS, 65(2-3), 177-187</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1387-1811</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.micromeso.2003.08.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7076</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7076</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>