<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9482</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>ON THE ROLE OF TRANSPORT IN THE COMBUSTION KINETICS OF A STEADY-STATE PREMIXED LAMINAR CO+H2+O2 FLAME</dc:title><dc:creator>MISHRA, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>YETTER, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>REUVEN, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>RABITZ, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>SMOOKE, MD</dc:creator><dc:subject>greens-function method</dc:subject><dc:subject>boundary-value methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitivity analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemical-kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:description>The role of mechanistic steps, diffusion, and their interrelation is explored in a steady-state premixed laminar CO + H-2 + O2 flame using a numerical model. Sensitivity coefficients and Green's functions calculated for this system offer systematic characterization of the role of diffusion and exothermicity in carbon monoxide oxidation kinetics. The results reveal that the uncertainties in transport parameters are as important to the model predictions as those in the kinetic steps. The rate controlling steps of the CO + H-2 + O2 reaction are found to be different for adiabatic and nonadiabatic premixed flames, and also for systems with and without transport. In particular, the reactions of the hydroperoxyl radical with hydrogen, oxygen, and hydroxyl radicals are found to be important at all temperatures in the fuel lean (40 torr) adiabatic flame studied here. The diffusive mixing of chemical species from the low and the high temperature portions of the flame and the larger heats of reaction associated with the hydroperoxyl radicals are found to be responsible for the increased importance of these reactions. (C) 1994 , Inc.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T11:10:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T11:10:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF CHEMICAL KINETICS, 26(4), 437-453</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0538-8066</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/kin.550260406</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9482</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9482</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>