<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1601</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dual auction (and recourse) opportunistic protocol for light-trail network design</dc:title><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHENG, SQ</dc:creator><dc:subject>bandwidth allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>multicast protocols</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical fibre networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>frequency allocation</dc:subject><dc:subject>virtual reality</dc:subject><dc:subject>wavelength division multiplexing</dc:subject><dc:description>A light-trail is a generalization of a lightpath such that multiple nodes can take part in communication along the path. Light-trail based networks lead to dynamic provisioning and optical multicasting while deploying a pragmatic low-cost platform. Dynamic connections can be setup and torn down over semi-permanent light-trails facilitating bandwidth-on-demand and optical multicasting. We introduce a protocol that enables efficient dynamic provisioning and fairness within light-trails. The protocol is based on a modification of the auction algorithm. We apply this protocol to bandwidth allocation within a light-trail as well as to the task of growth and reduction of the virtual topology of light-trails. The article presents an analysis of this protocol and its functioning. We extensively simulate this protocol. A new performance metric for light-trail networks called the opportunistic ratio (OR) is defined. The OR also enables computation of fairness in light-trail networks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-07-18T05:00:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:45:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-07-18T05:00:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:45:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on Wireless and Optical Communications Networks, Bangalore, India, 11-13 April 2006, 1-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1-4244-0340-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/WOCN.2006.1666639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1601</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1601</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>