<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12329</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-19T07:30:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>NUMERICAL-SOLUTION OF A MICROPOLAR FLUID-FLOW BETWEEN 2 ROTATING COAXIAL DISKS</dc:title><dc:creator>CHATURANI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARASIMMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>stationary disk</dc:subject><dc:subject>swirling flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>computation</dc:subject><dc:subject>steady</dc:subject><dc:subject>multiplicity</dc:subject><dc:description>Steady flow of a micropolar fluid between two rotating disks of infinite radius rotating at different/same speeds has been investigated. The lower and upper disks rotate with angular velocities 'OMEGA' and 'S-OMEGA' respectively. By using similarity transformation method, the equations of motion are reduced to a set of ordinary non-linear coupled differential equations. The resulting non-linear equations are linearized by quasilinearization technique and integrated with the help of fourth order Runge-Kutta method via orthonormalization. Effects of micropolarity parameters on velocity components for different values of Reynolds numbers Re (200, 1 000 etc.) and S (-1.0, 0.0, 0.5, 1.0) have been studied. Multiplicity of the solutions have been obtained for different values of S and micropolar parameters at Re = 1 000. It is found that only one of the four micropolar parameters (alpha-1) influences translation velocity components significantly. At high Re, flows similar to flows observed by Batchelor Stewartson and Holodniok etc., have been obtained. A new type of multiple solution has been obtained for S = 1.0 which needs further investigation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG WIEN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T13:13:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T13:13:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>1991</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA MECHANICA, 89(1-4), 133-145</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0001-5970</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/BF01171251</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12329</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12329</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>