<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-5803</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Direct radiative forcing from anthropogenic carbonaceous aerosols over India</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>particulate carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>sinks</dc:subject><dc:subject>area</dc:subject><dc:description>A chemical-meteorological box model has been formulated to estimate direct radiative forcing from carbonaceous aerosol constituents. Anthropogenic black carbon and organic matter aerosol emissions from industrial fuels and biomass burning in India were estimated at 0.44 and 2.47 Tg y(-1), respectively for 1990, Global black carbon and organic matter estimates were 12.30 and 81.00 Tg y(-1), respectively, from the same source inventory for the base year 1984. Meteorological parameters for 1990 from 18 India Meteorological Department (IMD) stations are used to estimate spatial average lifetimes and burdens of carbonaceous aerosols, The transport mechanisms considered are advection by surface winds, dry deposition and wet deposition. Estimated lifetimes of black carbon aerosols are lower in May to October (3.2 to 5.1 day) with effective wet deposition, and higher in November to April (6.2 to 12.9 day), with an annual mean lifetime of 6.5 +/- 4.7 day. Monthly mean burdens of black carbon aerosols range from 0.59 to 2.37 mg m(-2), and follow the same as lifetimes with an annual mean burden of 1.20 +/- 0.87 mg m(-2), Monthly mean direct radiative forcing from black carbon aerosols is positive (net warming) and is higher (+ 0.51 to + 0.72 W m(-2)) in December and January than May to October (+ 0.03 to + 0.16 W m(-2)), with an annual mean of + 0.27 +/- 0.17 W m(-2). Organic matter aerosol lifetimes, on the other hand are lower in May to October (2.0 to 3.7 day) and higher in November to April (4.6 to 11.9 day), with an annual average of 5.1 +/- 4.3 day. Their monthly mean burdens range from 2.07 to 12.10 mg m(-2) with an annual mean of 5.20 +/- 4.36 mg m(-2). Estimated monthly mean direct radiative forcing from organic matter is high (-1.49 to -2.11 W m(-2)) in December and January and is low (- 0.13 to 0.43 CV m(-2)) in May to October, with an annual mean of - 0.69 +/- 0.55 W m(-2) Organic matter aerosols cause a decrease in radiation flux of comparable magnitude to that previously estimated from sulphate aerosols (- 1.1 +/- 1.0 W m(-2)), while black carbon aerosols cause a one-quarter increase in the radiation flux. Further estimates of these effects from fly ash and mineral aerosols are needed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>CURRENT SCIENCE ASSN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T05:48:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T05:48:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:51:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CURRENT SCIENCE, 76(7), 1005-1011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0011-3891</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/5803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/5803</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>