<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14939</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:54:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental Investigation of Spray-Deposited Fe-Doped ZnO Nanoparticle Thin Films: Structural, Microstructural, and Optical Properties</dc:title><dc:creator>PRAJAPATI, CS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUSHWAHA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHAY, PP</dc:creator><dc:subject>Fe-doping</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZnO nanoparticle thin films</dc:subject><dc:subject>ROOM-TEMPERATURE FERROMAGNETISM</dc:subject><dc:subject>GAS SENSOR APPLICATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHOTOLUMINESCENCE PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSING CHARACTERISTICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZN1-XFEXO FILMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZINC</dc:subject><dc:subject>PYROLYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSTRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:description>Structural, microstructural, and optical properties of the undoped and Fe-doped zinc oxide (ZnO) thin films grown by spray pyrolysis technique using zinc nitrate as a host precursor have been reported here. X-ray diffraction spectra confirm that all the films have stable wurtzite structure and the effects of Fe dopants on the diffraction patterns have been found to be in agreement with the Vegard's law. Scanning electron microscopy results show good uniformity and dense surface having spherical-shaped grains. Energy dispersive x-ray analyses with elemental mapping of the Fe-doped films show that the Fe dopants are incorporated homogeneously into the ZnO film matrix. The x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy spectra confirm the presence of 3+ oxidation state of Fe in the doped films. Atomic force microscopy analyses clearly show that the average surface roughness and the grain size decrease with the addition of Fe dopants. Optical studies reveal that the optical band gap value decreases on Fe doping. The 1 at.% Fe-doped film shows normal dispersion for the wavelength range 450-700 nm. The PL spectra of the films show a strong ultraviolet emission centered at similar to 388 nm in the case of 1 at.% Fe-doped film. A slow photo current response in the films has been observed in the transient photoconductivity measurement.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:54:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:54:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THERMAL SPRAY TECHNOLOGY, 22(7)1230-1241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11666-013-9973-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14939</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>