<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15386</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T05:53:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrical transport and electromigration studies on nickel encapsulated carbon nanotubes: possible future interconnects</dc:title><dc:creator>KULSHRESTHA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHEMICAL-VAPOR-DEPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MASS-TRANSPORT</dc:subject><dc:subject>HIGH-DENSITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONDUCTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>RELIABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MULTIWALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILMS</dc:subject><dc:description>We nominate the nickel filled multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) as potential candidates to cope with challenges in persistent scaling for future interconnect technology. The insights into electrical transport through nickel filled carbon nanotubes provide an effective solution for major performance and reliability issues such as the increasing resistivity of metals at reduced scales, electromigration at high current densities and the problem of diffusion and corrosion faced by the existing copper interconnect technology. Furthermore, the nickel filled MWNTs outperform their hollow counterparts, the unfilled MWNTs, carrying at least one order higher current density, with increased time to failure. The results suggest that metal filled carbon nanotubes can provide a twofold benefit: (1) the metal filling provides an increased density of states for the system leading to a higher current density compared to hollow MWNTs, (2) metal out-diffusion and corrosion is prevented by the surrounding graphitic walls.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:53:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T05:53:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 24(18)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/24/18/185201</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15386</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>