<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14456</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T12:54:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigating the Frictional Response of Granitic Rock Surface: An Experimental Approach</dc:title><dc:creator>VISHAL, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, TN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Rock frictional behaviour</dc:subject><dc:subject>stick slip motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>steady motion</dc:subject><dc:subject>frictional constants</dc:subject><dc:subject>TIME-DEPENDENT FRICTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ASPERITY INDENTATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STICK-SLIP</dc:subject><dc:description>Rock friction varies as a function of mainly four parameters that are waiting time and velocity of motion between two frictional surfaces, surface roughness and normal stress. In this paper, a study on former two aspects of rock frictional behaviour has been attempted for granitic rock surface. In one experiment, waiting time for which the two surfaces remain in contact is increased from 20 seconds to 18 hours. In the second experiment, waiting time is kept constant for a series of rock slip experiments where the velocity is increased from 10 mu m/sec to 350 mu m/sec. The value of critical velocity is obtained from transformation of the stick slip motion to steady motion occurs. The relation of coefficients of dynamic and static friction with increasing velocity of motion is studied and these are used to calculate the frictional constants, namely 'a' and 'b' specific to the chosen simulation type.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:54:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T12:54:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 80(4)493-498</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14456</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>