<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18158</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:24:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Meeting Report: "Proteomics from Discovery to Function:'' 6th Annual Meeting of Proteomics Society, India and International Conference-A Milestone for the Indian Proteomics Community</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ATAK, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOLLAPALLI, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>JAIN, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, VG</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANTASALA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDALA, NG</dc:creator><dc:creator>PHAPALE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, VK</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZINGDE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, S</dc:creator><dc:description>Proteomics is at the epicenter of post-genomics biotechnologies that are currently driving the next generation system science. Moreover, proteomics is a truly global science. The 6(th) Annual Meeting of Proteomics Society, India (PSI) and International Conference on Proteomics from Discovery to Function held from December 7-9, 2014, was a transformative endeavor for global proteomics, bringing together the luminaries in the field of proteomics for the very first time in India. This meeting report presents the lessons learned and the highlights of this international scientific conference that was comprised of nine thematic sessions, pre- and post-conference workshops, and an opportunity to cultivate enduring collaborations for proteomics science to benefit both India and global society. The conference had an unforgettable impression on the participants: for the first time, India hosted past and present President and Council members from the Human Proteome Organization (HUPO), along with eminent scientists and young scholars from India and abroad in the field of proteomics at such a large scale, a major highlight of this international event. In all, the PSI 2014 was a milestone conference that has firmly poised the Indian life sciences community as a leading contributor to post-genomics life sciences, thus cultivating crucial trans-generational capacity and inspiration by recognizing the emerging scholars and omics systems scientists who can think and conduct science from cell to society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MARY ANN LIEBERT, INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:24:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:24:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>OMICS-A JOURNAL OF INTEGRATIVE BIOLOGY, 19(6)329-331</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1536-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1557-8100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1089/omi.2015.0044</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18158</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>