<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9812</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>The pore mouth tailoring of coal and coconut char through acid treatment followed by coke deposition</dc:title><dc:creator>KIM, TH</dc:creator><dc:creator>VIJAYALAKSHMI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SON, SJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>DONG, KJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>carbon molecular-sieves</dc:subject><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>activation</dc:subject><dc:subject>adsorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>coconut char</dc:subject><dc:subject>coal</dc:subject><dc:subject>pore constriction</dc:subject><dc:description>Carbon Molecular Sieves (CMS) obtained by coke deposition through deep cracking of hydrocarbons on the wide pore mouths of coal and coconut char are important adsorbents for separation of, difficult to separate, gaseous as well as liquid mixtures. The adsorption studies on these CMS show a high selectivity towards the adsorption of one or the other component from its mixture. In this work, CMS is prepared from pre treated raw materials like bituminous coal and coconut shell. The product samples are characterized in terms of kinetic adsorption and equilibrium adsorption of various gas adsorbents. It is observed that, all these samples are very good for CO2 removal from mixtures containing CH4 or H-2 in it. The CMS prepared from coconut shell showed an uptake ratio similar to4, for adsorption of O-2 and N-2, indicating that separation of nitrogen from air is viable by choosing suitable conditions in Pressure Swing Adsorption (PSA) Technique.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T08:32:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T08:32:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF POROUS MATERIALS, 9(4), 279-286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1380-2224</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9812</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9812</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>