<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1366</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>FTIR spectroscopy of multiwalled carbon nanotubes : a simple approach to study the nitrogen doping</dc:title><dc:creator>MISRA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>TYAGI, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>amorphous-carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitride films</dc:subject><dc:subject>cvd</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>modes</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman</dc:subject><dc:subject>n-2</dc:subject><dc:subject>mwnts</dc:subject><dc:subject>ftir</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>tga/dta</dc:subject><dc:description>The nitrogen doped multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWNTs) were synthesized by microwave plasma chemical vapor deposition (MPCVD) technique. In this paper, we report the results of FTIR, Raman, and TGA studies to confirm the presence of N-doping inside carbon nanotubes. Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) studies were carried out in the range 400-4000 cm(-1) to study the attachment of nitrogen impurities on carbon nanotubes. FTIR spectra of the virgin sample of MWNTs show dominant peaks which are corresponding to Si-O, C-N, N-CH3, CNT, C-O, and C-H-x, respectively. The Si-O peak has its origin in silicon substrate whereas the other peaks are due to the precursor gases present in the gas mixture. The peaks are sharp and highly intense showing the chemisorption nature of the dipole bond. The intensity of the peaks due to N-CH3, C-N, and C-H reduces after annealing. It is interesting to note that these peaks vanish on annealing at high temperature (900 degrees C). The presence of C-N peak may imply the doping of the MWNTs with N in substitution mode. The position of this intense peak is in agreement with the reported peak in carbon nitride samples prepared by plasma CVD process, since the Raman modes are also expected to be delocalized over both carbon and nitrogen sites it was found that the intensity ratio of the D and G peaks, /(D)//(G), varies as a function of ammonia concentration. The TGA measurements, carried out under argon flow, show that the dominant weight loss of the sample occurs in the temperature range 400-600 degrees C corresponding to the removal of the impurities and amorphous carbon.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T00:36:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T00:36:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF NANOSCIENCE AND NANOTECHNOLOGY,7(6)1820-1823</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1533-4880</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jnn.2007.723</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14545</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1366</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Nano Science and Technology (ICONSAT 2006),New Delhi, INDIA,MAR 16-18, 2006</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>