<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-6033</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:17Z</datestamp><dc:title>Delineation of the 85 degrees E ridge and its structure in the Mahanadi Offshore Basin, Eastern Continental Margin of India (ECMI), from seismic reflection imaging</dc:title><dc:creator>BASTIA, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RADHAKRISHNA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALE, AS</dc:creator><dc:creator>CATUNEANU, O</dc:creator><dc:subject>tectonics</dc:subject><dc:subject>bengal</dc:subject><dc:subject>ocean</dc:subject><dc:subject>volcanism</dc:subject><dc:subject>gravity</dc:subject><dc:subject>breakup</dc:subject><dc:subject>origin</dc:subject><dc:subject>traps</dc:subject><dc:subject>85 degrees e ridge</dc:subject><dc:subject>aseismic ridges</dc:subject><dc:subject>seaward dipping reflectors</dc:subject><dc:subject>kerguelen plume</dc:subject><dc:subject>eastern continental margin of india</dc:subject><dc:subject>indian ocean</dc:subject><dc:description>The passive Eastern Continental Margin of India (ECMI) evolved during the break up of India and East Antarctica in the Early Cretaceous. The 85 E ridge is a prominent linear aseismic feature extending from the Afanasy Nikitin Seamounts northward to the Mahanadi basin along the ECMI. Earlier workers have interpreted the ridge to be a prominent hot spot trail. In the absence of conclusive data, the extension of the ridge towards its northern extremity below the thick Bengal Fan sediments was a matter of postulation. In the present study, interpretation of high resolution 2-D reflection data from the Mahanadi Offshore Basin, located in the northern part of the ridge, unequivocally indicates continuation of the ridge across the continent ocean boundary into the slope and shelf tracts of the ECMI. Its morphology and internal architecture suggest a volcanic plume related origin that can be correlated with the activity of the Kerguelen hot spot in the nascent Indian Ocean. In the continental region, the plume related volcanic activity appears to have obliterated all seismic features typical of continental crust. The deeper oceanic crust, over which the hot spot plume erupted, shows the presence of linear NS aligned basement highs, corresponding with the ridge, underlain by a depressed Moho discontinuity. In the deep oceanic basin, the ridge influences the sediment dispersal pattern from the Early Cretaceous (?)/early part of Late Cretaceous times till the end of Oligocene, which is an important aspect for understanding the hydrocarbon potential of the basin.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-21T23:32:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-21T23:32:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MARINE AND PETROLEUM GEOLOGY, 27(9), 1841-1848</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0264-8172</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.marpetgeo.2010.08.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/6033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/6033</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>