<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10562</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>Atmospheric polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in Mumbai, India</dc:title><dc:creator>KULKARNI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>VENKATARAMAN, C</dc:creator><dc:subject>fine organic aerosol</dc:subject><dc:subject>source apportionment</dc:subject><dc:subject>emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>air</dc:subject><dc:subject>pollution</dc:subject><dc:subject>diesel</dc:subject><dc:subject>urban aerosols</dc:subject><dc:subject>pah</dc:subject><dc:subject>vehicular emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomass-burning stoves</dc:subject><dc:subject>industrial-oil burning</dc:subject><dc:description>Atmospheric particulate PAH concentrations were measured at two locations in Mumbai (formerly Bombay), India. Total PAH concentrations (seven compounds) at Saki Naka and Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) were 38.8 and 24.5 ng m(-3). Pyrene and benz(a)anthracene + chrysene were abundant at both sites while benzo(b)fluoranthene and benzo(k)fluoranthene were abundant, in addition, at the IIT site. The large amount of pyrene in the ambient samples in Mumbai is likely from cooking-fuel combustion (animal manure, kerosene and liquefied petroleum gas) in addition to vehicular emissions. Pyrene and chrysene are also emitted from industrial oil burning while the low concentrations of benzo(a)pyrene indicate that wood burning is not a significant source. At the IIT site, primarily vehicular emissions along with cooking fuel emissions are the likely contributors while industrial oil burning is an additional contributor at Saki Naka, accounting for the higher concentrations of pyrene and chrysene/benz(a)anthracene. In urban areas vehicular emissions are likely to be the primary contributor to PAH concentrations with additional local contributors like cooking fuel or industrial emissions. (C) 2000 . .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T15:41:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T15:41:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:19Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ATMOSPHERIC ENVIRONMENT, 34(17), 2785-2790</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1352-2310</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1352-2310(99)00312-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10562</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10562</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>