<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15553</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T12:31:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>An accurate higher order displacement model with shear and normal deformations effects for functionally graded plates</dc:title><dc:creator>JHA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANT, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRINIVAS, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, RK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Functionally graded plates</dc:subject><dc:subject>Navier solution</dc:subject><dc:subject>Free vibration</dc:subject><dc:subject>Natural frequency</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECTANGULAR-PLATES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIBRATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Functionally graded materials (FGMs) are the potential candidates under consideration for designing the first wall of fusion reactors with a view to make best use of potential properties of available materials under severe thermo-mechanical loading conditions. A higher order shear and normal deformations plate theory is employed for stress and free vibration analyses of functionally graded (FG) elastic, rectangular, and simply (diaphragm) supported plates. Although FGMs are highly heterogeneous in nature, they are generally idealized as continua with mechanical properties changing smoothly with respect to spatial coordinates. The material properties of FG plates are assumed here to vary through thickness of plate in a continuous manner. Young's modulii and material densities are considered to be varying continuously in thickness direction according to volume fraction of constituents which are mathematically modeled here as exponential and power law functions. The effects of variation of material properties in terms of material gradation index on deformations, stresses and natural frequency of FG plates are investigated. The accuracy of present numerical solutions has been established with respect to exact three-dimensional (3D) elasticity solutions and the other models' solutions available in literature. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:31:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T12:31:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FUSION ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 88(12)3199-3204</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0920-3796</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-7196</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1616/j.fusengdes.2013.10.002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15553</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>