<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11682</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Assembling metal phosphonates in the presence of monodentate-terminal and bidentate-bridging pyridine ligands. Use of non-covalent and covalent-coordinate interactions to build polymeric metal-phosphonate architectures</dc:title><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAN, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>butyl phosphate complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>ray crystal-structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>structural-characterization</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>pyrazole ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>copper phosphonates</dc:subject><dc:subject>cage structures</dc:subject><dc:subject>model compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>compound</dc:subject><dc:description>The cubic transition metal phosphonates [(BuPO3M)-Bu-t(2-apy)](4) (M= Zn (1), Co (2), whose core resembles the D4R SBU of zeolites, have been synthesized from a reaction between the corresponding metal acetate, tert-butylphosphonic acid and 2-aminopyridine (2-apy) at room temperature. X-Ray structure determination reveals that the molecules of 1 and 2, which crystallize in the tetragonal I4(1)/a space group with crystallographically imposed (4) over bar symmetry, form a 3-D supramolecular assembly aided by N-H center dot center dot center dot O hydrogen bonding. When the same reaction was carried out by using a bridging bidentate Lewis base such as 4,4'-bipyridine, insoluble precipitate is obtained for both zinc and cobalt. In the case of other metal salts such as copper, manganese and nickel, however, one-dimensional polymeric compounds such as [M((BuPO3H)-Bu-t) 2(4,4 '-bipy)(H2O)(2)](n) (M= Cu (3), Mn (4)), [{Ni(4,4 '-bipy)(H2O)(4)}-{ (BuPO3H)-Bu-t}(2){H2O}](n) (5) have been isolated. The solid-state structures of 3-5 have been determined by single crystal X-ray diffraction studies. Compounds 3 and 4 are isostructural and crystallize in the triclinic P (1) over bar space group with two phosphonate ligands coordinated to the metal centers in a [1.100] fashion, whereas in the case of compound 5, the polymeric backbone is formed by Ni-4,4 '-bipy units and the phosphonate anions show no bonding interaction to the metal. The 1-D polymeric chains of 3-5 organize in the solid-state as 3-D supramolecular assemblies with the aid of extensive hydrogen bonding interaction between coordinated water molecules and P-OH or P=O groups of the phosphonate ligands.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-27T14:02:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-27T14:02:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:57:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>DALTON TRANSACTIONS, (39), 5358-5367</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1477-9226</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/b805848b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11682</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11682</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>