<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12537</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:50:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Manual lifting load limit equation for adult Indian women workers based on physiological criteria</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, GG</dc:creator><dc:subject>workload</dc:subject><dc:subject>tasks</dc:subject><dc:subject>lifting load limit equation</dc:subject><dc:subject>physiological criterion</dc:subject><dc:subject>heart rate normalization</dc:subject><dc:description>A comprehensive equation for the evaluation of a maximum load limit for manual load lifting has been developed for the first time for Indian adult female workers, based on a physiological criterion due to the limitation of applicability of the NIOSH (1991) equation. Ten adult female workers, who had been engaged in building construction activities for at least 7 years participated in this study. The cut-off value was selected as the working heart rate corresponding to the 33% level of maximum aerobic power (i.e. V'O-2 max.) of this population, which was equivalent to a heart rate of 101.6 beats.min(-1) . An equation was developed based on the effects of the following three lifting parameters on working heart rate: vertical height (knee, waist, shoulder and maximum reach height), lifting frequency (1, 4, 7 and 14 lifts.min (-1)), and load weight (5, 10 and 15 kg). The variations of the specific lifting parameter values were selected from field observations. From this equation, the maximum load limit was calculated as 15.4 kg and the workers give this a psychophysical rating as in the moderate to heavy category.</dc:description><dc:publisher>TAYLOR &amp; FRANCIS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-31T01:49:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-31T01:49:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:59:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:50:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ERGONOMICS, 47(1), 59-74</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0014-0139</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00140130310001611116</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12537</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12537</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>