<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-43</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dynamic active earth pressure on retaining structures</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, DEEPANKAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHATTERJEE, SANTIRAM</dc:creator><dc:subject>earth (planet)</dc:subject><dc:subject>civil engineering</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>pressure effects</dc:subject><dc:description>Earth-retaining structures constitute an important topic of research in civil engineering, more so under earthquake conditions. For the analysis and design of retaining walls in earthquake-prone zones, accurate estimation of dynamic earth pressures is very important. Conventional methods either use pseudo-static
approaches of analysis even for dynamic cases or a simple single-degree of freedom model for the retaining wall–soil system. In this paper, a simpliﬁed two-degree of freedom mass–spring–dashpot (2-DOF) dynamic model has been proposed to
estimate the active earth pressure at the back of the retaining walls for translation modes of wall movement under seismic conditions. The horizontal zone of inﬂuence on dynamic earth force on the wall is estimated. Results in terms of displacement,velocity and acceleration-time history are presented for some typical cases, which show the ﬁnal movement of the wall in terms of wall height, which is required for the design. The non-dimensional design chart proposed in the present study can be used to compute the total dynamic earth force on the wall under different input ground motion and backﬁll conditions. Finally, the results obtained have been compared with those of the available Scott model and the merits of the present results have been discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Indian Academy of Sciences</dc:publisher><dc:date>2007-01-18T11:10:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:43:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007-01-18T11:10:58Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T12:43:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:08:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Sadhana 31(6), 721-730</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/43</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/43</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>