<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17922</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:23:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Asymmetric Dual-Catalytic Cascade by Chiral N-Heterocyclic Carbene and Quinuclidine: Mechanism and Origin of Enantioselectivity in Benzofuranone Formation</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>SUNOJ, RB</dc:creator><dc:subject>INTRAMOLECULAR STETTER REACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>LONE-PAIR</dc:subject><dc:subject>COOPERATIVE CATALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>REACTION INSIGHTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>PI INTERACTIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>3+2 ANNULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-LACTONES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACYL AZOLIUMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>asymmetric catalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition state</dc:subject><dc:subject>N-heterocyclic carbenes</dc:subject><dc:subject>noncovalent interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>Stetter reaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>dual catalysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>reaction mechanism</dc:subject><dc:description>Contemporary literature offers a number of interesting examples for asymmetric multicatalytic reactions using chiral N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHCs) in conjunction with other catalysts. One of the very recent examples demonstrated a convenient strategy toward realizing chiral benzofuranones from salicylaldehyde and dimethyl acetylenedicarboxylate (DMAD). In this article, we report the mechanism and insights on the origin of asymmetric induction as obtained through a comprehensive density functional theory (M06-2X and mPW1K) investigation. Different likely catalyst-substrate combinations as well as the timing/sequence of activation of different substrates are carefully examined so as to identify the most preferred pathway. In the lowest energy path, the activation of DMAD by quinuclidine occurs first; the resulting zwitterionic intermediate then undergoes a Michael addition with a salicylate ion to yield a salicylate-DMAD adduct, which, in turn, is intercepted by the chiral NHC. In the next crucial step, an enantioselective C-C bond formation via an intramolecular Stetter reaction furnishes the benzofuranone framework bearing a chiral carbon atom. Two transition state models, with and without an explicitly bound catechol (an additive employed in the reaction that resulted in enhanced enantioselectivity), are considered. A distinct energetic advantage, of the order of 3.4 kcal/mol, for the addition of the re face of the Breslow intermediate (derived from the chiral NHC and the salicylate-DMAD adduct) to the re face of the dimethyl maleate moiety is noticed in the stereocontrolling C-C bond formation step. The Gibbs free energy difference between the diastereomeric transition states for (re,re) and (re,si) modes of addition is traced to the differential nonbonding interactions (O-H center dot center dot center dot pi, lone pair (lp)center dot center dot center dot pi, and C-H center dot center dot center dot O). The predicted enantioselectivity is in good agreement with the experimental observations.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:23:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:23:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACS CATALYSIS, 5(3)1596-1603</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2155-5435</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/cs502006x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17922</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>