<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1489</identifier><datestamp>2012-01-02T10:56:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Transport and magnetic properties of encapsulated Ni-Ni-O/Zr-O nanostructures</dc:title><dc:creator>NAYAK, BB</dc:creator><dc:creator>VITTA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>NIGAM, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>nickel</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensor</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>encapsulated nanoparticles (nps)</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>transport properties</dc:subject><dc:description>The transport and magnetic properties of nickel (Ni) nanoparticles in the range 9-70 nm having a surface oxide layer of Ni or zirconium (Zr) have been studied. The oxide-encapsulated Ni has been prepared by chemical reduction of nickel and zirconium salts in an aqueous medium with sodium borohydride as a reducing agent. Both X-ray diffraction and transmission electron microscopy studies indicate the presence of amorphous Ni-O in the native state. With the addition of Zr-0, Ni crystalline peaks become strong, and amorphous Ni-O peaks become weak. The absolute resistivity decreases first (up to x &lt;= 0. 10 where x is the molar concentration of Zr salt in the starting solution), and then increases with increasing addition of Zr-O (x &gt;= 0. 15). The saturation magnetization increases with the addition of Zr-O up to x = 0.05 and then decreases. These results are in agreement with the microstructural results, which show that addition of Zr-O promotes Ni formation by suppressing the Ni-O shell. The resistivity drops initially (up to x &lt;= 0.10) due to better interparticle connectivity, whereas for x &gt;= 0. 10, the resistivity increases as the interparticle connectivity is reduced, due to Zr-O encapsulation. The low field magnetization shows a superparamagnetic behavior, observed in nanoscale structures.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-20T09:58:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-20T09:58:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON MAGNETICS,41(10)3298-3300</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9464</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TMAG.2005.854909</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14637</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1489</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Magnetics Conference 2005,Nagoya, JAPAN,APR 04-08, 2005</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>