<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17283</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:14:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Facile synthesis of reduced graphene oxide/Pt-Ni nanocatalysts: their magnetic and catalytic properties</dc:title><dc:creator>SAHOO, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANIGRAHY, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAHADUR, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>IN-SITU SYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>METHANOL OXIDATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCATALYTIC ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOY NANOPARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIMETALLIC CLUSTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXYGEN REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOSHEETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PLATINUM</dc:subject><dc:description>The catalytic performance of metals can be enhanced by intimately alloying different metals with Reduced Graphene Oxide (RGO). In this work, we have demonstrated a simplistic in situ one-step reduction approach for the synthesis of RGO/Pt-Ni nanocatalysts with different atomic ratios of Pt and Ni, without using any capping agent. The physical properties of the as-synthesized nanocatalysts have been systematically investigated by XRD, FTIR, Raman spectroscopy, XPS, EDX, ICP-AES, and TEM. The composition dependent magnetic properties of the RGO/Pt-Ni nanocatalysts were investigated at 5 and 300 K, respectively. The results confirm that the RGO/Pt-Ni nanocatalysts show a super-paramagnetic nature at room temperature in all compositions. Furthermore, the catalytic activities of the RGO/Pt-Ni nanocatalysts were investigated by analyzing the reduction of p-nitrophenol, and the reduction rate was found to be susceptible to the composition of Pt and Ni. Moreover, it has been found that RGO/Pt-Ni nanocatalysts show superior catalytic activity compared with the bare Pt-Ni of the same composition. Interestingly, the nanocatalysts can be readily recycled by a strong magnet and reused for the next reactions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:14:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:14:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>RSC ADVANCES, 4(89)48563-48571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2046-2069</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4ra07686a</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17283</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>