<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10217</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Confirmation studies of correlation between TL and ESR of natural calcium fluoride</dc:title><dc:creator>CHOUGAONKAR, MP</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, TKG</dc:creator><dc:subject>thermoluminescence</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron spin resonance</dc:subject><dc:subject>calcium fluoride</dc:subject><dc:description>Thermoluminescence (TL) and electron spin resonance (ESR) studies were carried out on natural calcium fluoride (Chougaonkar M P &amp; Gundu Rao T K, Proc NCLA-2005, 2005). It was speculated from the studies that the first two TL peaks appearing approximately at 115 and 200 degrees C may be related to two distinct O(2)(-)(I) and O(2)(-)(II) radicals, respectively. To assess the validity of the correlation between two ESR centres and file TL peaks, CaF(2) without oxygen impurities were obtained by growing single crystals of natural CaF(2), in oxygen free atmosphere. The oxygen contents ill the host material were also removed using PbF(2) as scavenger during the growth. ESR spectrum and TL glow curves were then recorded to study the effect of removal of oxygen from the lattice. The studies indicate that the addition of PbF(2) leads to the removal of precursors of O(2)(-) radicals as well as CaO present in the lattice and yields clear transparent crystals. It has also been observed that the glow peaks appearing at 115 and 200 degrees C were drastically reduced indicating the near absence of centres responsible for the TL peaks. ESR studies shows the absence radicals O(2)(-) I as well as O(2)(-) II, thus confirming that these centres are responsible for the TL peaks.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL INST SCIENCE COMMUNICATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-19T03:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-19T03:57:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDIAN JOURNAL OF PURE &amp; APPLIED PHYSICS, 47(6), 429-431</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0019-5596</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10217</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10217</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>