<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15099</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:26:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>An energy-based model for ballistic impact analysis of ceramic-composite armors</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RATNAVEER, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOSHI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>AKELLA, K</dc:creator><dc:subject>ceramic-composite armor</dc:subject><dc:subject>ballistic impact</dc:subject><dc:subject>fracture</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy-based model</dc:subject><dc:subject>ballistic limit velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>damage mechanisms</dc:subject><dc:subject>WOVEN FABRIC COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NUMERICAL-SIMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>THICK COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PENETRATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BEHAVIOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DAMAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROJECTILE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FAILURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORMULATION</dc:subject><dc:description>An analytical model is presented for the ballistic impact behavior of ceramic-composite armors. The model is based on wave theory and energy balance between the kinetic energy of the projectile and the energy absorbed by different mechanisms. The armor analyzed consists of front composite cover layer, ceramic plate, rubber layer and the composite backing plate. The projectile is cylindrical. The major damage and energy-absorbing mechanisms are compression of the target directly below the projectile, compression in the surrounding region around the point of impact, formation of ring cracks and radial cracks in the ceramic leading to tensile failure, shear plugging, pulverization of the ceramic, tension in the yarns, delamination and matrix cracking in the composite, bulge formation on the back face of the composite backing plate and friction between the target and the projectile. Projectile erosion and deformation are also considered. Kinetic energy, velocity and deceleration of the projectile, distance traveled by the projectile and the contact force are presented as a function of time. Ballistic limit velocity, contact duration and damage progression are also given. Further, solution procedure is presented for the study of ballistic impact behavior of ceramic-composite armors. Analytical predictions are validated with the experimental results. Finally, performance of a typical ceramic-composite armor is presented.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SAGE PUBLICATIONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:26:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:26:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF DAMAGE MECHANICS, 22(2)145-187</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/1056789511435346</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15099</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>