<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4594</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Dexamethasone release from uniform sized nanoengineered alginate microspheres</dc:title><dc:creator>JAYANT, RD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>encapsulates subcutaneous implants</dc:subject><dc:subject>multilayer microcapsules</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanofilm coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>glucose sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>tissue-response</dc:subject><dc:subject>biocompatibility</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>films</dc:subject><dc:subject>dexamethasone</dc:subject><dc:subject>controlled release</dc:subject><dc:subject>alginate</dc:subject><dc:subject>lbl.</dc:subject><dc:description>The main objective of this work is to develop a novel technology based on nanoengineered alginate microspheres made using the droplet generator technique for controlled delivery of an immunomodulating agent at the site of implantation. Uniform sized alginate microspheres have been prepared using a commercially available droplet generator. SEM and optical micrographs confirmed the structure and spherecity of the prepared alginate microspheres. Release studies, completed on uncoated alginate microspheres, did not provide the desired profile. Layer-by-Layer (LbL) self assembly technique was further implemented on the uncoated alginate microspheres using standard polyelectrolyte pair. SEM, zeta potential measurements and QCM measurements were used to confirm the nanofilm coating on the alginate microspheres. Release studies conducted on the uncoated dexamethasone alginate microspheres demonstrate a cumulative release of 78% of initially encapsulated dexamethasone as compared to one and two bilayer coated microspheres, which demonstrate a release of 40% and 32% respectively. Thus, the application of nanofilm coating helped in reducing the initial burst release, thereby providing a means to control the release of drug over a longer period of time.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SCIENTIFIC PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T02:25:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T02:25:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOMEDICAL NANOTECHNOLOGY, 3(3), 245-253</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-7033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1166/jbn.2007.039</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4594</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4594</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>