<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17918</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:21:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Thalidomide (5HPP-33) Suppresses Microtubule Dynamics and Depolymerizes the Microtubule Network by Binding at the Vinblastine Binding Site on Tubulin</dc:title><dc:creator>RASHID, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUPPA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUNWAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>ENDOTHELIAL GROWTH-FACTOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERIZATION INHIBITORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INDIVIDUAL MICROTUBULES</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETIC STABILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CELL-DIFFERENTIATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>COLCHICINE SITE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MCF-7 CELLS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANGIOGENESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>APOPTOSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MIGRATION</dc:subject><dc:description>Thalidomides were initially thought to be broad-range drugs specifically for curing insomnia and relieving morning sickness in pregnant women. However, its use was discontinued because of a major drawback of causing teratogenicity. In this study, we found that a thalidomide derivative, 5-hydroxy-2-(2,6-diisopropylphenyl)-1H-isoindole-1,3-dione (5HPP-33), inhibited the proliferation of MCF-7 with a half-maximal inhibitory concentration of 4.5 +/- 0.4 mu M. 5HPP-33 depolymerized microtubules and inhibited the reassembly of cold-depolymerized microtubules in MCF-7 cells. Using time-lapse imaging, the effect of 5HPP-33 on the dynamics of individual microtubules in live MCF-7 cells was analyzed. 5HPP-33 (5 mu M) decreased the rates of growth and shortening excursions by 34 and 33%, respectively, and increased the time microtubules spent in the pause state by 92% as compared to that of the vehicle-treated MCF-7 cells. 5HPP-33 (5 mu M) reduced the dynamicity of microtubules by 62% compared to the control. 5HPP-33 treatment reduced the distance between the two poles of a bipolar spindle, induced multipolarity in some of the treated cells, and blocked cells at mitosis. In vitro, 5HPP-33 bound to tubulin with a weak affinity. Vinblastine inhibited the binding of 5HPP-33 to tubulin, and 5HPP-33 inhibited the binding of BODIPY FL-vinblastine to tubulin. Further, a molecular docking analysis suggested that 5HPP-33 shares its binding site on tubulin with vinblastine. The results provided significant insight into the antimitotic mechanism of action of 5HPP-33 and also suggest a possible mechanism for the teratogenicity of thalidomides.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:21:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:21:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOCHEMISTRY, 54(12)2149-2159</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0006-2960</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/bi501429j</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17918</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>