<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4619</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:07Z</datestamp><dc:title>Glutamate-induced assembly of bacterial cell division protein FtsZ</dc:title><dc:creator>BEURIA, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KRISHNAKUMAR, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHAR, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>MESHRAM, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>microtubule-associated proteins</dc:subject><dc:subject>escherichia-coli</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic instability</dc:subject><dc:subject>binding-protein</dc:subject><dc:subject>gtp hydrolysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>brain tubulin</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymerization</dc:subject><dc:subject>ring</dc:subject><dc:subject>homolog</dc:subject><dc:subject>mechanism</dc:subject><dc:description>The polymerization of FtsZ is a finely regulated process that plays an essential role in the bacterial cell division process. However, only a few modulators of FtsZ polymerization are known. We identified monosodium glutamate as a potent inducer of FtsZ polymerization. In the presence of GTP, glutamate enhanced the rate and extent of polymerization of FtsZ in a concentration-dependent manner; similar to90% of the protein was sedimented as polymer in the presence of 1 m glutamate. Electron micrographs of glutamate-induced polymers showed large filamentous structures with extensive bundling. Furthermore, glutamate strongly stabilized the polymers against dilution-induced disassembly, and it decreased the GTPase activity of FtsZ. Calcium induced FtsZ polymerization and bundling of FtsZ polymers; interestingly, although 1 m glutamate produced a larger light-scattering signal than produced by 10 mm calcium, the amount of polymer sedimented in the presence of 1 m glutamate and 10 mm calcium was similar. Thus, the increased light scattering in the presence of glutamate must be due to its ability to induce more extensive bundling of FtsZ polymers than calcium. The data suggest that calcium and glutamate might induce FtsZ polymerization by different mechanisms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER SOC BIOCHEMISTRY MOLECULAR BIOLOGY INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-17T04:54:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-17T04:54:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:07Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF BIOLOGICAL CHEMISTRY, 278(6), 3735-3741</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0021-9258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M205760200</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4619</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4619</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>