<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17330</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:38:55Z</datestamp><dc:title>FORMATION OF MESO- AND MICRO-PORES IN FLY-ASH MUTES USING A THREE-STEP ACTIVATION</dc:title><dc:creator>JHA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, DN</dc:creator><dc:subject>fly-ash</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrothermal treatment</dc:subject><dc:subject>three-step activation</dc:subject><dc:subject>pore characteristics</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZEOLITES</dc:subject><dc:description>Researchers have comprehensively characterized alkali-activated fly-ash (the residue) and ascertained its highly zeolitic nature. In order to evaluate its potential for application as an adsorbent for the decontamination of waste water, the decisive parameters have mostly been the cation-exchange capacity, the mineralogy and the morphology of the residue. However, a study of the pore characteristics (e.g., the size and volume) of such residues is still warranted to anticipate their contaminant transport and the diffusion phenomena as a type of geotechnical engineering material. In this situation, the present study demonstrates the evolution of pores in the fly-ash after alkali activation up to three steps, and simultaneously, its effects' on other characteristics (e.g., the specific gravity, specific surface area and the cation-exchange capacity) of three types of similarly synthesized residues (the first, produced by using a NaOH aqueous solution and the other two residues, the result of alkali activation using a NaOH spent solution, the filtrates). Based on N-2 gas absorption isotherms and infrared transmittance spectra, residues obtained from the second and third steps, each involving 24 hours of treatment using filtrates of 1.5-M NaOH, are established to be significantly enriched in the finer meso- and micro-pores, respectively, in comparison with a pure and macro-porous zeolite 4A.</dc:description><dc:publisher>UNIV MARIBOR</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:38:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACTA GEOTECHNICA SLOVENICA, 11(1)63-69</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1854-0171</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17330</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>