<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8254</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>CHISEL programming operation of scaled NOR flash EEPROMs - Effect of voltage scaling, device scaling and technological parameters</dc:title><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, NR</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAIR, DR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAPATRA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUDE, JD</dc:creator><dc:subject>enhanced gate current</dc:subject><dc:subject>vlsi mosfets</dc:subject><dc:subject>part ii</dc:subject><dc:subject>memory</dc:subject><dc:subject>cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>channel hot electron (che)</dc:subject><dc:subject>channel initiated secondary electron (chisel)</dc:subject><dc:subject>device scaling</dc:subject><dc:subject>flash electrically erasable programmable read-only memories (eeproms)</dc:subject><dc:subject>hot carriers</dc:subject><dc:subject>monte carlo simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>programming efficiency</dc:subject><dc:description>The impact of programming biases, device scaling and variation of technological parameters on channel initiated secondary electron (CHISEL) programming performance of scaled NOR Flash electrically erasable programmable read-only memories (EEPROMs) is studied in detail. It is shown that CHISEL operation offers faster programming for all bias conditions and remains highly efficient at lower biases compared to conventional channel hot electron (CHE) operation. The physical mechanism responsible for this behavior is explained using full band Monte Carlo simulations. CHISEL programming efficiency is shown to degrade with device scaling, and various technological parameter optimization schemes required for its improvement are explored. The resulting increase in drain disturbs is also studied and the impact of technological parameter optimization on the programming performance versus drain disturb tradeoff is analyzed. It is shown that by judicious choice of technological parameters the advantage of CHISEL programming can be maintained for deeply scaled electrically erasable programmable read-only memory (EEPROM) cells.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T22:14:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T22:14:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE TRANSACTIONS ON ELECTRON DEVICES, 50(10), 2104-2111</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0018-9383</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TED.2003.817275</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8254</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>