<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16959</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T17:06:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Nonequilibrium magnetic properties in Nd5Ge3</dc:title><dc:creator>MAJI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, KG</dc:creator><dc:subject>Rare earth magnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>Spin glass</dc:subject><dc:subject>Aging</dc:subject><dc:subject>Memory effects</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPIN-GLASSES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>MEMORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRANSITION</dc:subject><dc:description>Using the field cooled (FC) and zero field cooled (ZFC) magnetization of Nd5Ge3 measured with intermittent stops and wait periods, we vividly demonstrate that it exhibits history dependent phenomena such as aging, memory effects and rejuvenation at temperatures below the spin glass freezing temperature (T-g). Memory effects are also observed in magnetization relaxation experiments with temporary cooling cycle. However, a small positive temperature cycle destroys the effect of previous aging and rejuvenates the system. Memory effects observed in different experimental protocols below T-g give a strong confirmation of the existence of spin glass like phase in the system. Asymmetric behavior of the relaxation data during hetaing and cooling cycles suggests that the hierarchical model for spin glasses to be valid in this compound. A comparison of different members of R5Ge3 series shows that Nd5Ge3 possesses special magnetic and related properties that make it unique among the other members of the series. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:06:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T17:06:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF ALLOYS AND COMPOUNDS, 60529-33</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-8388</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2014.03.115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16959</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>