<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15710</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:50:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Model order reduction for dynamic simulation of beams with forcing and geometric nonlinearities</dc:title><dc:creator>GAONKAR, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, SS</dc:creator><dc:subject>Model order reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>Modified TPWLMOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>Nonlinear FEM</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROELECTROMECHANICAL SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROSTATIC MEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEVICES</dc:subject><dc:description>The objective of the paper is to investigate the applicability of a model order reduction technique for dynamic simulation of beams with forcing and geometric nonlinearities. A cantilever and a doubly clamped beams actuated by an electrostatic force are considered in the paper. The governing partial differential equations for the two cases which account for the nonlinearities are presented. These equations are spatially discretized using the Galerkin finite element method (FEM). The resulting system of nonlinear ordinary differential equations is reduced using the trajectory piecewise linear model order reduction (TPWLMOR) method. Simulation indicates that the use of the original TPWLMOR method leads to the presence of a phase error in the long term dynamic simulation of the models. To improve the accuracy of the dynamic response, a modification to the original TPWLMOR based on minimization of residual at linearization point is proposed. Further, the parameters affecting the accuracy of the modified TPWLMOR are studied. (c) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:50:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:50:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>FINITE ELEMENTS IN ANALYSIS AND DESIGN, 7650-62</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-874X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1872-6925</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.finel.2013.08.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15710</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>