<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-3064</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:16:14Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of nano-zno addition on the silicone-modified alkyd-based waterborne coatings on its mechanical and heat-resistance properties</dc:title><dc:creator>DHOKE, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHANDARI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHANNA, AS</dc:creator><dc:subject>waterborne coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>nano-zno</dc:subject><dc:subject>heat-resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>stabilization</dc:subject><dc:subject>polyurethane</dc:subject><dc:subject>degradation</dc:subject><dc:subject>particles</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymers</dc:subject><dc:subject>resins</dc:subject><dc:description>A silicone-modified alkyd-based waterborne coating was developed using hexamethylmethoxymelamine (HMMM) as crosslinking agent and para-toluene sulphonic acid (p-TSA) as catalyst. The crosslinking ratio for resin and HMMM was fixed to 70:30, based on FTIR and DSC studies. Nano-ZnO particles were added to this system in different concentrations. The coatings with nano-ZnO particles were characterized using FTIR and DSC. The nano-composite coatings were applied on mild steel panels and were cured at 130 degrees C for 30 min. The coatings were evaluated for their mechanical and heat-resistance properties. They were exposed to 350 degrees C for 10min followed by water quenching. The process was repeated for 10 cycles. Heat-resistance property of the coatings was examined by TGA. Also, surface morphological changes were assessed using SEM and optical microscopy. It was found that the heat-resistance and mechanical properties of the coatings improved significantly as a function of nano-ZnO addition. (C) 2008 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-13T21:33:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-13T21:33:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:16:14Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Review</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROGRESS IN ORGANIC COATINGS,64(1)39-46</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-9440</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.porgcoat.2008.07.007</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/13856</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/3064</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>