<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4328</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:51Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrohydrodynamic instabilities at interfaces subjected to alternating electric field</dc:title><dc:creator>GAMBHIRE, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>THAOKAR, RM</dc:creator><dc:subject>thin liquid-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>stability analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>polymer-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>flow</dc:subject><dc:description>Instabilities at the interface of two immiscible fluids, either perfect or leaky dielectrics, subjected to alternating electric fields, is studied using a linear stability analysis in the limit of the electrode spacing being large compared to the wavelength of the perturbation. The Floquet analysis of the stability of this system indicates a significant effect of the frequency on the value of s(max), the growth rate of the fastest growing instabilities and E(Taylor), the minimum field required to excite an instability. It is seen that alternating fields act to damp the system instabilities compared to the direct current (dc) case. Moreover, the growth rate of the instabilities can be tuned from that of leaky dielectric fluids subjected to dc fields, in the low frequency limit, to that of perfect dielectrics in the high frequency limit. It is also observed that for a leaky dielectric-leaky dielectric interface, the alternating current (ac) fields can induce instabilities in a system which is stable at zero frequency, by increasing the frequency of the applied voltage. (C) 2010  [doi:10.1063/1.3431043]</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T16:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T16:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICS OF FLUIDS, 22(6), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1070-6631</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.3431043</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4328</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4328</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>