<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2554</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:15Z</datestamp><dc:title>Implementation scheme for End-to-end Quality of Service (QoS) sessions over Internet</dc:title><dc:creator>JOSHI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAPH, GP</dc:creator><dc:description>With the significant increase in the internet applications and services which have definite QoS requirements and the resources on the internet being shared, the need of end-to-end QoS sessions has become critical. The existing QoS mechanisms provide the path selection mechanism in distributed manner which do not necessarily support the end-to-end QoS requirements. We build propose an evolutionary framework which provides support for optimal end-to-end QoS sessions. Implementation of end to end QoS sessions fall under three distinct planes: Session Control Plane, Network Control Plane and Data Forwarding Plane. In this paper we describe the implementation requirements, various choices and the implementation scheme for building end-to-end QoS sessions over internet.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-26T00:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-26T00:50:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANTS: 2008 2ND INTERNATIONAL SYMPOSIUM ON ADVANCED NETWORKS AND TELECOMMUNICATION SYSTEMS,55-57</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-3600-2</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15863</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2554</dc:identifier><dc:source>2nd International Symposium on Advanced Networks and Telecommunication Systems,Mumbai, INDIA,DEC 15-17, 2008</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>