<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1541</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Contribution of sp(3) clusters in films and fibers obtained from camphor</dc:title><dc:creator>RZEPKA, E</dc:creator><dc:creator>LUSSON, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>LEVY-CLEMENT, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>MUKHOPADHYAY, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARON, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>carbon-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>diamondlike carbon</dc:subject><dc:subject>raman-scattering</dc:subject><dc:subject>deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>methane</dc:subject><dc:subject>dlc</dc:subject><dc:subject>sp(3) cluster</dc:subject><dc:subject>microraman</dc:subject><dc:subject>camphor</dc:subject><dc:description>Considerable attention has been focused on the growth of carbon-based films or fibers by various methods. Diamond-like carbon (DLC) films may be of greater importance in some specific electronic applications such as flat panel displays, which represent a very large market. In this study, carbon-based thin films and fibers obtained from doped camphor soot were studied by confocal microRaman spectroscopy at 632.8 nm. Different contributions were identified between 1000 and 1650 cm(-1) in the Raman spectra of the as-grown and laser-annealed films and fibers. The contributions were the D-like and G-like peaks of polycrystalline graphite at about 1345 and 1530 cm(-1), respectively, with a FWHM value about 5 times larger than in a:C. It is now well established from correlation between Raman signature and grain size measurements that the width of the Raman line is a decreasing function of the graphite grain size. From these results, one can estimate that the grain size of this polycrystalline graphitic phase was small. An additional feature is observed at about 1240 cm(-1) which could be due to sp(3)-bonded carbon clusters. (C) 1999 Elsevier Science S.A. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:26:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-21T22:26:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>DIAMOND AND RELATED MATERIALS,8,481-484</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0925-9635</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0925-9635(98)00403-8</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/14753</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1541</dc:identifier><dc:source>9th European Conference on Diamond, Diamond-like Materials, Nitrides and Silicon Carbide (Diamond 1998),IRAKLION, GREECE,SEP 13-18, 1998</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>