<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2534</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Theoretical scheme for a vibration based detection of a crack in stepped beams</dc:title><dc:creator>NANDWANA, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:description>A theoretical scheme with potential for detection of location and size of a crack in slender stepped beams based on measurement of transverse natural frequencies is presented. The crack is modelled by a rotational spring. The characteristic equation obtained with this modelling is manipulated to give a variation of the stiffness with crack location for the three lowest natural frequencies. The three curves intersect at a common point giving the crack location and the spring stiffness. The crack size is then obtained using the standard relationship between the stiffness and the crack size. A numerical study to demonstrate the utility and accuracy is presented considering a two step beam. The accuracy of prediction of location is goad for crack size greater than 10% of section depth for both the cantilever and simply supported beams. The maximum error is about 1.5%. The error in prediction of crack size is also satisfactory.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A A BALKEMA PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T12:09:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T12:09:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>MODERN PRACTICE IN STRESS AND VIBRATION ANALYSIS,135-141</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-5410-896-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16293</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2534</dc:identifier><dc:source>3rd International Conference on Modern Practice in Stress and Vibration Analysis,DUBLIN, IRELAND,SEP 03-05, 1997</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>