<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17306</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:26:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Numerical and experimental investigation on friction stir lap welding of aluminium to steel</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>JANA, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>PAL, TK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DE, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>Friction stir welding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Lap joint</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dissimilar material</dc:subject><dc:subject>PHASE-FORMATION SEQUENCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>EFFECTIVE HEAT</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORMATION RULE</dc:subject><dc:subject>JOINTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:description>Use of multimaterial fabrication such as aluminium to steel to reduce overall vehicular body weight has gained significant attention in the automotive industries. Since fusion welding of aluminium to steel is difficult, friction stir welding of the same is considered as an effective recourse. Quantitative studies on friction stir welding of aluminium to steel are thus important but scarce in the literature. We present here a numerical and experimental study on friction stir lap welding of AA6061 to high strength interstitial free coated steel sheets under different combinations of tool rotational speed and welding speed. The computed values of thermal cycle, torque and traverse force are found to be in good agreement with the corresponding experimentally measured values. The computed thermal cycles along the AA6061 to steel interfaces are related qualitatively with the experimentally measured trend and distribution in Fe-Al intermetallics along the weld joint interface.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MANEY PUBLISHING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:26:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:26:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY OF WELDING AND JOINING, 19(1)69-75</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1362-1718</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1179/1362171813Y.0000000166</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17306</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>