<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1428</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Investigation of the conductivity of Na2SO4–PbTiO3 composite electrolyte system: Non linear electrical behavior at Curie temperature of the dispersoid</dc:title><dc:creator>BOBADE, S M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KULKARNI, AR</dc:creator><dc:creator>GOPALAN, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>composite materials</dc:subject><dc:subject>ionic conductivity</dc:subject><dc:subject>sodium compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>curie temperature</dc:subject><dc:description>The effect of dielectric constant of the PbTiO3 dispersoid on the conductivity of Na2SO4 has been probed. At the Curie temperature, 490 °C, PbTiO3 undergoes ferroelectric to paraelectric phase transition followed by a sharp change in the dielectric constant. The Na2SO4–PbTiO3 composites have been prepared at two different temperatures, namely 600 and 900 °C. Compositions containing 5, 10, 20, 30, 40, 50 m% PbTiO3 have been investigated using Impedance Spectroscopy, Differential Scanning Calorimetry (DSC), X-ray diffraction (XRD) and Rietveld analysis. The series of compositions prepared at 900 °C exhibit a maxima in the conductivity for 20 m% PbTiO3. The composites prepared at 600 °C exhibit a peak in the conductivity at 20 m% PbTiO3 in addition to the percolation threshold at 40 m% PbTiO3. The enhancement in the conductivity by a factor of 40 at 300 °C has been observed for the system prepared at 600 °C while an enhancement in the conductivity by a factor of 8 at 300 °C has been observed for the system prepared at 900 °C. Further, the transition temperature of Na2SO4 remains unaltered for both series. A slight nonlinearity has been observed in the vicinity of the transition temperature of the dispersoid</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-05T04:19:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:43:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-05T04:19:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T07:43:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Solid State Ionics  178(29-30), 1585-1589</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-2738</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.ssi.2007.10.001</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1428</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>