<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14921</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:45:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>On "P" property and the column-W property</dc:title><dc:creator>PRIYADARSHAN, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>PILLAI, HK</dc:creator><dc:subject>P-matrix</dc:subject><dc:subject>Column-W property</dc:subject><dc:subject>Feedback</dc:subject><dc:subject>Well-posedness</dc:subject><dc:subject>Regularisation of linear complementarity systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Regularisation of piecewise linear systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>Separation theorem</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYBRID SYSTEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATRICES</dc:subject><dc:description>P-matrices play an important role in the well-posedness of a linear complementarity problem (LCP). Similarly, the well-posedness of a horizontal linear complementarity problem (HLCP) is closely related to the column-W property of a matrix k-tuple. In this paper we first consider the problem of generating P-matrices from a given pair of matrices. Given a matrix pair (D, F) where D is a square matrix of order m and matrix F has m rows, "what are the conditions under which there exists a matrix G such that (D + FG) is a P-matrix?". We obtain necessary and sufficient conditions for the special case when the column rank of F is m - 1. A decision algorithm of complexity O(m(2)) to check whether the given pair of matrices (D, F) is P-matrisable is obtained. We also obtain a necessary and an independent sufficient condition for the general case when rank(F) is less than m - 1. We then generalise the P-matrix generating problem to the generation of matrix k-tuples satisfying the column-W property from a given matrix (k 1)-tuple. That is, given a matrix (k + 1)-tuple (D-1,D- ... , D-k, F), where D(j)s are square matrices of order m and F is a matrix having m rows, we determine the conditions under which the matrix k-tuple (D-1 + FG(1), ... , D-k + FG(k)) satisfies the column-W property. As in the case of P-matrices we obtain necessary and sufficient conditions for the case when rank(F) = m - 1. Using these conditions a decision algorithm of complexity O(km(2)) to check whether the given matrix (k + 1)-tuple is column-W matrisable is obtained. Then for the case when rank(F) is less than m - 1, we obtain a necessary and an independent sufficient condition. For a special sub-class of P-matrices we give a polynomial time decision algorithm for P-matrisability. Finally, we obtain a geometric characterisation of column-W property by generalising the well known separation theorem for P-matrices. (C) 2011 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:45:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:45:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LINEAR ALGEBRA AND ITS APPLICATIONS, 436(7)1969-1989</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.laa.2011.10.034</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14921</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>