<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1212</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Fold-recognition and comparative modeling of human β3GalT I, II, IV, V and VI and β3GalNAcT I: prediction of residues conferring acceptor substrate specificity</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, RONAK Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>BALAJI, PETETY V</dc:creator><dc:subject>mapping</dc:subject><dc:subject>mutagenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>data acquisition</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:description>β3GalTs are type II transmembrane proteins that transfer galactose from UDP-Gal donor substrate to acceptor GlcNAc, GalNAc or Gal in β1 → 3-linkage. β1 → 3-linked galactose have been found to be a part of many glycans like glycosphingolipids, core tetrasaccharide of proteoglycans, type 1 chains. The 3-D structure of none of the β3GalTs is known to date. In this study, the 3-D structures of human β3GalT I, II, IV, V, VI and β3GalNAcT I have been modeled using fold-recognition and comparative modeling methods. Residues that constitute the UDP-Gal binding site have been predicted. The models are able to qualitatively rationalize data from the site-directed mutagenesis experiments reported in the literature. Residues likely to be involved in conferring differential acceptor substrate specificity have been predicted by a combination of specificity determining positions prediction (SDPs) and subsequent mapping on the generated 3-D models.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:40:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-23T11:40:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:25:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Journal of Molecular Graphics and Modelling 26(1), 255-268</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1093-3263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.jmgm.2006.12.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1212</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1212</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>