<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14984</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T13:17:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Esterification of fusel oil using reactive distillation - Part I: Reaction kinetics</dc:title><dc:creator>PATIDAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHAJANI, SM</dc:creator><dc:subject>Reactive distillation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Esterification</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fusel oil</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reaction kinetics</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ion exchange resins</dc:subject><dc:subject>ION-EXCHANGE-RESINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACETIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>POTENTIAL UTILIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROPYL ALCOHOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACETATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ISOBUTANOL</dc:subject><dc:description>Fusel oil is a mixture of C2-C5 alcohols such as ethanol, n-propanol, iso-butanol and iso-amyl alcohol. It is expected that reactive distillation (RD), which is a proven intensification strategy for esterification of individual alcohols can also be a promising option for simultaneous esterification of all the alcohols in fusel oil. To evaluate its feasibility and design a unit on large scale, kinetic and phase equilibrium models are necessary. In this work, we experimentally investigate reaction kinetics for all the esterification and trans-esterification reactions of the different constituents of fusel oil with acetic acid. The reactions are performed in the presence of cation exchange resin, Amberlyst-15, in a batch reactor over a wide range of parameters such as temperature, mole ratio and catalyst loading. A unified Langmuir-Hinshelwood-Hougen-Watson (LHHW) model is proposed for the reacting system consisting of all the alcohols and the experimental data is used to estimate the model parameters. The predictions are in line with the experimental data for individual alcohols as well as their mixtures. A feasible process based on reactive distillation is simulated in ASPEN PLUS using the kinetics developed in this work. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:17:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T13:17:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMICAL ENGINEERING JOURNAL, 207377-387</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2012.06.139</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14984</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>