<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18226</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T09:01:49Z</datestamp><dc:title>A New Self-Training-Based Unsupervised Satellite Image Classification Technique Using Cluster Ensemble Strategy</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BOVOLO, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BRUZZONE, L</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHAUDHURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAN, BK</dc:creator><dc:subject>REMOTE-SENSING IMAGES</dc:subject><dc:subject>Clustering</dc:subject><dc:subject>ensemble learning</dc:subject><dc:subject>image segmentation</dc:subject><dc:description>This letter addresses the problem of unsupervised land-cover classification of remotely sensed multispectral satellite images from the perspective of cluster ensembles and self-learning. The cluster ensembles combine multiple data partitions generated by different clustering algorithms into a single robust solution. A cluster-ensemble-based method is proposed here for the initialization of the unsupervised iterative expectation-maximization (EM) algorithm which eventually produces a better approximation of the cluster parameters considering a certain statistical model is followed to fit the data. The method assumes that the number of land-cover classes is known. A novel method for generating a consistent labeling scheme for each clustering of the consensus is introduced for cluster ensembles. A maximum likelihood classifier is henceforth trained on the updated parameter set obtained from the EM step and is further used to classify the rest of the image pixels. The self-learning classifier, although trained without any external supervision, reduces the effect of data overlapping from different clusters which otherwise a single clustering algorithm fails to identify. The clustering performance of the proposed method on a medium resolution and a very high spatial resolution image have effectively outperformed the results of the individual clustering of the ensemble.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:01:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T09:01:49Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE GEOSCIENCE AND REMOTE SENSING LETTERS, 12(4)741-745</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1545-598X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1558-0571</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/LGRS.2014.2360833</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18226</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>