<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1885</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Structural changes In Nickel Nanaorods encapsulated In Carbon Nanotubes By 200 KV electron irradiation In TEM</dc:title><dc:creator>KULSHRESTHA, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>HAZRA, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>ROY, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAJPAI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOHAPATRA, DR</dc:creator><dc:creator>MISRA, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>magnetic-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanoparticles</dc:subject><dc:subject>tips</dc:subject><dc:subject>carbon nanotubes</dc:subject><dc:subject>electroplating</dc:subject><dc:subject>ni nanorods</dc:subject><dc:subject>electron irradiation</dc:subject><dc:description>Nickel nanorods encapsulated inside multiwalled carbon nanotubes were synthesized using microwave plasma chemical vapor deposition (MPCVD) technique. HRTEM study of these tubes exhibits long, good crystalline nickel filled CNTs with well-graphitized walls. Different orientations of filled metal with respect to graphitic walls have been observed and the orientations were found to get affected by the electron accelerating voltages of 200 KV. We report that by deliberate e-irradiation at specific sites the crystalline planes of nickel can change their orientation. With continuous irradiation for 10-15 minutes the nickel starts evolving out of the tube. We propose that metal at the tip of the tube may be exposed by employing e-beam irradiation and it may be useful to study the true electrical properties of both the multiwalled carbon nanotubes and Ni nanorod inside the tube.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:33:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:33:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PHYSICS OF EMERGING FUNCTIONAL MATERIALS (PEFM-2010),1313,259-261</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-0-7354-0868-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0094-243X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15130</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1885</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Physics of Emerging Functional Materials,Mumbai, INDIA,SEP 22-24, 2010</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>