<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13981</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:55:02Z</datestamp><dc:title>Geospatial contour mapping of shear wave velocity for Mumbai city</dc:title><dc:creator>MHASKE, SY</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>PSEUDODYNAMIC METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>RETAINING WALL</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEISMIC DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>LIQUEFACTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROZONATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>EARTHQUAKE</dc:subject><dc:subject>STABILITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>REGION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DELHI</dc:subject><dc:subject>GIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Geospatial contour map</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shear wave velocity</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPT 'N' value</dc:subject><dc:description>Shear wave velocity is one of the most important input parameter in the analysis of geotechnical earthquake engineering problems, particularly to estimate site-specific amplification factor and ground response study. Dynamic in situ tests such as spectral analysis of surface waves (SASW) or multichannel analysis of surface waves (MASW) are very expensive. Also due to lack of specialized personnel, these tests are generally avoided in many soil investigation programs. Worldwide, several researchers have developed correlations between the SPT 'N' value and shear wave velocity 'V (s)', which are useful for determining the dynamic soil properties. In the present study, more than 400 numbers of soil borehole data were collected from various geotechnical investigation agencies, government engineering institutes and geotechnical laboratories from different parts of Mumbai city, which is financial capital of India with highest population density. In this paper, an attempt has been made to develop the correlation between the SPT 'N' value and shear wave velocity 'V (s)' for various soil profile of Mumbai city and compared with other existing correlations for different cities in India. Using Geographical Information System (GIS), a geospatial contour map of shear wave velocity profile for Mumbai city is prepared with contour intervals of 25 and 50 m/s. The scarcity of database or maps of shear wave velocity profile for Mumbai city will make the present geospatial contour maps extremely useful and beneficial to the designer, practitioners for seismic hazard study involved in geotechnical earthquake engineering.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:55:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:55:02Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NATURAL HAZARDS,59(1)317-327</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-030X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-011-9758-z</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13981</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>