<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-580</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:53Z</datestamp><dc:title>Forward body-biased single halo MOS devices for low voltage analog circuits</dc:title><dc:creator>NARASIMHULU, K</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMGOPAL RAO, V</dc:creator><dc:subject>semiconductor doping</dc:subject><dc:subject>threshold voltage</dc:subject><dc:subject>analog computers</dc:subject><dc:subject>sensitivity analysis</dc:subject><dc:description>Forward body bias has been shown to be an effective way to improve the digital performance of CMOS circuits. However, as the technologies scale into the sub 100 nm regime, body bias sensitivity degrades, making the application of body bias less attractive for scaled CMOS technologies. In this work, we show for the first time that, Single Halo (SH) MOSFETS exhibit superior body bias sensitivity in the sub 100 nm regime compared to conventional technologies, which can be utilized for improving the performance of forward body-biased MOS devices such as dynamic threshold (DTMOS) and body-driven (BDMOS) transistors for low-voltage (LV) analog designs with the scaled technologies. Our result show that SH doping in these devices results in more than 50 % improvement of intrinsic gain and about a factor of two improvement in transconductance for DTMOS and BDMOS devices respectively, compared to their conventional counterparts.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-01-22T05:57:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:15:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-01-22T05:57:55Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T07:15:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on Simulation of Semiconductor Processes and Devices, Tokyo, Japan,  1-3 September 2005, 255-258</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>4-9902762-0-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/580</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/580</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>