<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4155</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Very Strongly Ferromagnetically Coupled Diradicals from Mixed Radical Centers: Nitronyl Nitroxide Coupled to Oxoverdazyl via Polyene Spacers</dc:title><dc:creator>LATIF, IA</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DATTA, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>density-functional theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>transition-metal-complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>broken symmetry approach</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic-properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>exchange interactions</dc:subject><dc:subject>ab-initio</dc:subject><dc:subject>electronic-structure</dc:subject><dc:subject>verdazyl diradicals</dc:subject><dc:subject>organic radicals</dc:subject><dc:subject>mo calculations</dc:subject><dc:description>We predict extremely large and positive intramolecular magnetic exchange coupling constants (J) for coupled diradicals constructed from nitronyl nitroxide (NN) and oxoverdazyl (o-VER). These radicals have the general formula o-VER(N)-nC-NN where nC represents an olefinic spacer with n = 0, 2, 4, 6, and 8. Species like o-VER(C)-nC-NN have negative coupling constants. The atoms in the parentheses show the point of attachment of the coupler to the verdazyl moiety. Both the N-linked series and C-linked series have comparable stability. The triplet molecular geometries were optimized by the density functional (UB3LYP) method using the 6-311 g(d,p) basis set. This was followed by single-point UB3LYP calculations using 6-311++g(3df,3pd) basis. To calculate J, single-point broken-symmetry computations were performed on the optimized triplet geometries and using the same basis set. The N-linked diradicals coupled through conjugated polyenes are topologically different. These are found to have coupling constants of the order of 1000 cm(-1), whereas the C-linked diradicals show coupling constants of the order of -100 cm(-1). In general, for both cases, the absolute magnitude of the coupling constant decreases with the increase in the length of the spacer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-15T04:37:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-15T04:37:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:15Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF PHYSICAL CHEMISTRY A, 113(8), 1595-1600</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1089-5639</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/jp808314u</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4155</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4155</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>