<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14741</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T10:25:54Z</datestamp><dc:title>Methodology for indirect determination of air and flue-gas leakage in a typical glass furnace in India</dc:title><dc:creator>SARDESHPANDE, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>GAITONDE, UN</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANERJEE, R</dc:creator><dc:description>A methodology is proposed for quantification of the air leakage in a typical glass furnace in India based on modelled and measured parameters. Fossil fuels (natural gas or heavy fuel oil) are used for glass melting at high temperature in these furnaces which are usually equipped with regenerators for waste heat recovery. The combustion chamber is maintained at a mean positive pressure of 0.2 to 1 mm H2O to avoid leakage of cold air into the combustion chamber, but there are leakages due to local interactions, leading to higher fuel consumption. The quantification of air leakage helps in controlling the leakage thus improving fuel economy. The flue gas composition is estimated by mass balance of a furnace based on stoichiometric reactions for combustion and glass melting. The quantity of air leakage is estimated based on gaps inside the furnace wall and the differential pressure. The methodology is used for an industrial furnace where air leakage of 3.1% of combustion air flow and flue gas leakage of 2.6% of total flue gas flow was estimated. The estimated combustion air flow based on stoichiometric reactions is validated with experimental data.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC GLASS TECHNOLOGY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:25:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T10:25:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GLASS TECHNOLOGY-EUROPEAN JOURNAL OF GLASS SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY PART A, 54(6)233-241</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1753-3546</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1753-3554</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14741</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>