<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9301</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:45Z</datestamp><dc:title>Boundary Layer Control with a moving belt system for studies on Wing-in-Ground-Effect</dc:title><dc:creator>AHMED, MR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIROGANE, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>KOHAMA, Y</dc:creator><dc:subject>boundary layer control</dc:subject><dc:subject>aerodynamics</dc:subject><dc:subject>tandem wings</dc:subject><dc:subject>ground effect</dc:subject><dc:subject>lift</dc:subject><dc:subject>drag</dc:subject><dc:description>Results from studies on the performance of a moving belt system are presented. Velocity measurements were performed above the moving belt with a hot-wire anemometer at a free-stream velocity of 15 m/s. The belt speed was same as the freestream velocity. Boundary layer suction was applied upstream of the moving belt to obtain a uniform free-stream It is found that with the help of moving belt system, it is possible to minimize the growth of boundary layer, The boundary layer grew by only 1 mm over a distance of 700 mm. Such a system is highly desirable for studies on ground effect aerodynamics. Measurements of lift and drag forces are performed on a tandem wing configuration in ground effect using the system with and without the belt moving. Influence of angles of attack for the wings on the aerodynamic characteristics of a tandem wing configuration with a variable distance between them is also studied for the two cases, with a very small ground clearance.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JAPAN SOC MECHANICAL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-04T08:36:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-04T08:36:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>1999</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JSME INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL SERIES B-FLUIDS AND THERMAL ENGINEERING, 42(4), 619-625</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1340-8054</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9301</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9301</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>