<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17157</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:09:33Z</datestamp><dc:title>Characterization of the full cone pressure swirl spray nozzles for the nuclear reactor containment spray system</dc:title><dc:creator>JAIN, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOHN, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>IYER, KN</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>DISCHARGE COEFFICIENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DROPLET SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ATOMIZERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT</dc:subject><dc:description>The objective of the present study is to characterize a full cone pressure swirl nozzle for the Containment Spray System (CSS) of Indian Pressurized heavy Water reactors (IPHWR). The influence of Reynolds number and geometric parameters on the coefficient of discharge, spray cone angle, mass flux density distribution, droplet size distribution, Sauter mean diameter (SMD is studied for full cone pressure swirl full cone nozzles. The nozzles of orifice diameter range from 1.3 to 7.2 mm are studied. Experiments are conducted with water at room temperature as the working medium. The nozzles are operated with the pressure ranging from I to 8 bar. The measurements of the drop size distributions are performed with laser illuminated imaging technique. The spray cone-angle of the full cone nozzles is measured by the evaluation of images recorded with a camera using IMAGE J software. Correlations for coefficient of discharge, spray cone angle and Sauter mean diameter are suggested on the basis of the experimental results. Rosin-Rammler model and Nukiyama-Tanasawa distributions predict the mass fraction distribution reasonably well. However, the droplet size distribution is predicted by Nukiyama-Tanasawa model only. (c) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:09:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:09:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR ENGINEERING AND DESIGN, 273131-142</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5493</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.nucengdes.2014.02.025</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17157</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>