<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-18171</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T08:31:48Z</datestamp><dc:title>Edge configurational effect on band gaps in graphene nanoribbons</dc:title><dc:creator>DEEPIKA</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, TJD</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHUKLA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>EPITAXIAL GRAPHENE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RIBBONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEMICONDUCTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SURFACES</dc:subject><dc:description>In this article, we put forward a resolution to the prolonged ambiguity in energy band gaps between theory and experiments of fabricated graphene nanoribbons (GNRs). Band structure calculations using density functional theory are performed on oxygen-passivated GNR supercells of customized edge configurations without disturbing the inherent sp(2) hybridization of carbon atoms. Direct band gaps are observed for both zigzag and armchair GNRs, consistent with the experimental reports. In addition, we provide an explanation of the experimentally observed scattered band gap values of GNRs as a function of width in a crystallographic orientation on the basis of edge configurations. We conclude that edge configurations of GNRs significantly contribute to band gap formation in addition to its width for a given crystallographic orientation and will play a crucial role in band gap engineering of GNRs for future research on fabrication of nanoelectronic devices.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:31:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T08:31:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW B, 91(11)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1098-0121</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1550-235X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevB.91.115428</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/18171</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>