<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12059</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of Policies Derived from Stochastic Dynamic Programming and Genetic Algorithm Models</dc:title><dc:creator>JOTHIPRAKASH, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANTHI, G</dc:creator><dc:subject>reservoir-system operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>multireservoir systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>management</dc:subject><dc:subject>stochastic dynamic programming</dc:subject><dc:subject>genetic algorithm</dc:subject><dc:subject>multi-purpose reservoir operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>synthetic stream flow generation</dc:subject><dc:description>A comprehensive Genetic Algorithm (GA) model has been developed and applied to derive optimal operational strategies of a multi-purpose reservoir, namely Perunchani Reservoir, in Kodaiyar Basin in Tamil Nadu, India. Most of the water resources problem involves uncertainty, in order to see that the GA model takes care of uncertainty in the input variable, the result of the GA model is compared with the performance of a detailed Stochastic Dynamic Programming (SDP) model. The SDP models are well established and proved that it takes care of uncertainty in-terms of either implicit or explicit approach. In the present study, the objective function of the models is set to minimize the annual sum of squared deviation from desired target release and desired storage volume. In the SDP model the optimal policies are derived by varying the state variables from 3 to 9 representative class intervals, and then the cases are evaluated for their performance using a simulation model for longer length of inflow data, generated using a Thomas-Fiering model. From the performance of the SDP model policies, it is found that the system encountered irrigation deficit, whereas GA model satisfied the demand to a greater extent. The sensitivity analysis of the GA model in selecting optimal population, optimal crossover probability and the optimal number of generations showed the values of 150, 0.76 and 175 respectively. On comparing the performance of SDP model policy with GA model, it is found that GA model has resulted in a lesser irrigation deficit. Thus based on the present case study, it may be concluded that the GA model performs better than the SDP model.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T10:49:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>WATER RESOURCES MANAGEMENT, 23(8), 1563-1580</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0920-4741</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11269-008-9341-x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12059</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12059</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>