<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1563</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:04Z</datestamp><dc:title>Kinetic and equilibrium studies on the biosorption of reactive black 5 dye by aspergillus foetidus</dc:title><dc:creator>PATEL, RACHNA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, SUMATHI</dc:creator><dc:subject>adsorbents</dc:subject><dc:subject>azo dyes</dc:subject><dc:subject>biomass</dc:subject><dc:subject>biosorption</dc:subject><dc:subject>concentration</dc:subject><dc:subject>fungi</dc:subject><dc:subject>reaction kinetics</dc:subject><dc:description>An isolated fungus, Aspergillus foetidus had the ability to decolourize growth unsupportive medium containing 100 mg L−1 of reactive black 5 (RB5) dye with &gt;99% efficiency at acidic pH (2–3). Pre-treatment of fungal biomass by autoclaving or exposure to 0.1 M sodium hydroxide facilitated more efficient uptake of dye as compared to untreated fungal biomass. Pre-equilibrium biosorption of RB5 dye onto fungus under different temperatures followed pseudo-second-order kinetic model with high degree of correlation coefficients (R2 &gt; 0.99). Biosorption isotherm data fitted better into Freundlich model for lower concentrations of dye probably suggesting the heterogeneous nature of sorption process. Based on the Langmuir isotherm plots the maximum biosorption capacity (Q0) value was calculated to be 106 mg g−1 at 50 °C for fungal biomass pre-treated with 0.1 M NaOH. Thermodynamic studies revealed that the biosorption process was favourable, spontaneous and endothermic in nature. Recovery of both adsorbate (dye) and adsorbent (fungal biomass) was possible using sodium hydroxide. Recovered fungal biomass could be recycled number of times following desorption of dye using 0.1 M NaOH. Fungal biomass pre-treated with NaOH was efficient in decolourizing solution containing mixture of dyes as well as composite raw industrial effluent generated from leather, pharmaceutical and dye manufacturing company.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-06-22T05:29:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:03:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-06-22T05:29:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T08:03:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:02:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Bioresource Technology 99(1), 51-58</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0960-8524</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.biortech.2006.12.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1563</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1563</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>