<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14012</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T06:10:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Applying mechanistic models to reliability evaluation of mechanical components - An illustration</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, MH</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, GR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVIDYA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>VERMA, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>Mechanistic models</dc:subject><dc:subject>Failure modes</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORM</dc:subject><dc:subject>SORM</dc:subject><dc:description>The traditional reliability analyses, considers components to be in binary state, either functional or faulty, and does not consider the concept of multi state or intermediate states between these two binary states. However, there are several components, which need to be operated in different states and their failure criterion also depend on these states. Hence, when dealing with these types of components one should use multi state concept. This can be achieved by modeling the components with mechanistic models, which can give a new dimension for reliability analysis for multiple states. The mechanistic model approach is based on the first principles of science and engineering which provides details about the various failure mechanisms and thereby improved understanding of the associated root causes of the failure and driving forces responsible for component failures. In this paper a general methodology for modeling the components with mechanistic models has been explained and is further illustrated with an example component. A case study on feed water system (consisting of control valves and other mechanical components) of a typical nuclear reactor has been presented. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T06:10:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANNALS OF NUCLEAR ENERGY,38(7)1447-1451</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0306-4549</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.anucene.2011.04.011</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14012</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>