<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17784</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:41:52Z</datestamp><dc:title>Microstructure and mechanical behavior of annealed MP35N alloy wire</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASAD, MJNV</dc:creator><dc:creator>REITERER, MW</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, KS</dc:creator><dc:subject>FCC METALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>NICKEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>TWINS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Annealed</dc:subject><dc:subject>Recrystallized</dc:subject><dc:subject>Alloy wire</dc:subject><dc:subject>Medical devices</dc:subject><dc:subject>Yield strength</dc:subject><dc:subject>Fatigue life</dc:subject><dc:description>In a previous paper, the microstructure, monotonic, and cyclic response of as-drawn similar to 100 pm diameter MP35N low-Ti alloy wire were presented and discussed. In this sequel paper, the effects of annealing the same cold-drawn wire on microstructure and mechanical properties are examined. Specifically, segments of the wire were annealed for 1 h at 973 K, 1023 K, 1073 K, 1123 K and 1173 K in a vacuum furnace. The resulting microstructure was characterized by SEM, EBSD and TEM and compared to the asdrawn microstructure. In-situ heating in the TEM of MP35N ribbon in a similarly cold worked condition enabled corroboration of microstructure evolution during annealing. Annealed wires were tested monotonically and cyclically in uniaxial tension at room temperature, the latter using a stress ratio (R) of 0.3. In addition, the annealed wires were tested cyclically at R= -1 using the rotating beam bending fatigue test. Post-deformation structures and fracture surfaces were characterized using TEM and SEM respectively. Annealing the cold drawn wire results in recrystallization and grain growth; the extent is dependent on the annealing temperature. Deformation twin boundaries in the as-drawn structure illustrate faceted bulging and eventually complete elimination, the microstructure evolving into fine equiaxed grains containing coarser annealing twins with no significant change in texture. Yield strength decreases rapidly with recrystallization to almost half the value of the as-drawn condition, but is accompanied by an increase in modulus (by similar to 25%) and tensile elongation reaching 30%. Cyclic response by the way of S-N curves is not enhanced by annealing on an absolute stress scale (due to the loss in yield strength) although the annealed wires are cyclically superior when the stress data are normalized by yield stress. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:41:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:41:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING, 636,340-351</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2015.03.103</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17784</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>