<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1889</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Constant-factor approximation algorithms for domination problems on circle graphs</dc:title><dc:creator>DAMIAN-IORDACHE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PEMMARAJU, SV</dc:creator><dc:description>A graph G = (V, E) is called a circle graph if there is a one- to-one correspondence between vertices in V and a set C of chords in a circle such that two vertices in V are adjacent if and only if the corresponding chords in C intersect. A subset V' of V is a dominating set of G if for all u is an element of V either u is an element of V' or u has a neighbor in V'. In addition, if G[V'] is connected, then V' is called a connected dominating set; if G[V'] has no isolated vertices, then V' is called a total dominating set. Keil (Discrete Applied Mathematics, 42 (1993), 51-63) shows that the minimum dominating set problem (MDS), the minimum connected dominating set problem (MCDS) and the minimum total domination problem (MTDS) are all NP-complete even for circle graphs. He mentions designing approximation algorithms for these problems as being open. This paper presents O(1)-approximation algorithms for all three problems - MDS, MCDS, and MTDS on circle graphs. For any circle graph with n vertices and m edges, these algorithms take O(n(2) + nm) time and O(n(2)) space. These results, along with the result on the hardness of approximating minimum independent dominating set on circle graphs (Damian-Iordache and Pemmaraju, in this proceedings) advance our understanding of domination problems on circle graphs significantly.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T12:53:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>ALGORITHMS AND COMPUTATIONS,1741,70-82</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>3-540-66916-7</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0302-9743</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15134</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1889</dc:identifier><dc:source>10th Annual International Symposium on Algorithms and Computation (ISAAC 99),CHENNAI, INDIA,DEC 16-18, 1999</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>