<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-1793</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:11:00Z</datestamp><dc:title>Determination of anomalous elastic-scattering of gamma-rays of energies close to K-shell binding thresholds</dc:title><dc:creator>BASAVARAJU, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>KANE, PP</dc:creator><dc:description>Anomalous'' scattering corrections to Rayleigh scattering amplitudes calculated in the form factor approximation are of considerable interest in the study of elastic-scattering of gamma-rays and X-rays. When photon energies are close to binding energies of atomic inner shell electrons, the corrections have relatively large magnitudes. But under such conditions, the comparatively weak elastic-scattering contribution cannot be resolved even with semiconductor detectors from most of the components of target K beta(2)' X-rays. It is shown that elastic-scattering in such an interesting energy regime can be determined with the help of a least-squares-fitting procedure for the composite spectrum. The procedure is illustrated with a detailed study of 81.0 keV gamma-ray scattering from gold having a K shell binding energy of 80.723 keV. Data were obtained at several angles with gold and other targets of different atomic number Z.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-23T04:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-23T04:47:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:11:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>1994</dc:date><dc:type>Article; Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NUCLEAR INSTRUMENTS &amp; METHODS IN PHYSICS RESEARCH SECTION A-ACCELERATORS SPECTROMETERS DETECTORS AND ASSOCIATED EQUIPMENT,353,209-211</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0168-9002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/0168-9002(94)91639-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/15042</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/1793</dc:identifier><dc:source>8th Symposium on Radiation Measurements and Applications,ANN ARBOR, MI,MAY 16-19, 1994</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>