<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16551</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:35:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Optimization of a plasma immersion ion implantation process for shallow junctions in silicon</dc:title><dc:creator>RAY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>NORI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATT, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>LODHA, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>PINTO, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>JOMARD, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>NEUMANN-SPALLART, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ENERGY-DISTRIBUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISCHARGE</dc:subject><dc:description>A plasma immersion ion implantation (PIII) process has been developed for realizing shallow doping profiles of phosphorus and boron in silicon using an in-house built dual chamber cluster tool. High Si etch rates observed in a 5% PH3 in H-2 plasma have been ascribed to high concentration of H(alpha) radicals. Therefore, subsequent work was carried out with 5% PH3 in He, leading to much smaller etch rates. By optical emission spectroscopy, the radical species H(alpha), PH*(2), and PH* have been identified. The concentration of all three species increased with pressure. Also, ion concentrations increased with pressure as evidenced by Langmuir data, with a maximum occurring at 0.12 mbar. The duty cycle of pulsed DC bias has a significant bearing on both the implantation and the etching process as it controls the leakage of positive charge collected at the surface of the silicon wafer during pulse on-time generated primarily due to secondary electron emission. The P implant process was optimized for a duty cycle of 10% or less at a pressure of 0.12 mbar with implant times as low as 30 s. Secondary ion mass spectroscopy showed a P dopant depth of 145 nm after rapid thermal annealing (RTA) at 950 degrees C for 5 s, resulting in a sheet resistance of 77 Omega/square. Si n(+)/p diodes fabricated with phosphorus implantation using optimized PIII and RTA conditions exhibit J(on)/J(off) &gt; 10(6) with an ideality factor of nearly 1.2. Using similar conditions, shallow doping profiles of B in silicon have also been realized. (C) 2014 American Vacuum Society.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A V S AMER INST PHYSICS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:35:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:35:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VACUUM SCIENCE &amp; TECHNOLOGY A, 32(6)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0734-2101</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-8559</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1116/1.4896756</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16551</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>