<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2781</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparison of aquifer parameters with lineaments derived from remotely sensed data in Kinzig basin, Germany</dc:title><dc:creator>ANBAZHAGAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>ASCHENBRENNER, F</dc:creator><dc:creator>KNOBLICH, K</dc:creator><dc:description>Lineaments interpreted from aerial photographs and satellite imagery plays a crucial role in various geological applications like groundwater exploration, artificial recharge, mineral exploration, seismic studies, landslide mitigation etc. Since, it invariably indicates the weathered and fractured subsurface condition and increased permeability, lineaments have been widely applied in the field of groundwater exploration. However, only limited studies have been conducted in the view of hydrogeological significance by comparing aquifer parameters with lineaments. Comparison of lineaments with various aquifer parameters like well yield and transmissivity is necessary for development of confident measures in groundwater exploration. Kinzig basin falls in 'Main' river system in Germany was taken for this lineament validation study. The minor and major lineaments were interpreted from aerial photographs and Landsat Thematic Mapper satellite data. The aquifer parameters were correlated with the lineaments through overlaying technique available in ILWIS GIS software. The results have shown good correlation with different aquifer parameters.</dc:description><dc:publisher>A A BALKEMA PUBLISHERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T00:14:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T00:14:57Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2001</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>NEW APPROACHES CHARACTERIZING GROUNDWATER FLOW, VOLS 1 AND 2,883-886</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>90-2651-848-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16176</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2781</dc:identifier><dc:source>31st International-Association-of-Hydrogeologists Congress,MUNICH, GERMANY,SEP 10-14, 2001</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>