<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15612</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:01:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of Sensitivity of Equilibrium Constant to Reaction Conditions for Esterification of Fatty Acids with Alcohols</dc:title><dc:creator>HASSAN, SZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>VINJAMUR, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>ION-EXCHANGE-RESIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>CURCAS L. OIL</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACETIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>OLEIC-ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIODIESEL PRODUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>PALMITIC ACID</dc:subject><dc:subject>KINETICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATALYST</dc:subject><dc:subject>METHANOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>ETHANOL</dc:subject><dc:description>The equilibrium constant (K-eq) depends on temperature only, but reported measurements for esterification reactions show that it also depends on reactant concentration and amount of catalyst. In this work, analysis of sensitivity of K-eq to errors in equilibrium composition of esterification reactions at different reaction conditions is presented. Rigorous error and Taguchi analyses showed that K-eq is indeed a function of temperature only and not of molar ratio (MR) of the reactants and catalyst loading; reported dependency of K-eq on reactants concentrations and catalyst loadings is due to errors in analysis of equilibrium composition. Sensitivity of K-eq to these errors depends strongly on molar ratio (MR), and calculations show that K-eq is least sensitive to error at 1.5 MR. However, phase separation of the reaction mixture is possible at 1.5 MR which can cause errors in measured equilibrium composition. K-eq of esterification reactions should be obtained through kinetic data fitting to the rate model. For sulfuric acid-catalyzed esterification of oleic acid with methanol, a single K-eq value for each reaction temperature is obtained through kinetics data fitting as 1.53 (+/-0.05), 1.67 (+/-0.04), and 1.91 (+/-0.06) at 313, 323, and 338 K, respectively. Equilibrium compositions are calculated reasonably well with these K-eq values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:01:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:01:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 52(3)1205-1215</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-5045</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie301881g</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15612</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>