<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-302</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:57:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Cross layer routing for multihop cellular networks</dc:title><dc:creator>KANNAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>wireless networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>constraint theory</dc:subject><dc:subject>radio interference</dc:subject><dc:description>We propose a unified cross layer routing protocol with multiple constraints for CDMA multihop cellular networks (MCN). Multiple constraints are imposed on intermediate relay node selection and source to destination path selection. The relay node constraints for routing protocol design are cooperation, interference caused to other nodes and sufficient neighborhood connectivity. Path constraints for routing are end-to-end throughput and end-to-end delay. We do not assume full cooperation for call forwarding and present a facile incentive mechanism to motivate the cooperation for call forwarding. We incorporate a realistic mobility model and dynamic call dropping notion in our system. Flat fading i.i.d Rayleigh channel is assumed between mobile nodes. Simulation results show that the proposed algorithm reduces intracell interference by more than 70% as compared to nearest neighbour routing algorithm. Furthermore, the proposed algorithm achieves better throughput and maintains the delay at tolerable level. We also demonstrate that the proposed routing algorithm is superior to many standard routing protocols.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-12T04:44:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:36:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-12T04:44:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:36:45Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications Workshops (V 2), Niagara Falls, Canada, 21-23 May 2007, 165-170</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-2847-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/AINAW.2007.139</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/302</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/302</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>