<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15463</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T06:43:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Electrical actuation and readout in a nanoelectromechanical resonator based on a laterally suspended zinc oxide nanowire</dc:title><dc:creator>KHADERBAD, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOI, Y</dc:creator><dc:creator>HIRALAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>AZIZ, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, N</dc:creator><dc:creator>DURKAN, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>THIRUVENKATANATHAN, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>AMARATUNGA, GAJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SESHIA, AA</dc:creator><dc:subject>FIELD-EFFECT TRANSISTORS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZNO NANOWIRE</dc:subject><dc:subject>ARRAYS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE</dc:subject><dc:subject>FILM</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, we present experimental results describing enhanced readout of the vibratory response of a doubly clamped zinc oxide (ZnO) nanowire employing a purely electrical actuation and detection scheme. The measured response suggests that the piezoelectric and semiconducting properties of ZnO effectively enhance the motional current for electromechanical transduction. For a doubly clamped ZnO nanowire resonator with radius similar to 10 nm and length similar to 1.91 mu m, a resonant frequency around 21.4 MHz is observed with a quality factor (Q) of similar to 358 in vacuum. A comparison with the Q obtained in air (similar to 242) shows that these nano-scale devices may be operated in fluid as viscous damping is less significant at these length scales. Additionally, the suspended nanowire bridges show field effect transistor (FET) characteristics when the underlying silicon substrate is used as a gate electrode or using a lithographically patterned in-plane gate electrode. Moreover, the Young's modulus of ZnO nanowires is extracted from a static bending test performed on a nanowire cantilever using an AFM and the value is compared to that obtained from resonant frequency measurements of electrically addressed clamped-clamped beam nanowire resonators.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:43:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T06:43:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>NANOTECHNOLOGY, 23(2)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/23/2/025501</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15463</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>