<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1665</identifier><datestamp>2013-11-26T05:29:59Z</datestamp><dc:title>A CAVALIER architecture for metro Data Center Networking</dc:title><dc:creator>LODHA, AKHIL</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUMASTE, ASHWIN</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, JIANPING</dc:creator><dc:creator>GHANI, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>metropolitan area networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>multicast communication</dc:subject><dc:subject>optical fibre networks</dc:subject><dc:description>Data Center Networking (DCNs) is a fast emerging enterprise application that is driving metropolitan bandwidth needs. This paper evaluates the needs of this emerging IT-centric, bandwidth voluminous and service rendering application from a metro optical networking perspective. We identify a set of needs called CAVALIER (Consolidation, Automation, Virtualization, Adaptability, Latency, Integration, Economy and Reliability) that are underlying requirements for a network to support DCN services. The CAVALIER requirements are met by proposing a metro optical solution which is based on light-trail ROADM technology. Light-trails exhibit properties such as dynamic bandwidth provisioning, optical multicasting, sub-wavelength granular support and low-cost for deployment. Adapting light-trails to DCN needs is discussed in this paper through engineering requirements and network-wide design. Each aspect of the CAVALIER requirement is then mapped on to light-trail technology. Simulation results are shown to lead to performance betterments.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-09-24T07:22:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:57:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-09-24T07:22:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-28T08:57:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:57:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the Fifthth International Conference on Broadband Communications, Networks and Systems, London, UK, 8-11 September 2008, 169-174</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2391-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/BROADNETS.2008.4769063</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1665</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1665</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>