<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-384</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:58:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>FPGA implementation of QFT based controller for a buck type DC-DC power converter and comparison with fractional and integral order PID controllers</dc:title><dc:creator>JAYAKRISHNA, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGARWAL, VIVEK</dc:creator><dc:subject>computational methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>two term control systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>power converters</dc:subject><dc:subject>electric power measurement</dc:subject><dc:description>This paper presents the details of FPGA (Field Programmable Gate Array) implementation of a QFT based controller for a buck type dc-dc power converter. The performance of QFT controller is compared with PID and fractional order PID controllers. Computer simulations of the QFT based approach as well as integral order and fractional order PID controllers have been carried out. Nominal averaged and linearized model of the converter is used for all the simulations. It is observed that the QFT based controller exhibits better transient performance and higher stability against line voltage and load variations compared to the PID controllers. The QFT controller is implemented using a SPARTAN-3 FPGA board consisting of 400K gates. All the analytical, simulation and hardware results are included and discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-18T04:48:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T15:19:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-18T04:48:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T15:19:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:58:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the 11th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics, Zurich, Switzerland, 17-20 August 2008, 1-6</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>978-1-4244-2550-1</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/COMPEL.2008.4634689</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/384</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/384</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>