<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17649</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T13:45:41Z</datestamp><dc:title>Proper cavity shape can mitigate confinement effect in synthetic jet impingement cooling</dc:title><dc:creator>BHAPKAR, US</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>HEAT-TRANSFER CHARACTERISTICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLAT-PLATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AIR-JETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ACTUATOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>DRIVEN</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>Orifice cavity</dc:subject><dc:subject>Confinement</dc:subject><dc:subject>Resonance frequency</dc:subject><dc:subject>Synthetic jet</dc:subject><dc:description>Experimental study was conducted to investigate the effect of orifice cavity shape on resonance frequency and heat transfer characteristics of synthetic jets. The main purpose of the study is to characterise the effect of orifice cavity shapes at small jet-to-surface spacings. The velocity measurement results show that the resonance frequency is a weak function of cavity volume as the resonance frequency remains same for all the cavity shapes considered in the present study. It is noticed that approximately the same pressure is generated inside different orifice cavities at a given radial location of the orifice cavity. The results of heat transfer experiments reveal that the orifice cavity confinement plays a major role at smaller jet-to-surface spacings. The heat transfer enhancement at lower jet-to-surface spacings for orifice cavity with least confinement is three times higher as compared with that of orifice cavity with maximum confinement. At higher jet-to-surface spacings, the confinement effect is negligible and maximum heat transfer enhancement is obtained for all the orifice cavities irrespective of their shape. The application of optimum orifice cavity shape can overcome the limitation of degradation of performance of synthetic jet at lower jet-to-surface spacings. The results of the present study are important as it identifies the region (z/d&lt; 2) within which the orifice cavity shape plays key role in improving the heat transfer enhancement with synthetic jets. In this region cavity air temperature is more relevant from design point of view. Beyond zld&gt; 2, the effect of orifice cavity shape is negligible. These results are important from practical point of view as it shows the strong impact of the orifice cavity confinement at lower jet-to-surface spacings on heat transfer enhancement. With selection of proper orifice cavity shape the drawback of poor performance of synthetic jet at lower jet-to-surface spacings can be overcome. (C) 2015 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:45:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T13:45:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTAL THERMAL AND FLUID SCIENCE, 68,392-401</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0894-1777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1879-2286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2015.05.006</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17649</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>