<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17267</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T06:05:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>Auxiliary ligand-aided tuning of aggregation of transition metal benzoates: isolation of four different types of coordination polymers</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJAKANNU, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>BUTCHER, RJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUGAVEL, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>SECONDARY BUILDING UNITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RAY CRYSTAL-STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ORGANIC FRAMEWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRAL CHARACTERIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRUCTURAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>COPPER(II) COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>MAGNETIC-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDRATED POLYMORPH</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDROGEN STORAGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>1,10-PHENANTHROLINE</dc:subject><dc:description>Reactions of alkyl-substituted aromatic monocarboxylic acids with first-row transition metal ions in the presence of chelating and bridging N, N-donor ligands produce a variety of discrete and polymeric complexes, depending on the position of the substituent on benzoic acid and the ability of the auxiliary ligand to act as a chelating or a bridging ligand. The eleven different compounds isolated in the present study fall into two different structural types, viz., discrete mono or/dinuclear complexes ([Cu(L-1)(2)(AL(1))(H2O)] (1), [Mn(L-1)(2)(AL(1))](2) (2) and [Zn(L-1)(2)(AL(1))](2) (3)) and polymeric compounds (4-11). The polymeric compounds isolated can further be classified into four different structural types, viz., 1D helical polymers, linear 1D polymeric chains, railroad-like polymers and 2D polymeric sheets. The structure modulation is a result of the combination of the types of substituents on the aryl ring of the benzoic acid and the nature of the auxiliary ligand used. For example, when 1,10-phenanthroline was used as the auxiliary ligand and the carboxylic acid used was 4-tert-butylbenzoic acid, discrete complexes were isolated. However, for the same auxiliary ligand, when 2,4,6-trimethylbenzoic acid was used, a series of 1D helical polymers ([M(L-2)(2)(AL(1))(H2O)](n); M = Mn (4), Co (5), Cu (6), and Zn (7)) were obtained. This clearly demonstrates the ability of o, o'-disubstituted benzoic acids to form helical polymers, whereas p-substitution on the aryl ring results in discrete complexes. The reactions of metal acetates with benzoic acid in the presence of 4,4'-bipyridine were found to be sensitive to the ortho substituents on the acid. When two equivalents of 2,4,6-triisopropylbenzoic acid were used, a linear polymer ([Zn(L-3)(2)(AL(2))](n) (8)) was obtained. The use of either one or two equivalents of 2,4,6-trimethyl benzoic acid invariably leads to the isolation of railroad-like polymers ([M(L-2)(OAc)(AL(2))](n); M = Mn (9) and Zn (10)) where the rails are bridged by the acetate ligand. Replacing the carboxylic acid by a phosphate diester leads to the isolation of a 2D polymer ([Zn(L-4)(2)(AL(2))](n) (11)) due to the ability of phosphate to act exclusively as a bridging ligand. In addition to extensive analytical and spectroscopic characterization of the products, the solid-state structures of all the new compounds were determined using single-crystal X-ray diffraction.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:05:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T06:05:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CRYSTENGCOMM, 16(36)8429-8441</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1466-8033</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/c4ce01043d</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17267</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>