<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-340</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:56:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>End-to-end QoS in interdomain routing</dc:title><dc:creator>NISHANT KUMAR</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARAPH, GIRISH P</dc:creator><dc:subject>internet protocols</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>quality of service</dc:subject><dc:subject>telecommunication traffic</dc:subject><dc:description>Providing end-to-end quality of service (QoS) guarantees for interdomain routing remains a challenge for next generation Internet. As various real-time, mission-critical, and bandwidth-sensitive applications are migrating to the IP networks the need for end-to-end QoS is becoming acute. Large existing base of BGP compliant networks rules out the acceptability of new routing protocol. However, inherent nature and functionality of BGP makes the QoS extensions rather difficult. The paper presents a novel approach to achieve end-to-end QoS support by proposing a new alliance network model. The most important aspect of the proposed model is its compatibility with existing BGP infrastructure, such that the traditional BGP traffic continues in a normal fashion. The alliance network sets-up interdomain paths for premium traffic that require specific QoS guarantees using interdomain MPLS tunnels with resource reservation. The alliance network provides enhanced geographical reach and market penetration for the alliance partners through premium service offerings.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2008-12-16T11:33:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T11:42:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008-12-16T11:33:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-27T11:42:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:56:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Proceedings of the International Conference on Networking and Services, Slicon Valley, CA, USA, 19-21 July 2006, 82</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7695-2622-5</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1109/ICNS.2006.45</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/340</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/340</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>