<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-843</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:54:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>A differential scanning calorimetric study on the irreversible thermal unfolding of concanavalin A</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJEE, TUHINA</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAND KISHORE</dc:creator><dc:subject>calorimetry</dc:subject><dc:subject>concanavalin a</dc:subject><dc:subject>irreversible thermal denaturation</dc:subject><dc:subject>enthalpy</dc:subject><dc:subject>activation energy</dc:subject><dc:description>A differential scanning calorimetry study on the thermal denaturation of concanavalin A at pH 5.2 where it exists in the dimeric form was carried out. The calorimetric transitions were observed to be irreversible and the transition temperature of the protein increased with increasing scan rate, indicating that the thermal denaturation process is under kinetic control. The thermal unfolding, and its scan rate dependence could be explained according to the kinetic scheme N2 →k 2U with k as first-order kinetic constant whose change with temperature is given by the Arrhenius equation. Using this model, rate constant as a function of temperature and activation energy of the process have been calculated. The average activation energy of the kinetic process using different approaches is 129±10 kJ mol−1. The differential scanning calorimetric results on transition temperatures and calorimetric enthalpies supported by intrinsic fluorescence indicate that the irreversibility in the calorimetric transitions of concanavalin A includes a combination of post-transition aggregation, chain separation and loss of cofactor.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-03-02T09:30:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:22:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-03-02T09:30:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-11-25T18:22:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:06:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:54:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Thermochimica Acta 411(2), 195-201</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0040-6031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tca.2003.08.012</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/843</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/843</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>