<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11988</identifier><datestamp>2012-02-09T21:02:19Z</datestamp><dc:title>New method for the simultaneous spectrophotometric determination of nitrate and nitrite in water samples using column preconcentration</dc:title><dc:creator>PURI, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SATAKE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>WANG, GF</dc:creator><dc:subject>flow-injection system</dc:subject><dc:subject>4-nitroaniline</dc:subject><dc:subject>reduction</dc:subject><dc:description>A column preconcentration-spectrophotometric method has been developed for the simultaneous determination of nitrate and nitrite. Nitrate is reduced to nitrite in a copper-coated cadmium column which is then treated with azo dye reagent and after a preconcentration step of the azo dye, the absorbance due to the sum of nitrite and nitrate is measured; nitrate is determined from the difference in absorbance values. The nitrite ion reacts with procaine hydrochloride in the pH range 1.0-3.0 in hydrochloric acid medium to form a diazonium cation, which is subsequently coupled with 1-naphthol-4-sulfonic acid sodium in the pH range 9.5-12.0 to form a stable azo dye to be retained on biphenyltetradecyldimethylbenzylammonium (TDBA)-Tiron material packed in a column. The solid mass is dissolved from the column with 5 ml of a final dimethylformamide (DMF) solution and the absorbance is measured at 552 nm. Various analytical parameters, such as effect of acidity (pH), flow rate, reaction time, temperature, reagent concentration and interfering species, were studied. The calibration curve was linear over the concentration range 90-1800 ng NO2-N and 67-1340 ng NO3-N in 15 ml of final aqueous solution (i.e. 6-120 ng NO2-N /ml and 4.5-90 ng NO3-N /ml in aqueous sample) and the concentration factor is 20 (ratio of maximum volume of aqueous to organic phases). The method has detection limits of 5.0 ng NO2-N /ml and 3.7 ng NO3-N /ml. The method has been successfully applied to water samples.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SOC CHIMICA ITALIANA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:07:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T06:07:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ANNALI DI CHIMICA, 88(9-10), 685-695</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0003-4592</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11988</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11988</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>