<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-11803</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:47:36Z</datestamp><dc:title>Ruthenium-mediated selective activation of a C-H bond. Direct aromatic thiolation in the complexes [Ru-II{o-SC6H3(R)N=NC5H4N}(2)] (R=H, Me or Cl)</dc:title><dc:creator>SANTRA, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>oxidation levels</dc:subject><dc:subject>2-(arylazo)pyridine complexes</dc:subject><dc:subject>redox properties</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal oxidation</dc:subject><dc:subject>chemistry</dc:subject><dc:subject>family</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrodesulfurization</dc:subject><dc:subject>reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>ligands</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of the complexes ctc-[Ru(II)L(2)Cl(2)] (L = arylazopyridine, RC(6)H(4)N=NC5H4N, where R = H, m-Me, p-Me or p-Cl; ctc = cis-trans-cis with respect to chlorides, pyridine and azo nitrogens respectively) with KS(2)COR' (R' = Me, Et, Pr-n, Bu(n) or CH(2)Ph) in boiling dimethylformamide afforded [Ru-II{o-SC6H3(R)N=NC5H4N}(2)] where the a-carbon atom of the pendant phenyl ring of both ligands L has been selectively and directly thiolated. The newly formed tridentate thiolated ligands are bound in a meridional fashion. When one methyl group is present at the meta position of the pendant phenyl ring of L the reaction resulted in two isomeric complexes due to free rotation of the singly bonded meta-substituted phenyl ring with respect to the azo group. The molecular geometry of the complexes in solution has been determined by H-1 NMR spectroscopy. This revealed the presence of an intimate mixture of the two isomers in solution in a 2:1 ratio. In the visible region the complexes exhibit two metal-to-ligand charge-transfer transitions at approximate to 700 and approximate to 560 nm respectively and in the UV region intraligand (pi-pi*, n-pi*) transitions. In acetonitrile solution the complexes exhibit one reversible ruthenium(n) reversible arrow ruthenium(III) oxidation couple near 0.4 V and an irreversible oxidative response near 1 V due to oxidation of the co-ordinated thiol group. Reduction of the co-ordinated azo groups occurs at ca -0.8 and -1.4 V respectively. Coulometric oxidation of the complexes [Ru-II{o-SC6H3(R)N=NC5H4N}(2)] at 0.6 V versus the saturated calomel electrode in dichloromethane produced unstable ruthenium(III) congeners. When R = p-Me, the presence of trivalent ruthenium in the oxidised solution was evidenced by a rhombic EPR spectrum having g(1) = 2.359, g(2) = 2.300 and g(3) = 1.952.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ROYAL SOC CHEMISTRY</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-28T17:46:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-28T17:46:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:47:36Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE CHEMICAL SOCIETY-DALTON TRANSACTIONS, (1), 129-135</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0300-9246</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1039/a603955c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/11803</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/11803</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>