<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4934</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:36:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Overtopping Probability Constrained Optimal Design of Composite Channels Using Swarm Intelligence Technique</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, MJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>ADARSH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>open drainage channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>trapezoidal channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>reservoir operation</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>irrigation channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>optimal design</dc:subject><dc:subject>swarm intelligence</dc:subject><dc:subject>elitist mutation</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle swarm optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>overtopping probability</dc:subject><dc:subject>probabilistic cost function</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper swarm intelligence based methodology is proposed for optimal and reliable design of irrigation channels. The input parameters involved in channel design are prone to uncertainty and the solution of deterministic model may result in flooding risk and affect the stability of the channel. To provide reliability in the design, an overtopping probability constrained design is presented in this study. The deterministic equivalent of the probabilistic constraint is derived by following the principle of first order uncertainty analysis. In order to account for the uncertainty of design parameters in the objective function, a modified cost function is proposed. A methodology is propounded to solve it in a metaheuristic environment and solved it using elitist-mutated particle swarm optimization (EMPSO) method. The EMPSO based solutions are found to be quite successful and better than the classical optimization methods. Finally, it is concluded that the proposed methodology has a good potential for reliable design of composite channels for designer specified reliability values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ASCE-AMER SOC CIVIL ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-18T13:34:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-18T13:34:51Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:50:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:36:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF IRRIGATION AND DRAINAGE ENGINEERING-ASCE, 136(8), 532-542</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0733-9437</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)IR.1943-4774.0000217</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4934</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4934</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>