<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15642</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:16:24Z</datestamp><dc:title>TEM Studies of Boron-Modified 17Cr-7Ni Precipitation-Hardenable Stainless Steel via Rapid Solidification Route</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHARGAVA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>TEWARI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>TIWARI, AN</dc:creator><dc:subject>ALLOY</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TECHNOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>ADDITIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHROMIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>BORIDES</dc:subject><dc:description>Commercial grade 17Cr-7Ni precipitation-hardenable stainless steel has been modified by adding boron in the range 0.45 to 1.8 wt pct and using the chill block melt-spinning technique of rapid solidification (RS). Application of RS has been found to increase the solid solubility of boron and hardness of 17Cr-7Ni precipitation-hardenable stainless steel. The hardness of the boron-modified rapidly solidified alloys has been found to increase up to similar to 280 pct after isochronal aging to peak hardness. A TEM study has been carried out to understand the aging behavior. The presence of M-23(B,C)(6) and M-2(B,C) borocarbides and epsilon-carbide in the matrix of austenite and ferrite with a change in heat treatment temperature has been observed. A new equation for Creq is also developed which includes the boron factor on ferrite phase stability. The study also emphasizes that aluminum only takes part in ferrite phase stabilization and remains in the solution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:16:24Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 44A(9)4248-4256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-013-1793-9</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15642</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>