<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15946</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T04:26:56Z</datestamp><dc:title>Abelian gauge extension of the standard model: Dark matter and radiative neutrino mass</dc:title><dc:creator>BORAH, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>ADHIKARI, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>UNITARITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>VIOLATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRIPLET</dc:subject><dc:subject>BOUNDS</dc:subject><dc:description>We study a simple extension of the standard model where the gauge group is extended by an additional U(1)(X) gauge symmetry. Neutrino mass arises both at tree level as well as radiatively by the anomaly-free addition of one singlet fermion N-R and two triplet fermions Sigma(1R), Sigma(2R) with suitable Higgs scalars. The spontaneous gauge symmetry breaking is achieved in a way that results in a residual Z(2) symmetry and hence provides a stable cold dark matter candidate. We study the possible dark matter candidates in this model by incorporating the constraints from cosmology as well as direct detection experiments. We discuss both low- and high-mass ( from GeV to the TeV scale) regimes of fermionic and scalar dark matter candidates in the model. We show that scalar dark matter relic density, although not significantly affected by the presence or absence of annihilation into U(1)(X) gauge boson pairs, is however affected by choice of U(1)(X) gauge charges. We discuss the neutrino mass phenomenology and its compatibility with the allowed dark matter mass ranges and we also comment on the implications of the model on Higgs signatures at colliders including those related to the fourth fermion generation.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:26:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T04:26:56Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PHYSICAL REVIEW D, 85(9)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.85.095002</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15946</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>