<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12062</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Corrosion of 2205 duplex stainless steel weldment in chloride medium containing sulfate-reducing bacteria</dc:title><dc:creator>ANTONY, PJ</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, RKS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAN, R</dc:creator><dc:subject>heat-affected zone</dc:subject><dc:subject>pitting corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>sigma-phase</dc:subject><dc:subject>microstructure</dc:subject><dc:subject>304-stainless-steel</dc:subject><dc:subject>adhesion</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal</dc:subject><dc:subject>precipitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>toughness</dc:subject><dc:description>Influence of changes in microstructure caused due to welding on microbiologically influenced corrosion of a duplex stainless steel was studied by exposing the weldment and parent metal to chloride medium containing sulfate-reducing bacteria (SRB). Identically prepared coupons (same area and surface finish) exposed to sterile medium were used as the control. Etching-type attack was observed in the presence of SRB, which was predominant in the heat-affected zone (HAZ) of the weldment. The anodic polarization studies indicated an increase in current density for coupon exposed to SRB-containing medium as compared to that obtained for coupon exposed to sterile medium. The scanning electron microscopy (SEM) observations after anodic polarization revealed that the attack was preferentially in the ferrite phase of HAZ of the weldment, whereas it was restricted to the austenite phase of the parent metal.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T11:02:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T11:02:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:33Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2008</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>METALLURGICAL AND MATERIALS TRANSACTIONS A-PHYSICAL METALLURGY AND MATERIALS SCIENCE, 39A(11), 2689-2697</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1073-5623</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11661-008-9626-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12062</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12062</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>