<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17785</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T04:42:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of aluminum content on the texture and mechanical behavior of Mg-1 wt% Mn wrought magnesium alloys</dc:title><dc:creator>BIAN, MZ</dc:creator><dc:creator>TRIPATHI, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>YU, H</dc:creator><dc:creator>NAM, ND</dc:creator><dc:creator>YAN, LM</dc:creator><dc:subject>SINGLE-CRYSTALS</dc:subject><dc:subject>NONBASAL SLIP</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>MICROSTRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECRYSTALLIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ANISOTROPY</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOLUTE</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnesium alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>Extrusion</dc:subject><dc:subject>Dynamic recrystallization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Twinning</dc:subject><dc:description>The mechanical response of as-extruded magnesium-aluminum-manganese alloy with varying (1-4 wft) aluminum content has been examined, while the concentration of manganese is kept constant at 1 wt%. Results indicated that microstructure exhibits more uniform and equiaxed grain structure, and gradual decrease of texture intensity with increasing aluminum content. Mechanical testing results revealed tensile and compressive yield strengths decreased, while yield anisotropy, tensile uniform elongation and strain hardening exponent increased with increasing aluminum content. Weaker texture was considered to be responsible for lower yield strength, and in particular for significant decrease in tensile yield strength. In addition, simulation results revealed that prismatic &lt;a&gt; and basal &lt;a&gt; slips played a very important role during tensile deformation, and the contribution of prismatic &lt;a&gt; slip decreased with increase in aluminum content. On the other hand, {10 (1) over bar2} twin was the major deformation mode at the initial stage of the compressive deformation in addition to the basal &lt;a&gt; slip, and the relative activity of the {1012} twin decreased with increasing aluminum content. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:42:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T04:42:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MATERIALS SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING A-STRUCTURAL MATERIALS PROPERTIES MICROSTRUCTURE AND PROCESSING, 639,320-326</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0921-5093</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1873-4936</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2015.05.022</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17785</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>