<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17402</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T10:50:23Z</datestamp><dc:title>Colored HOMFLY polynomials of knots presented as double fat diagrams</dc:title><dc:creator>MIRONOV, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOROZOV, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MOROZOV, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMADEVI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, VK</dc:creator><dc:subject>CHERN-SIMONS THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENUS EXPANSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIFFERENTIAL HIERARCHY</dc:subject><dc:subject>DISTINGUISHING MUTANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>MATRIX FACTORIZATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUANTUM GROUPS</dc:subject><dc:subject>LINK HOMOLOGY</dc:subject><dc:subject>INVARIANTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALGEBRA</dc:subject><dc:subject>REPRESENTATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Quantum Groups</dc:subject><dc:subject>Chern-Simons Theories</dc:subject><dc:subject>Topological Field Theories</dc:subject><dc:description>Many knots and links in S-3 can be drawn as gluing of three manifolds with one or more four-punctured S-2 boundaries. We call these knot diagrams as double fat graphs whose invariants involve only the knowledge of the fusion and the braiding matrices of four-strand braids. Incorporating the properties of four-point conformal blocks in WZNW models, we conjecture colored HOMFLY polynomials for these double fat graphs where the color can be rectangular or non-rectangular representation. With the recent work of Gu-Jockers, the fusion matrices for the non-rectangular [21] representation, the first which involves multiplicity is known. We verify our conjecture by comparing with the [21] colored HOMFLY of many knots, obtained as closure of three braids. The conjectured form is computationally very effective leading to writing [21]-colored HOMFLY polynomials for many pretzel type knots and non-pretzel type knots. In particular, we find class of pretzel mutants which are distinguished and another class of mutants which cannot be distinguished by [21] representation. The difference between the [21]-colored HOMFLY of two mutants seems to have a general form, with A-dependence completely defined by the old conjecture due to Morton and Cromwell. In particular, we check it for an entire multi-parametric family of mutant knots evaluated using evolution method.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:50:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T10:50:23Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HIGH ENERGY PHYSICS(7)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1029-8479</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/JHEP07(2015)109</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17402</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>