<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7548</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:38:35Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tribological behaviour and residual stress of electrodeposited Ni/Cu multilayer films on stainless steel substrate</dc:title><dc:creator>GHOSH, SK</dc:creator><dc:creator>LIMAYE, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SWAIN, BP</dc:creator><dc:creator>SONI, NL</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, RG</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUSANE, RO</dc:creator><dc:creator>GROVER, AK</dc:creator><dc:subject>electrochemical deposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>thin-films</dc:subject><dc:subject>cu</dc:subject><dc:subject>wear</dc:subject><dc:subject>coatings</dc:subject><dc:subject>alloys</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>metal</dc:subject><dc:subject>ni/cu multilayers</dc:subject><dc:subject>residual stress</dc:subject><dc:subject>xrd</dc:subject><dc:subject>electrodeposition</dc:subject><dc:subject>coefficient of friction</dc:subject><dc:subject>wear</dc:subject><dc:subject>tribology</dc:subject><dc:description>In the present study, [Ni (4.5 nm)/Cu (t(Cu)=2, 4 and 8 nm)] multilayers were pulse electrodeposited on stainless steel (AISI SS 304) substrate from sulphate based single bath technique. X-ray diffraction (XRD) was used to investigate the structure and stress of the Ni/Cu multilayer. The results from XRD analysis indicated that the deposited multilayers had a preferred crystal orientation of [111] and presence of satellite reflection suggested the formation of superlattice. The stress level within the deposited multilayers was found to be sensitive to the sublayer thickness. Sliding wear behaviour of electrodeposited Ni/Cu multilayer films has been investigated against a tungsten carbide (WC) ball as the counter body and compared with that of the constituents, Cu and Ni coatings. The wear tests were carried out by using a reciprocating ball-on-flat geometry at translation frequencies of 5 and 10 Hz, slip amplitude of I mm and at five different loads of 3, 5, 7, 9 and 11N. Friction force was recorded on-line during the tests. At the end of the tests, the wear scars were examined by laser surface profilometry and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). Friction coefficient was found to be dependent on load and Cu layer thickness (t(Cu)) and the values for multilayers were border between Ni and Cu. Among multilayers, sample with minimum t(Cu) has shown the lowest friction coefficient and wear rate. With increasing t(Cu), the wear mechanism changes from pure abrasive wear at t(Cu) = 2 nm, to particle entrapment at t(Cu) = 4 nm to particle embedding at t(Cu) = 8 nm. Detailed investigation of the wear scar morphology as well as wear rate measurement revealed that at low loads, (HIE) ratio and residual stress governed the wear rate and the principle wear mode was abrasive cutting. At intermediate loads, the role of residual stress became insignificant while wear was governed by (HIE) ratio and plastic deformation. However, at higher loads, plastic deformation played the major role. (c) 2006</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-29T02:08:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-29T02:08:17Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:38:35Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SURFACE &amp; COATINGS TECHNOLOGY, 201(8), 4609-4618</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0257-8972</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2006.09.314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7548</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7548</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>