<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-2524</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-15T09:12:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Control of longitudinal dynamics of aircraft using periodic output feedback</dc:title><dc:creator>KHAN, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BANDYOPADHYAY, B</dc:creator><dc:subject>time-invariant systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>pole assignment</dc:subject><dc:subject>simultaneous stabilization</dc:subject><dc:description>In this paper, the problem of pole placement by periodic output feedback is presented. The poles of the discrete time control system could be assigned arbitrarily (with the natural restriction that they should be located symmetrically with respect to the real axis), provided that the number of gain changes is not less than the system's controllability index. Linearized models of aircraft are obtained at 10 different flight conditions and controller is designed for controlling the longitudinal dynamics of aircraft using periodic output feedback. The family of 8 plants, representing the longitudinal dynamic, is also simultaniously stabilized. The controller consisted of solely of gain elements and did not include a dynamical system, such as an observer, hence easier to implement on line.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-10-27T03:02:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-10-27T03:02:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-15T09:12:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Proceedings Paper</dc:type><dc:identifier>PROCEEDINGS OF IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON INDUSTRIAL TECHNOLOGY 2000, VOLS 1 AND 2,95-100</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0-7803-5812-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/16218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/100/2524</dc:identifier><dc:source>International Conference on Industrial Technology (IEEE ICIT 2000),GOA, INDIA,JAN 19-22, 2000</dc:source><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>