<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9701</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:44:01Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tuned liquid dampers for controlling earthquake response of structures</dc:title><dc:creator>BANERJI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>MURUDI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHAH, AH</dc:creator><dc:creator>POPPLEWELL, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>excitation</dc:subject><dc:subject>earthquake response</dc:subject><dc:subject>tuned liquid dampers</dc:subject><dc:subject>vibration control</dc:subject><dc:subject>sloshing</dc:subject><dc:subject>energy dissipation</dc:subject><dc:subject>tld design</dc:subject><dc:description>Numerical simulations of a single-degree-of-freedom (SDOF) structure, rigidly supporting a tuned liquid damper (TLD) and subjected to both real and artificially generated earthquake ground motions, show that a properly designed TLD can significantly reduce the structure's response to these motions. The TLD is a rigid, rectangular tank with shallow water in it. Its fundamental linear sloshing frequency is tuned to the structure's natural frequency. The TLD is more effective in reducing structural response as the ground excitation level increases. This is because it then dissipates more energy due to sloshing and wave breaking. A larger water-depth to tank-length ratio than previous studies suggested, which still falls within the constraint of shallow water theory, is shown to be more suitable for excitation levels expected in strong earthquake motions. A larger water-mass to structure-mass ratio is shown to be required for a TLD to remain equally effective as structural damping increases. Furthermore, the reduction in response is seen to be fairly insensitive to the bandwidth of the ground motion but is dependent on the structure's natural frequency relative to the significant ground frequencies. Finally, a practical approach is suggested for the design of a TLD to control earthquake response. Copyright (C) 2000 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T02:05:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T02:05:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:44:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2000</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EARTHQUAKE ENGINEERING &amp; STRUCTURAL DYNAMICS, 29(5), 587-602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0098-8847</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9845(200005)29:5&lt;587::AID-EQE926&gt;3.0.CO;2-I</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9701</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9701</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>