<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1254</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Effect of deformation on the electrochemical behavior of hot-dip galvanized steel sheets</dc:title><dc:creator>VAGGE, ST</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJA, VS</dc:creator><dc:creator>NARAYANAN, RGANESH</dc:creator><dc:subject>galvanizing</dc:subject><dc:subject>deformation</dc:subject><dc:subject>steel corrosion</dc:subject><dc:subject>potentiodynamic polarization</dc:subject><dc:description>The main purpose of employing pre-coated steel sheets is to minimize corrosion of steel. However, coatings can be severely affected by forming processes. In the forming processes, due to the different modes of deformation, the strain levels are different and so can affect the properties of the coatings to a varying degree. Special attention has to be paid to the influence of deformation conditions on the performance of the coating, as regards protection against corrosion. The adhesion of the coating must remain good, and the surface should not be damaged during forming. Therefore, it is necessary to study the behavior of its corrosion resistance against the deformation.

In this work, effect of strain path on the corrosion behavior of hot-dip galvanized steel sheets has been studied. Corrosion behavior of hot-dip galvanized steel sheets at various strain levels has been evaluated under four different strain paths namely, biaxial, plane strain, uniaxial (drawing) and tensile modes. The sheets were deformed by a limiting dome height test (LDH) set-up. A correlation between the degree of deformation and the loss in extent of corrosion protection offered by the coating has been established by carrying out electrochemical studies such as potentiodynamic polarization and impedance spectroscopy (EIS) in 3.5% NaCl solution. The present study shows that increase in deformation increases the extent of delamination of the coating for all the modes of deformation. The severity of deformation on delamination, however, has been found to vary in the order of, tensile &lt; uniaxial &lt; plane &lt; biaxial.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-28T05:24:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:37:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-28T05:24:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:37:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Applied Surface Science 253(20), 8415-8421</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0169-4332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/j.apsusc.2007.04.045</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1254</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>