<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14476</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T13:05:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Frequency detection in vortex flowmeter for low Reynolds number using piezoelectric sensor and installation effects</dc:title><dc:creator>VENUGOPAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>AGRAWAL, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>PRABHU, SV</dc:creator><dc:subject>Piezoelectric sensors</dc:subject><dc:subject>Vortex flowmeter</dc:subject><dc:subject>Trapezoid</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMD</dc:subject><dc:subject>Autocorrelation</dc:subject><dc:subject>EMPIRICAL MODE DECOMPOSITION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIGNAL QUALITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BLUFF-BODY</dc:subject><dc:subject>SHEDDER</dc:subject><dc:subject>PROBE</dc:subject><dc:description>Piezoelectric sensors are one of the most widely used sensors for vortex flowmeter application due to their low cost. Various researchers have employed piezoelectric sensor for this application. However, the location of the sensor and the performance of vortex flowmeter under disturbed conditions are seldom reported. In the present study, experimental investigations are conducted with water as the working medium in a circular pipe of diameter 52.5 mm. The optimum position of the piezoelectric sensor behind the trapezoidal bluff body is found out be 0.85 times the width of the bluff body. A new algorithm based on empirical mode decomposition and autocorrelation decay rate is suggested to identify the vortex shedding frequency under low Reynolds numbers flow condition. The performance of the flowmeter is also evaluated under different disturbed flow conditions to quantify the sensitivity of the flowmeter. The disturbances studied are single 90 degrees bend, gate valve, globe valve, and two 90 degrees out of plane bends. The overall uncertainty in the Strouhal number is within +/- 1.71%. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE SA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:05:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T13:05:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SENSORS AND ACTUATORS A-PHYSICAL, 18478-85</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.sna.2012.07.004</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14476</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>