<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12263</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:49:31Z</datestamp><dc:title>HOMOGENEITY AND CRITICAL-CURRENT DENSITY OF SN-DOPED PBMO6S8 SUPERCONDUCTORS</dc:title><dc:creator>SELVAM, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>CORS, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>CATTANI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>DECROUX, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>FISCHER, O</dc:creator><dc:creator>SEIBT, EW</dc:creator><dc:subject>auger-electron spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>upper critical fields</dc:subject><dc:subject>chevrel phases</dc:subject><dc:subject>lattice instability</dc:subject><dc:subject>eumo6s8</dc:subject><dc:description>With the overall critical current density, J(c), remaining low for PbMo6S8, the addition of 0.3 at. % Sn noticeably improved the performance. The enhancement occurs despite the presence of excess Pb and a slightly suppressed T-c. The increase in J(c) can be attributed to a better homogeneity with respect to the chemical composition of the samples, which may be as a consequence of Sn substitution in the lattice. Detailed calorimetric investigation of undoped PbMo6S8 showed a T-c distribution down to 9 K evidenced by a smearing of T-c. This may be due to a progressive degradation of the sample quality leading to a plausible off-stoichiometry. High-resolution Auger electron spectroscopic experiments suggest a variation in composition indicating excellent correspondence with the specific heat data. However, no such deviation was detected for the Sn-doped samples and therefore the observed raise in J(c). The results are discussed in conjunction with oxygen, lead and tin incorporated PbMo6S8.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER VERLAG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-30T09:16:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-30T09:16:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:49:31Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>APPLIED PHYSICS A-MATERIALS SCIENCE &amp; PROCESSING, 61(6), 615-621</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0721-7250</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s003390050249</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12263</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12263</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>