<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16249</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T09:08:44Z</datestamp><dc:title>Compositional diversity of near-, far-side transitory zone around Naonobu, Webb and Sinus Successus craters: Inferences from Chandrayaan-1 Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M-3) data</dc:title><dc:creator>BHARTI, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAMAKRISHNAN, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, KD</dc:creator><dc:subject>Imaging spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M-3)</dc:subject><dc:subject>Naonobu crater</dc:subject><dc:subject>planetary exploration</dc:subject><dc:subject>spectral deconvolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>SPECTRAL MIXTURE ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>IMAGING SPECTROMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>THORIUM ABUNDANCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>LUNAR-SURFACE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRUST</dc:subject><dc:description>This study investigated the potential of Moon Mineralogy Mapper (M-3) data for studying compositional variation in the near-, far-side transition zone of the lunar surface. For this purpose, the radiance values of the M3 data were corrected for illumination and emission related effects and converted to apparent reflectance. Dimensionality of the calibrated reflectance image cube was reduced using Independent Component Analysis (ICA) and endmembers were extracted by using Pixel Purity Index (PPI) algorithm The selected endmembers were linearly unmixed and resolved for mineralogy using United States Geological Survey (USGS) library spectra of minerals. These mineralogically resolved endmembers were used to map the compositional variability within, and outside craters using Spectral Angle Mapper (SAM) algorithm. Cross validation for certain litho types was attempted using band ratios like Optical Maturity (OMAT), Color Ratio Composite and Integrated Band Depth ratio (IBD). The identified lithologies for highland and basin areas match well with published works and strongly support depth related magmatic differentiation. Prevalence of pigeonite-basalt, pigeonite-norite and pyroxenite in crater peaks and floors are unique to the investigated area and are attributed to local, lateral compositional variability in magma composition due to pressure, temperature, and rate of cooling.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:08:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T09:08:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF EARTH SYSTEM SCIENCE, 123(1)233-246</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0253-4126</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-774X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16249</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>