<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16518</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:27:06Z</datestamp><dc:title>A Schiff Base and Its Copper(II) Complex as a Highly Selective Chemodosimeter for Mercury(II) Involving Preferential Hydrolysis of Aldimine over an Ester Group</dc:title><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUBEY, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, RK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>KALITA, AC</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDEY, DS</dc:creator><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AQUEOUS-MEDIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>METAL IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>HG2+ IONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLUORESCENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>SENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>METHYLMERCURY</dc:subject><dc:subject>CHEMOSENSOR</dc:subject><dc:subject>ENVIRONMENT</dc:subject><dc:subject>DERIVATIVES</dc:subject><dc:description>The syntheses of a new Schiff base, diethyl-5-(2-hydroxybenzylidene)aminoisophthalate (HL), and a copper complex, [Cu(L-2)] (1), imparting L, have been described. Both the ligand HL and complex 1 have been thoroughly characterized by elemental analyses, electrospray ionization mass spectrometry, FT-IR, NMR (H-1 and C-13), electronic absorption, and emission spectral studies and their structures determined by X-ray single-crystal analyses. Distinctive chemodosimetric behavior of HL and 1 toward Hg2+ has been established by UV/vis, emission, and mass spectral studies. Comparative studies further revealed that the chemodosimetric response solely originates from selective hydrolysis of the aldimine moiety over the ester group and 1 exhibited greater selectivity toward Hg2+ relative to HL while the sensitivity order is reversed. Further, these followed different hydrolytic pathways but ended up with the same product analyzed for diethyl-5-aminoisophthalate (DEA). Hg2+-induced displacement of Cu2+ and subsequent hydrolysis of the -HC=N-moiety in 1 affirmed the identity of the actual species undergoing hydrolysis as HL. The occurrence of Cu2+ displacement and Hg2+ detection via hydrolytic transformation has been supported by various physicochemical studies.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:27:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:27:06Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 53(10)4944-4955</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-510X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ic403149b</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16518</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>