<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16686</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T13:12:40Z</datestamp><dc:title>Alumina Nanoparticle Filled Epoxy Resin: High Strain Rate Compressive Behavior</dc:title><dc:creator>NAIK, NK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PANDYA, KS</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAVALA, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>ZHANG, W</dc:creator><dc:creator>KORATKAR, NA</dc:creator><dc:subject>MECHANICAL-PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOUGHENING MECHANISMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>POLYMERIC COMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NANOCOMPOSITES</dc:subject><dc:subject>INCLUSION</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRENGTH</dc:subject><dc:subject>SIZE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOUGHNESS</dc:subject><dc:description>This study demonstrates high strain rate behavior of neat epoxy and epoxy resin reinforced with 2 wt% and 5 wt% alumina nanoparticles. The present study investigates effect of strain rate as well as effect of alumina nanoparticle dispersion on the compressive stress - compressive strain behavior of epoxy resin. Studies were carried out on compressive split Hopkinson pressure bar apparatus in the strain rate range of 700-3200 per sec. Significant enhancement of compressive strength of epoxy resin up to 147% was noted at high strain rate compared with that at quasi-static loading. The corresponding increase for alumina nanoparticle filled epoxy resin was up to 142%. It was also observed that the compressive strength of epoxy resin increases up to 8.6% with the addition of alumina nanoparticles at a strain rate of 3000 per sec. Synthesis of alumina nanoparticle filled epoxy resin, high strain rate and quasi-static testing and main findings of the study are presented in this article. POLYM. ENG. SCI., 54:2896-2901, 2014. (c) 2014 Society of Plastics Engineers</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-BLACKWELL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:12:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T13:12:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>POLYMER ENGINEERING AND SCIENCE, 54(12)2896-2901</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0032-3888</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1548-2634</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/pen.23850</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16686</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>