<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-13947</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T05:17:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Mineral fish: their morphological classification, usefulness as shear sense indicators and genesis</dc:title><dc:creator>MUKHERJEE, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>SQUARE OBJECTS</dc:subject><dc:subject>S-C</dc:subject><dc:subject>MYLONITIC ROCKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RIGID PARTICLES</dc:subject><dc:subject>NEW-ZEALAND</dc:subject><dc:subject>DEFORMATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ZONES</dc:subject><dc:subject>STRAIN</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOMETRY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FABRICS</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mineral fish</dc:subject><dc:subject>Mica Fish</dc:subject><dc:subject>Morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>Genesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Shear sense indicators</dc:subject><dc:subject>Ductile shearing</dc:subject><dc:subject>Karakoram</dc:subject><dc:description>Mineral fish are sheared and commonly asymmetric mineral grains or clusters of grains. This work reports 11 sub-types of mineral fish showing a top-to-SE sense of ductile shearing in the Karakoram Metamorphic Complex (KMC). The mineral fish are of three broad geometries: sigmoid, lenticular and parallelogram. Reliable senses of shear are indicated by the overall asymmetry and inclination of mineral fish. On the other hand, the true shear sense is not always indicated by either the orientations of their cleavage planes or those of the individual grains in composite mineral fish. The ranges of local orientations of single sigmoid mineral fish that include the lower values (&lt; 23A degrees) in the KMC indicate their extensive ductile shearing. The studied mineral fish were products of a range of deformation mechanisms including homogeneous deformation, simple shear, intra-granular slip, crystal-plastic deformation, fracturing and synthetic shearing. Additionally, some examples might have undergone duplex slips and a few nucleated and grew either prior to or during the top-to-SE shearing.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:17:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T05:17:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF EARTH SCIENCES,100(6)1303-1314</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1437-3254</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00531-010-0535-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/13947</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>