<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9755</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:37:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>Emissions of gaseous and particulate pollutants in a port and harbour region in India</dc:title><dc:creator>GUPTA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, RS</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>so2</dc:subject><dc:subject>nox</dc:subject><dc:subject>acidification</dc:subject><dc:subject>inventories</dc:subject><dc:subject>asia</dc:subject><dc:subject>emission inventory</dc:subject><dc:subject>fugitive emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>nitrogen dioxide emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>pm10 emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>sulfur dioxide emissions</dc:subject><dc:subject>tsp</dc:subject><dc:description>Ports can generate large quantity of pollutants in the atmosphere due to various activities like loading and unloading, transportation, and construction operations. Determination of the character and quantity of emissions from individual sources is an essential step in any project to control and minimize the emissions. In this study a detailed emission inventory of total suspended particulate matter (TSP), particulate matter less than 10 mum (PM10), sulfur dioxide (SO2) and nitrogen oxides (NOx) for a port and harbour project near Mumbai is compiled. Results show that the total annual average contributions of TSP and PM10 from all the port activities were 872 and 221 t yr(-1), respectively. Annual average emissions of gaseous pollutants SO2 and NOx were 56 and 397 t yr(-1), respectively, calculated by using emission factors for different port activities. The maximum TSP emission (419 t yr(-1)) was from paved roads, while the least (0.4 t yr(-1)) was from bulk handling activity. The maximum PM10 emission (123 t yr(-1)) was from unpaved roads and minimum (0.2 t yr(-1)) from bulk handling operations. Similarly the ratio of TSP and PM10 emission was highest (5.18) from paved roads and least (2.17) from bulk handling operations. Regression relation was derived from existing emission data of TSP and PM10 from various port activities. Good correlation was observed between TSP and PM10 having regression coefficient &gt;0.8.</dc:description><dc:publisher>KLUWER ACADEMIC PUBL</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:10:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-17T05:10:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:37:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2002</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING AND ASSESSMENT, 80(2), 187-205</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0167-6369</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/A:1020641014104</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9755</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9755</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>