<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16157</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T06:14:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Reliability analysis of composite channels using first order approximation and Monte Carlo simulations</dc:title><dc:creator>ADARSH, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>REDDY, MJ</dc:creator><dc:subject>Composite channels</dc:subject><dc:subject>First order second moment method</dc:subject><dc:subject>Monte Carlo simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>Reliability</dc:subject><dc:subject>Uncertainty modeling</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONSTRAINED OPTIMAL-DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPEN DRAINAGE CHANNELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRAPEZOIDAL CHANNELS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RISK ANALYSIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNCERTAINTY</dc:subject><dc:subject>FLOW</dc:subject><dc:subject>SECTION</dc:subject><dc:description>Artificial open channels being costlier infrastructure, their design should ensure reliability along with optimality in project cost. This paper presents reliability analysis of composite channels, considering uncertainty associated with various design parameters such as friction factors, longitudinal slope, channel width, side slope, and flow depth. This study also considers uncertainties of watershed characteristics, rainfall intensity and drainage area to quantify the uncertainty of runoff. For uncertainty modeling, the advanced first order second moment method and Monte Carlo simulation are used and it is found that the results by both approaches show good agreement. Then, a reliability index that can be used to design a composite channel to convey design discharge for a specified risk or probability of failure is presented, and its sensitivity with different channel design parameters are analyzed. To validate the effectiveness of the present approach, the reliability values and safety factors for variable system loading scenario are obtained under static and dynamic environment. The sensitivity analysis shows that flow depth and bed width are the most influencing parameters that affect the safety factor and reliability.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T06:14:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T06:14:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>STOCHASTIC ENVIRONMENTAL RESEARCH AND RISK ASSESSMENT, 27(2)477-487</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00477-012-0663-0</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16157</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>