<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17161</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:11:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Stability of non-vertical waterfront retaining wall supporting inclined backfill under earthquake and tsunami</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABORTY, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHOUDHURY, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>Non-vertical waterfront retaining wall</dc:subject><dc:subject>Inclined backfill</dc:subject><dc:subject>Tsunami</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hydrodynamic pressure</dc:subject><dc:subject>Sliding</dc:subject><dc:subject>Factor of safety</dc:subject><dc:subject>SEISMIC PASSIVE RESISTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PSEUDODYNAMIC METHOD</dc:subject><dc:subject>PRESSURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORCES</dc:subject><dc:subject>DESIGN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SOILS</dc:subject><dc:description>The stability analysis has been carried out for generalized non-vertical waterfront retaining wall supporting inclined backfill under combined action of earthquake and tsunami forces. Closed-form design solutions for factor of safety against sliding have been obtained using limit equilibrium method. For estimating seismic passive earth pressure and the wall inertia force, the pseudo-dynamic approach has been adopted. Different methods available in literature are used to estimate tsunami wave pressure and hydrodynamic pressure. It has been observed that parameters like seismic accelerations in both horizontal and vertical directions, time period, soil and wall friction angles, wall batter, ground inclination, pore pressure ratio, tsunami wave height have significant effect on the sliding stability of the waterfront retaining wall under combined action of earthquake and tsunami. Comparison of results with available results in literature for special case of vertical waterfront retaining wall supporting horizontal backfill has indicated a very good agreement. It is expected that the proposed design charts and tables presented in this paper will be helpful for the design engineers to design waterfront retaining wall against sliding mode of failure under combined action of earthquake and tsunami. (C) 2013 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:11:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:11:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>OCEAN ENGINEERING, 781-10</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-8018</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.oceaneng.2013.11.024</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17161</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>