<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14157</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:39:09Z</datestamp><dc:title>A novel architecture for improving slew rate in FinFET-based op-amps and OTAs</dc:title><dc:creator>THAKKER, RA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>TAILOR, KH</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGHINI, MS</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHARMA, DK</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, VR</dc:creator><dc:creator>PATIL, MB</dc:creator><dc:subject>OPERATIONAL-AMPLIFIER</dc:subject><dc:subject>High slew rate op-amp</dc:subject><dc:subject>Look-up table</dc:subject><dc:subject>FinFET</dc:subject><dc:subject>Hierarchical particle swarm optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Circuit design</dc:subject><dc:description>A new architecture for improvement of slew rate (SR) of an op-amp or an operational transconductance amplifier (OTA) in FinFET technology is proposed. The principle of operation of the proposed architecture is based on a set of additional current sources which are switched on, only when OTA should provide a high current, usually for charge or discharge of large load capacitor. Therefore, the power overhead is less compared to conventional high SR designs. The commonly used two-stage Miller-compensated op-amp, designed and optimized in sub 45 nm FinFET technology with 1 V single supply voltage, is used as an example for demonstration of the proposed method. For the same FinFET technology and with optimal design, it is shown that the slew rate of the op-amp is significantly improved. The slew rate is improved from 273 to 5590 V/mu s for an input signal with a rise time of 100 ps. The other performance measures such as gain and phase margin remain unchanged with the additional circuitry used for slew rate enhancement. (C) 2011 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCI LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:39:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:39:09Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>MICROELECTRONICS JOURNAL,42(5)758-765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0026-2692</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.mejo.2011.01.010</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14157</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>