<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14148</identifier><datestamp>2012-06-26T07:34:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydrogeochemical and isotopic study of thermal and mineralized waters from the Nevsehir (Kozakli) area, Central Turkey</dc:title><dc:creator>PASVANOGLU, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>CHANDRASEKHARAM, D</dc:creator><dc:subject>WESTERN ANATOLIA</dc:subject><dc:subject>GEOTHERMAL-FIELD</dc:subject><dc:subject>BORATE DEPOSITS</dc:subject><dc:subject>QUATERNARY</dc:subject><dc:subject>Turkey geothermal province</dc:subject><dc:subject>Kozakli</dc:subject><dc:subject>Anatolian geothermal provinces</dc:subject><dc:subject>travertine</dc:subject><dc:subject>hydrogeochemistty</dc:subject><dc:description>In the Kozakli geothermal province, thermal waters are manifested along a valley 1.5 km long and 200 m in width. Thermal waters utilised by the resort and some other hotels are mostly discharged from bore wells. The issuing temperatures of the thermal waters vary from 40-50 degrees C in thermal springs and 45-96 degrees C in bores and open wells. The geochemical and isotopic signatures of the thermal water suggest mixing of thermal waters with formation waters and cold near-surface groundwaters before emerging to the surface, and hence geochemical indicators fail to indicate the near true reservoir temperatures. However, the oxygen and hydrogen isotopic signatures strongly suggest a high temperature reservoir (&gt;220 degrees C) in the crystalline basement rocks. Long circulation of meteoric waters within the basement rocks is indicated by low tritium values in the thermal waters. Major involvement of Miocene Marls in modifying the chemical signatures of the thermal waters is inferred from the trace element concentrations. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:34:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012-06-26T07:34:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF VOLCANOLOGY AND GEOTHERMAL RESEARCH,202(3-4)241-250</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0377-0273</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jvolgeores.2011.03.003</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14148</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>