<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15100</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:27:03Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modeling Pedestrian Delay and Level of Service at Signalized Intersection Crosswalks Under Mixed Traffic Conditions</dc:title><dc:creator>NAGRAJ, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>VEDAGIRI, R</dc:creator><dc:description>The objectives of this study were to identify the factors affecting pedestrian level of service (LOS) at signalized intersection crosswalks under mixed traffic conditions and to propose a suitable method for estimating pedestrian LOS. The study attempted to develop a pedestrian LOS model for signalized intersection crosswalks in Mumbai, India, by using pedestrians' perceptions of various influencing factors. The important factors considered to develop the model were turning traffic, through traffic, number of pedestrians, and pedestrian delay. Pedestrian delay is one of the key performance indicators for signalized intersection crosswalks; it is necessary to estimate delays accurately to assess LOS. As in the Highway Capacity Manual method, pedestrian delay can be calculated with the help of Webster's delay model, which assumes pedestrians arrive at a uniform rate at an intersection and all will comply with the signal; however, that assumption is not true for the Indian scenario. A pedestrian delay model for Indian conditions was developed by considering nonuniform arrival rate and signal noncompliance behavior. A video graphic technique was conducted for six selected crosswalks. A questionnaire survey was conducted to obtain the perceived LOS of pedestrians. Pedestrian delay was found with the use of the new model. A Pearson correlation analysis was done to find the significant factors that affect LOS. With perceived LOS as a dependent variable and significant factors as independent variables, stepwise regression was done to develop the model that fit for urban mixed traffic conditions.</dc:description><dc:publisher>NATL ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:27:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:27:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSPORTATION RESEARCH RECORD, (2394)70-76</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0361-1981</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>2169-4052</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.3141/2394-09</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15100</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>