<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10050</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:42:37Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hindi Verb Knowledge Base and Noun Incorporation in Hindi</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAKRABARTI, D</dc:creator><dc:creator>SARMA, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>BHATTACHARYYA, P</dc:creator><dc:subject>simple verbs</dc:subject><dc:subject>conjunct verbs</dc:subject><dc:subject>hindi wordnet (hwn)</dc:subject><dc:subject>universal networking language (unl) and unl knowledge base</dc:subject><dc:subject>noun plus verb (n plus v) combination</dc:subject><dc:subject>noun incorporation (ni)</dc:subject><dc:description>The work reported in this paper deals with the Hindi verbs. This paper can be divided into two parts. The first part is a description of a lexicon where the verbs are arranged hierarchically according to their super-ordinate terms. In this hierarchy, verbs are first listed according to their specific senses. This lexicon is named as Hindi Verb Knowledge Base (HVKB). HVKB uses constructs and Knowledge Base of Universal Networking language (UNL), an interlingua, CIIL (Central Institute of Indian Languages) Corpora and partially Hindi Wordnet (henceforth HWN). In the second part of the paper we have presented the structural description of the Hindi verbs. A type of complex verb, namely, Noun+Verb combinations are studied in detail. The motivation behind this study was to look for a principled approach in storing the Noun+Verb combinations in HWN. Different syntactic tests are applied to identify such verbs. Various syntactic and semantic properties of this group emerged through these tests. These properties help identifying this group as a process of lexical compound. These lexical compounds are then stored in the hierarchy. Finally, the paper shows how HVKB will prove beneficial for HWN.</dc:description><dc:publisher>MASARYKOVA UNIV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-18T14:39:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-18T14:39:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:48Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:42:37Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>GWC 2006: THIRD INTERNATIONAL WORDNET CONFERENCE, PROCEEDINGS, (), 43-50</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10050</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10050</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>