<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14930</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T12:50:10Z</datestamp><dc:title>Comparative Phylogenomics of Pathogenic and Non-Pathogenic Mycobacterium</dc:title><dc:creator>PRASANNA, AN</dc:creator><dc:creator>MEHRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>GENOME-LEVEL CHARACTERS</dc:subject><dc:subject>GENE ORDER PHYLOGENY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TUBERCULOSIS PATHOGENESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>EVOLUTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TREES</dc:subject><dc:subject>TOOL</dc:subject><dc:subject>RECONSTRUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>BIOSYNTHESIS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INFECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>SMEGMATIS</dc:subject><dc:description>Mycobacterium species are the source of a variety of infectious diseases in a range of hosts. Genome based methods are used to understand the adaptation of each pathogenic species to its unique niche. In this work, we report the comparison of pathogenic and non-pathogenic Mycobacterium genomes. Phylogenetic trees were constructed using sequence of core orthologs, gene content and gene order. It is found that the genome based methods can better resolve the inter-species evolutionary distances compared to the conventional 16S based tree. Phylogeny based on gene order highlights distinct evolutionary characteristics as compared to the methods based on sequence, as illustrated by the shift in the relative position of M. abscessus. This difference in gene order among the Mycobacterium species is further investigated using a detailed synteny analysis. It is found that while rearrangements between some Mycobacterium genomes are local within synteny blocks, few possess global rearrangements across the genomes. The study illustrates how a combination of different genome based methods is essential to build a robust phylogenetic relationship between closely related organisms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>PUBLIC LIBRARY SCIENCE</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:50:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T12:50:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PLOS ONE, 8(8)</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0071248</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14930</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>