<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3736</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:11Z</datestamp><dc:title>Biomimicking Altruistic Behavior of Honey Bees in Multi-objective Genetic Algorithm</dc:title><dc:creator>RAMTEKE, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUPTA, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>carcinogenesis</dc:subject><dc:subject>evolution</dc:subject><dc:subject>operator</dc:subject><dc:subject>cancers</dc:subject><dc:subject>models</dc:subject><dc:subject>ga</dc:subject><dc:description>The altruistic behavior of honey bees provides an interesting contrast to natural selection in evolutionary biology. This is biomimicked in the framework of a multiobjective optimization algorithm, namely, genetic algorithm. GA, by exploiting the concept of elitism (preserving good parents). The effects of altruism and natural selection oil the total fitness of the colony are compared. This basic algorithm is used for studying the evolution process It is then modified to enhance the convergence rates of optimization problems and to simulate the carcinogenesis of cells using multiple queens, unlike in honeycombs, mimicking other species of hymenopterans, e.g., ants, wasps, etc. This algorithm provides a new approach for studying three problems, bee evolution, optimization, and cancer, and is used to understand conflicts in animal behavior, increase the speed of convergence of optimization problems, and for an improved understanding of the causes of cancer.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-13T17:59:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-13T17:59:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:01Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:11Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INDUSTRIAL &amp; ENGINEERING CHEMISTRY RESEARCH, 48(21), 9671-9685</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0888-5885</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ie9004817</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3736</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3736</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>