<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16586</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-28T12:45:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hydroxo-Bridged Dimers of Oxo-Centered Ruthenium(III) Triangle: Synthesis and Spectroscopic and Theoretical Investigations</dc:title><dc:creator>UPADHYAY, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJPUROHIT, J</dc:creator><dc:creator>SINGH, MK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DUBEY, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIVASTAVA, AK</dc:creator><dc:creator>KUMAR, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAJARAMAN, G</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHANMUGAM, M</dc:creator><dc:subject>cluster compounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>density functional calculations</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetism</dc:subject><dc:subject>NMR spectroscopy</dc:subject><dc:subject>ruthenium</dc:subject><dc:subject>SINGLE-MOLECULE MAGNETS</dc:subject><dc:subject>INTRAMOLECULAR ELECTRON-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>N-HETEROCYCLIC LIGANDS</dc:subject><dc:subject>SCHIFF-BASE COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>H BOND ACTIVATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>X-RAY-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRINUCLEAR RUTHENIUM</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRIRUTHENIUM COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>REDOX PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTROCHEMICAL PROPERTIES</dc:subject><dc:description>The homometallic hexameric ruthenium cluster of the formula [Ru-6(III)((3)-O)(2)(-OH)(2)((CH3)(3)CCO2)(12)(py)(2)] (1) (py=pyridine) is solved by single-crystal X-ray diffraction. Magnetic susceptibility measurements performed on 1 suggest that the antiferromagnetic interaction between the Ru-III centers is dominant, and this is supported by theoretical studies. Theoretical calculations based on density functional methods yield eight different exchange interaction values for 1: J(1)=-737.6, J(2)=+63.4, J(3)=-187.6, J(4)=+124.4, J(5)=-376.4, J(6)=-601.2, J(7)=-657.0, and J(8)=-800.6cm(-1). Among all the computed J values, six are found to be antiferromagnetic. Four exchange values (J(1), J(6), J(7) and J(8)) are computed to be extremely strong, with J(8), mediated through one -hydroxo and a carboxylate bridge, being by far the largest exchange obtained for any transition-metal cluster. The origin of these strong interactions is the orientation of the magnetic orbitals in the Ru-III centers, and the computed J values are rationalized by using molecular orbital and natural bond order analysis. Detailed NMR studies (H-1, C-13, HSQC, NOESY, and TOCSY) of 1 (in CDCl3) confirm the existence of the solid-state structure in solution. The observation of sharp NMR peaks and spin-lattice time relaxation (T1 relaxation) experiments support the existence of strong intramolecular antiferromagnetic exchange interactions between the metal centers. A broad absorption peak around 600-1000nm in the visible to near-IR region is a characteristic signature of an intracluster charge-transfer transition. Cyclic voltammetry experiments show that there are three reversible one-electron redox couples at -0.865, +0.186, and +1.159V with respect to the Ag/AgCl reference electrode, which corresponds to two metal-based one-electron oxidations and one reduction process.</dc:description><dc:publisher>WILEY-V C H VERLAG GMBH</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-28T12:45:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>CHEMISTRY-A EUROPEAN JOURNAL, 20(20)6061-6070</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0947-6539</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1521-3765</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/chem.201304826</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16586</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>