<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3318</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:20Z</datestamp><dc:title>NON-NEWTONIAN FLOW OF BLOOD IN AN ARTERIOSCLEROTIC BLOOD-VESSEL WITH RIGID PERMEABLE WALLS</dc:title><dc:creator>DAS, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>BATRA, RL</dc:creator><dc:subject>fluid</dc:subject><dc:subject>stenosis</dc:subject><dc:description>The steady, laminar and fully developed flow of blood in an arteriosclerotic blood vessel with rigid permeable walls is investigated, taking into account the slip condition at the vessel walls. The constitutive equation of blood is represented by a Casson fluid model. The model is used to study the influence of the yield stress on blood flow through arteriosclerotic arteries. The variation of the flow resistance and wall shear stress, with permeability parameter, slip parameter and Casson number are obtained for different sizes of growth of the arteriosclerotic lesions. Comparison of the results is made with available results that consider the impervious wall and those that consider blood as a Newtonian fluid. It is found that permeability has a significant effect on the values of flow resistance and wall shear stress. Biological implications of the present model on different arterial diseases are discussed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ACADEMIC PRESS (LONDON) LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-12T12:01:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-12T12:01:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:48:52Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:20Z</dc:date><dc:date>1995</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THEORETICAL BIOLOGY, 175(1), 1-11</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0022-5193</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1006/jtbi.1995.0115</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3318</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3318</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>