<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17535</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-14T12:47:34Z</datestamp><dc:title>Indigenous Development and Industrial Application of Metal Casting Simulation Software</dc:title><dc:creator>RAVI, B</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIVARAMAN, S</dc:creator><dc:creator>SASIKUMAR, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>MARWAH, AM</dc:creator><dc:subject>Metal casting</dc:subject><dc:subject>Defects analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>Methods design</dc:subject><dc:subject>Computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:description>Metal casting is a multi-physics process involving many physical phenomena like fluid flow, phase transformation, heat transfer, microstructure evolution, defect formation and thermal stresses. Virtual casting based on process modeling and computer simulation of the above phenomena enables foundry engineers to reduce physical trials, and optimize various process parameters to achieve the desired quality and yield. A multi-disciplinary team of researchers from IIT Bombay and CSIR-NIIST combined their work in casting design and simulation, respectively, and teamed up with 3D Foundry Tech to create an integrated software package called AutoCAST FLOW+. Foundry engineers are able to visualize mold filling, temperature profiles during casting solidification and cooling curves; predict related defects like air blow hole, cold shut, shrinkage porosity and hard zones; and optimize the feeding and gating design. Two industrial case studies demonstrating its successful application for quality improvement are presented. The software has been implemented in several engineering institutes, raising the awareness and interest among students as well as teachers in metal casting field. These efforts are expected to lead to indigenous capability in casting simulation technology suitable for the local requirements.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:47:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-14T12:47:34Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>TRANSACTIONS OF THE INDIAN INSTITUTE OF METALS, 68(6)1227-1233</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0972-2815</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0975-1645</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12666-015-0710-x</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17535</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>