<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17884</identifier><datestamp>2016-01-15T06:03:43Z</datestamp><dc:title>Revelation of Varying Bonding Motif of Alloxazine, a Flavin Analogue, in Selected Ruthenium(II/III) Frameworks</dc:title><dc:creator>MONDAL, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAY, R</dc:creator><dc:creator>DAS, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>LAHIRI, GK</dc:creator><dc:subject>DENSITY-FUNCTIONAL THEORY</dc:subject><dc:subject>BRIDGED DIRUTHENIUM COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDATION-STATE COMBINATIONS</dc:subject><dc:subject>UNUSUAL COORDINATION MODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-DIKETONATE LIGAND</dc:subject><dc:subject>CRYSTAL-STRUCTURE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERCHLORATE TETRAHYDRATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>METALLOFLAVIN COMPLEXES</dc:subject><dc:subject>ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURES</dc:subject><dc:subject>EXCITATION-ENERGIES</dc:subject><dc:description>The reaction of alloxazine (L) and Ru-II(acac)(2)(CH3CN)(2) (acac(-) = acetylacetonate) in refluxing methanol leads to -the simultaneous formation of Ru-II(acac)(2)(L) (1 = bluish-green) and Ru-III(acac)(2)(L-) (2 = red) encompassing a usual neutral alpha-iminoketo chelating form of L and an unprecedented monodeprotonated alpha-iminoenolato chelating form of L-, respectively. The crystal structure of 2 establishes that N5,O4(-) donors of L- result in a nearly planar five-membered chelate with the {Ru-III(acac)(2)(+)} metal fragment. The packing diagram of 2 further reveals its hydrogen-bonded dimeric form as well as pi-pi interactions between the nearly planar tricyclic rings of coordinated alloxazirie ligands in nearby molecules. The paramagnetic 2 and one-electron-oxidized 1(+) display ruthenium(III)-based anisotropic axial EPR in CH3CN at 77 K with &lt; g &gt;/Delta g of 2.136/0.488 and 2.084/0.364, respectively (&lt; g &gt; = {1/3(g(1)(2) + g(2)(2) g(3)(2))}(1/2), and Delta g= g(1)-g(3)). The multiple electron-transfer processes of 1 and 2 in CH3CN -have been analyzed by DFT-calculated MO compositions and Mulliken spin density distributions at the paramagnetic states, which suggest successive two-electron uptake by the pi-system of the heterocyclic ring of L (L -&gt; L center dot- -&gt; L2-) or L- (L- -&gt; L center dot 2- -&gt; L3-) besides metal-based (Ru-II/Ru-III) redox process. The origin of the ligand as well as mixed metal-ligand-based multiple electronic transitions of 1(n) (n = +1, 0, -1, -2) and 2(n) (n = 0, -1, -2) in the UV and -visible regions, respectively, has been assessed by TD-DFT calculations in each redox state. The pK(a) values of 1 and 2 incorporating two and one NH protons of 6.5 (N3H, pK(a1))/8.16 (N1H, pK(a2)) and 8.43 (N1H, pK(a1)), respectively, are estimated by monitoring their spectral Changes as a function of pH in CH3CN-H2O (1:1). 1 and 2 in.CH3CN also participate in proton-driven internal reorganizations involving- the coordinated alloxatine moiety, i.e., transformation of an alpha-iminoketo chelating form to an alpha-iminoenolato chelating form and the reverse process without any electron-transfer step: Ru-II(acac)(2)(L) (1) -&gt; Ru-II(acac)(2)(L-) (2(-)) and Ru-III(acac)(2)(L-) (2) -&gt; Ru-III(acac)(2)(L) (1(+)).</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:03:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2016-01-15T06:03:43Z</dc:date><dc:date>2015</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INORGANIC CHEMISTRY, 54(6)3012-3021</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0020-1669</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1520-510X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.5b00122</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17884</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>