<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9579</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>A MULTICORNER VARIABLE ORDER SINGULARITY TRIANGLE TO MODEL NEIGHBORING SINGULARITIES</dc:title><dc:creator>MAITI, SK</dc:creator><dc:subject>finite-elements</dc:subject><dc:subject>crack</dc:subject><dc:subject>microcracks</dc:subject><dc:description>A six noded triangular finite element has been proposed to model variable order singularities in the first derivatives of field variables occurring at multiple locations (up to three) lying in close proximity. The element satisfies the convergence requirements fully. The element will be very useful in the analysis of neighbouring cracks, zig-zag cracks. kinked cracks. etc., involving mechanical and/or thermal loadings. The first degenerate form, which is a two point variable order singularity element, can be used, for example, to cover the distance between two adjacent crack tips. The second degenerate form, which is a one point variable order singularity element, can be used around a crack tip like any other crack tip elements. Six case studies have been reported, three involving mechanical loadings and the other three thermal loadings. These have helped to check the performance of the element and its two degenerate forms. The accuracy of the results in all the examples is good.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:51:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:51:54Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>1992</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL FOR NUMERICAL METHODS IN ENGINEERING, 35(2), 391-408</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0029-5981</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/nme.1620350210</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9579</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9579</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>