<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15650</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-16T13:20:26Z</datestamp><dc:title>Modified enthalpy method for the simulation of melting and solidification</dc:title><dc:creator>GUDIBANDE, NN</dc:creator><dc:creator>IYER, KN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Melting</dc:subject><dc:subject>enthalpy method</dc:subject><dc:subject>wavy interface</dc:subject><dc:subject>mushy zone constant</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOVING-BOUNDARY-PROBLEMS</dc:subject><dc:subject>DIFFUSION PHASE-CHANGE</dc:subject><dc:subject>PURE SUBSTANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>HEAT-TRANSFER</dc:subject><dc:subject>CONVECTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>TRACKING</dc:subject><dc:subject>FORMULATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WALL</dc:subject><dc:description>Enthalpy method is commonly used in the simulation of melting and solidification owing to its ease of implementation. It however has a few shortcomings. When it is used to simulate melting)solidification on a coarse grid, the temperature time history of a point close to the interface shows waviness. While simulating melting with natural convection, in order to impose no-slip and impermeability boundary conditions, momentum sink terms are used with some arbitrary constants called mushy zone constants. The values of these are very large and have no physical basis. Further, the chosen values affect the predictions and hence have to be tuned for satisfactory comparison with experimental data. To overcome these deficiencies, a new cell splitting method under the framework of the enthalpy method has been proposed. This method does not produce waviness nor requires mushy zone constants for simulating melting with natural convection. The method is then demonstrated for a simple one-dimensional melting problem and the results are compared with analytical solutions. The method is then demonstrated to work in two-dimensions and comparisons are shown with analytical solutions for problems with planar and curvilinear interfaces. To further benchmark the present method, simulations are performed for melting in a rectangular cavity with natural convection in the liquid melt. The solid-liquid interface obtained is compared satisfactorily with the experimental results available in literature.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACAD SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:20:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-16T13:20:26Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>SADHANA-ACADEMY PROCEEDINGS IN ENGINEERING SCIENCES, 38(6)1259-1285</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-2499</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0973-7677</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15650</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>