<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-17202</identifier><datestamp>2014-12-29T05:32:42Z</datestamp><dc:title>Intercalation Anode Material for Lithium Ion Battery Based on Molybdenum Dioxide</dc:title><dc:creator>SEN, UK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SHALIGRAM, A</dc:creator><dc:creator>MITRA, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>lithium ion battery</dc:subject><dc:subject>intercalation anode</dc:subject><dc:subject>LiFePO4</dc:subject><dc:subject>MoO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>nanobelt morphology</dc:subject><dc:subject>GRAPHITE NEGATIVE ELECTRODES</dc:subject><dc:subject>BINDER-FREE ANODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>AC-IMPEDANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>MOO2</dc:subject><dc:subject>PERFORMANCE</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATHODE</dc:subject><dc:subject>OXIDES</dc:subject><dc:subject>CAPACITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>TITANATE</dc:subject><dc:subject>LICOO2</dc:subject><dc:description>MoO2 is one of the most studied anode systems in lithium ion batteries. Previously, the reaction of MoO2 with lithium via conversion reaction has been widely studied. The present study highlights the possible application of MoO2 as an intercalation-based anode material to improve the safety of lithium ion batteries. Nanobelts of MoO2 are prepared by reduction of MoO3 nanobelts under hydrogen atmosphere. The intercalation behavior of MoO2 is specially focused upon by limiting the charge-discharge cycling to narrow potential window of 1.0 to 2.2 V vs Li/Li+ to avoid conversion reaction. An excellent electrochemical stability over 200 cycles is achieved at a current rate of 100 mAh g(-1). A phase transformation from monoclinic to orthorhombic to monoclinic is observed during the lithiation process, which is reversible during delithiation process and is confirmed by ex-situ XRD and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. To further demonstrate the viability of MoO2 as a commercial anode material, MoO2 is tested in a full-cell configuration against LiFePO4. The full-cell assembly is cycled for 100 cycles and stable performance is observed. The combination showed an energy density of 70 Wh kg(-1) after 100 cycles.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:32:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-12-29T05:32:42Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>ACS APPLIED MATERIALS &amp; INTERFACES, 6(16)14311-14319</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1944-8244</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/am503605u</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/17202</dc:identifier><dc:language>English</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>