<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-1251</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:46:08Z</datestamp><dc:title>Micro-simulation of residential location choice and its variation</dc:title><dc:creator>RAJU, KA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SIKDAR, PK</dc:creator><dc:creator>DHINGRA, SL</dc:creator><dc:subject>computer simulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>data reduction</dc:subject><dc:subject>mathematical models</dc:subject><dc:subject>neural networks</dc:subject><dc:description>Traditionally land use models are designed to represent aggregate behaviour even though land use development patterns are the manifestation of micro-level individual location choices. This paper develops a micro-simulation model for residential location choice in a medium-sized city in India. The model consists of two major parts: (a) the simulation of the characteristics of the individual decision units, the households of the city, and (b) the simulation of their locational choice for residences. The first submodel simulates the characteristics of households using the Monte Carlo method; the second is developed using Artificial Neural Network (ANN) theory. The integrated model simulates variations in the locational choices of the population and the residential land use distribution by aggregating the decisions of all the individual decision units. This model is developed and tested using data from the Indian city of Guwahati.</dc:description><dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher><dc:date>2009-04-28T05:23:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:36:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009-04-28T05:23:59Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-08T06:36:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T13:01:41Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:46:08Z</dc:date><dc:date>1998</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>Computers, Environment and Urban Systems 22(3), 203-218</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0198-9715</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>10.1016/S0198-9715(98)00043-X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/1251</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/1251</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>