<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8649</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:40:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Hartree-Fock variational bounds for ground state energy of chargeless fermions with finite magnetic moment in the presence of a hard core potential: A stable ferromagnetic state</dc:title><dc:creator>JHA, SS</dc:creator><dc:creator>MAHANTI, SD</dc:creator><dc:subject>chargeless fermions</dc:subject><dc:subject>magnetic dipole-dipole interaction</dc:subject><dc:subject>hartree-fock bounds</dc:subject><dc:subject>ferromagnetic ground state</dc:subject><dc:subject>neutrino-like gas</dc:subject><dc:description>We use different determinantal Hartree-Fock (HF) wave functions to calculate true variational upper bounds for the ground state energy of N spin-half fermions in volume V-0, with mass m, electric charge zero, and magnetic moment it, interacting through magnetic dipole-dipole interaction. We find that at high densities when the average interparticle distance ro becomes small compared to the magnetic length r(m) equivalent to 2m mu(2)/h(2), a ferromagnetic state with spheroidal occupation function n(up arrow)((k) over right arrow), involving quadrupolar deformation, gives a lower upper bound compared to the variational energy for the uniform paramagnetic state or for the state with dipolar deformation. This system is unstable towards infinite density collapse, but we show explicitly that a suitable short-range repulsive (hard core) interaction of strength U-0 and range a can stop this collapse. The existence of a stable equilibrium high density ferromagnetic state with spheroidal occupation function is possible as long as the ratio of coupling constants Gamma(cm) equivalent to (U(0)a(3)/mu(2)) is not very small compared to 1.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INDIAN ACADEMY SCIENCES</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-02T03:54:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-02T03:54:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:53:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:40:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>PRAMANA-JOURNAL OF PHYSICS, 68(5), 819-830</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0304-4289</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12043-007-0080-y</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8649</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8649</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>