<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-3830</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:35:22Z</datestamp><dc:title>Eroded myelin figures</dc:title><dc:creator>ARUNAGIRINATHAN, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MANOHAR, C</dc:creator><dc:creator>BELLARE, JR</dc:creator><dc:subject>nonionic surfactants</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic behavior</dc:subject><dc:subject>lamellar phases</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>phosphatidylcholine</dc:subject><dc:subject>detergency</dc:subject><dc:description>Myelin figures with unusual surface morphology were observed on contacting Tween85 with water. Myelins, which are normally smooth rodlike forms in other surfactants, are in this system found to be with an irregular, rough surface with vesiclelike structures adhered to the myelin tubes. Besides these, smooth myelin figures were also observed. We term the myelin figures with a rough surface eroded myelin figures. The same myelin could show a coexistence of smooth and rough areas with a sharp boundary between the smooth surface at one end whereas the other end shows a rough texture. The transformation of smooth myelins into eroded forms were observed often whereas the reverse is quite rare. In the later stage, the tip of the eroded myelin figures transforms into tentacles and acts as a source for new myelins and the growth of vesiclelike structures which were expelled into the surrounding medium. The eroded myelin figures are stable for a longer period in comparison to simple, smooth rodlike forms. By studying the myelin growth at different temperatures, it was found that eroded myelin figures were stable in the temperature range of 22-42 degreesC and at greater than or equal to42 degreesC only smooth myelin figures were observed.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T02:04:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T02:04:10Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:47:30Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:35:22Z</dc:date><dc:date>2004</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>LANGMUIR, 20(11), 4318-4321</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0743-7463</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/la036069c</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/3830</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/3830</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>