<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-15108</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-15T14:31:12Z</datestamp><dc:title>Distributed execution of cognitive relaying with time incentive: multiple PU scenario</dc:title><dc:creator>NADKAR, T</dc:creator><dc:creator>THUMAR, V</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:subject>Cognitive radio</dc:subject><dc:subject>Symbiotic cooperative relaying</dc:subject><dc:subject>Cross-layer optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Distributed algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>OFDM</dc:subject><dc:subject>OPTIMIZATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>NETWORKS</dc:subject><dc:subject>RADIO</dc:subject><dc:description>The prime focus of this study is in developing distributed algorithms for cognitive relaying with time incentive for multiple primary users (CRTI-M). CRTI-M is a symbiotic paradigm in which the incumbent primary users (PUs) of the spectrum, with weak transmission links, seek cooperation from the cognitive secondary user (SU) nodes in their vicinity, and in return reward them with an incentive time for the latter's own communication. When relaying through the SU network, each PU can either use its own spectrum or that of the other PUs. Cross-layer optimization problems are formulated to enable both these possibilities in a multi-hop multi-channel cognitive radio network with the objective of maximizing the cumulative time incentive for the SUs. Corresponding distributed algorithms are developed, which face the challenge of meeting the constraints of the formulated problems with only local information and the lack of a centralized controller. Further, to make the CRTI-M schemes practically realizable, a MAC scheduling protocol is suggested, which gives emphasis to the distributed implementation and provides a unified framework for the PUs and SUs. Simulation results are furnished to demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed algorithms.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPRINGER INTERNATIONAL PUBLISHING AG</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:31:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-15T14:31:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2012</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EURASIP JOURNAL ON WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS AND NETWORKING,</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/1687-1499-2012-332</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/15108</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>