<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-10521</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:13Z</datestamp><dc:title>Analysis of an asymmetric polling system</dc:title><dc:creator>KHALID, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>VYAVAHARE, PD</dc:creator><dc:creator>KEKRE, HB</dc:creator><dc:subject>local area networks</dc:subject><dc:subject>net</dc:subject><dc:subject>lan</dc:subject><dc:description>Polling models are used extensively in the field of operations research to analyze the performance of a variety of systems that can be viewed as a distributed queuing system served by a single server and to evaluate their operational characteristics. In the context of computer communication, a Local Area Network (LAN) with controlled access on a single transmission media can be viewed as such a polling system in which queues are being served in cyclic order. In this article, a LAN with reverse round robin scheduling for channel arbitration, called M-net [1], is modeled as a discrete time Markov chain representing an asymmetric polling system. Expressions for its performance measures like average channel utilization, mean and variance of delay and blocking probability at a station are derived. For a system of M stations, the solution complexity is of the order of 2(2(M-1)). The analysis approach is applicable to both round robin and reverse round robin systems. Finally, performance measures of such a system are compared with that of Expressnet, as a representative example of round robin system. It is found that at lower arrival rates, the performance of M-net is comparable to that of Expressnet. However, with increasing values of arrival rates, M-net outperforms Expressnet. The analysis presented is applicable to the class of systems in operations research that can be viewed as multiple single buffer queues served by a server in round robin or reverse round robin fashion. (C) 1997 .</dc:description><dc:publisher>PERGAMON-ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-23T12:44:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-23T12:44:39Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:27Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:13Z</dc:date><dc:date>1997</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>COMPUTERS &amp; OPERATIONS RESEARCH, 24(4), 317-333</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0305-0548</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S0305-0548(96)00057-3</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/10521</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/10521</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>