<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8026</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:50Z</datestamp><dc:title>From 1 Sun to 10 Suns c-Si Cells by Optimizing Metal Grid, Metal Resistance, and Junction Depth</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAUDHARI, VA</dc:creator><dc:creator>SOLANKI, CS</dc:creator><dc:subject>solar-cells</dc:subject><dc:subject>crystalline silicon</dc:subject><dc:subject>series resistance</dc:subject><dc:subject>modules</dc:subject><dc:subject>technology</dc:subject><dc:subject>point</dc:subject><dc:description>Use of a solar cell in concentrator PV technology requires reduction in its series resistance in order to minimize the resistive power losses. The present paper discusses a methodology of reducing the series resistance of a commercial c-Si solar cell for concentrator applications, in the range of 2 to 10 suns. Step by step optimization of commercial cell in terms of grid geometry, junction depth, and electroplating of the front metal contacts is proposed. A model of resistance network of solar cell is developed and used for the optimization. Efficiency of unoptimized commercial cell at 10 suns drops by 30% of its 1 sun value corresponding to resistive power loss of about 42%. The optimized cell with grid optimization, junction optimization, electroplating, and junction optimized with electroplated contacts cell gives resistive power loss of 20%, 16%, 11%, and 8%, respectively. An efficiency gain of 3% at 10 suns for fully optimized cell is estimated.</dc:description><dc:publisher>HINDAWI PUBLISHING CORPORATION</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-31T07:16:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-31T07:16:47Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:53Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:50Z</dc:date><dc:date>2009</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF PHOTOENERGY, (), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1110-662X</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2009/827402</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8026</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8026</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>