<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-8929</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:41:25Z</datestamp><dc:title>Satellite based post graduate courses in information technology for industry professionals and engineering college teachers</dc:title><dc:creator>DESHPANDE, MU</dc:creator><dc:description>The Distance Education Program (DEP) of the Indian Institute of Technology Bombay is an innovative endeavor to deliver postgraduate courses in Information Technology to large number of learners through satellite transmission mode. The courses include the curriculum of the postgraduate programs offered live on campus at the Kanwal Rekhi School of Information Technology (KReSIT). DEP has Satellite links with training departments of industry for extending these courses to their engineers. This is in addition to similar links with the educational institutions, where participants attend classes in mornings and evenings. Currently a total of fifteen geographically dispersed Remote Centers receive these courses. In this paper, the mode of Distance education is explained against the background of the Academia-Industry collaboration as a viable model for delivering courses to assist industry professionals in upgrading their knowledge and skills and for the teachers to update their subject area knowledge. The paper also examines the advantages of synchronous accessibility of lectures via VSAT terminals in the context of learning needs and prevailing learning culture. The paper touches upon the steps taken in the ongoing experiment and outlines the challenges faced. Some strategies envisaged to overcome the challenges have also been outlined.</dc:description><dc:publisher>INST ELECTRONICS TELECOMMUNICATION ENGINEERS</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-03T06:38:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-03T06:38:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:54:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:41:25Z</dc:date><dc:date>2005</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IETE TECHNICAL REVIEW, 22(1), 43-50</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0256-4602</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/8929</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/8929</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>