<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-16038</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-17T05:13:29Z</datestamp><dc:title>Enablement of Consumer-Oriented Interoperable Systems With Integration of CIM and Green Button Standards</dc:title><dc:creator>BALIJEPALLI, VSKM</dc:creator><dc:creator>KHAPARDE, SA</dc:creator><dc:subject>CIM</dc:subject><dc:subject>consumer migration</dc:subject><dc:subject>consumer tagging</dc:subject><dc:subject>green button</dc:subject><dc:subject>NAESB</dc:subject><dc:subject>NIST</dc:subject><dc:subject>SGIP</dc:subject><dc:subject>smart grid</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMMON INFORMATION MODEL</dc:subject><dc:subject>XML</dc:subject><dc:description>Future grid evolutions promise to promote the interoperability in the consumer domain. CIM (mainly IEC61970 and IEC61968) is an established standard in the industry to enable the interoperable data exchanges at the upstream levels like generation, transmission and distribution, while the Green Button standards (OpenADE, NAESB ESPI, NIST SGIP-PAP 20, PAP10) are the emerging smart grid standards to standardize the information on energy usage, interfaces at the downstream end-consumer level. This paper presents the various modeling issues, and techniques to move toward integrating these standards to enable the interoperable services at the consumer levels. The challenging task is to identify the options to promote the interoperability between the end-consumer and upstream levels for future grid evolutions. This paper begins to address this issue by identifying the requirements like integrating the external services data from the end-consumer oriented third party tools to EMS/DMS, hierarchical tagging of consumers, combined semantics for third party applications, inter-utility migration of consumers/prosumers, and dynamic consumer/prosumer open access interactions. However, this involves extensions and mappings between the existing CIM, and the green button standards. Without affecting much the base packages, it should be either incorporated in the CIM or Green Button standards at the domain modeling as a separate package. A set of new classes and attributes to the existing CIM and the corresponding XML tags for Green Button standards to realize the integration is proposed. The authors' contributions also strengthen the arguments for creating a separate green button profile for the existing upstream standards.</dc:description><dc:publisher>IEEE-INST ELECTRICAL ELECTRONICS ENGINEERS INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:13:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-17T05:13:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>IEEE SYSTEMS JOURNAL, 7(4)681-691</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1932-8184</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>1937-9234</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSYST.2013.2254980</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/16038</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>