<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7173</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:45:16Z</datestamp><dc:title>Experimental investigations on decay heat removal in advanced nuclear reactors using single heater rod test facility: Air alone in the annular gap</dc:title><dc:creator>BOPCHE, SB</dc:creator><dc:creator>SRIDHARAN, A</dc:creator><dc:subject>pebble bed reactors</dc:subject><dc:subject>natural-convection</dc:subject><dc:subject>surface radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>droplet flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>bundles</dc:subject><dc:subject>core</dc:subject><dc:subject>coolant</dc:subject><dc:subject>water</dc:subject><dc:subject>circulation</dc:subject><dc:subject>design</dc:subject><dc:subject>radiation</dc:subject><dc:subject>decay-heat-removal</dc:subject><dc:subject>single rod</dc:subject><dc:subject>fuel bundle</dc:subject><dc:subject>nuclear</dc:subject><dc:subject>experimental</dc:subject><dc:description>During a loss of coolant accident in nuclear reactors, radiation heat transfer accounts for a significant amount of the total heat transfer in the fuel bundle. In case of heavy water moderator nuclear reactors, the decay heat of a fuel bundle enclosed in the pressure tube and outer concentric calandria tube can be transferred to the moderator. Radiation heat transfer plays a significant role in removal of decay heat from the fuel rods to the moderator, which is available outside the calandria tube. A single heater rod test facility is designed and fabricated as a part of preliminary investigations. The objective is to anticipate the capability of moderator to remove decay heat, from the reactor core, generated after shut down. The present paper focuses mainly on the role of moderator in removal of decay heat, for situation with air alone in the annular gap of pressure tube and calandria tube. It is seen that the naturally aspirated air is capable of removing the heat generated in the system compared to the standstill air or stagnant water situations. It is also seen that the flowing moderator is capable of removing a greater fraction of heat generated by the heater rod compared to a stagnant pool of boiling moderator.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE INC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-27T08:47:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-27T08:47:12Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:56:28Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:45:16Z</dc:date><dc:date>2010</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>EXPERIMENTAL THERMAL AND FLUID SCIENCE, 34(8), 1456-1474</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0894-1777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.expthermflusci.2010.07.009</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7173</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7173</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>