<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-7857</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:39:21Z</datestamp><dc:title>Factor analysis of sphericity and roundness statistics and correspondence analysis of size statistics of the sediments of Gujarat Coast</dc:title><dc:creator>BEHERA, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>SAHU, BK</dc:creator><dc:creator>BAGCHI, J</dc:creator><dc:subject>quartz grains</dc:subject><dc:subject>factor analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>correspondence analysis</dc:subject><dc:subject>sediments</dc:subject><dc:subject>gujarat coast</dc:subject><dc:description>The present study aims at characterization of beach environment of a part of Gujarat Coast (the entire Saurashtra Coast and the southern portion of Kutch Coast - all facing open sea) with respect to its physical parameters. Prevailing marine forces along with the seasonal fluvial conditions play the pivotal role in bringing out this modem sedimentary environment under discussion. The textural parameters of grain size and shape are chosen for statistical analysis and interpretation. R-mode factor analysis was carried out on the four sample statistics of two-dimensional projection sphericity and those of two-dimensional projection roundness of beach sand grains ranging in size fom 0.3 mm to 0.149 mm. The third factor loadings show that the grains possess bimodality. The factor score interpretations thereof clearly explain this phenomenon in terms of the mixing of sediments from fluvial and marine sources. Correspondence analysis was used to visually represent an interrelationship between individuals (i.e. samples) and attributes (i.e. variables such as size statistics) on the same factorial axes. It is again revealed that sorting does not co-vary with kurtosis suggesting bimodal size distribution.</dc:description><dc:publisher>GEOLOGICAL SOC INDIA</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-30T05:11:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-30T05:11:00Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:52:40Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:39:21Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF THE GEOLOGICAL SOCIETY OF INDIA, 62(1), 51-62</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0016-7622</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/7857</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/7857</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>