<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-100-14525</identifier><datestamp>2014-10-14T17:06:18Z</datestamp><dc:title>Reductive transformation of endosulfan in aqueous phase using magnesium-palladium bimetallic systems: A comparative study</dc:title><dc:creator>THANGADURAI, P</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURESH, S</dc:creator><dc:subject>Dechlorination</dc:subject><dc:subject>Desulfurization</dc:subject><dc:subject>Endosulfan</dc:subject><dc:subject>Magnesium</dc:subject><dc:subject>Palladium</dc:subject><dc:subject>PD-CU</dc:subject><dc:subject>NITRATE REDUCTION</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALPHA-ENDOSULFAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>BETA-ENDOSULFAN</dc:subject><dc:subject>SUPPORTED PD</dc:subject><dc:subject>COMPLETE DECHLORINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>CATALYTIC-ACTIVITY</dc:subject><dc:subject>HYDRODECHLORINATION</dc:subject><dc:subject>WATER</dc:subject><dc:subject>ALUMINA</dc:subject><dc:description>The efficiencies of reductive transformation of endosulfan by bimetallic systems consisting of zerovalent magnesium (Mg-0) as the electron donor and three forms of palladium as the catalyst (Pd-0-alumina, Pd-0-carbon and Pd-K-2 PdCl6) were compared in this investigation. Results revealed that both Pd-0-alumina and Pd-0-carbon were able to remove 90 and 93% of 10 mg L-1 of endosulfan, respectively in 30 min with the concomitant accumulation of trace concentrations of partially chlorinated compounds in the reaction medium. Removal of endosulfan followed first-order kinetics and the rate constant (k(obs)) value was computed to be 0.2 min(-1) for both Pd-0-alumina and Pd-0-carbon. Pd-0-carbon was relatively more stable and reusable in comparison to Pd -alumina. More than 99% of 10 mgL(-1) endosulfan was converted to hydrocarbon end product by Pd-K-2 PdCl6 system within 6 min of reaction. The formation of hydrocarbon end product suggested desulfurization and complete dechlorination of endosulfan. The efficiencies of removal of alpha and beta endosulfan isomers were nearly the same in reaction media containing acetone or Tween 80 as the pesticide solubilizing agents. Results obtained in this study suggest the possibility of developing a reactor containing immobilized palladium for the treatment of water contaminated with endosulfan. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description><dc:publisher>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</dc:publisher><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:06:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2014-10-14T17:06:18Z</dc:date><dc:date>2013</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>JOURNAL OF HAZARDOUS MATERIALS, 246245-256</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2012.12.031</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/jspui/handle/100/14525</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>