<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-4017</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:34:46Z</datestamp><dc:title>Productivity improvement in xanthan gum fermentation using multiple substrate optimization</dc:title><dc:creator>CHAITALI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>KAPADI, M</dc:creator><dc:creator>SURAISHKUMAR, GK</dc:creator><dc:creator>GUDI, RD</dc:creator><dc:subject>xanthomonas-campestris</dc:subject><dc:subject>dynamic optimization</dc:subject><dc:subject>parameter-estimation</dc:subject><dc:subject>batch fermentations</dc:subject><dc:subject>growth</dc:subject><dc:subject>cultures</dc:subject><dc:subject>state</dc:subject><dc:description>A novel and more comprehensive formulation of the optimal control problem that reflects the operational requirements of a typical industrial fermentation has been proposed in this work. This formulation has been applied to a fed-batch bioreactor with three control variables, i.e., feed rates of carbon source, nitrogen source, and an oxygen source, to result in a 148.7% increase in product formation. Xanthan gum production using Xanthomonas campestris has been used as the model system for this optimization study, and the liquid-phase oxygen supply strategy has been used to supply oxygen to the fermentation. The formulated optimization problem has several constraints associated with it due to the nature of the system. A robust stochastic technique, differential evolution, has been used to solve this challenging optimization problem. The infinite dimensional optimization problem has been approximated to a finite dimensional one by control vector parametrization. The state constraints that are path constraints have been addressed by using penalty functions and by integrating them over the total duration to ensure a feasible solution. End point constraints on final working volume of the reactor and on the final residual concentrations of carbon and nitrogen sources have been included in the problem formulation. Further, the toxicity of the oxygen source, H2O2, has been addressed by imposing a constraint on its maximum usable concentration. In addition, the initial volume of the bioreactor contents and feed concentrations have been handled as decision variables, which has enabled a well-grounded choice for their values from the optimization procedure; adhoc values are normally used in the industry. All results obtained by simulation have been validated experimentally with good agreements between experimental and simulated values.</dc:description><dc:publisher>AMER CHEMICAL SOC</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-07-14T17:10:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-07-14T17:10:44Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:34:46Z</dc:date><dc:date>2003</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>BIOTECHNOLOGY PROGRESS, 19(4), 1190-1198</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>8756-7938</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/bp0257269</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/4017</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/4017</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>