<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-9577</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</datestamp><dc:title>A kinematic-wave-based distributed watershed model using FEM, GIS and remotely sensed data</dc:title><dc:creator>REDDY, KV</dc:creator><dc:creator>ELDHO, TI</dc:creator><dc:creator>RAO, EP</dc:creator><dc:creator>HENGADE, N</dc:creator><dc:subject>finite-element model</dc:subject><dc:subject>catchment model</dc:subject><dc:subject>overland-flow</dc:subject><dc:subject>infiltration</dc:subject><dc:subject>interception</dc:subject><dc:subject>rain</dc:subject><dc:subject>finite element method</dc:subject><dc:subject>geographical information systems</dc:subject><dc:subject>infiltration</dc:subject><dc:subject>interception</dc:subject><dc:subject>kinematic wave model</dc:subject><dc:subject>remotely sensed data</dc:subject><dc:subject>watershed</dc:subject><dc:description>For the appropriate management of water resources in a watershed, it is essential to calculate the time distribution of runoff for the given rainfall event. In this paper, a kinematic-wave-based distributed watershed model using finite element method (FEM), geographical information systems (GIS) and remote-sensing-based approach is presented for the runoff simulation of small watersheds. The kinematic wave equations are solved using FEM for overland and channel flow to generate runoff at the outlet of the watershed concerned. The interception loss is calculated by an empirical model based on leaf area index (LAI). The Green-Ampt Mein Larson (GAML) model is used for the estimation of infiltration. Remotely sensed data has been used to extract land use (LU)/land cover (LC). GIS have been used to prepare finite element grid and input files such as Manning's roughness and slope. The developed overland flow model has been checked with an analytical solution for a hypothetical watershed. The model has been applied to a gauged watershed and an ungauged watershed. From the results, it is seen that the model is able to simulate the hydrographs reasonably well. A sensitivity analysis of the model is carried out with the calibrated infiltration parameters, overland flow Manning's roughness, channel flow Manning's roughness, time step and grid size. The present model is useful in predicting the hydrograph in small, ungauged watersheds. Copyright (c) 2007 , Ltd.</dc:description><dc:publisher>JOHN WILEY &amp; SONS LTD</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-16T17:49:05Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:55:04Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:43:38Z</dc:date><dc:date>2007</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>HYDROLOGICAL PROCESSES, 21(20), 2765-2777</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0885-6087</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/hyp.6490</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/9577</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/9577</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>