<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd"><identifier>ir-10054-12019</identifier><datestamp>2011-12-27T05:48:32Z</datestamp><dc:title>Tracking of multiple-point targets using multiple-model-based particle filtering in infrared image sequence</dc:title><dc:creator>ZAVERI, MA</dc:creator><dc:creator>MERCHANT, SN</dc:creator><dc:creator>DESAI, UB</dc:creator><dc:subject>monte-carlo methods</dc:subject><dc:subject>multitarget tracking</dc:subject><dc:subject>algorithms</dc:subject><dc:subject>particle filtering</dc:subject><dc:subject>interacting multiple model</dc:subject><dc:subject>automated model selection</dc:subject><dc:subject>data association</dc:subject><dc:description>Particle filtering is investigated extensively due to its importance in target tracking for nonlinear and non-Gaussian models. A particle filter can track an arbitrary trajectory only if the target dynamics models are known and the time instant when trajectory switches from one model to another model is known a priori. In real applications, it is unlikely to meet both these conditions. We propose a novel method that overcomes the lack of this knowledge. In the proposed method, an interacting multiple-model-based approach is exploited along with particle filtering. Moreover, we automate the model selection process for tracking an arbitrary trajectory. In the proposed approach, a priori information about the exact model that a target may follow is not required. Another problem with multiple trajectory tracking using a particle filter is data association, namely, observation to track fusion. For data association, we use three methods. In the first case, an implicit observation to track assignment is performed using a nearest neighbor (NN) method for data association; this is fast and easy to implement. In the second method, the uncertainty about the origin of an observation is overcome by using a centroid of measurements to evaluate weights for particles as well as to calculate the likelihood of a model. In the third method, a Markov random field (MRF)-based method is used. The MRF method enables us to exploit the neighborhood concept for data association, i.e., the association of a measurement influences an association of its neighboring measurement. (C) 2006 Society of Photo-Optical Instrumentation Engineers.</dc:description><dc:publisher>SPIE-INT SOCIETY OPTICAL ENGINEERING</dc:publisher><dc:date>2011-08-29T07:51:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-08-29T07:51:03Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-26T12:58:29Z</dc:date><dc:date>2011-12-27T05:48:32Z</dc:date><dc:date>2006</dc:date><dc:type>Article</dc:type><dc:identifier>OPTICAL ENGINEERING, 45(5), -</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>0091-3286</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/1.2205858</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://dspace.library.iitb.ac.in/xmlui/handle/10054/12019</dc:identifier><dc:identifier>http://hdl.handle.net/10054/12019</dc:identifier><dc:language>en</dc:language></oai_dc:dc>